<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
	<character>
		<version>32</version>
		<uid>3703</uid>
		<name>Rogue Halfling Criminal</name>
		<race>
			<source>1</source>
			<name>Lightfoot Halfling</name>
			<size>1</size>
			<speed>25</speed>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Halfling. The Halfling language isn't secret, but halflings are loath to share it with others. They write very little, so they don't have a rich body of literature. Their oral tradition, however, is very strong. Almost all halflings speak Common to converse with the people in whose lands they dwell or through which they are traveling.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Lucky</name>
				<text>When you roll a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Brave</name>
				<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Halfling Nimbleness</name>
				<text>You can move through the space of any creature that is of a size larger than yours.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Naturally Stealthy</name>
				<text>You can attempt to hide even when you are obscured only by a creature that is at least one size larger than you.</text>
			</feat>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>1</type>
				<value>2</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>5</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
		</race>
		<class>
			<source>1</source>
			<id>3690</id>
			<name>Rogue</name>
			<hd>2</hd>
			<wealth>4d4x10</wealth>
			<proficiency>3</proficiency>
			<proficiency>116</proficiency>
			<proficiency>100</proficiency>
			<proficiency>1</proficiency>
			<proficiency>108</proficiency>
			<proficiency>115</proficiency>
			<numClassSkills>4</numClassSkills>
			<armor>Light armor</armor>
			<weapons>Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</weapons>
			<tools>Thieves' tools, playing cards, carpenter's tools</tools>
			<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			<slotsCurrent>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
			<feat>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>At 1st level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves' tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.
    At 6th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies (in skills or with thieves' tools) to gain this benefit.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Sneak Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe's distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.
    You don't need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn't incapacitated, and you don't have disadvantage on the attack roll.
    The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as shown in the Sneak Attack column of the Rogue table.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Thieves' Cant</name>
				<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves' cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves' cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.
    In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves' guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
			</feat>
			<autolevel>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Expertise</name>
					<text>At 1st level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves' tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.
    At 6th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies (in skills or with thieves' tools) to gain this benefit.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Sneak Attack</name>
					<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe's distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.
    You don't need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn't incapacitated, and you don't have disadvantage on the attack roll.
    The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as shown in the Sneak Attack column of the Rogue table.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Thieves' Cant</name>
					<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves' cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves' cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.
    In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves' guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>2</level>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Cunning Action</name>
					<text>Starting at 2nd level, your quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can b e used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>3</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Roguish Archetype</name>
					<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you emulate in the exercise of your rogue abilities: Thief, Assassin, or Arcane Trickster, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your archetype choice grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Thief: Fast Hands</name>
					<text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, use your thieves' tools to disarm a trap or open a lock, or take the Use an Object action.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Thief: Second-Story Work</name>
					<text>Starting at 3rd level, you gain the ability to climb faster than normal; climbing no longer costs you extra movement.
    In addition, when you make a running jump, the distance you cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Dexterity modifier.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>4</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>5</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
					<text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>6</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>7</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Evasion</name>
					<text>Beginning at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon's fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>8</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>9</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Thief: Supreme Sneak</name>
					<text>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on a Dexterity (Stealth) check if you move no more than half your speed on the same turn.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>10</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>11</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Reliable Talent</name>
					<text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>12</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>13</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Thief: Use Magic Device</name>
					<text>By 13th level, you have learned enough about the workings of magic that you can improvise the use of items even when they are not intended for you. You ignore all class, race, and level requirements on the use of magic items.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>14</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Blindsense</name>
					<text>Starting at 14th level, if you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>15</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Slippery Mind</name>
					<text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>16</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>17</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Thief: Thief's Reflexes</name>
					<text>When you reach 17th level, you have become adept at laying ambushes and quickly escaping danger. You can take two turns during the first round of any combat. You take your first turn at your normal initiative and your second turn at your initiative minus 10. You can't use this feature when you are surprised.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>18</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Elusive</name>
					<text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has advantage against you while you aren't incapacitated.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>19</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>20</level>
				<spellSlotsOptional>1</spellSlotsOptional>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Stroke of Luck</name>
					<text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.
    Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<spellAbility>3</spellAbility>
		</class>
		<background>
			<name>Criminal</name>
			<align>Neutral</align>
			<personality>I never have a plan, but I'm great at making things up as I go along. Also, the best way to get me to do something is to tell me I can't do it.</personality>
			<ideals>People. I'm loyal to my friends, not to any ideal. Everyone else can take a trip on the River Styx for all I care.</ideals>
			<bonds>Welling Alderlead, my aunt, has a farm in Phandalin.  I always give her some of my ill-gotten gains.</bonds>
			<flaws>My aunt must never know the deeds I did as member of the Redbrands.</flaws>
			<feat>
				<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Deception, Stealth</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
				<text>One type of gaming set, thieves' tools</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Equipment</name>
				<text>A crowbar, a set of dark common clothes including a hood, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Feature: Criminal Contact</name>
				<text>You have a reliable and trustworthy contact who acts as your liaison to a network of other criminals. You know how to get messages to and from your contact, even over great distances; specifically, you know the local messengers, corrupt caravan masters, and seedy sailors who can deliver messages for you.</text>
			</feat>
			<mod>
				<category>4</category>
				<type>16</type>
			</mod>
			<proficiency>104</proficiency>
			<proficiency>116</proficiency>
		</background>
		<unarmed>1</unarmed>
		<abilities>8,14,12,13,10,15,</abilities>
		<hpMax>9</hpMax>
		<hpCurrent>9</hpCurrent>
		<attack>
			<name>Sneak Attack</name>
			<damage>1d6</damage>
		</attack>
		<tracker>
			<label>Thieves' Tool</label>
			<type>2</type>
			<formula>1d20+%2+%8+%8</formula>
		</tracker>
		<item>
			<name>Shortsword</name>
			<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 149</text>
			<type>5</type>
			<slot>2</slot>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d6</damage1H>
			<damageType>2</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>10</weaponProperty>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Shortbow</name>
			<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons" later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 149</text>
			<type>6</type>
			<value>25.0</value>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d6</damage1H>
			<damageType>2</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>257</weaponProperty>
			<weaponRange>80</weaponRange>
			<weaponLongRange>320</weaponLongRange>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Arrows</name>
			<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<type>7</type>
			<quantity>20</quantity>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>0.05</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Leather Armor</name>
			<text>The breastplate and shoulder protectors of this armor are made of leather that has been stiffened by being boiled in oil. The rest of the armor is made of softer and more flexible materials.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 144</text>
			<type>1</type>
			<slot>5</slot>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>10.0</weight>
			<ac>11</ac>
		</item>
		<item>
			<source>1</source>
			<name>Thieves' tools</name>
			<text>This set of tools includes a small file, a set of lock picks, a small mirror mounted on a metal handle, a set of narrow-bladed scissors, and a pair of pliers. Proficiency with these tools lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make to disarm traps or open locks.</text>
			<value>25.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Backpack</name>
			<text>A backpack can hold one cubic foot or 30 pounds of gear. You can also strap items, such as a bedroll or a coil of rope, to the outside of a backpack.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Bell</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Candle</name>
			<quantity>5</quantity>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Crowbar</name>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Hammer</name>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Piton</name>
			<quantity>10</quantity>
			<weight>0.25</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Lantern, hooded</name>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Oil (flask)</name>
			<quantity>2</quantity>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Rations (1 day)</name>
			<quantity>5</quantity>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Tinderbox</name>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Waterskin</name>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Rope, hempen (50 feet)</name>
			<weight>10.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Dark common clothes with hood</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Pouch</name>
			<text>A cloth or leather pouch can hold up to 20 sling bullets or 50 blowgun needles, among other things. A compartmentalized pouch for holding spell components is called a component pouch. A pouch can hold up to 1/5 cubic foot or 6 pounds of gear.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<container>
			<name>Money</name>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Copper (cp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.01</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Silver (sp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.1</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Electrum (ep)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.5</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Gold (gp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>15</quantity>
				<value>1.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Platinum (pp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>10.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
		</container>
		<note>
			<name>Rogue</name>
			<text>Rogues rely on skill, stealth, and their foes' vulnerabilities to get the upper hand in any situation. They have a knack for finding the solution to just about any problem.</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Background</name>
			<text>The town of Phandalin is built on the ruins of an older settlement, vacant for five centuries until some hardy settlers set about rebuilding it some years back. Drawn by stories of gold and platinum in the nearby foothills, you came to Phandalin as well, not to earn a living, but to prey on those who struck it rich. You joined a gang calling itself the Redbrands and made some decent coin as a burglar, enforcer, or fence.
	But you must have made an enemy among your fellow Redbrands. Someone set you up. On that person's word, the head of the Redbrands—a wizard called Glasstaff—tried to have you killed. You escaped, barely alive and thanking Tymora, the goddess of good fortune, for your luck. You fled Phandalin, almost penniless and with only the tools of your trade to your name.

	Personal Goal: Get Your Revenge. Someone in the Redbrands nearly got you killed, and you sure would like to know who it was. And then you'd like to take your revenge—on that person, on Glasstaff, maybe on all the Redbrands. And you just got a tip that might help you: someone named Halia Thornton also has it out for the Redbrands. She lives in Phandalin, which means showing your face to the Redbrands who still want you dead.

	Alignment: Neutral. You tend to do whatever seems best at the time. Sure, you've done some things you're not proud of, and you're not personally committed to making the world a better place. But you have no interest in causing suffering or making things worse than they already are.</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Halfling</name>
			<text>The comforts of home are the goals of most halflings' lives: a place to settle in peace and quiet, far from marauding monsters and clashing armies; a blazing fire and a generous meal; and fine drink and fine conversation. Though some halflings live out their days in remote agricultural communities, others form nomadic bands that travel constantly, lured by the open road and the wide horizon to discover the wonders of new lands and peoples. But even these wanderers love peace, food, hearth, and home, though home might be a wagon jostling along an old dirt road.
	The diminutive halflings survive in a world full of larger creatures by avoiding notice or, barring that, avoiding offense. Standing about 3 feet tall, they appear relatively harmless and so have managed to survive for centuries in the shadow of empires and on the edges of wars and political strife. They're concerned with basic needs and simple pleasures and have little use for ostentation.
	Halflings are an affable and cheerful people. They cherish the bonds of family and friendship, as well as the comforts of hearth and home, harboring few dreams of glory. Even adventurers among them usually venture into the world for reasons of community, friendship, wanderlust, or curiosity.

A halfling has a given name, a family name, and possibly a nickname. Family names are often nicknames that stuck so tenaciously they have been passed down through the generations.

Male Names: Alton, Ander, Cade, Corrin, Eldon, Errich, Finnan, Garret, Lindal, Lyle, Merric, Milo, Osborn, Perrin, Reed, Roscoe, Wellby

Female Names: Andry, Bree, Callie, Cora, Euphemia, Jillian, Kithri, Lavinia, Lidda, Merla, Nedda, Paela, Portia, Seraphina, Shaena, Trym, Vani, Verna

Family Names: Brushgather, Goodbarrel, Greenbottle, High-hill, Hilltopple, Leagallow, Tealeaf, Thorngage, Tosscobble, Underbough</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Expertise</name>
			<text>When you make a Dexterity (Stealth) check or a check using thieves' tools, your proficiency bonus is doubled. This benefit is included in your Stealth bonus.</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Common, Halfling</text>
		</note>
	</character>
</pc>
