<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Cleric" UA="Cleric">
		<name>Cleric (Forge)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Forge (UA)</name>
                <text>The gods of the forge are patrons of artisans who work with metal, from a humble blacksmith who keeps a village in horseshoes and plow blades to the mighty elf artisan whose diamond-tipped arrows of mithral have felled demon lords. The gods of the forge teach that, with patience and hard work, even the most intractable metal can transform from a lump of ore to a beautifully wrought object. Clerics of these deities quest to search for objects lost to the forces of darkness, liberate mines overrun by orcs, and uncover rare and wondrous materials necessary to create potent magic items. Followers of these gods take great pride in their work, and they are willing to craft and use heavy armor and powerful weapons to protect them. Deities of this domain include Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Forge Domain Spells </text>
                <text>1st - searing smite, shield </text>
                <text>3rd - heat metal, magic weapon </text>
                <text>5th - elemental weapon, protection from energy </text>
                <text>7th - fabricate, wall of fire </text>
                <text>9th - animate objects, creation</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Divine Domain is from Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Blessing of the Forge</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to imbue magic into a weapon or armor. At the end of a long rest, touch one nonmagical object that is a suit of armor or a simple or martial weapon. Until the end of your next long rest, the object becomes a magic item, granting a +1 bonus to AC if it's armor or a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls if it's a weapon. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain Channel Divinity: Artisan's Blessing</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create simple items. </text>
                <text>	Starting at the beginning of a short rest, you conduct a ritual to your deity that grants you the ability to craft a finished item that is at least part metal. The item is completed at the end of the rest. </text>
                <text>	The object can be worth no more than 100 gp, and as part of this ritual you must expend metals, such as coins or other finished items, with a value equal to the item you want to make. The item can be an exact duplicate of a nonmagical item, such as a copy of a key, if you possess the original during your short rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Soul of the Forge</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, your mastery of the forge grants you a number of special abilities: </text>
                <text>• You gain a +1 bonus to AC while you are wearing medium or heavy armor. </text>
                <text>• You gain resistance to fire damage. </text>
                <text>• When you hit a construct with an attack, you deal additional force damage to it equal to your cleric level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with the fiery power of the forge. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 fire damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Saint of Forge and Fire</name>
                <text>At 17th level, your affinity for fire and metal becomes more powerful due to your deity's blessing. You gain immunity to fire damage, and while you're wearing heavy armor, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
