<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
  <subclass baseclass="Fighter">
	<name>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Arcane Archer (UA)</name>
		<text>An Arcane Archer studies a unique elven method of archery that weaves magic into attacks to produce supernatural effects. Among elves, Arcane Archers are some of their most elite warriors. These archers stand watch over the fringes of elven domains, keeping a keen eye out for trespassers and using magic-infused arrows to defeat monsters and invaders before they can reach elven settlements. Over the centuries, the methods of these elf archers have been learned by members of other races who can also balance arcane aptitude with archery.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Arrow</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn to channel magic into your attacks with a longbow or shortbow.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Create Magic Arrow:</text>
		<text>	As a bonus action on your turn, you can create one magic arrow in your hand. The arrow lasts until the end of the turn or until it hits or misses a target. You can fire the arrow from a shortbow or longbow. The arrow is a magic weapon that deals an additional 2d6 force damage on a hit.</text>
		<text>	You have two uses of this feature, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Arcane Shot:</text>
		<text>	When you gain this feature, you learn two Arcane Shot options of your choice (see the Arcane Shots section below). Whenever you create a magic arrow with this feature, you can apply the benefits of one of your Arcane Shot options to that arrow.</text>
		<text>	You gain an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice at 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Archer's Lore</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you learn a few skills relating to the typical duties of an Arcane Archer. You learn to understand magical theory and develop survival skills for wandering the wilds.</text>
		<text>	You gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Arcana, Athletics, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Conjure Arrows</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you learn a minor but useful magical trick. As an action, you can conjure 20 nonmagical arrows. The arrows appear in your hand or in a container, such as a quiver, on your body. The arrows remain for 10 minutes or until you use this feature again; they then vanish.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (3rd)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (4th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Ever-Ready Arrow</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, you can conjure forth a magic-infused arrow more often than before. One minute after expending your last remaining use of Arcane Arrow, you regain one use of it.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (5th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Deadly Arrow</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your Arcane Arrow's bonus damage increases to 4d6 force damage.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (6th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </subclass>
</compendium>