<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Bard" HB="HB">
		<name>Bard (Virtue)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Bard College: College of Virtue</name>
				<text> e movements of the celestial bodies and the delicate dance of the planes of existence create a form of music, one reflected in the orderly universe. The College of Virtue emerged as an institution devoted to its study and to preserve the universe’s harmony against those forces of chaos and destruction that would disrupt it. Steeped in religious mysticism, the College’s bards act as forces of good and order in the world, working to thwart evil wherever they  nd it and uplift others with the music they create. Most see themselves as holy warriors, champions of the gods, and they commit their lives to furthering their interests in the material plane.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Virtue: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Upon joining the College of Virtue at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in medium armor and shields. Additionally, you gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text>
				<proficiency>Wisdom</proficiency>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Virtue: Music of the Spheres</name>
				<text>Also at 3rd level, you learn how to make the music of the heavens and inspire others to greatness. When a creature you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration. Roll a Bardic Inspiration die and add the number to the total of the creature’s attack roll. You can use this feature after the creature makes the roll, but before the GM determines whether the attack roll succeeds or fails. If the target of the attack is a fiend or undead, it takes extra radiant damage equal to the number rolled on the Bardic Inspiration die.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Virtue: Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, when you take the Attack action.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Virtue: Bolstering Words</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you speak with the voice of heaven. Your words bolster confidence and awaken courage in others. As a bonus action, you can choose one creature within 60 feet of you. If the target creature can see and hear you, you can expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration and roll the Bardic Inspiration die. The target creature gains a number of temporary hit points equal to the number rolled. These temporary hit points last until they are lost or the target creature completes a long rest. While it has these temporary hit points, the creature becomes immune to the frightened condition.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>