<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<race name="Elf (Drow)" source="PHB">
		<name>Elf (Drow)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Cha 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Superior Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to the depths of the Underdark, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Sunlight Sensitivity</name>
			<text>You have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight when you, the target of your attack, or whatever you are trying to perceive is in direct sunlight.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Drow Magic</name>
			<text>You know the dancing lights cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can cast the faerie fire spell once per day; you must finish a long rest in order to cast the spell again using this trait. When you reach 5th level, you can also cast the darkness spell once per day; you must finish a long rest in order to cast the spell again using this trait. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
		</trait>
		<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
		<spells>Dancing Lights, Faerie Fire, Darkness</spells>
		<trait>
			<name>Drow Weapon Training</name>
			<text>You have proficiency with rapiers, shortswords, and hand crossbows.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Elf (Eladrin DMG)" source="DMG">
		<name>Elf (Eladrin DMG)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Int 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Elf Weapon Training</name>
			<text>You have proficiency with the longsword, shortsword, shortbow, and longbow.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Step</name>
			<text>You can cast the misty step spell once using this trait. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		</trait>
		<spells>Misty Step</spells>
	</race>
	<race name="Elf (High)" source="PHB">
		<name>Elf (High)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Int 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Elvish, and one extra language of your choice. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Elf Weapon Training</name>
			<text>You have proficiency with the longsword, shortsword, shortbow, and longbow.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Cantrip</name>
			<text>You know one cantrip of your choice from the wizard spell list. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for it.</text>
		</trait>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	</race>
	<race name="Elf (Wood)" source="PHB">
		<name>Elf (Wood)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>35</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Wis 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Elf Weapon Training</name>
			<text>You have proficiency with the longsword, shortsword, shortbow, and longbow.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fleet of Foot</name>
			<text>Your base walking speed increases to 35 feet.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Mask of the Wild</name>
			<text>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Elf (Eladrin)" source="MToF">
		<name>Elf (Eladrin)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Cha 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Seasons</name>
			<text>Eladrin are elves native to the Feywild, a realm of beauty, unpredictable emotion, and boundless magic. An eladrin is associated witb one of the four seasons and has coloration reminiscent of that season, which can also affect the eladrin's mood:</text>
			<text>	Autumn is the season of peace and goodwill, when summer's harvest is shared with all.</text>
			<text>	Winter is the season of contemplation and dolor, when the vibrant energy of the world slumbers.</text>
			<text>	Spring is the season of cheerfulness and celebration, marked by merriment as winter's sorrow passes.</text>
			<text>	Summer is the season of boldness and aggression. a time of unfettered energy.</text>
			<text>	Some eladrin remain associated with a particular season for their entire lives, whereas other eladrin transform, adopting characteristics of a new season.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>When finishing a long rest, any eladrin can change their season. An eladrin might choose the season that is present in the world or perhaps the season that most closely matches the eladrin's current emotional state. For example, an eladrin might shift to autumn if filled with contentment, another eladrin could change to winter if plunged into sorrow, still another might be bursting with joy and become an eladrin of spring, and fury might cause an eladrin to change to summer.</text>
			<text>	The following tables offer personality suggestions for eladrin of each season. You can roll on the tables or use them as inspiration for characteristics of your own.</text>
			<text>	AUTUMN</text>
			<text>	d4 Autumn Personality Trait</text>
			<text>	1  If someone is in need, you never withhold aid.</text>
			<text>	2  You share what you have, with little regard for your own needs.</text>
			<text>	3  There are no simple meals, only lavish feasts.</text>
			<text>	4  You stock up on fine food and drink. You hate going</text>
			<text>	without such comforts.</text>
			<text>	d4 Autumn Flaw</text>
			<text>	1  You trust others without a second thought.</text>
			<text>	2  You give to others, to the point that you leave yourself without necessary supplies.</text>
			<text>	3  Everyone is your friend, or a potential friend.</text>
			<text>	4  You spend excessively on creature comforts.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>	WINTER</text>
			<text>	d4 Winter Personality Trait</text>
			<text>	1  The worst case is the most likely to occur.</text>
			<text>	2  You preserve what you have. Better to be hungry to· day and have food for tomorrow.</text>
			<text>	3  Life is full of dangers, but you are ready for them.</text>
			<text>	4  A penny spent is a penny lost forever.</text>
			<text>	Winter Flaw</text>
			<text>	1  Everything dies eventually. Why bother building anything that is supposedly meant to last?</text>
			<text>	2  Nothing matters to you, and you allow others to guide your actions.</text>
			<text>	3  Your needs come first. In winter, all must watch out for themselves.</text>
			<text>	4  You speak only to point out the flaws in others' plans.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>	SPRING</text>
			<text>	Spring Personality Trait</text>
			<text>	1  Every day is the greatest day ofyour life.</text>
			<text>	2  You approach everything with enthusiasm, even the most mundane chores.</text>
			<text>	3  You love music and song. You supply a tune yourself if no one else can.</text>
			<text>	4  You can't stay still.</text>
			<text>	Spring Flaw</text>
			<text>	1  You overdrink.</text>
			<text>	2  Toil is for drudges. Yours should be a life of leisure.</text>
			<text>	3  A pretty face infatuates you in an instant, but your fancy passes with equal speed.</text>
			<text>	4  Anything worth doing is worth doing again and again.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>	SUMMER</text>
			<text>	d4 Summer Personality Trait</text>
			<text>	1  You believe that direct confrontation is the best way to solve problems.</text>
			<text>	2  Overwhelming force can accomplish almost anything. The tougher the problem, the more force you apply.</text>
			<text>	3  You stand tall and strong so that others can lean on you.</text>
			<text>	4  You maintain an intimidating front. It's better to prevent fights with a show offorce than to harm others.</text>
			<text>	d4 Summer Flaw</text>
			<text>	1  You are stubborn. Let others change.</text>
			<text>	2  The best option is one that is swift, unexpected, and overwhelming.</text>
			<text>	3  Punch first. Talk later.</text>
			<text>	4  Your fury can carry you through anything.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Step</name>
			<text>As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. Once you use this trait, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			<text>When you reach 3rd level, your Fey Step gains an additional effect based on your season; if the effect requires a saving throw, the DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier:</text>
			<text>	Autumn. Immediately after you use your Fey Step, up to two creatures of your choice that you can see within 10 feet ofyou must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you for 1 minute, or until you or your companions deal any damage to it.</text>
			<text>	Winter. When you use your Fey Step, one creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you before you teleport must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</text>
			<text>	Spring. When you use your Fey Step, you can touch one willing creature within 5 feet of you. That creature then teleports instead of you, appearing in an unoccupied space of your choice that you can see within 30 feet ofyou.</text>
			<text>	Summer. Immediately after you use your Fey Step, each creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet ofyou takes fire damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage).</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Elf (Sea)" source="MToF">
		<name>Elf (Sea)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Con 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Elvish, and Aquan. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Sea Elf Training</name>
			<text>You have proficiency with the spear, trident, light crossbow, and net.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Child of the Sea</name>
			<text>You have a swimming speed of 30 feet, and you can breathe air and water.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Friend of the Sea</name>
			<text>Using gestures and sounds, you can communicate simple ideas with any beast that has an innate swimming speed.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Elf (Shadar-Kai)" source="MToF">
		<name>Elf (Shadar-Kai)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Con 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to twilit forests and the night sky, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common, and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Necrotic Resistance</name>
			<text>You have resistance to necrotic damage.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Blessing of the Raven Queen</name>
			<text>As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see. Once you use this trait, you can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			<text>	Starting at 3rd level, you also gain resistance to all damage when you teleport using this trait. The resistance lasts until the start of your next turn. During that time, you appear ghostly and translucent.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
</compendium>
