<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Paladin" HB="HB">
		<name>Paladin (Perfection)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Sacred Oath: Oath of the Perfection</name>
				<text>Though many would perceive those who swear the Oath of Perfection as arrogant and prideful, nothing could be further from the truth. Paladins who swear this oath are driven to excel, and fear no hard work to do so. The Oath of Perfection urges paladins who swear it to become the best swordsmen, peerless riders, paragons of virtue, and fearless leaders. A paladin who swears the Oath of Perfection seeks  awless beauty—beauty in the most perfect strike of a sword that wastes no effort, beauty in the perfectly chosen word to sway the mind of the king, beauty in taking that one perfect step to avoid the charging manticore. The paladins who swear this Oath are constantly honing their skills and seeking to better themselves, and their internal perfection is often reflected by an outward flawlessness.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Tenets of the Perfection</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Swearing an Oath of Perfection is a pledge to always strive to be the very best and eradicate one's  aws. An Oath of Perfection is an oath of personal achievement and refinement; while some who swear such an oath might encourage others around them to similarly strive for perfection, the tenets of an Oath of Perfection bind only the paladin who gives it.</text>
				<text>	Eliminate Flaws: To reach the apex of your skill, you must focus  rst on eliminating  aws. Keep yourself free or corruption, vice, and weakness. So too should you strive to eliminate those who corrupt and wound the world around you; if something is willfully making the world worse, it is your sacred duty to stop it.</text>
				<text>	Perfection Comes Through Practice: There is no such thing as natural perfection; you might be gifted in an area, but you are not born perfect. Only through hard work, continuous practice, and constant reflection and self-evaluation can perfection be achieved.</text>
				<text>	Blemishes are to be Pitied, Not Scorned: Not everyone can devote their lives to the pursuit of perfection and mastery, and the world is full of people who are flawed, physically or otherwise. They are not to be scorned, shunned, judged, or rejected. Instead, it is your duty to offer them comfort, succor, and aid.</text>
				<text>	Only the Gods can be Truly Perfect: No matter how great your skill, no matter how perfect your execution, no matter how beautiful your appearance, you will never achieve perfection. Do not allow yourself to give into the flaw of pride by believing that you are perfect in any way; only the gods can be truly perfect, and you are no god.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Perfection: Oath Spells</name>
				<text>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>3rd - comprehend languages, healing word</text>
				<text/>
				<text>5th - enhance ability, lesser restoration</text>
				<text/>
				<text>9th - dispel magic, protection from energy</text>
				<text/>
				<text>13th - death ward, freedom of movement</text>
				<text/>
				<text>17th - greater restoration, mass cure wounds</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Perfection Channel Divinity: Divine Skill</name>
				<text>As an action, you can imbue yourself with positive energy, using your Channel Divinity. For 1 minute, your proficiency bonus is doubled for ability checks you make that use one skill that you choose at the time that you use this feature. You cannot choose a skill in which you already gain double your proficiency bonus when used. If you fall unconscious, the effect ends.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Perfection Channel Divinity: Unearthly Precision</name>
				<text>When you make an attack roll, after you roll you can suffuse the attack with positive energy, using your Channel Divinity. You use a 19 instead of the number you rolled on the die for that attack roll.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Perfection: Aura of the Unblemished</name>
				<text>Beginning at 7th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you are immune to petrification and any effect that would alter your physical form against your will.</text>
				<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Perfection: Unmarred</name>
				<text>Starting at 15th level, when you are at your maximum hit points, you reduce all bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons by 10.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Perfection: Apex of Perfection</name>
				<text>At 20th level, as an action, you can transform into a perfect specimen of your kind, shedding all flaws and blemishes like a snake shedding its skin. For 1 minute, you are immune to being blinded, charmed, deafened, frightened, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, or stunned. Additionally, for the duration, at the start of each of your turns you regain 10 hit points, and any severed or destroyed body parts reform instantaneously.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until youfinish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Paladin (Perfection)">
		<index name="Comprehend Languages"/>
		<index name="Healing Word"/>
		<index name="Enhance Ability"/>
		<index name="Lesser Restoration"/>
		<index name="Dispel Magic"/>
		<index name="Protection from Energy"/>
		<index name="Death Ward"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Greater Restoration"/>
		<index name="Mass Cure Wounds"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
