<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Paladin" HB="HB">
		<name>Paladin (Ascetic)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Sacred Oath: Oath of the Ascetic</name>
				<text>The Oath of the Ascetic is a rejection of possessions and material wealth, positing such things lead only to temptation and corruption of the spirit. Ascetics live simply, embracing their poverty to better understand themselves and their devotion to their god. As noble and virtuous as other paladins, they strive to be examples to others, to live unimpeachable lives and devote themselves to helping others. Ascetics wear simple and unadorned armor, if they bother with it. When not fighting, they don simple clothing, looking like the commoners they fight to protect.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Tenets of Poverty</text>
				<text/>
				<text>The Oath of the Ascetic liberates the paladin from temptations and encourages humility and virtue. It has four basic tenets:</text>
				<text>	Humility: Be humble in all dealings with others. All are equal in the eyes of the gods.</text>
				<text>	Charity: Keep only what you need to survive and give all excess to those in need.</text>
				<text>	Temperance: Your body is a temple, so treat it as such. Eat and drink only what is needed to sustain you.</text>
				<text>	Courage: Do what must be done with enthusiasm and zeal, but have the wisdom to know when such action would be futile.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Ascetic: Oath Spells</name>
				<text>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>3rd - mage armor, purify food and drink</text>
				<text/>
				<text>5th - lesser restoration, warding bond</text>
				<text/>
				<text>9th - create food and water, mass healing word</text>
				<text/>
				<text>13th - aura of purity, freedom of movement</text>
				<text/>
				<text>17th - greater restoration, mass cure wounds</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Ascetic Channel Divinity: Armor of Faith</name>
				<text>As an action, you can surround yourself in an invisible field of force using your Channel Divinity. For 1 minute, you add your Charisma modifier to your Armor Class and to all saving throws (minimum +1). In addition, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin level (minimum of 1 temporary hit point). The temporary hit points remain until lost or you use this Channel Divinity option again. If you fall unconscious, this effect ends.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Ascetic Channel Divinity: Blessing of Courage</name>
				<text>You can use your Channel Divinity to bestow a blessing onto an ally. As an action, one creature within 30 feet of you gains temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin level (minimum of 1 temporary hit point). While the creature has these temporary hit points, it has advantage on saving throws made to resist being frightened.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Ascetic: Aura of Sacrifice</name>
				<text>Starting at 7th level, your sel ess nature manifests as a palpable aura that protects people around you. Whenever a creature within 10 feet of you takes damage, you can choose to take some or all of that damage on behalf of that creature.</text>
				<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Ascetic: Temple of Flesh</name>
				<text>Beginning at 15th level, you become as a living temple. You cannot be physically scarred by any means. You are immune to petrification, poison, and any effect that would change your form. You no longer need to eat or drink, though you can do so if you wish. Finally, you appear to be at the prime of your life and do not physically age, though you still die when your time is up.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of the Ascetic: Embodiment of Virtue</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you achieve a state of physical perfection that exempli es the best qualities of your race. You permanently gain 20 hit points and when you spend a Hit Die to regain hit points, you always regain the maximum number of hit points. In addition, whenever you would make a saving throw using an ability other than Charisma, you can make a Charisma saving throw instead.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Paladin (Ascetic)">
		<index name="Mage Armor"/>
		<index name="Purify Food and Drink"/>
		<index name="Lesser Restoration"/>
		<index name="Warding Bond"/>
		<index name="Create Food and Water"/>
		<index name="Mass Healing Word"/>
		<index name="Aura of Purity"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Greater Restoration"/>
		<index name="Mass Cure Wounds"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
