<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Monk" HB="HB">
		<name>Monk (Atonement)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Monastic Tradition: Way of Atonement</name>
				<text>Monks of the Way of Atonement seek absolve themselves for their past transgressions, sins, and current indiscretions by giving up their possessions and atoning through peaceful and sel ess service. Seeking not the zealot's path, they believe that through calming and controlling their fervor, they can bolster the universal well-being of all mortal creatures. These monks seek to protect delicate balance struck by the presence of the pantheons and strike out in malice only to defend those who can't defend themselves from the greater evils that lurk within this realm and beyond.</text>
				<text>	Feared by those with wealth, and praised by those who lack it, these monks are easy to spot in their dusty burlap robes and bare feet. The Atoned sacrifice, not only in material possessions but, flesh to find their way to forgiveness and often carve or brand the markings of the gods on their skin in homage.</text>
				<text>	In exchange for the strength to seek perfect purity in an existence full of ambition and hubris, followers of this path endeavor to abstain from anger, envy, and corruption. Not so naïve as to believe that the gods' designs won't require skirting the edges of temptation, and sometimes justify ends by their means, they willingly pay the price in flesh for their actions. As part of their atonement, they learn to encourage wicked and vile denizens of their world to repent using only a heavy, unadorned club that each refers to as their penance.</text>
				<text>	To take this path, the acolyte must commit to the poorest lifestyle, renouncing all that they were before atonement.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of Atonement: Atonement</name>
				<text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can channel your vitality to fuel your wrath. You have a pool of Atonement Dice, represented by a number of d8s equal to your monk level which you can use to empower your Way of Atonement features.</text>
				<text>	You regain all expended dice when you atone at the end of a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	Atonement requires deep contemplation, and usually making amends for the pain you inflict on others by inflicting that pain on yourself during contemplation or prayer. To atone, roll the Atonement Dice you spent and add them together. You deal bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage to yourself equal to the total. You deal this damage after you regain hit points from any Hit Dice you spend at the end of a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of Atonement: Penance</name>
				<text>Also at 3rd level, you learn a ritual prayer that creates a divine bond between you and one of civilization's earliest weapons, the club. You perform these prayers over the course of 1 hour, which can be during a short rest.</text>
				<text>	During this ritual, you carve notches that represent your past atonements, and each time you take a short rest, you're compelled to consider any additional sins you have committed and add notches to its stock to atone. While your penance is paid, your weapon is bonded to you, counts as your monk weapon, and can't be disarmed of that weapon unless you are incapacitated.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of Atonement: Strength of Faith</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you learn to focus your anger to strike harder, delivering justice with your penance at the expense of your own vitality.</text>
				<text>	When you hit with an unarmed attack or a club, you can channel your zeal through your ki and spend Atonement Dice to add an additional 2d8 force damage for each you spend. When you use this feature, you can expend 1 ki point and spend a number of Atonement Dice equal to half your monk level or less.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of Atonement: Armament of Atonement</name>
				<text>At 6th level, your strict adherence of a simple life has earned you the gods' favor. When you wield your penance in one hand, and nothing in the other, you gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls with your penance and unarmed strikes. Your penance and unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage. While you hold this weapon, you gain a +1 bonus to Armor Class and saving throws.</text>
				<text>	This bonus to attack, damage, AC, and saves increases to +2 at 8th level, +3 at 13th level, and +4 at 18th level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you reach 6th level, you lose 1 Atonement Die for each permanent magic item you currently own, except for your penance, and lose 1 Atonement Die whenever you acquire a new permanent magic item. You can't regain these Atonement Dice when you atone until you no longer possess the magic item.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of Atonement: Labor of the Gods</name>
				<text>At 11th level, constant suffering has made you no stranger to pain. When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can use your reaction to spend an Atonement Die, roll it, and recover hit points equal to that number plus your Constitution modifier. You can't use this feature again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	At 17th level, you gain one additional use of this feature between rests, and can spend any number of Atonement Dice to when you do.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of Atonement: Enlightened Voice</name>
				<text>Starting at 17th level, your time spent in quiet contemplation, prayer and servitude has granted you supreme wisdom. Whenever you make an ability or skill check that you aren't proficient with, you can spend 1 ki point to gain proficiency in that check and use your Wisdom modifier in place of the skill's ability modifier. Additionally, when in counsel with any creature that you're able to speak with, and can understand you, you can spend a number of Atonement Dice equal to half your monk level or less and add the total to the result of any one Charisma, Intelligence, or Wisdom check or saving throw.</text>
				<text>	You can't use this feature again until you complete a short or long rest. If you use this feature to deceive or bribe, you can't use it again until you complete a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>