<race>
  <name>Aligrine</name>
  <ability>Dexterity 2, Charisma 1</ability>
  <speed>30</speed>
  <size>M</size>
  
  <trait>
	<name>Physical Description</name>
	<text>Any aligrine is remarkably similar to that of a human, albeit with an unusually fair complexion and slender frame. They tend to be slightly taller and thinner than humans, and often have hair and eyes of unusual matching, but soft hues—pale yellow, light green, auburn, and others. Most notably, however, are the magnificent pair of feathered wings on the back of every aligrine. These wings usually bear feathers of the same hue as the aligrine's hair and eyes, but may resemble the wings of other creatures depending upon one's heritage. </text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
	<name>History</name>
	<text>Native to the elemental plane of air, these rather intelligent beings were cast out to the material plane for an unknown reason by a powerful genie. Over time, the aligrine evolved to the material plane: primarily stronger leg muscles, albeit at the cost of less powerful and glorious wings.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
	<name>Society</name>
	<text>Aligrine tend to be nomadic and impermanent, favoring freedom over the power and security of large settlements. They generally form temporary settlements in trees, mountains, or other places out of reach from most predators, and survive through hunting and gathering. Generally, aligrines are intolerant of other races, xenophobic, and whenever possible stick to their own kind. Humans and halflings in particular are generally seen as inferior counterparts due to being physiologically similar to aligrines, but lacking wings. Those of this race tend to be similarly condescending towards most other terrestrial races. Only begrudgingly are aarakockra or angelic beings to be peers, but aligrines even then prefer to avoid intermingling of any sort. </text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
	<name>Aligrine Names</name>
	<text>Male: Cargaep, Mynock, Magitus </text>
	<text>Female: Anonious, Calulup, Varveil </text>
	</trait>
<trait>
<name>Age</name>
<text>Algrine matuer much slower than other races. THey mature at 30 years old and the oldest of the Aligrine can reach 400 years old.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Alignment</name>
<text>Aligrine typically rely on their own judgement for their actions and have a strong moral compass. It is rare for an Aligrine to be Evil.</name>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Size</name>
<text>Aligrine tend to be similar in build to humans. Although Aligrine tend to be taller and weigh slightly less than humans. Your size is Medium.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Wings</name>
<text>Although your wings are weaker than those of your ancestors, you can still maintain modest flight. You have a fly speed of 30 feet. You cannot use this fly speed while wearing heavy armor, nor while you are encumbered.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Keen Senses</name>
<text>Your ancestors developed keen senses in the elemtal plain of air. You have proficiency in Perception.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Languages</name>
<text>You can read, write, and speak both Auran and Common.</text>
</trait>
</race>
