<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
<race>
<name>Alleozsa</name>
<size>M</size>
<speed>25</speed>
<trait>
<name>Physical Description</name>
<text>The Alleozsa are Astral beings in a constant state of flux. Their bodies are always shigting in size, shape, and color.If they are in a brightly-lit area, the Alleozsa may sine in a multitude of colors. At times, they are able to control their colors. In darkness, the Alleoza are nearly invisble, seen only as a slight blur of blues, purples, or greens.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>History</name>
<text>Alleozsa hail from a plane of existence known only to their own kind,. After a catstrophic event on their plane, the Alleozsa forced their way into the forgotten Realms, wher ethey sought refuge in caverns of rare gems. Slowly, the Alleozsa began to integrate into societ, some even finding jobs after several yares. Though it has been a long time since their break from the plane of their birth, their peregnination to the Forgotten Realms is still a touchy subject. It is unwise to ask an Alleozsa about this part of their history. At best, they will refuse to explain. At worst, they may lash out at you for prying.</text>
</trait>
<name>Society</name>
<text>THe Alleozsa are extremely driven and independent. Once set upon a task, an Alleozsa will stop at nothing to complete it. When they reach their much-coveted goal, Alleoza feel no satisfaction, instead immediately seeking out another task to busy themselves. Desperate for a new objective, they become lost and desperate. Should an Alleozsa fail to meet its mark, it may become irritated and distant. Alleozsa have been known to vanish for weeks ore even months at a time after a Particularly shameful failure. Alleozsa congregate in places where lots of light reflects and refracts, or in places with no light whatsover. The Alleozsa are extremely independnet, and while they can enjoy the company of one another, they feel compelled to show others that they are competent on their own. </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Alleozsa Names</name>
<text>Alleozsa are partial to names refrencing gemstones. Others may refer to themselves at their favored colors.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Age</name>
<text>Alleozsa are created and instantly mature. They live about 200 to 250 years before they dissipate from existence.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Alignment</name>
<text>Alleozsa are always true neutral</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Size</name>
<text> Alleozsa usually stand aroudn 6 ft tall and are virtually weightless. Your size is Medium.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Astral Energy</name>
<text>You can cast the speak with dead spell once per day, requiring no material components. You regain the ability to do so once you complete a long rest.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
  <name>Darkvision</name>
  <text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
  </trait>
<trait>
  <name>Levitation</name>
  <text>You float a few feet above the ground. This allows you to ignore most forms of difficult terrain and make you immune to being knocked prone. However, you can float no higher than 5 feet and when you are reduced to 0 hit points you stop hovering. In addition, while falling you are treated as if under the effect of the feather fall spell.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
  <name>Languages</name>
  <text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language of your choice.</text>
</trait>
</race>
</compendium>
  
