<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
<race>
<name>Aloii</name>
<size>M</size>
<speed>35</speed>
<ability>Dexterity 1, Constitution 1, Intelligence 1</ability>
<trait>
<name>Aloii</name>
<text>Highly logical, liquid metal beings with a thirst for knowledge</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Physical Description</name>
<text>Aloii are humanoid beings made entirely of what appears to be liquid metal. Their bodies run the gamut from dull iron to gleaming silver in appearance. However, the material of which Aloii are actually comprised is a jealously guarded secret kept by their first creator (presumed dead). </text>
<text  />
<text>Aloii are usually tall and slender with virtually featureless faces. They have slight evidence of eye depressions and a shallowly raised, angular area which could be interpreted as a nose. Most have no mouth to speak of (a thin, bowed line at most where a mouth ought to be.) What features are evident tend to be sharp and angular in males and more gently curved in females. </text>
<text  />
<text>Aloii bodies, in their default state, are so soft and malleable that they cannot support the weight of much more than light fabrics. As such, they are unable to wear even the lightest of armors nor can they wield a weapon (Though they can still make minor, temporary exertions for simple tasks such as opening doors, etc.). Instead, they have been created with the ability to selectively harden their bodies when attacked. Aloii are only able to do this very briefly without exhausting themselves. As they live longer and gain better control of their abilities they become more skilled at this and can harden larger portions of their bodies for longer. </text>
<text  />
<text>In lieu of traditional weapons, Aloii use the amorphous nature of their bodies to form their limbs into exact replicas of the weapons they choose to use. At the beginning, an Aloii only knows how to form a select few weapons. It is possible, however, for them to learn others under the correct circumstances. </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>History</name>
<text>The first two Aloii were created by a Genasi Scholar centuries ago as servants. Aloii historians say that the scholar had intended to craft 2 living statues. One to stand guard before his tower and the other to perform tasks within it. </text>
<text  />
<text>In time, the scholar and his servants (dubbed 1 and 2 by their successors) passed into the pages of history. His notes and other information about Aloii as well as his other creations have been lost. Yet, Aloii remain and have flourished. </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Society</name>
<text>Aloii are very independent, purpose-driven beings. When Aloii are born, they already know their purpose. They need not be taught how to perform the basic tasks required by their class and often spend little time in the community of their birth; preferring to go out into the world and fulfill their purpose. </text>
<text  />
<text>Aloii live in small communities on the outskirts of developed settlements. They prefer to be near colleges and other places of learning. They are loosely knit communities’ mostly consisting of a few male/female pairs. One community is much like another as one Aloii is much like another. It is easy for an Aloii from one community to slip into the society of another. </text>
<text  />
<text>A very logical race, they think in much the same way machine would. The concepts of humor and sarcasm are beyond them as they take all things literally. A Halfling stumbling upon one of their communities reported than conversing with one of them was “much like talking to a distracted adding machine.” </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Aloii Names</name>
<text>Aloii do not have names like other races do. Instead they have strings of numbers. The numbers build upon each other and, as more Aloii are created they are each assigned the next number in the sequence. As their numbers have become quite lengthy over the generations, most Aloii refer to each other by the last digit or two in their number. Aloii are always created in pairs, one male, one female. As such, males tend to have odd numbers and females tend to have even. </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Age</name>
<text>Aloii do not age as other beings do. They are essentially immortal as far as years are concerned. The original two Aloii may still be around, though none know for sure.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Alignment</name>
<text>Aloii are not restricted to any particular alignment</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Size</name>
<text> Aloii are about the same size as humans, ranging from 5 to 6 feet tall. Your size is Medium.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Speed</name>
<text>Your base walking speed is 35 feet. Aloii also have the Amorphous Movement trait which allows them to move through openings at half their movement speed.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Amorphous Movement</name>
<text>Due to the fluidity of their bodies, Aloii can alter their shape to fit through any opening larger than 2 inches in diameter. When moving outside of their natural shape, Aloii are only able to move at half speed.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Darkvision</name>
<text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Liquid Body</name>
<text>Aloii cannot wear armor or wield weaponry of any kind</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Liquimetal Weaponry</name>
<text>As an action, you can transform one of your limbs into a replica of one of a weapon that you are proficient in or back to your original hands. All weapon properties such as finesse, versatile, and two-handed apply. In addition, while you cannot wear armor you can take on the hardness as if you were wearing armor as an action, provided you are proficient in that armor and that armor is present. The armor is then absorbed into you and you gain all the properties of that armor as if you were wearing it.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Living Construct</name>
<text> Even though you were constructed, you are a living creature. You are immune to diseases. You do not need to eat or breathe, but you can ingest food and drink if you wish. Instead of sleeping, you enter an inactive state for 4 hours each day. You do not dream in this state; you are fully aware of your surroundings and notice approaching enemies and other events as normal.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Languages</name>
<text>You speak Common and Aloii. Aloii is a language unique to its people. To the lay person, it sounds like a thick bubbling similar to magma or molten metal and it uses the Primordial Terran script.</text>
</trait>
</race>
</compendium>
