<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
<race>
<name>Alu-Demon (Royal Bloodline)</name>
<size>M</size>
<ability>Constitution 2, Strength 1</ability>
<speed>30</speed>
<trait>
<name>Alu-Demons</name>
<text>Alu-Demons are horrid creatures, the progeny of one mortal and one demon parent. Distrust against these beings usually serves as a means of self-preservation for most people, rather than prejudice.</text>
  <text  />
  <text>Alu-Demons of this bloodline descend from or are the direct spawn of the Demon Lords. These Lords include, but aren't limited to: Fraz-Urb'luu, Graz'zt, Orcus, Demogorgon, and Yeenoghu</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Monstrous At Best</name>
    <text> While most physical characteristics differ between Alu-Demons depending on the nature of their demonic lineage, all share a few basic traits. Alu-Demons are bipedal and roughly humanoid in appearance. Their facial features are a mix of both their mundane, mortal bloodline, and the horrifying demonic visage: For example, an elven Alu-Demon may retain the pointed ears of their people, but also possess the blackened skin and curved forehead-mounted horn of a Babau. A human Alu-Demon may have fair white skin, with the compound, bug-like eyes of the Chasme. The more mundane Alu-Demons are sometimes mistaken for Tieflings; however, Alu-Demon traits tend to be much more gruesome and bizarre than their infernal cousins. Other examples of demonic traits include sharpened claws, an exterior skull, gray, black, or green skin, ram horns, boney protrusions, or a leathery tail. </text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Progeny of the Abyss</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons are, by nature, cruel, vicious beings, with the taint of a demonic bloodline corrupting everything they do. While an Alu-Demon is all too happy to kill, maim, and destroy on a whim, working with a team of adventurers requires a bit more coercion.</text>
    <text  />
    <text>Alu-Demons are highly motivated by greed, lust, and the baser impulses. While an Alu-Demon will happily annihilate a team of Orcs attacking the village, the difficulty is in stopping the Alu-Demon from annihilating the village, too. Adventuring teams may find them difficult to work with unless they maintain sufficient bribes in the form of treasure and promises of future slaughters. </text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Society</name>
    <text>On the mortal planes, Alu-Demons tend to integrate with already established communities in which their parents live. If too outlandish appearing, or if the natives are superstitious enough, they can be exiled. Pure Alu-Demon communities are few and lacking in structural economies, although they can exist. </text>
    <text  />
    <text>In the Abyss, however, Alu-Demons fit in quite well with the savage nature of the realm. They tend to stick close to parents, either in cooperation or in service. Alu-Demons traveling alone in the Abyss tend to naturally gravitate towards a Layer holding their own kind. </text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Alu-Demon Names</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons are often proud of their heritage and will name themselves either partially or entirely after other demon species. Other Alu-Demons will base their names on the Abyssal root words for evil or immoral concepts. Almost all Alu-Demons pride their names on being difficult or uncomfortable to speak and pronounce. </text>
    <text  />
    <text>Male: Abraxes, Forneus, Cthugha, Valas, Kazri, Yochlo, Kastig, Maurez </text>
    <text  />
    <text>Female: Kali, Zhah, Bali Raj, Nyogtha, Bebeli, Orla, Maril, Shizu </text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Age</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons mature at the same rate as normal humans, but their deomic bloodline allows them to live indefinetely well over 1,000 years.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Alignment</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons are innately chaotic evil. Alu-Demons of other alignments must constantly battle against their natural urges.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Size</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons range in size, from just taller than a dwarf, to well over 8 feet tall. Your size is Medium.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Speed</name>
    <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Darkvision</name>
    <text>Thanks to your demonic heritage, you can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in the darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray. Due to their evil natures, some Alu-Demons see shades of red or green as opposed to shades of gray.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Demonic Resistance</name>
    <text>You have resistance to poison damage and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Unholy Weakness</name>
    <text>Due to your abyssal nature, you are vulnerable to radiant damage.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Natural Armor</name>
    <text>Your skin is scaled and hardened due to your demonic lineage. While unarmored, your Armor Class is equal to 13 + your dexterity modifier</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Demon Blood</name>
    <text>You have a clear demonic lineage. Your creature type is fiend and humanoid.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Languages</name>
    <text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Abyssal, and one other language of your choice</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Savage Attacks</name>
    <text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapons damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of a critical hit.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Abyssal Endurance</name>
    <text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can’t use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
  </trait>
</race>  

<race>
<name>Alu-Demon (Obyrith Bloodline)</name>
<size>M</size>
<ability>Constitution 2, Intelligence 1</ability>
<speed>30</speed>
<trait>
<name>Alu-Demons</name>
<text>Alu-Demons are horrid creatures, the progeny of one mortal and one demon parent. Distrust against these beings usually serves as a means of self-preservation for most people, rather than prejudice.</text>
  <text  />
  <text>Alu-Demons with an Obyrinth bloodline are not descended from actual demons, but rather from aberrations, Great Old ones, and other monsters so hideous as to be unimaginable. Obyrinth Alu-Demons may fare from the Far Realms, or from the deepest, unnamed layers of the Abyss. Residents of these locations include Lord Dagon, Cthulhu, dretches, hezrous, krakens, and many others.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Monstrous At Best</name>
    <text> While most physical characteristics differ between Alu-Demons depending on the nature of their demonic lineage, all share a few basic traits. Alu-Demons are bipedal and roughly humanoid in appearance. Their facial features are a mix of both their mundane, mortal bloodline, and the horrifying demonic visage: For example, an elven Alu-Demon may retain the pointed ears of their people, but also possess the blackened skin and curved forehead-mounted horn of a Babau. A human Alu-Demon may have fair white skin, with the compound, bug-like eyes of the Chasme. The more mundane Alu-Demons are sometimes mistaken for Tieflings; however, Alu-Demon traits tend to be much more gruesome and bizarre than their infernal cousins. Other examples of demonic traits include sharpened claws, an exterior skull, gray, black, or green skin, ram horns, boney protrusions, or a leathery tail. </text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Progeny of the Abyss</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons are, by nature, cruel, vicious beings, with the taint of a demonic bloodline corrupting everything they do. While an Alu-Demon is all too happy to kill, maim, and destroy on a whim, working with a team of adventurers requires a bit more coercion.</text>
    <text  />
    <text>Alu-Demons are highly motivated by greed, lust, and the baser impulses. While an Alu-Demon will happily annihilate a team of Orcs attacking the village, the difficulty is in stopping the Alu-Demon from annihilating the village, too. Adventuring teams may find them difficult to work with unless they maintain sufficient bribes in the form of treasure and promises of future slaughters. </text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Society</name>
    <text>On the mortal planes, Alu-Demons tend to integrate with already established communities in which their parents live. If too outlandish appearing, or if the natives are superstitious enough, they can be exiled. Pure Alu-Demon communities are few and lacking in structural economies, although they can exist. </text>
    <text  />
    <text>In the Abyss, however, Alu-Demons fit in quite well with the savage nature of the realm. They tend to stick close to parents, either in cooperation or in service. Alu-Demons traveling alone in the Abyss tend to naturally gravitate towards a Layer holding their own kind. </text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Alu-Demon Names</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons are often proud of their heritage and will name themselves either partially or entirely after other demon species. Other Alu-Demons will base their names on the Abyssal root words for evil or immoral concepts. Almost all Alu-Demons pride their names on being difficult or uncomfortable to speak and pronounce. </text>
    <text  />
    <text>Male: Abraxes, Forneus, Cthugha, Valas, Kazri, Yochlo, Kastig, Maurez </text>
    <text  />
    <text>Female: Kali, Zhah, Bali Raj, Nyogtha, Bebeli, Orla, Maril, Shizu </text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Age</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons mature at the same rate as normal humans, but their deomic bloodline allows them to live indefinetely well over 1,000 years.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Alignment</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons are innately chaotic evil. Alu-Demons of other alignments must constantly battle against their natural urges.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Size</name>
    <text>Alu-Demons range in size, from just taller than a dwarf, to well over 8 feet tall. Your size is Medium.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Speed</name>
    <text>Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Darkvision</name>
    <text>Thanks to your demonic heritage, you can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in the darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray. Due to their evil natures, some Alu-Demons see shades of red or green as opposed to shades of gray.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Demonic Resistance</name>
    <text>You have resistance to poison damage and have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Unholy Weakness</name>
    <text>Due to your abyssal nature, you are vulnerable to radiant damage.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Natural Armor</name>
    <text>Your skin is scaled and hardened due to your demonic lineage. While unarmored, your Armor Class is equal to 13 + your dexterity modifier</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Demon Blood</name>
    <text>You have a clear demonic lineage. Your creature type is fiend and humanoid.</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Languages</name>
    <text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Abyssal, and one other language of your choice</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Tongue of Ancient Lands</name>
    <text>You can speak, read, and write Deep Speech instead of Abyssal</text>
  </trait>
  <trait>
    <name>Aberrant Ancestry</name>
    <text>You have advantage on all Intelligence and Wisdom saving throws against magic</text>
  </trait>
  </race>
</compendium>
  
  
      
