<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
  <compendium version="5">
   <race>
		 <name>Alu-Fiend</name>
		 <size>M</size>
		 <speed>30</speed>
		 <ability>Dexterity 1, Wisdom 1, Charisma 1</ability>
		 <trait>
			 <name>Alu-Fiend</name>
			 <text>"Less commonly, a succubus or incubus reproduces with a humanoid. From this unholy union, a cambion child is conceived. Invariably, the fiendish offspring is as wicked as its fiendish parent."  -5e Monster Manual </text>
			 <text  />
			 <text>Alu-fiends are the female spawn from the union between a Succubus/Incubus and another race (typically human). Naturally charismatic, this race maintains the power of presence and desire for intimacy that is characteristic of their demonic parent. </text>
		 </trait>
		 <trait>
			 <name>Physical Description</name>
			 <text>An Alu-fiend may inherit a number of physical traits from their demonic parent. Glowing eyes, a tail, claws, bat-like wings and horns are among the most common of these potential appendages. Aside from these, they ultimately appear as an exceptionally beautiful form of whatever race their other parent was. Unlike Succubi/Incubi, Alu-fiends do not have the power of shape-shifting for long periods of time. Some go to great lengths to try and conceal their origins, covering their horns and hiding their tails in public to avoid suspicion. Bolder and more boastful Alu-Fiends, however, embrace their dark heritage, showing off their abilities and publicly denouncing all who would persecute them.</text>
		 </trait>
		 <trait>
			 <name>Species</name>
			 <text>Occasionally when a Succubus/Incubus seduces a humanoid, they refrain from murdering the poor soul for some reason (it's almost never through compassion; usually it's because they were slain or called elsewhere by a greater fiend before they could complete the deed). Whether it is a male humanoid or female one, both unions with a Succubus/Incubus have the potential to create an Alu-fiend. Alu-fiends are always female. From its hellish origin, the Alu-Fiend is gifted with an innate ability to deceive and/or beguile others. They also have a need for companionship like no other race does. Like their demonic parent, an Alu-fiend craves interaction as much as they crave air. Unlike their demonic parent, however, their desire for socialization is not exclusive to sex. Any form of social interaction that their mortal half might enjoy, becomes a need as immediate as any other form of sustenance. They are practically a race of social butterflies. Because of this, sometimes an Alu-fiend or Cambion (their male counterpart) will reject their evil origins, and seek to use their powers for good. </text>
		 </trait>
		 <trait>
			 <name>Society</name>
			 <text>If raised by her non-demon parent, the Alu-fiend is likely to endure a great amount of prejudice levied against her. Few societies will allow a demon to be raised alongside their children; if they allow the demon to live at all. Nine out of ten times a non-demon who parents a demonic child will be run out of town, at best. An Alu-fiends one saving grace in this regard is their naturally charismatic presence. Even at a young age, an Alu-fiend is capable of melting the hardest of hearts with their supernaturally infectious smile. While this natural charm isn't enough to stop villagers from ostracizing the half-demon, it makes it hard for them to gather up an angry mob against the child-like Alu-fiend. </text>
				 <text  />
				 <text>An Alu-fiend also matures faster than a human does. This adds to feelings of isolation she might feel growing up - which is especially detrimental to a race who craves social interaction as much as an Alu-fiend. Most will leave home around this time, seeking out some form of identity and a society that will accept them. Choosing to hide their appearance will make it much easier to find a new village, where no one knows her parentage. However, with her natural charm, it isn't impossible for an Alu-fiend to find acceptance somewhere even if she chooses not to hide. </text>
		 </trait>
		 <trait>
			 <name>History</name>
			 <text>Given the nature of an Alu-fiends conception, relatively few are known to have existed. However, given the Alu-fiends extended lifetime and their insatiable desire for social interaction, there are several stories associated with them that one could find if they knew where to look. Stories exist of Alu-fiends who made no attempts to hide who they were are obviously easier to find. However, most of these stories appear to end with the dead at the hand of a Demon Hunter. There are also more stories, however, of famously charming and well-respected women who (upon very close inspection) are likely to be Alu-fiends as well. Then there are rumours of devious and dangerous women who would throw extravagant parties, always ending with guests found drained of their life essence. Though there is no way to know if these were Alu-fiends or not. To someone who knows what they are looking for, there are a plethora of rumours or tales of individuals who could potentially have been Alu-fiends. </text>
				 <text  />
				 <text>Despite this, the fact that an Alu-fiend can live exceptionally long, disguise their appearance, and seeks out companionship wherever they go; raises the question of whether all of these stories sprinkled throughout history detail the lives of all different Alu-fiends or are the snapshots into the lives of only a handful. </text>
		 </trait>
		 
