<race>
  <name>Cave Goron</name>
  <size>M</size>
  <speed>20</speed>
  <Ability>Strength 1, Constitution 2, Dexterity -2</Ability>
 <trait>
  <name>Physiology</name>
  <text>Built like mountains, eating rocks, wading through lava -- Gorons are nothing if not hardy and impregnable.</text>
	<text  />
	<text>Gorons stand taller and wider than hylians, and universally have skin of an orange-brown hue. What little "hair" they possess is so stiff and thick it resembles solid rock, and usually grows only high on a goron's scalp and across its upper back. A few gorons are also able to grow beards or other facial hair, especially if they are of advanced age. A pair of goron eyes are wide set, perfectly circular, and completely dark—possessing no whites like those of a hylian's or gerudo's eyes. Goron noses are flat. Jaws are very wide, powerful, and composed entirely of molars—used to crush and pulverize the rocks which famously make up goron diets. </text>
  <text  />
  <text>Although they are physiologically more similar to earth elementals than mammals, gorons nonetheless take a humanoid shape. They are required to eat and sleep to live. Drinking serves no purpose for them. They can persist indefinitely without breathing, but doing so is unpleasant, especially when the goron is exerting itself. Mysteriously, gorons dine on rocks and other solid minerals—tastes vary between tribes, as some prefer coarse ores, others savor gemstones, but they generally dislike less solid earth such as sand or dirt. A few dine on more traditional foods such as meat or mushrooms, but this seems to be for pleasure rather than sustenance. </text>
  <text  />
  <text>Because they are literally made of rock, gorons have an inherent durability to their bodies, but are also particularly dense and heavy. This makes traditional movement difficult for them over anything but short distances. When traveling more than a few feet, a goron will usually tuck itself into a ball and roll, which allows it to traverse ground at much greater speed. This speed of this "goron roll" combined with a goron's weight makes it a powerful charging attack for chasing down foes. Aside from this, gorons battle with powerful punches—punches so powerful that fighting unarmed is the norm in their race. </text>
  <text  />
  <text>Gorons only possess one apparent sex, which they universally refer to as male. "Brother" is a very common term of endearment among them, and friends of a goron tribe are often referred to as brothers—regardless of whether or not they are male. </text>
 </trait>
 <trait>
   <name>Society</name>
	 <text>Living underground and inside of cavernous hills, your people are well adapted to subterranean life. Cave gorons are generally more sociable with other races, and are significantly more populous than their mountainous counterparts. </text>
	 <text  />
   <text>Goron cities and villages are almost universally built into caves or the sides of mountains, where the tastiest and most nutritious rocks are abundant. Their reliance on eating rocks makes their cultures particularly dependent on mining to survive, to the extent that the majority of gorons have experience in this profession. Many anthropologists believe gorons evolved to be as physically powerful and enduring as they are due to their race's inherent dependency on mining. Stronger gorons with greater strength made better miners, which enabled them to better survive and provide for their kin. </text>
   <text  />
<text>Due to their mining dependency, goron culture heavily involves stonework and the working of metals. Blacksmiths are abundant among them, and their structures are constructed almost entirely of metal. They're also one of few races that have widely adopted the use of explosive powder, and when in battle they often make use of bombs or other explosives. Their resistance to heat gives them an edge over most foes when using such powerful, but esoteric weapons. </text>
<text  />
<text>Gorons almost always place a high degree of value on physical strength and stamina, pride, honesty, and trustworthiness. Gorons most readily get along with races which share these values, usually including the like of subrosians, rito, and most hylians. A friend is rarely lost on a goron unless that friend is caught in a lie. Unsurprisingly, gorons often have a difficult time with people from less prideful cultures. </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Goron Names</name>
<text>Although gorons only have one gender, all goron names are all considered male. These names more often than not consist of at least one "go" or "da" syllable. Deep vowel sounds such as "ah," "oh," and "oo" are prominent. "R" consonants are also very common, especially in the center of the name. </text>
<text  />><text>Male: Biggoron, Darbus, Daruk, Darmani, Darunia, Gongoron, Gorko, Gortram, Kabetta, Kagoron, Lyndae, Medigoron, Reagah, Rohan, Strade, Tanko, Volcon, Yunobo </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
<text>Your Strength and Constitution scores each increase by 1 each, but your Dexterity score decreases by 2.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Age</name>
<text>Gorons reach adulthood in 9 to 12 years but can live to be over 100.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Alignment</name>
<text>Although gorons can alienate those outside their kin group, they form strong bonds with those they trust. They have a tendency towards lawful good.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Size</name>
<text> Gorons are usually between 6 and 8 feet in height, and quite stocky. Your size is Medium.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Speed</name>
<text>Your base walking speed is 20 ft.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Stone Armor</name>
<text>When you aren’t wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use this natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor. While you use your natural armor, you are vulnerable to thunder damage.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Stone Fists</name>
<text>Your unarmed strike inflicts bludgeoning damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Goron Roll</name>
<text>When you use your action to Dash action, you can increase your speed by 40 feet instead of the normal amount. If you take the Dash action and move at least 20 feet straight towards a creature, you can make an unarmed strike against that creature as a bonus action.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Weighted</name>
<text>You sink to the bottom of any body of water you enter. You have disadvantage on ability checks and saving throws made to keep your balance or avoid being knocked prone.</text<
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Languages</name>
<text>You can speak, read, and writ Common and Goro.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Volcanic Native</name>
<text>You can endure unusually dry or hot climates without difficulty. Your body cannot catch flame.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Darkvison</name>
<text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Goron Grit</name>
<text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a lvl.</text>
</trait>
</race>

<race>
  <name>Mountain Goron</name>
  <size>M</size>
  <speed>20</speed>
  <Ability>Strength 2, Constitution 1, Dexterity -2</Ability>
 <trait>
  <name>Physiology</name>
  <text>Built like mountains, eating rocks, wading through lava -- Gorons are nothing if not hardy and impregnable.</text>
	<text  />
	<text>Gorons stand taller and wider than hylians, and universally have skin of an orange-brown hue. What little "hair" they possess is so stiff and thick it resembles solid rock, and usually grows only high on a goron's scalp and across its upper back. A few gorons are also able to grow beards or other facial hair, especially if they are of advanced age. A pair of goron eyes are wide set, perfectly circular, and completely dark—possessing no whites like those of a hylian's or gerudo's eyes. Goron noses are flat. Jaws are very wide, powerful, and composed entirely of molars—used to crush and pulverize the rocks which famously make up goron diets. </text>
  <text  />
  <text>Although they are physiologically more similar to earth elementals than mammals, gorons nonetheless take a humanoid shape. They are required to eat and sleep to live. Drinking serves no purpose for them. They can persist indefinitely without breathing, but doing so is unpleasant, especially when the goron is exerting itself. Mysteriously, gorons dine on rocks and other solid minerals—tastes vary between tribes, as some prefer coarse ores, others savor gemstones, but they generally dislike less solid earth such as sand or dirt. A few dine on more traditional foods such as meat or mushrooms, but this seems to be for pleasure rather than sustenance. </text>
  <text  />
  <text>Because they are literally made of rock, gorons have an inherent durability to their bodies, but are also particularly dense and heavy. This makes traditional movement difficult for them over anything but short distances. When traveling more than a few feet, a goron will usually tuck itself into a ball and roll, which allows it to traverse ground at much greater speed. This speed of this "goron roll" combined with a goron's weight makes it a powerful charging attack for chasing down foes. Aside from this, gorons battle with powerful punches—punches so powerful that fighting unarmed is the norm in their race. </text>
  <text  />
  <text>Gorons only possess one apparent sex, which they universally refer to as male. "Brother" is a very common term of endearment among them, and friends of a goron tribe are often referred to as brothers—regardless of whether or not they are male. </text>
 </trait>
 <trait>
   <name>Society</name>
	 <text>Living atop mountains and hills, your people are taller and more athletic than other gorons. These tribes tend to live in relative isolation.  </text>
	 <text  />
   <text>Goron cities and villages are almost universally built into caves or the sides of mountains, where the tastiest and most nutritious rocks are abundant. Their reliance on eating rocks makes their cultures particularly dependent on mining to survive, to the extent that the majority of gorons have experience in this profession. Many anthropologists believe gorons evolved to be as physically powerful and enduring as they are due to their race's inherent dependency on mining. Stronger gorons with greater strength made better miners, which enabled them to better survive and provide for their kin. </text>
   <text  />
<text>Due to their mining dependency, goron culture heavily involves stonework and the working of metals. Blacksmiths are abundant among them, and their structures are constructed almost entirely of metal. They're also one of few races that have widely adopted the use of explosive powder, and when in battle they often make use of bombs or other explosives. Their resistance to heat gives them an edge over most foes when using such powerful, but esoteric weapons. </text>
<text  />
<text>Gorons almost always place a high degree of value on physical strength and stamina, pride, honesty, and trustworthiness. Gorons most readily get along with races which share these values, usually including the like of subrosians, rito, and most hylians. A friend is rarely lost on a goron unless that friend is caught in a lie. Unsurprisingly, gorons often have a difficult time with people from less prideful cultures. </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Goron Names</name>
<text>Although gorons only have one gender, all goron names are all considered male. These names more often than not consist of at least one "go" or "da" syllable. Deep vowel sounds such as "ah," "oh," and "oo" are prominent. "R" consonants are also very common, especially in the center of the name. </text>
<text  />
<text>Male: Biggoron, Darbus, Daruk, Darmani, Darunia, Gongoron, Gorko, Gortram, Kabetta, Kagoron, Lyndae, Medigoron, Reagah, Rohan, Strade, Tanko, Volcon, Yunobo </text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
<text>Your Strength and Constitution scores each increase by 1 each, but your Dexterity score decreases by 2.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Age</name>
<text>Gorons reach adulthood in 9 to 12 years but can live to be over 100.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Alignment</name>
<text>Although gorons can alienate those outside their kin group, they form strong bonds with those they trust. They have a tendency towards lawful good.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Size</name>
<text> Gorons are usually between 6 and 8 feet in height, and quite stocky. Your size is Medium.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Speed</name>
<text>Your base walking speed is 20 ft.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Stone Armor</name>
<text>When you aren’t wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use this natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield’s benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor. While you use your natural armor, you are vulnerable to thunder damage.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Stone Fists</name>
<text>Your unarmed strike inflicts bludgeoning damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Goron Roll</name>
<text>When you use your action to Dash action, you can increase your speed by 40 feet instead of the normal amount. If you take the Dash action and move at least 20 feet straight towards a creature, you can make an unarmed strike against that creature as a bonus action.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Weighted</name>
<text>You sink to the bottom of any body of water you enter. You have disadvantage on ability checks and saving throws made to keep your balance or avoid being knocked prone.</text<
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Languages</name>
<text>You can speak, read, and writ Common and Goro.</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Natural Athlete</name>
<text>you are proficient in the Athletics skill</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Fire Resistance</name>
<text>You have resistance to fire damage, and do not catch flame</text>
</trait>
<trait>
<name>Breathless</name>
<text>You can hold your breath indefinitely. While you hold your breath for longer than you would otherwise be able, however, you have disadvantage on all ability checks and attack rolls.</text>
</trait>
</race>
