<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><compendium version="5" auto_indent="YES">
	<item>		<name>Bullets (Modern)</name>		<type>A</type>		<weight>0.1</weight>		<text>The ammunition of a firearm is destroyed upon use. Modern firearms use bullets. </text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Dynamite (Stick)</name>		<type>G</type>		<weight>1</weight>		<text>Dynamite is a modern-era explosive.</text>		<text>As an action, a creature can light a s tick of dynamite and throw it at a point up to 60 feet away. Each creature within 5 feet of that point must make a DC 12 Dexterity saving throw, taking 3d6 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>		<text>A character can bind sticks of dynamite together so they explode at the same time. Each additional stick increases the damage by 1d6 (to a maximum of 10d6) and the burst radius by 5 feet (to a maximum of 20 feet).</text>		<text>Dynamite can be rigged with a longer fuse to explode after a set amount of time, usually 1 to 6 rounds. Roll initiative for the dynamite. After the set number of rounds goes by, the dynamite explodes on that initiative.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Fragmentation Grenade</name>		<type>G</type>		<weight>1</weight>		<text>A fragmentation grenade is a modern-era explosive.</text>		<text>As an action, a character can throw a grenade at a point up to 60 feet away. With a grenade launcher, the character can propel the grenade up to 120 feet away.</text>		<text>Each creature within 20 feet of an exploding fragmentation grenade must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 5d6 piercing damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Grenade Launcher</name>		<type>G</type>		<weight>7</weight>		<text>A grenade launcher is a modern-era item.</text>		<text>With a grenade launcher, a character can propel a grenade up to 120 feet away.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Smoke Grenade</name>		<type>G</type>		<weight>2</weight>		<text>A smoke grenade is a modern-era explosive</text>		<text>As an action, a character can throw a grenade at a point up to 60 feet away. With a grenade launcher, the character can propel the grenade up to 120 feet away.</text>		<text>One round after a smoke grenade lands, it emits a cloud of smoke that creates a heavily obscured area in a 20-foot radius. A moderate wind (at least 10 miles per hour) disperses the smoke in 4 rounds; a strong wind (20 or more miles per hour) disperses it in 1 round.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Forced Entry Unit</name>		<type>HA</type>		<ac>18</ac>		<strength>13</strength>		<stealth>YES</stealth>		<weight>20</weight>		<text>A forced entry unit is modern armot.  It provides resistance to ballistic and slashing damage.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Land Warrior Armor</name>		<type>HA</type>		<ac>17</ac>		<strength>13</strength>		<stealth>YES</stealth>		<weight>10</weight>		<text>Land warrior armor is modern armor.  It reduces damage from ballistic or slashing attacks by 5.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Special Response Vest</name>		<type>HA</type>		<ac>15</ac>		<strength>10</strength>		<stealth>YES</stealth>		<weight>15</weight>		<text>A special response vest is modern armor.  It provides resistance to ballistic damage.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Heavy Coat</name>		<type>LA</type>		<ac>11</ac>		<stealth>YES</stealth>		<weight>6</weight>		<text>A heavy coat is modern armor.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Kevlar-Lined Coat</name>		<type>LA</type>		<ac>12</ac>		<weight>8</weight>		<text>A kevlar-lined coat is modern armor.  It reduces damage from ballistic attacks by 2.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Leather Jacket</name>		<type>LA</type>		<ac>11</ac>		<weight>4</weight>		<text>A leather jacket is modern armor.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Light Undercover Shirt</name>		<type>LA</type>		<ac>11</ac>		<weight>2</weight>		<text>A light undercover shirt is modern armor.  It reduces damage from ballistic attacks by 2.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Undercover Vest</name>		<type>LA</type>		<ac>13</ac>		<weight>3</weight>		<text>An undercover vest is modern armor.  It reduces damage from ballistic attacks by 2.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Concealable Vest</name>		<type>MA</type>		<ac>13</ac>		<weight>4</weight>		<text>A concealable vest is modern armor.  It reduces damage from ballistic attacks by 3.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Light-Duty Vest</name>		<type>MA</type>		<ac>14</ac>		<weight>8</weight>		<text>A light-duty vest is modern armor.  It reduces damage from ballistic attacks by 3.  Additionally, you may apply up to 3 points of your Dex modifier to your AC while wearing it if your Dexterity is 16 or higher.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Tactical Vest</name>		<type>MA</type>		<ac>15</ac>		<strength>10</strength>		<stealth>YES</stealth>		<weight>10</weight>		<text>A tactical vest is modern armor.  It provides resistance to ballistic damage.</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Behind the Screens: My New d20 Modern Campaign</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Automatic Pistol</name>		<type>R</type>		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>		<weight>3</weight>		<property>A</property>		<range>50/150</range>		<text>An automatic pistol is a modern-era firearm.</text>		<text>Reload (15 Shots): A limited number of shots can be made with a weapon that has the reload property. A character must then reload it using an action or a bonus action (the character's choice).</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Automatic Rifle</name>		<type>R</type>		<dmg1>2d8</dmg1>		<weight>8</weight>		<property>A,2H</property>		<range>80/240</range>		<text>An automatic rifle is a modern-era firearm.</text>		<text>Burst Fire: A weapon that has the burst fire property can make a normal single-target attack, or it can spray a 10-foot-cube area within normal range with shots. Each creature in the area must succeed on a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw or take the weapon's normal damage. This action uses ten pieces of ammunition.</text>		<text>Reload (30 Shots): A limited number of shots can be made with a weapon that has the reload property. A character must then reload it using an action or a bonus action (the character's choice).</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Hunting Rifle</name>		<type>R</type>		<dmg1>2d10</dmg1>		<weight>8</weight>		<property>A,2H</property>		<range>80/240</range>		<text>A hunting rifle is a modern-era firearm.</text>		<text>Reload (5 Shots): A limited number of shots can be made with a weapon that has the reload property. A character must then reload it using an action or a bonus action (the character's choice).</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Revolver</name>		<type>R</type>		<dmg1>2d8</dmg1>		<weight>3</weight>		<property>A</property>		<range>40/120</range>		<text>A revolver is a modern-era firearm.</text>		<text>Reload (6 Shots): A limited number of shots can be made with a weapon that has the reload property. A character must then reload it using an action or a bonus action (the character's choice).</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
	<item>		<name>Shotgun</name>		<type>R</type>		<dmg1>2d8</dmg1>		<weight>7</weight>		<property>A,2H</property>		<range>30/90</range>		<text>A shotgun is a modern-era firearm.</text>		<text>Reload (2 Shots): A limited number of shots can be made with a weapon that has the reload property. A character must then reload it using an action or a bonus action (the character's choice).</text>		<text />		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide p. 267</text>	</item>
</compendium>
