<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<!--Mordenkainen's Tome of Foes-->
	<item>
		<name>Greater Silver Sword</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>6</weight>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a creature that has psionic ability</text>
		<text>This magic weapon grants a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it. While you hold the sword, you have advantage on Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws, you are immune to being charmed, and you have resistance to psychic damage. In addition, if you score a critical hit with it against a creature's astral body, you can cut the silvery cord that tethers the target to its material body, instead of dealing damage.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands when you attack with it.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +3</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +3</modifier>
		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
		<dmg2/>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>M,H,2H</property>
		<range/>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Infernal Tack</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a creature of evil alignment</text>
		<text>A narzugon binds a nightmare to its service with infernal tack, which consists of a bridle, bit, reins, saddle, stirrups, and spurs. A nightmare equipped with infernal tack must serve whoever wears the spurs until the wearer dies or the tack is removed. You can use an action to call a nightmare equipped with infernal tack by clashing the spurs together or scraping them through blood. The nightmare appears at the start of your next turn, within 20 feet of you. It acts as your ally and takes its turn on your initiative count. It remains for 1 day, until you or it dies, or until you dismiss it as an action. If the nightmare dies, it reforms in the Nine Hells within 24 hours, after which you can summon it again. The tack doesn't conjure a nightmare from thin air; one must first be subdued so the tack can be placed on it. No nightmare accepts this forced servitude willingly, but some eventually form strong loyalties to their masters and become true partners in evil.</text>
	</item>
</compendium>
