<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<!--Princes of the Apocalypse-->
	<item>
		<name>Drown</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>4</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>T,V</property>
		<range>20/60</range>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>A steel trident decorated with bronze barnacles along the upper part of its haft, Drown has a sea-green jewel just below the tines and a silver shell at the end of its haft. It floats on the surface if dropped onto water, and it floats in place if it is released underwater. The trident is always cool to the touch, and it is immune to any damage due to exposure to water. Drown contains a spark of Olhydra, the Princess of Evil Water.</text>
		<text>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. When you hit with it, the targets take an extra 1d8 cold damage.</text>
		<text>Water Mastery: You gain the following benefits while you hold Drown:</text>
		<text>• You can speak Aquan fluently.</text>
		<text>• You have resistance to cold damage.</text>
		<text>• You can cast dominate monster (save DC 17) on a water elemental. Once you have done so, Drown can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>Tears of Endless Anguish: While inside a water node, you can perform a ritual called the Tears of Endless Anguish, using Drown to create a devastation orb of water (see the devastation orb description for the time and cost of the ritual). Once you perform the ritual, Drown can't be used to perform the ritual again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>Flaw: Drown makes its wielder covetous. While attuned to the weapon, you gain the following flaw: "I demand and deserve the largest share of the spoils, and I refuse to part with anything that's mine." In addition, if you are attuned to Drown for 24 consecutive hours, barnacles form on your skin. The barnacles can be removed with a greater restoration spell or similar magic, but not while you are attuned to the weapon.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 224</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
		<roll>1d8</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Ironfang</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>A war pick forged from a single piece of iron, Ironfang has a fang-like head inscribed with ancient runes. The pick is heavy in the hand, but when the wielder swings the pick in anger, the weapon seems almost weightless. This weapon is immune to any form of rust, acid, or corrosion — nothing seems to mark it. Ironfang contains a spark of Ogremoch, the Prince of Evil Earth.</text>
		<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. When you hit with it, the target takes an extra 1d8 thunder damage.</text>
		<text>Earth Mastery: You gain the following benefits while you hold Ironfang:</text>
		<text>• You can speak Terran fluently.</text>
		<text>• You have resistance to acid damage.</text>
		<text>• You have tremorsense out to a range of 60 feet.</text>
		<text>• You can sense the presence of precious metals and stones within 60 feet of you, but not their exact location.</text>
		<text>• You can cast dominate monster (save DC 17) on an earth elemental. Once you have done so, Ironfang can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>Shatter: Ironfang has 3 charges. You can use your action to expend 1 charge and cast the 2nd-level version of shatter (DC 17). Ironfang regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
		<text>The Rumbling: While inside an earth node, you can perform a ritual called the Rumbling, using Ironfang to create a devastation orb of earth (see the devastation orb description for the time and cost of the ritual). Once you perform the ritual, Ironfang can't be used to perform the ritual again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>Flaw: Ironfang heightens its wielder's destructive nature. While attuned to the weapon, you gain the following flaw: "I like to break things and cause ruin."</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 224</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
		<roll>1d8</roll>
		<roll>1d3</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Orcsplitter</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>7</weight>
		<dmg1>1d12</dmg1>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>H,2H</property>
		<text>Requires Attunement by a good-aligned dwarf, fighter, or paladin</text>
		<text/>
		<text>A mighty axe wielded long ago by the dwarf king Torhild Flametongue, Orcsplitter is a battered weapon that appears unremarkable at first glance. Its head is graven with the Dwarvish runes for "orc", but the runes are depicted with a gap or slash through the markings; the word "orc" is literally split in two.</text>
		<text>You gain the following benefits while holding this magic weapon:</text>
		<text>• You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with it.</text>
		<text>• When you roll a 20 on an attack roll with this weapon against an orc, that orc must succeed on a DC 17 Constitution saving throw or drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<text>• You can't be surprised by orcs while you're not incapacitated. You are also aware when orcs are within 120 feet of you and aren't behind total cover, although you don't know their location.</text>
		<text>• You and any of your friends within 30 feet of you can't be frightened while you're not incapacitated.</text>
		<text>Sentience: Orcsplitter is a sentient, lawful good weapon with an Intelligence of 6, a Wisdom of 15, and a Charisma of 10. It can see and hear out to 120 feet and has darkvision. It communicates by transmitting emotions to its wielder, although on rare occasions it uses a limited form of telepathy to bring to the wielder's mind a couplet or stanza of ancient Dwarvish verse.</text>
		<text>Personality: Orcsplitter is grim, taciturn, and inflexible. It knows little more than the desire to face orcs in battle and serve a courageous, just wielder. It disdains cowards and any form of duplicity, deception, or disloyalty. The weapon's purpose is to defend dwarves and to serve as a symbol of dwarven resolve. It hates the traditional foes of dwarves — giants, goblins, and, most of all, orcs — and silently urges its possessor to meet such creatures in battle.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 224</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Tinderstrike</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>F,L,T</property>
		<range>20/60</range>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>A flint dagger, Tinderstrike is uncommonly sharp, and sparks cascade off its edge whenever it strikes something solid. Its handle is always warm to the touch, and the blade smolders for 1d4 minutes after it is used to deal damage. It contains a spark of Imix, Prince of Evil Fire.</text>
		<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon. When you hit with it, the target takes an extra 2d6 fire damage.</text>
		<text>Fire Mastery: You gain the following benefits while you hold Tinderstrike:</text>
		<text>• You can speak Ignan fluently.</text>
		<text>• You have resistance to fire damage.</text>
		<text>• You can cast dominate monster (save DC 17) on a fire elemental. Once you have done so, Tinderstrike can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>Dance of the All-Consuming Fire: While inside a fire node, you can perform a ritual called the Dance of the All-Consuming Fire, using Tinderstrike to create a devastation orb of fire (see the devastation orb description for the time and cost of the ritual). Once you perform the ritual, Tinderstrike can't be used to perform the ritual again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>Flaw: Tinderstrike makes its wielder impatient and rash. While attuned to the weapon, you gain the following flaw: "I act without thinking and take risks without weighing the consequences."</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 224</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Windvane</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>T,V</property>
		<range>20/60</range>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>A silver spear, Windvane has dark sapphires on the filigreed surface of its polished head. Held by its shining haft, the weapon feels insubstantial, as if clutching a cool, gently flowing breeze. The spear contains a spark of Yan-C-Bin, the Prince of Evil Air.</text>
		<text>You have a +2 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls you make with this magic weapon, which has the finesse weapon property. When you hit with it, the target takes an extra 1d6 lightning damage.</text>
		<text>Air Mastery: You gain the following benefits while you hold Windvane:</text>
		<text>• You can speak Auran fluently.</text>
		<text>• You have resistance to lightning damage.</text>
		<text>• You can cast dominate monster (save DC 17) on an air elemental. Once you have done so, Windvane can't be used this way again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>Song of the Four Winds: While inside an air node, you can perform a ritual called the Song of the Four Winds, using Windvane to create a devastation orb of air (see the devastation orb description for the time and cost of the ritual). Once you perform the ritual, Windvane can't be used to perform the ritual again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>Flaw: Windvane makes its wielder mercurial and unreliable. While attuned to the weapon, you gain the following flaw: "I break my vows and plans. Duty and honor mean nothing to me."</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 224</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +2</modifier>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Bottled Breath</name>
		<type>P</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>0.5</weight>
		<text>This bottle contains a breath of elemental air. When you inhale it, you either exhale it or hold it.</text>
		<text>If you inhale the breath, you gain the effect of the gust of wind spell. If you hold the breath, you don't need to breathe for 1 hour, though you can end this benefit early (for example, to speak). Ending it early doesn't give you the benefit of exhaling the breath.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 222</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Seeker Dart</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>0.25</weight>
		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>F,T</property>
		<range>20/60</range>
		<text>This small dart is decorated with designs like windy spirals that span the length of its shaft.</text>
		<text>When you whisper the word "seek" and hurl this dart, it seeks out a target of your choice within 120 feet of you. You must have seen the target before, but you don't need to see it now. If the target isn't within range or if there is no clear path to it, the dart falls to the ground, its magic spent and wasted. Otherwise, elemental winds guide the dart instantly through the air to the target. The dart can pass though openings as narrow as 1 inch wide and can change direction to fly around corners.</text>
		<text>When the dart reaches its target, the target must succeed on a DC 16 Dexterity saving throw or take 1d4 piercing damage and 3d4 lightning damage. The dart's magic is then spent, and it becomes an ordinary dart.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 223</text>
		<roll>3d4</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Storm Boomerang</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<range>60/120</range>
		<text>This boomerang is a ranged weapon carved from griffon bone and etched with the symbol of elemental air. When thrown, it has a range of 60/120 feet, and any creature that is proficient with the javelin is also proficient with this weapon. On a hit, the boomerang deals 1d4 bludgeoning damage and 3d4 thunder damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 10 Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of its next turn. On a miss, the boomerang returns to the thrower's hand.</text>
		<text>Once the boomerang deals thunder damage to a target, the weapon loses its ability to deal thunder damage and its ability to stun a target. These properties return after the boomerang spends at least 1 hour inside an elemental air node.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 223</text>
		<roll>3d4</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Spider Staff</name>
		<type>ST</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>6</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The top of this black, adamantine staff is shaped like a spider. The staff weighs 6 pounds. You must be attuned to the staff to gain its benefits and cast its spells. The staff can be wielded as a quarterstaff. It deals 1d6 extra poison damage on a hit when used to make a weapon attack.</text>
		<text>The staff has 10 charges, which are used to fuel the spells within it. With the staff in hand, you can use your action to cast one of the following spells from the staff if the spell is on your class's spell list: spider climb (1 charge) or web (2 charges, spell save DC 15). No components are required.</text>
		<text>The staff regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges each day at dusk. If you expend the staff's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff crumbles to dust and is destroyed.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Lost Mines of Phandelver, page 53</text>
		<roll>1d6+4</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Staff of Defense</name>
		<type>ST</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d8</dmg2>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This slender, hollow staff is made of glass yet is as strong as oak. It weighs 3 pounds. You must be attuned to the staff to gain its benefits and cast its spells.</text>
		<text>While holding the staff, you have a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.</text>
		<text>The staff has 10 charges, which are used to fuel the spells within it. With the staff in hand, you can use your action to cast one of the following spells from the staff if the spell is on your class's spell list: mage armor (1 charge) or shield (2 charges). No components are required.</text>
		<text>The staff regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges each day at dawn. If you expend the staff's last charge, roll a d20. On a 1, the staff shatters and is destroyed.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Lost Mines of Phandelver, page 53</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
		<roll>1d6+4</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Balloon Pack</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<text>This backpack contains the spirit of an air elemental and a compact leather balloon. While you're wearing the backpack, you can deploy the balloon as an action and gain the effect of the levitate spell for 10 minutes, targeting yourself and requiring no concentration. Alternatively, you can use a reaction to deploy the balloon when you're falling and gain the effect of the feather fall spell for yourself.</text>
		<text>When either spell ends, the balloon slowly deflates as the elemental spirit escapes and returns to the Elemental Plane of Air. As the balloon deflates, you descend gently toward the ground for up to 60 feet. IF you are still in the air at the end of this distance, you fall if you have no other means of staying aloft.</text>
		<text>After the spirit departs, the backpack's property is unusable unless the backpack is recharged for 1 hour in an elemental air node, which binds another spirit to the backpack.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 222</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Black Dragon Mask</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This horned mask of glossy ebony has horns and a skull-like mien. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Damage Absorption: You have damage resistance to acid. If you already have damage resistance to acid from another source, you gain immunity to acid damage. If you already have immunity to acid damage from another source, you regain hit points equal to half of any acid damage you are dealt.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision with a radius of 60 feet, or an additional 60 feet of darkvision if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to a range of 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against black dragons.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Water Breathing: You can breathe underwater.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Hoard of the Dragon Queen, page 94</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Blue Dragon Mask</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This mask of glossy azure has spikes around its edges and a ridged horn in its center. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Damage Absorption: You have resistance against lightning damage. If you already have resistance to lightning damage from another source, you instead have immunity to lightning damage. If you already have immunity to lightning damage from another source, whenever you are subjected to acid damage, you take none of that damage and regain a number of hit points equal to half the damage dealt of that type.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, or to an additional 60 feet if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Blue Dragons.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Lingering Shock: If you deal lightning damage to a creature, it can't take reactions until its next turn.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Rise of Tiamat Online Supplement, page 4</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Claws of the Umber Hulk</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<text>These heavy gauntlets of brown iron are forged in the shape an umber hulk's claws, and they fit the wearer's hands and forearms all the way up to the elbow. While wearing both claws, you gain a burrowing speed of 20 feet, and you can tunnel through solid rock at a rate of 1 foot per round.</text>
		<text>You can use a claw as a melee weapon while wearing it. You have proficiency with it, and it deals 1d8 slashing damage on a hit (your Strength modifier applies to the attack and damage rolls, as normal)</text>
		<text>While wearing the claws, you can't manipulate objects or cast spells with somatic components</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 222</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Devastation Orb of Air</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<text>A devastation orb is an elemental bomb that can be created at the site of an elemental node by performing a ritual with an elemental weapon. The type of orb created depends on the node used. For example, an air node creates a devastation orb of air. The ritual takes 1 hour to complete and requires 2,000 gp worth of special components, which are consumed.</text>
		<text>A devastation orb measures 12 inches in diameter, weighs 10 pounds, and has a solid outer shell. The orb detonates 1d100 hours after its creation, releasing the elemental energy it contains. The orb gives no outward sign of how much time remains before it will detonate. Spells such as identify and divination can be used to ascertain when the orb will explode. An orb has AC 10, 15 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing it to 0 hit points causes it to explode instantly.</text>
		<text>A special container can be crafted to contain a devastation orb and prevent it from detonating. The container must be inscribed with symbols of the orb's opposing element. For example, a case inscribed with earth symbols can be used to contain a devastation orb of air and keep it from detonating. While in the container, the orb thrums. If it is removed from the container after the time when it was supposed to detonate, it explodes 1d6 rounds later, unless it is returned to the container.</text>
		<text>Regardless of the type of orb, its effect is contained within a sphere with a 1 mile radius. The orb is the sphere's point of origin. The orb is destroyed after one use.</text>
		<text>Air Orb: When this orb detonates, it creates a powerful windstorm that lasts for 1 hour. Whenever a creature ends its turn exposed to the wind, the creature must succeed on a DC 18 Constitution saving throw or take 1d4 bludgeoning damage, as the wind and debris batter it. The wind is strong enough to uproot weak trees and destroy light structures after at least 10 minutes of exposure. Otherwise, the rules for strong wind apply, as detailed in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 222</text>
		<roll>1d4</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Devastation Orb of Earth</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<text>A devastation orb is an elemental bomb that can be created at the site of an elemental node by performing a ritual with an elemental weapon. The type of orb created depends on the node used. For example, an air node creates a devastation orb of air. The ritual takes 1 hour to complete and requires 2,000 gp worth of special components, which are consumed.</text>
		<text>A devastation orb measures 12 inches in diameter, weighs 10 pounds, and has a solid outer shell. The orb detonates 1d100 hours after its creation, releasing the elemental energy it contains. The orb gives no outward sign of how much time remains before it will detonate. Spells such as identify and divination can be used to ascertain when the orb will explode. An orb has AC 10, 15 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing it to 0 hit points causes it to explode instantly.</text>
		<text>A special container can be crafted to contain a devastation orb and prevent it from detonating. The container must be inscribed with symbols of the orb's opposing element. For example, a case inscribed with earth symbols can be used to contain a devastation orb of air and keep it from detonating. While in the container, the orb thrums. If it is removed from the container after the time when it was supposed to detonate, it explodes 1d6 rounds later, unless it is returned to the container.</text>
		<text>Regardless of the type of orb, its effect is contained within a sphere with a 1 mile radius. The orb is the sphere's point of origin. The orb is destroyed after one use.</text>
		<text>Earth Orb: When this orb detonates, it subjects the area to the effects of the earthquake spell for 1 minute (spell save DC 18). For the purpose of the spell's effects, the spell is cast on the turn that the orb explodes.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 222</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Devastation Orb of Fire</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<text>A devastation orb is an elemental bomb that can be created at the site of an elemental node by performing a ritual with an elemental weapon. The type of orb created depends on the node used. For example, an air node creates a devastation orb of air. The ritual takes 1 hour to complete and requires 2,000 gp worth of special components, which are consumed.</text>
		<text>A devastation orb measures 12 inches in diameter, weighs 10 pounds, and has a solid outer shell. The orb detonates 1d100 hours after its creation, releasing the elemental energy it contains. The orb gives no outward sign of how much time remains before it will detonate. Spells such as identify and divination can be used to ascertain when the orb will explode. An orb has AC 10, 15 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing it to 0 hit points causes it to explode instantly.</text>
		<text>A special container can be crafted to contain a devastation orb and prevent it from detonating. The container must be inscribed with symbols of the orb's opposing element. For example, a case inscribed with earth symbols can be used to contain a devastation orb of air and keep it from detonating. While in the container, the orb thrums. If it is removed from the container after the time when it was supposed to detonate, it explodes 1d6 rounds later, unless it is returned to the container.</text>
		<text>Regardless of the type of orb, its effect is contained within a sphere with a 1 mile radius. The orb is the sphere's point of origin. The orb is destroyed after one use.</text>
		<text>Fire Orb: When this orb detonates, it creates a dry heat wave that lasts for 24 hours. Within the area of effect, the rules for extreme heat apply, as detailed in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide. At the end of each hour, there is a ten percent chance that the heat wave starts a wildfire in a random location within the area of effect. The wildfire covers a 10-foot-square area initially but expands to fill another 10-foot square each round until the fire is extinguished or burns itself out. A creature that comes within 10 feet of a wildfire for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there takes 3d6 fire damage.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 222</text>
		<roll>3d6</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Devastation Orb of Water</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<text>A devastation orb is an elemental bomb that can be created at the site of an elemental node by performing a ritual with an elemental weapon. The type of orb created depends on the node used. For example, an air node creates a devastation orb of air. The ritual takes 1 hour to complete and requires 2,000 gp worth of special components, which are consumed.</text>
		<text>A devastation orb measures 12 inches in diameter, weighs 10 pounds, and has a solid outer shell. The orb detonates 1d100 hours after its creation, releasing the elemental energy it contains. The orb gives no outward sign of how much time remains before it will detonate. Spells such as identify and divination can be used to ascertain when the orb will explode. An orb has AC 10, 15 hit points, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing it to 0 hit points causes it to explode instantly.</text>
		<text>A special container can be crafted to contain a devastation orb and prevent it from detonating. The container must be inscribed with symbols of the orb's opposing element. For example, a case inscribed with earth symbols can be used to contain a devastation orb of air and keep it from detonating. While in the container, the orb thrums. If it is removed from the container after the time when it was supposed to detonate, it explodes 1d6 rounds later, unless it is returned to the container.</text>
		<text>Regardless of the type of orb, its effect is contained within a sphere with a 1 mile radius. The orb is the sphere's point of origin. The orb is destroyed after one use.</text>
		<text>Water Orb: When this orb detonates, it creates a torrential rainstorm that lasts for 24 hours. Within the area of effect, the rules for heavy precipitation apply, as detailed in chapter 5 of the Dungeon Master's Guide. If there is a substantial body of water in the area, it floods after 2d10 hours of heavy rain, rising 10 feet above its banks and inundating the surrounding area. The flood advances at a rate of 100 feet per round, moving away from the body of water where it began until it reaches the edge of the area of effect: at that point, the water flows downhill (and possibly recedes back to its origin). Light structures collapse and wash away. Any Large or smaller creature caught in the flood's path is swept away. The flooding destroys crops and might trigger mudslides, depending on the terrain.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 222</text>
	</item>
</compendium>
