<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
<!--Hoard of the Dragon Queen/Rise of Tiamat-->
<item>
	<name>Draakhorn</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>The Draakhorn was a gift from Tiamat in the war between dragons and giants. It was once the horn of her ancient red dragon consort, Ephelomon, that she gave to dragonkind to help them in their war against the giants. The Draakhorn is a signaling device, and it is so large that it requires two Medium creatures (or one Large or larger) to hold it while a third creature sounds it, making the earth resonate to its call. The horn has been blasted with fire into a dark ebony hue and is wrapped in bands of bronze with draconic runes that glow with purple eldritch fire.</text>
	<text>The low, moaning drone of the Draakhorn discomfits normal animals within a few miles, and it alerts all dragons within two thousand miles to rise and be wary, for great danger is at hand. Coded blasts were once used to signal specific messages. Knowledge of those codes has been lost to the ages.</text>
	<text>Those with knowledge of the Draakhorn's history know that it was first built to signal danger to chromatic dragons — a purpose the Cult of the Dragon has corrupted to call chromatic dragons to the Well of Dragons from across the North.</text>
	<text>Within 50 feet of any enclosed space where the horn is blown, the air begins to shimmer from the sound. Any character within 20 feet of the entry to the enclosed space must succeed on a DC 12 Strength check to continue pushing against the pressure of the sound. A failure indicates the character can advance no farther toward the entry.</text>
	<text>For any character entering the enclosed space, the sound fades to silence — because any creature that enters the enclosed space is temporarily deafened and must make a DC 12 Constitution saving throw. Success indicates the deafness ends 2 minutes after the Draakhorn ceases to sound. Failure indicates the character remains deafened for 1 hour after the Draakhorn ceases to sound.</text>
	<text>While the horn is sounding, a creature must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw the first time on a turn the creature enters a 150-foot cone in front of the horn or starts its turn there. On a failed save, the creature takes 27 (6d8) thunder damage and is knocked prone. On a successful save, the creature takes half damage and isn't knocked prone.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: The Rise of Tiamat, page 93</text>
	<roll>6d8</roll>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Dragontooth Dagger</name>
	<type>M</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<weight>1</weight>
	<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
	<dmgType>P</dmgType>
	<property>F,L,T</property>
	<range>20/60</range>
	<text>A dagger fashioned from the tooth of a dragon. While the blade is obviously a fang or predator's tooth, the handle is leather wrapped around the root of the tooth, and there is no crossguard.</text>
	<text>You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls you make with this weapon. On a hit with this weapon, the target takes an extra 1d6 acid damage.</text>
	<text>Draconic Potency: Against enemies of the Cult of the Dragon, the dagger's bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls increases to 2, and the extra acid damage increases to 2d6.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: The Rise of Tiamat, page 94</text>
	<modifier category="bonus">weapon attacks +1</modifier>
	<modifier category="bonus">weapon damage +1</modifier>
	<roll>1d6</roll>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Green Dragon Mask</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>This mottled green mask is surmounted by a frilled crest and has leathery spiked plates along its jaw. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Damage Absorption: You have resistance against poison damage. If you already have resistance to poison damage from another source, you instead have immunity to poison damage. If you already have immunity to poison damage from another source, whenever you are subjected to poison damage, you take none of that damage and regain a number of hit points equal to half the damage dealt of that type.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, or to an additional 60 feet if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Green Dragons.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Water Breathing: You can breathe underwater.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Rise of Tiamat Online Supplement, page 4</text>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Hazirawn</name>
	<type>M</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<weight>6</weight>
	<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
	<dmgType>S</dmgType>
	<property>H,2H</property>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>A sentient (neutral evil) greatsword, Hazirawn is capable of speech in Common and Netherese. Even if you aren't attuned to the sword, you gain a +1 bonus on attack rolls and damage rolls made with this weapon. If you are attuned to Hazirawn, you deal an extra 1d6 necrotic damage when you hit with the weapon.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Increased Potency: While you are attuned to this weapon, its bonus on attack rolls and damage rolls increases to +2, and a hit deals an extra 2d6 necrotic damage (instead of 1d6)</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Spells: Hazirawn has 4 charges to cast spells. As long as the sword is attuned to you and you are holding it in your hand, you can cast detect magic (1 charge), detect evil and good (1 charge), or detect thoughts (2 charges). Each night at midnight, Hazirawn regains 1d4 expended charges.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Wounding: While you are attuned to the weapon, any creature that you hit with Hazirawn can't regain hit points for 1 minute. The target can make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending this effect early on a success.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Hoard of the Dragon Queen, page 94</text>
	<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
	<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
	<roll>1d6</roll>
	<roll>2d6</roll>
	<roll>1d4</roll>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Insignia of Claws</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>The jewels in the insignia of the Cult of the Dragon flare with purple light when you enter combat, empowering your natural fists or natural weapons.</text>
	<text>While wearing the insignia you gain a +1 bonus to the attack rolls and the damage rolls you make with unarmed strikes and natural weapons. Such attacks are considered to be magical.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Hoard of the Dragon Queen, page 94</text>
	<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
	<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Lost Crown of Besilmer</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>This dwarven battle-helm consists of a sturdy open-faced steel helmet, decorated with a golden circlet above the brow from which seven small gold spikes project upward. You gain the following benefits while wearing the crown:</text>
	<text>• You have resistance to psychic damage.</text>
	<text>• You have advantage on saving throws against effects that would charm you.</text>
	<text>• You can use a bonus action to inspire one creature you can see that is within 60 feet of you and that can see or hear you. Once before the end of your next turn, the inspired creature can roll a d6 and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. This uses 1 charge from the crown. It has 3 charges, and it regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 223</text>
	<roll>1d3</roll>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Mask of the Dragon Queen</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Individually, the five dragon masks resemble the dragons they are named for. When two or more of the dragon masks are assembled, however, they transform magically into the Mask of the Dragon Queen. Each mask shrinks to become the modeled head of a chromatic dragon, appearing to roar its devotion to Tiamat where all the masks brought together are arranged crown-like on the wearer's head. Below the five masks, a new mask shapes itself, granting the wearer a draconic visage that covers the face, neck, and shoulders.</text>
	<text>While you are attuned to and wear this mask, you can have any of the properties from any one mask. Additionally, you gain the Damage Absorption from each of the five dragon masks, and you gain five uses of the Legendary Resistance property.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: The Rise of Tiamat, page 94</text>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Red Dragon Mask</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>This mask of glossy crimson has swept-back horns and spiked cheek ridges. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Damage Absorption: You have resistance against fire damage. If you already have resistance to fire damage from another source, you instead have immunity to fire damage. If you already have immunity to fire damage from another source, whenever you are subjected to fire damage, you take none of that damage and regain a number of hit points equal to half the damage dealt of that type.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, or to an additional 60 feet if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against Red Dragons.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Fire: If you deal fire damage to a creature or flammable object, it starts burning. At the start of each of its turns, a creature burning in this way takes 1d6 fire damage. A creature that can reach the burning target can use an action to extinguish the fire.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Rise of Tiamat Online Supplement, page 4</text>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Weird Tank</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>A weird tank is a ten-gallon tank of blown glass and sculpted bronze with a backpack-like carrying harness fashioned from tough leather. A water weird (see the Monster Manual for statistics) is contained within the tank. While wearing the tank, you can use an action to open it, allowing the water weird to emerge. The water weird acts immediately after you in the initiative order, and it is bound to the tank.</text>
	<text>You can command the water weird telepathically (no action required) while you wear the tank. You can close the tank as an action only if you have first commanded the water weird to retract into it or if the water weird is dead.</text>
	<text>If the water weird is killed, the tank loses its magical containment property until it spends at least 24 hours inside an elemental water node. When the tank is recharged, a new water weird forms inside it.</text>
	<text>The tank has AC 15, 50 hit points, vulnerability to bludgeoning damage, and immunity to poison and psychic damage. Reducing the tank to 0 hit points destroys it and the water weird contained within it.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 223</text>
</item>
<item>
	<name>White Dragon Mask</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>This gleaming mask is white with highlights of pale blue and is topped by a spined crest. The mask reshapes to fit a wearer attuned to it. While you are wearing the mask and attuned to it, you can access the following properties.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Damage Absorption: You have resistance against cold damage. If you already have resistance to cold damage from another source, you instead have immunity to cold damage. If you already have immunity to cold damage from another source, whenever you are subjected to cold damage, you take none of that damage and regain a number of hit points equal to half the damage dealt of that type.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Draconic Majesty: While you are wearing no armor, you can add your Charisma bonus to your Armor Class.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Breath: If you have a breath weapon that requires rest to recharge, it gains a recharge of 6.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Sight: You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, or to an additional 60 feet if you already have that sense. Once per day, you can gain blindsight out to 30 feet for 5 minutes.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Dragon Tongue: You can speak and understand Draconic. You also have advantage on any Charisma check you make against White Dragons.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Legendary Resistance: (1/Day) If you fail a saving throw, you can choose to succeed instead.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Winter's Fury: While your current hit points are equal to or less than half your hit point maximum, you deal an extra 1d8 cold damage with your melee attacks.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Rise of Tiamat Online Supplement, page 4</text>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Wingwear</name>
	<type>W</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>This snug uniform has symbols of air stitched into it and leathery flaps that stretch along the arms, waist, and legs to create wings for gliding. A suit of wingwear has 3 charges. While you wear the suit, you can use a bonus action and expend 1 charge to gain a flying speed of 30 feet until you land. At the end of each of your turns, your altitude drops by 5 feet. Your altitude drops instantly to 0 feet at the end of your turn if you didn't fly at least 30 feet horizontally on that turn. When your altitude drops to 0 feet, you land (or fall), and you must expend another charge to use the suit again.</text>
	<text>The suit regains all of its expended charges after spending at least 1 hour in an elemental air node.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Princes of the Apocalypse, page 223</text>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Wand of Winter</name>
	<type>WD</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text/>
	<text>This wand looks and feels like an icicle. You must be attuned to the want to use it.</text>
	<text>The wand has 7 charges, which are used to fuel the spells within it. With the wand in hand, you can use your action to cast one of the following spells from the wand, even if you are incapable of casting spells: ray of frost (no charges, or 1 charge to cast at 5th level; +5 to hit with ranged spell attack), sleet storm (3 charges; spell save DC 15), or ice storm (4 charges; spell save DC 15). No components are required. The wand regains 1d6 + 1 expended charges each day at dawn. If you expend the wand's last charge, roll a d20. On a 20, the wand melts away, forever destroyed.</text>
	<text/>
	<text>Source: Hoard of the Dragon Queen, page 94</text>
</item>
</compendium>
