<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Ranger" HB="HB">
		<name>Ranger (Wasteland Wanderer)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Ranger Conclave: Wasteland Wanderer Conclave</name>
				<text>Some worlds thrive, with large swathes of the land covered with  ora and fauna that can be both beautiful and dangerous while other lands, or other worlds, become desolate wastelands through cataclysmic occurrences either natural or manufactured.</text>
				<text>Apocalyptic events turn the land into hazardous voids more dangerous than any monster. Only the hardiest life forms survive, and even they are often mutated into hideous reflections of their natural selves.</text>
				<text>The Sea of Silt in Dark Sun's Athas, the Mournland of Eberron, and the spellplagued areas of Faerûn are just some examples in lore.</text>
				<text>Forged in the harsh kiln of apocalyptic survival are the Wasteland Wanderer. These rangers of ruin rely on the skills and knowledge they have gathered by surviving the terrible conditions of their world— and often helping others survive as well.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Wasteland Wanderer Conclave: Wasteland Wanderer Magic</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you learn an additional spell with you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Wasteland Wanderer Spells table. The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, but it doesn't count against the number of ranger spells you know.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>3rd-purify food and drink</text>
				<text>5th-aid</text>
				<text>9th-mass healing word</text>
				<text>13th-death ward</text>
				<text>17th-mass cure wounds</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Wasteland Wanderer Conclave: Vigilant Guardian</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you become harder to ambush and can't be surprised while within your favored terrain. If a member of your party is surprised at the start of combat, you have advantage on initiative rolls.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you can use your bonus action to make a Wisdom (Perception) or Intelligence (Investigation) check to notice hidden enemies. If you notice a hidden creature, you can immediately move up to half your speed and make one additional weapon attack against that target, as part of that same bonus action. When you do, you have advantage on the attack and you deal an additional 2d8 damage on a hit.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Wasteland Wanderer Conclave: Trail of Trouble</name>
				<text>Starting at 7th level, you have a +5 bonus to your passive Wisdom (Perception) and passive Intelligence (Investigation) scores. You gain this benefit even while traveling at a normal pace, instead of a slow pace, while you are in your favored terrain.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you can use your Primeval Awareness feature to focus your senses to unnatural disturbances nearby. For 1 minute per level of the spell slot you expend, you can divine the types of traps to a range of 60 feet, learning how they trigger, and the type of damage they deal. When you do so, you also gain resistance to traps you identify with this feature until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Wasteland Wanderer Conclave: Shared Succor</name>
				<text>At 11th level, when you cast a ranger spell that restores hit points to a creature other than you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points regained as having rolled their maximum value, and you regain hit points equal that number plus your wisdom modifier.</text>
				<text>	At 15th level, you can choose one additional creature within range of the spell, to regain that number of hit points.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Wasteland Wanderer Conclave: Safety in Numbers</name>
				<text>At 15th level, you gain the ability to use an enemy's momentum against it. When a creature within 30 feet of you deals damage to anyone other than you, you can use your reaction to grant its target resistance to the attack's damage and you can make a special weapon attack as part of the same reaction. You have advantage on the attack roll, and if it hits, your target has disadvantage on its next attack roll until the end of its next turn.</text>
				<text>	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum of 1). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Ranger (Wasteland Wanderer)">
		<index name="Purify Food and Drink"/>
		<index name="Aid"/>
		<index name="Mass Healing Word"/>
		<index name="Death Ward"/>
		<index name="Mass Cure Wounds"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
