<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Ranger" HB="HB">
		<name>Ranger (Burghal Explorer)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Ranger Conclave: Burghal Explorer Conclave</name>
				<text>Burghal Explorers are at home in tight places, making their living as urban bounty hunters or guiding magical search crews through dangerous ruins. Dark slums and ruined cities, choked with thirsty weeds and decorated with crumbling remnants of once-thriving communities, become gathering points for desperate innocents—and for sneak-thieves and bandits who prey on the helpless.</text>
				<text>	Burghal Explorers toe the line between the natural forest and cityscapes, moonlighting as vigilantes, or fending off unnatural horrors that reach covetously toward the darkest, deepest, plots of land.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Burghal Explorer Conclave: Burghal Explorer Magic</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you learn an additional spell with you reach certain levels in this class, as shown in the Ruin Dweller Spells table. The spell counts as a ranger spell for you, but it doesn't count against the number of ranger spells you know.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>3rd-Find Familiar</text>
				<text>5th-Misty Step</text>
				<text>9th-Tongues</text>
				<text>13th-Mordenkainen's faithful hound</text>
				<text>17th-animate objects</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Burghal Explorer Conclave: Grazing Strike</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you gain the ability to hinder your foes with your strikes. Whenever you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can graze your target's arm, leg, chest, or head. When you do, the creature takes an additional 1d4 damage of the weapon's type and you impose one of the follow effects on that target:</text>
				<text>	Head. It has disadvantage the next saving throw it makes before the end of its next turn.</text>
				<text>	Arm. It has disadvantage on the next Strength check or attack roll it makes before the end of its next turn.</text>
				<text>	Leg. Its movement speed is reduced by 10 feet until the end of its next turn.</text>
				<text>	Chest. It must succeed a Strength saving throw. If it fails, you can push it up to 5 feet away from you. If it hits a wall, or other permanent structure as a result of being pushed, it takes an additional 1d6 bludgeoning damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Burghal Explorer Conclave: Above and Below</name>
				<text>At 7th level, you can identify the fastest routes across cityscapes or crumbling ruins, whether the path leads through the sewers below or the roofs above. Climbing and swimming no longer costs you extra movement and you can hold your breath for twice as long as normal.</text>
				<text>	In addition, when you make a running jump, the distance you cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Dexterity modifier.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Burghal Explorer Conclave: Streetwise</name>
				<text>At 11th level, you disappear into crowds without hesitation. While you are hidden, moving through a crowd that isn't hostile to you, you can don a disguise if you have prepared it in advance and you have at least one hand free, and Wisdom (Insight) checks against this disguise have disadvantage.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you can take the Disengage action as a bonus action on your turn. When you do, you can move through the space of any creature that is size Medium or larger and you ignore half cover when you make an attack against another creature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Burghal Explorer Conclave: Close Quarters</name>
				<text>At 15th level, you always gain the benefits of half cover whenever two or more creatures are within 5 feet of you. As a bonus action while holding a shield, you can grant this to benefit to one of the creatures adjacent to you until the start of your next turn or it moves 10 feet away from you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Ranger (Burghal Explorer)">
		<index name="Find Familiar"/>
		<index name="Misty Step"/>
		<index name="Tongues"/>
		<index name="Mordenkainen's faithful hound"/>
		<index name="Animate Objects"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
