<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
	<character>
		<version>32</version>
		<uid>4078</uid>
		<name>Human Druid</name>
		<race>
			<name>Human</name>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice. Humans typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects. They are fond of sprinkling their speech with words borrowed from other tongues: Orc curses, Elvish musical expressions, Dwarvish military phrases, and so on.</text>
			</feat>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>1</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>2</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>3</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>4</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>5</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
		</race>
		<class>
			<id>3917</id>
			<name>Druid</name>
			<level>4</level>
			<hd>2</hd>
			<hdCurrent>4</hdCurrent>
			<proficiency>4</proficiency>
			<proficiency>106</proficiency>
			<proficiency>109</proficiency>
			<proficiency>110</proficiency>
			<proficiency>105</proficiency>
			<proficiency>3</proficiency>
			<armor>Light armor, medium armor, shields</armor>
			<weapons>Clubs, daggers, darts, javelins, maces, quarterstaffs, scimitars, sickles, slings, spears</weapons>
			<tools>Harps, herbalism kit</tools>
			<slots>3,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			<slotsCurrent>3,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields (druids will not wear armor or use shields made of metal)
Weapons: clubs, daggers, darts, javelins, maces, quarterstaffs, scimitars, sickles, slings, spears
Tools: herbalism kit
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, Animal Handling, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Religion, and Survival</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.

• (a) a wooden shield or (b) any simple weapon
• (a) a scimitar or (b) any simple melee weapon
• Leather armor, an explorer's pack, and a druidic focus

Alternatively, you may start with 2d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Druidic</name>
				<text>You know Druidic, the secret language of druids. You can speak the language and use it to leave hidden messages. You and others who know this language automatically spot such a message. Others spot the message's presence with a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Perception) check but can't decipher it without magic.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>Drawing on the divine essence of nature itself, you can cast spells to shape that essence to your will. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the druid spell list.

Cantrips
At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. You learn additional druid cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Druid table.

Preparing and Casting Spells
The Druid table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these druid spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of druid spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the druid spell list. When you do so, choose a number of druid spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your druid level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you are a 3rd-level druid, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level ar 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can also change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of druid spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.

Spellcasting Ability
Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your druid spells, since your magic draws upon your devotion and attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a druid spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier

Ritual Casting
You can cast a druid spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.

Spellcasting Focus
You can use a druidic focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your druid spells</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Wild Shape</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your action to magically assume the shape of a beast that you have seen before. You can use this feature twice. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.
	Your druid level determines the beasts you can transform into, as shown in the Beast Shapes table. At 2nd level, for example, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower that doesn't have a flying or swimming speed.

Beast Shapes
Level  Max. CR   Limitations                    Example
2nd    1/4       No flying or swimming speed    Wolf
4th    1/2       No flying speed                Crocodile
8th    1         —                              Giant eagle

	You can stay in a beast shape for a number of hours equal to half your druid level (rounded down). You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.
	While you are transformed, the following rules apply:
• Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the beast, but you retain your alignment, personality, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. You also retain all of your skill and saving throw proficiencies, in addition to gaining those of the creature. If the creature has the same proficiency as you and the bonus in its stat block is higher than yours, use the creature's bonus instead of yours. If the creature has any legendary or lair actions, you can't use them.
• When you transform, you assume the beast's hit points and Hit Dice. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. However, if you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. For example, if you take 10 damage in animal form and have only 1 hit point left, you revert and take 9 damage. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious.
• You can't cast spells, and your ability to speak or take any action that requires hands is limited to the capabilities of your beast form. Transforming doesn't break your concentration on a spell you've already cast, however, or prevent you from taking actions that are part of a spell, such as call lightning, that you've already cast.
• You retain the benefit of any features from your class, race, or other source and can use them if the new form is physically capable of doing so. However, you can't use any of your special senses, such as darkvision, unless your new form also has that sense.
• You choose whether your equipment falls to the ground in your space, merges into your new form, or is worn by it. Worn equipment functions as normal, but the DM decides whether it is practical for the new form to wear a piece of equipment, based on the creature's shape and size. Your equipment doesn't change size or shape to match the new form, and any equipment that the new form can't wear must either fall to the ground or merge with it. Equipment that merges with the form has no effect until you leave the form.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Druid Circle</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you choose to identify with a circle of druids: the Circle of the Land or the Circle of the Moon, both detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Optional Rule: Wild Shape Forms</name>
				<text>Known Beast Shapes: 
	When you gain the Wild Shape feature at 2nd level, you are deeply familiar with three beasts of your choice and can transform into them. 
	To choose the three beast shapes, you first need to determine whether your druid grew up in a temperate or a tropical region, consulting with your DM. Then refer to the Common Beast Shapes table that corresponds to the region you selected. That table lists the beasts you can choose from, based on your druid level. The table presents the animals that a druid is most likely to have seen as a novice, to have learned about through mystic research, or to have a special affinity with. 
	Each time you gain a druid level later, you can choose one more beast shape from the same table you used at 2nd level.

Gaining Beast Shapes:
	In addition to the beast shapes you gain for free when you level up, you can acquire new shapes on your adventures. Do you see a dinosaur, a saber-toothed tiger, a giant eagle, or some other exotic critter that you want to turn into? This rule gives you a method for learning how to do so. It requires you to abide by the limitations in the Wild Shape feature (see the Beast Shapes table in the Player's Handbook, page 66). 
	When you see a beast whose shape you'd like to learn, you have two options: 

Observation: 
	You learn the beast's shape after observing its behavior for at least 1 hour and succeeding on an Intelligence (Nature) check with a DC equal to 10 + the beast's challenge rating. For this observation period, your vantage point—whether physical or magical— must be within 150 feet of the beast. If you previously spent at least 1 hour reading a scholarly work about the creature, you have advantage on the check. 

Interaction: 
	You learn the beast's shape after interacting with it peacefully for 10 minutes and succeeding on a Wisdom (Animal Handling) check with a DC equal to 10 + the beast's challenge rating. For this interaction period, you must be within 15 feet of the beast, and if you spend at least a minute petting it, you have advantage on the check. 

	Either of these options can be assisted by magic. For example, divination magic can be used to provide safe observation of a dangerous animal, and a spell like animal friendship can lay the groundwork for peaceful interaction.

This optional rule is from Unearthed Arcana: Druid Circles and Wild Shape, and as such may not be used in your game. Consult your DM about this rule.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Druid Circle: Circle of the Moon</name>
				<text>Druids of the Circle of the Moon are fierce guardians of the wilds. Their order gathers under the full moon to share news and trade warnings. They haunt the deepest parts of the wilderness, where they might go for weeks on end before crossing paths with another humanoid creature, let alone another druid.

Changeable as the moon, a druid of this circle might prowl as a great cat one night, soar over the treetops as an eagle the next day, and crash through the undergrowth in bear form to drive off a trespassing monster. The wild is in the druid's blood.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Circle of Moon: Combat Wild Shape</name>
				<text>You gain the ability to use Wild Shape on your turn as a bonus action, rather than as an action.
	Additionally, while you are transformed by Wild Shape, you can use a bonus action to expend one spell slot to regain 1d8 hit points per level of the spell slot expended.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Circle of Moon: Circle Forms</name>
				<text>The rites of your circle grant you the ability to transform into more dangerous animal forms. Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Wild Shape to transform into a beast with a challenge rating as high as 1 (you ignore the Max. CR column of the Beast Shapes table, but must abide by the other limitations there).
	Starting at 6th level, you can transform into a beast with a challenge rating as high as your druid level divided by 3, rounded down.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
			</feat>
			<autolevel>
				<slots>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
					<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields (druids will not wear armor or use shields made of metal)
Weapons: clubs, daggers, darts, javelins, maces, quarterstaffs, scimitars, sickles, slings, spears
Tools: herbalism kit
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, Animal Handling, Insight, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Religion, and Survival</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Equipment</name>
					<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.

• (a) a wooden shield or (b) any simple weapon
• (a) a scimitar or (b) any simple melee weapon
• Leather armor, an explorer's pack, and a druidic focus

Alternatively, you may start with 2d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Druidic</name>
					<text>You know Druidic, the secret language of druids. You can speak the language and use it to leave hidden messages. You and others who know this language automatically spot such a message. Others spot the message's presence with a successful DC 15 Wisdom (Perception) check but can't decipher it without magic.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Spellcasting</name>
					<text>Drawing on the divine essence of nature itself, you can cast spells to shape that essence to your will. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the druid spell list.

Cantrips
At 1st level, you know two cantrips of your choice from the druid spell list. You learn additional druid cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Druid table.

Preparing and Casting Spells
The Druid table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these druid spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of druid spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the druid spell list. When you do so, choose a number of druid spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your druid level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you are a 3rd-level druid, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level ar 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can also change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of druid spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.

Spellcasting Ability
Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your druid spells, since your magic draws upon your devotion and attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a druid spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier

Ritual Casting
You can cast a druid spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.

Spellcasting Focus
You can use a druidic focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your druid spells</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>2</level>
				<slots>2,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Wild Shape</name>
					<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your action to magically assume the shape of a beast that you have seen before. You can use this feature twice. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.
	Your druid level determines the beasts you can transform into, as shown in the Beast Shapes table. At 2nd level, for example, you can transform into any beast that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower that doesn't have a flying or swimming speed.

Beast Shapes
Level  Max. CR   Limitations                    Example
2nd    1/4       No flying or swimming speed    Wolf
4th    1/2       No flying speed                Crocodile
8th    1         —                              Giant eagle

	You can stay in a beast shape for a number of hours equal to half your druid level (rounded down). You then revert to your normal form unless you expend another use of this feature. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using a bonus action on your turn. You automatically revert if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die.
	While you are transformed, the following rules apply:
• Your game statistics are replaced by the statistics of the beast, but you retain your alignment, personality, and Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores. You also retain all of your skill and saving throw proficiencies, in addition to gaining those of the creature. If the creature has the same proficiency as you and the bonus in its stat block is higher than yours, use the creature's bonus instead of yours. If the creature has any legendary or lair actions, you can't use them.
• When you transform, you assume the beast's hit points and Hit Dice. When you revert to your normal form, you return to the number of hit points you had before you transformed. However, if you revert as a result of dropping to 0 hit points, any excess damage carries over to your normal form. For example, if you take 10 damage in animal form and have only 1 hit point left, you revert and take 9 damage. As long as the excess damage doesn't reduce your normal form to 0 hit points, you aren't knocked unconscious.
• You can't cast spells, and your ability to speak or take any action that requires hands is limited to the capabilities of your beast form. Transforming doesn't break your concentration on a spell you've already cast, however, or prevent you from taking actions that are part of a spell, such as call lightning, that you've already cast.
• You retain the benefit of any features from your class, race, or other source and can use them if the new form is physically capable of doing so. However, you can't use any of your special senses, such as darkvision, unless your new form also has that sense.
• You choose whether your equipment falls to the ground in your space, merges into your new form, or is worn by it. Worn equipment functions as normal, but the DM decides whether it is practical for the new form to wear a piece of equipment, based on the creature's shape and size. Your equipment doesn't change size or shape to match the new form, and any equipment that the new form can't wear must either fall to the ground or merge with it. Equipment that merges with the form has no effect until you leave the form.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Druid Circle</name>
					<text>At 2nd level, you choose to identify with a circle of druids: the Circle of the Land or the Circle of the Moon, both detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Optional Rule: Wild Shape Forms</name>
					<text>Known Beast Shapes: 
	When you gain the Wild Shape feature at 2nd level, you are deeply familiar with three beasts of your choice and can transform into them. 
	To choose the three beast shapes, you first need to determine whether your druid grew up in a temperate or a tropical region, consulting with your DM. Then refer to the Common Beast Shapes table that corresponds to the region you selected. That table lists the beasts you can choose from, based on your druid level. The table presents the animals that a druid is most likely to have seen as a novice, to have learned about through mystic research, or to have a special affinity with. 
	Each time you gain a druid level later, you can choose one more beast shape from the same table you used at 2nd level.

Gaining Beast Shapes:
	In addition to the beast shapes you gain for free when you level up, you can acquire new shapes on your adventures. Do you see a dinosaur, a saber-toothed tiger, a giant eagle, or some other exotic critter that you want to turn into? This rule gives you a method for learning how to do so. It requires you to abide by the limitations in the Wild Shape feature (see the Beast Shapes table in the Player's Handbook, page 66). 
	When you see a beast whose shape you'd like to learn, you have two options: 

Observation: 
	You learn the beast's shape after observing its behavior for at least 1 hour and succeeding on an Intelligence (Nature) check with a DC equal to 10 + the beast's challenge rating. For this observation period, your vantage point—whether physical or magical— must be within 150 feet of the beast. If you previously spent at least 1 hour reading a scholarly work about the creature, you have advantage on the check. 

Interaction: 
	You learn the beast's shape after interacting with it peacefully for 10 minutes and succeeding on a Wisdom (Animal Handling) check with a DC equal to 10 + the beast's challenge rating. For this interaction period, you must be within 15 feet of the beast, and if you spend at least a minute petting it, you have advantage on the check. 

	Either of these options can be assisted by magic. For example, divination magic can be used to provide safe observation of a dangerous animal, and a spell like animal friendship can lay the groundwork for peaceful interaction.

This optional rule is from Unearthed Arcana: Druid Circles and Wild Shape, and as such may not be used in your game. Consult your DM about this rule.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Druid Circle: Circle of the Moon</name>
					<text>Druids of the Circle of the Moon are fierce guardians of the wilds. Their order gathers under the full moon to share news and trade warnings. They haunt the deepest parts of the wilderness, where they might go for weeks on end before crossing paths with another humanoid creature, let alone another druid.

Changeable as the moon, a druid of this circle might prowl as a great cat one night, soar over the treetops as an eagle the next day, and crash through the undergrowth in bear form to drive off a trespassing monster. The wild is in the druid's blood.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of Moon: Combat Wild Shape</name>
					<text>You gain the ability to use Wild Shape on your turn as a bonus action, rather than as an action.
	Additionally, while you are transformed by Wild Shape, you can use a bonus action to expend one spell slot to regain 1d8 hit points per level of the spell slot expended.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of Moon: Circle Forms</name>
					<text>The rites of your circle grant you the ability to transform into more dangerous animal forms. Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Wild Shape to transform into a beast with a challenge rating as high as 1 (you ignore the Max. CR column of the Beast Shapes table, but must abide by the other limitations there).
	Starting at 6th level, you can transform into a beast with a challenge rating as high as your druid level divided by 3, rounded down.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>3</level>
				<slots>2,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>4</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>5</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>6</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of Moon: Primal Strike</name>
					<text>Starting at 6th level, your attacks in beast form count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>7</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>8</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>9</level>
				<slots>3,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>10</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of Moon: Elemental Wild Shape</name>
					<text>At 10th level, you can expend two uses of Wild Shape at the same time to transform into an air elemental, an earth elemental, a fire elemental, or a water elemental.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>11</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>12</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>13</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>14</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Circle of Moon: Thousand Forms</name>
					<text>By 14th level, you have learned to use magic to alter your physical form in more subtle ways. You can cast the alter self spell at will.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>15</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>16</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>17</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>18</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Timeless Body</name>
					<text>Starting at 18th level, the primal magic that you wield causes you to age more slowly. For every 10 years that pass, your body ages only 1 year.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Beast Spells</name>
					<text>Beginning at 18th level, you can cast many of your druid spells in any shape you assume using Wild Shape. You can perform the somatic and verbal components of a druid spell while in a beast shape, but you aren't able to provide material components.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>19</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>20</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Archdruid</name>
					<text>At 20th level, you can use your Wild Shape an unlimited number of times.
	Additionally, you can ignore the verbal and somatic components of your druid spells, as well as any material components that lack a cost and aren't consumed by a spell. You gain this benefit in both your normal shape and your beast shape from Wild Shape.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<spellAbility>4</spellAbility>
			<spell>
				<name>Thunderwave</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self (15-foot cube)</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A wave of thunderous force sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 thunder damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn't pushed.

In addition, unsecured objects that are completely within the area of effect are automatically pushed 10 feet away from you by the spell's effect, and the spell emits a thunderous boom audible out to 300 feet.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>2d8</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Detect Poison and Disease</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a yew leaf</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you can sense the presence and location of poisons, poisonous creatures, and diseases within 30 feet of you. You also identify the kind of poison, poisonous creature, or disease in each case.

The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Warding Wind</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>A strong wind (20 miles per hour) blows around you in a 10-foot radius and moves with you, remaining centered on you. The wind lasts for the spell's duration.

The wind has the following effects.

• It deafens you and other creatures in its area.

• It extinguishes unprotected flames in its area that are torch-sized or smaller.

• It hedges out vapor, gas, and fog that can be dispersed by strong wind.

• The area is difficult terrain for creatures other than you.

• The attack rolls of ranged weapon attacks have disadvantage if the attacks pass in or out of the wind.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Charm Person</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You attempt to charm a humanoid you can see within range. It must make a Wisdom saving throw, and does so with advantage if you or your companions are fighting it. If it fails the saving throw, it is charmed by you until the spell ends or until you or your companions do anything harmful to it. The charmed creature regards you as a friendly acquaintance. When the spell ends, the creature knows it was charmed by you.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Darkvision</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>either a pinch of dried carrot or an agate</materials>
				<duration>8 hours</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing creature to grant it the ability to see in the dark. For the duration, that creature has darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.</text>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Find Traps</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You sense the presence of any trap within range that is within line of sight. A trap, for the purpose of this spell, includes anything that would inflict a sudden or unexpected effect you consider harmful or undesirable, which was specifically intended as such by its creator. Thus, the spell would sense an area affected by the alarm spell, a glyph of warding, or a mechanical pit trap, but it would not reveal a natural weakness in the floor, an unstable ceiling, or a hidden sinkhole.

This spell merely reveals that a trap is present. You don't learn the location of each trap, but you do learn the general nature of the danger posed by a trap you sense.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Cure Wounds</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A creature you touch regains a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<roll>1d8+%0</roll>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Pass Without Trace</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>ashes from a burned leaf of mistletoe and a sprig of spruce</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>A veil of shadows and silence radiates from you, masking you and your companions from detection. For the duration, each creature you choose within 30 feet of you (including you) has a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks and can't be tracked except by magical means. A creature that receives this bonus leaves behind no tracks or other traces of its passage.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Heat Metal</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a piece of iron and a flame</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Choose a manufactured metal object, such as a metal weapon or a suit of heavy or medium metal armor, that you can see within range. You cause the object to glow red-hot. Any creature in physical contact with the object takes 2d8 fire damage when you cast the spell. Until the spell ends, you can use a bonus action on each of your subsequent turns to cause this damage again.

If a creature is holding or wearing the object and takes the damage from it, the creature must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or drop the object if it can. If it doesn't drop the object, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks until the start of your next turn.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot above 2nd.</text>
				<roll>2d8</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Locate Animals or Plants</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a bit of fur from a bloodhound</materials>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Describe or name a specific kind of beast or plant. Concentrating on the voice of nature in your surroundings, you learn the direction and distance to the closest creature or plant of that kind within 5 miles, if any are present.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Faerie Fire</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Each object in a 20-foot cube within range is outlined in blue, green, or violet light (your choice). Any creature in the area when the spell is cast is also outlined in light if it fails a Dexterity saving throw. For the duration, objects and affected creatures shed dim light in a 10-foot radius.

Any attack roll against an affected creature or object has advantage if the attacker can see it, and the affected creature or object can't benefit from being invisible.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Purify Food and Drink</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>10 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>All nonmagical food and drink within a 5-foot-radius sphere centered on a point of your choice within range is purified and rendered free of poison and disease.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Beast Bond</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a bit of fur wrapped in a cloth</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You establish a telepathic link with one beast you touch that is friendly to you or charmed by you. The spell fails if the beast's Intelligence is 4 or higher. Until the spell ends, the link is active while you and the beast are within line of sight of each other. Through the link, the beast can understand your telepathic messages to it, and it can telepathically communicate simple emotions and concepts back to you. While the link is active, the beast gains advantage on attack rolls against any creature within 5 feet of you that you can see.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Jump</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a grasshopper's hind leg</materials>
				<duration>1 minute</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature. The creature's jump distance is tripled until the spell ends.</text>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Enhance Ability</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>fur or a feather from a beast</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature and bestow upon it a magical enhancement. Choose one of the following effects - the target gains the effect until the spell ends.

Bear's Endurance: The target has advantage on Constitution checks. It also gains 2d6 temporary hit points, which are lost when the spell ends.

Bull's Strength: The target has advantage on Strength checks, and his or her carrying capacity doubles.

Cat's Grace: The target has advantage on Dexterity checks. It also doesn't take damage from falling 20 feet or less if it isn't incapacitated.

Eagle's Splendor: The target has advantage on Charisma checks.

Fox's Cunning: The target has advantage on Intelligence checks.

Owl's Wisdom: The target has advantage on Wisdom checks.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 2nd.</text>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Earth Tremor</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>10 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You cause a tremor in the ground within range. Each creature other than you in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage and is knocked prone. If the ground in that area is loose earth or stone, it becomes difficult terrain until cleared, with each 5-foot-diameter portion requiring at least 1 minute to clear by hand.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<roll>1d6</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Detect Magic</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.

The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Create or Destroy Water</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a drop of water if creating water or a few grains of sand if destroying it</materials>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You either create or destroy water.

Create Water: You create up to 10 gallons of clean water within range in an open container. Alternatively, the water falls as rain in a 30-foot cube within range, extinguishing exposed flames in the area.

Destroy Water: You destroy up to 10 gallons of water in an open container within range. Alternatively, you destroy fog in a 30-foot cube within range.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you create or destroy 10 additional gallons of water, or the size of the cube increases by 5 feet, for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Ice Knife</name>
				<school>2</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a drop of water or piece of ice</materials>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You create a shard of ice and fling it at one creature within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 piercing damage. Hit or miss, the shard then explodes. The target and each creature within 5 feet of it must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 2d6 cold damage.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the cold damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<roll>1d20+%0+%8</roll>
				<roll>1d10</roll>
				<roll>2d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Druidcraft</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Whispering to the spirits of nature, you create one of the following effects within range.

• You create a tiny, harmless sensory effect that predicts what the weather will be at your location for the next 24 hours. The effect might manifest as a golden orb for clear skies, a cloud for rain, falling snowflakes for snow, and so on. This effect persists for 1 round.

• You instantly make a flower blossom, a seed pod open, or a leaf bud bloom.

• You create an instantaneous, harmless sensory effect, such as falling leaves, a puff of wind, the sound of a small animal, or the faint odor of skunk. The effect must fit in a 5-foot cube.

• You instantly light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Longstrider</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a pinch of dirt</materials>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature. The target's speed increases by 10 feet until the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Thorn Whip</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You create a long, vine-like whip covered in thorns that lashes out at your command toward a creature in range. Make a melee spell attack against the target. If the attack hits, the creature takes 1d6 piercing damage, and if the creature is Large or smaller, you pull the creature up to 10 feet closer to you.

This spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</text>
				<roll>1d20+%0+%8</roll>
				<roll>1d6</roll>
				<roll>2d6</roll>
				<roll>3d6</roll>
				<roll>4d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Locate Object</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a forked twig</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>Describe or name an object that is familiar to you. You sense the direction to the object's location, as long as that object is within 1,000 feet of you. If the object is in motion, you know the direction of its movement.

The spell can locate a specific object known to you, as long as you have seen it up close - within 30 feet - at least once. Alternatively, the spell can locate the nearest object of a particular kind, such as a certain kind of apparel, jewelry, furniture, tool, or weapon.

This spell can't locate an object if any thickness of lead, even a thin sheet, blocks a direct path between you and the object.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Spike Growth</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>150 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>seven sharp thorns or seven small twigs, each sharpened to a point</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>The ground in a 20-foot radius centered on a point within range twists and sprouts hard spikes and thorns. The area becomes difficult terrain for the duration. When a creature moves into or within the area, it takes 2d4 piercing damage for every 5 feet it travels.

The transformation of the ground is camouflaged to look natural. Any creature that can't see the area at the time the spell is case must make a Wisdom (Perception) check against your spell save DC to recognize the terrain as hazardous before entering it.</text>
				<roll>2d4</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Animal Friendship</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a morsel of food</materials>
				<duration>24 hours</duration>
				<text>This spell lets you convince a beast that you mean it no harm. Choose a beast that you can see within range. It must see and hear you. If the beast's Intelligence is 4 or higher, the spell fails. Otherwise, the beast must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be charmed by you for the spell's duration. If you or one of your companions harms the target, the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a 2nd level spell slot or higher, you can affect one additional beast for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Moonbeam</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>several seeds of any moonseed plant and a piece of opalescent feldspar</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A silvery beam of pale light shines down in a 5-foot radius, 40-foot-high cylinder centered on a point within range. Until the spell ends, dim light fills the cylinder.

When a creature enters the spell's area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it is engulfed in ghostly flames that cause searing pain, and it must make a Constitution saving throw. It takes 2d10 radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.

A shapechanger makes its saving throw with disadvantage. If it fails, it also instantly reverts to its original form and can't assume a different form until it leaves the spell's light.

On each of your turns after you cast this spell, you can use an action to move the beam 60 feet in any direction.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 2nd.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>2d10</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Speak with Animals</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You gain the ability to comprehend and verbally communicate with beasts for the duration. The knowledge and awareness of many beasts is limited by their intelligence, but at minimum, beasts can give you information about nearby locations and monsters, including whatever they can perceive or have perceived within the past day. You might be able to persuade a beast to perform a small favor for you, at the DM's discretion.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Goodberry</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a sprig of mistletoe</materials>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Up to ten berries appear in your hand and are infused with magic for the duration. A creature can use its action to eat one berry. Eating a berry restores 1 hit point, and the berry provides enough nourishment to sustain a creature for one day.

The berries lose their potency if they have not been consumed within 24 hours of the casting of this spell.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Protection from Poison</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature. If it is poisoned, you neutralize the poison. If more than one poison afflicts the target, you neutralize one poison that you know is present, or you neutralize one at random.

For the duration, the target has advantage on saving throws against being poisoned, and it has resistance to poison damage.</text>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Gust of Wind</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self (60-foot line)</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a legume seed</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A line of strong wind 60 feet long and 10 feet wide blasts from you in a direction you choose for the spell's duration. Each creature that starts its turn in the line must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 15 feet away from you in a direction following the line.

Any creature in the line must spend 2 feet of movement for every 1 foot it moves when moving closer to you.

The gust disperses gas or vapor, and it extinguishes candles, torches, and similar unprotected flames in the area. It causes protected flames, such as those of lanterns, to dance wildly and has a 50 percent chance to extinguish them.

As a bonus action on each of your turns before the spell ends, you can change the direction in which the line blasts from you.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Beast Sense</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing beast. For the duration of the spell, you can use your action to see through the beast's eyes and hear what it hears, and continue to do so until you use your action to return to your normal senses.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Hold Person</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a small, straight piece of iron</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Choose a humanoid that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be paralyzed for the duration. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, you can target on additional humanoid for each slot level above 2nd. The humanoids must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Barkskin</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a handful of oak bark</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch a willing creature. Until the spell ends, the target's skin has a rough, bark-like appearance, and the target's AC can't be less than 16, regardless of what kind of armor it is wearing.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Earthbind</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>300 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Choose one creature you can see within range. Yellow strips of magical energy loop around the creature. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw or its flying speed (if any) is reduced to 0 feet for the spell's duration. An airborne creature affected by this spell descends at 60 feet per round until it reaches the ground or the spell ends.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Healing Word</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>1d4+%0</roll>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Entangle</name>
				<school>2</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>90 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Grasping weeds and vines sprout from the ground in a 20-foot square starting from a point within range. For the duration, these plants turn the ground in the area into difficult terrain.

A creature in the area when you cast the spell must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be restrained by the entangling plants until the spell ends. A creature restrained by the plants can use its action to make a Strength check against your spell save DC. On a success, it frees itself.

When the spell ends, the conjured plants wilt away.</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Snare</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 minute</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>25 feet of rope, which the spell consumes</materials>
				<duration>8 hours</duration>
				<text>As you cast this spell, you use the rope to create a circle with a 5-foot radius on the ground or the floor. When you finish casting, the rope disappears and the circle becomes a magic trap.

This trap is nearly invisible, requiring a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC to be discerned.

The trap triggers when a Small, Medium, or Large creature moves onto the ground or the floor in the spell's radius. That creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be magically hoisted into the air, leaving it hanging upside down 3 feet above the ground or the floor. The creature is restrained there until the spell ends.

A restrained creature can make a Dexterity saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success. Alternatively, the creature or someone else who can reach it can use an action to make an Intelligence (Arcana) check against your spell save DC. On a success, the restrained effect ends.

After the trap is triggered, the spell ends when no creature is restrained by it.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Flaming Sphere</name>
				<school>2</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a bit of tallow, a pinch of brimstone, and a dusting of powdered iron</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A 5-foot-diameter sphere of fire appears in an unoccupied space of your choice within range and lasts for the duration. Any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of the sphere must make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.

As a bonus action, you can move the sphere up to 30 feet. If you ram the sphere into a creature, that creature must make the saving throw against the sphere's damage, and the sphere stops moving this turn.

When you move the sphere, you can direct it over barriers up to 5 feet tall and jump it across pits up to 10 feet wide. The sphere ignites flammable objects not being worn or carried, and it sheds bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.</text>
				<roll>2d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Absorb Elements</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 reaction, which you take when you take acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>1 round</duration>
				<text>The spell captures some of the incoming energy, lessening its effect on you and storing it for your next melee attack. You have resistance to the triggering damage type until the start of your next turn. Also, the first time you hit with a melee attack on your next turn, the target takes an extra 1d6 damage of the triggering type, and the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the extra damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<roll>1d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Fog Cloud</name>
				<school>2</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You create a 20-foot-radius sphere of fog centered on a point within range. The sphere spreads around corners, and its area is heavily obscured. It lasts for the duration or until a wind of moderate or greater speed (at least 10 miles per hour) disperses it.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the radius of the fog increases by 20 feet for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Animal Messenger</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a morsel of food</materials>
				<duration>24 hours</duration>
				<text>By means of this spell, you use an animal to deliver a message. Choose a Tiny beast you can see within range, such as a squirrel, a blue ray, or a bird. You specify a location, which you must have visited, and a recipient who matches a general description, such as a man or woman dressed in the uniform of the town guard or a red-haired dwarf wearing a pointed hat. You also speak a message of up to twenty-five words. The target beast travels for the duration of the spell towards the specified location, covering about 50 miles per 24 hours for a flying messenger or 25 miles for other animals.

When the messenger arrives, it delivers your message to the creature that you described, replicating the sound of your voice. The messenger speaks only to a creature matching the description you gave. If the messenger doesn't reach its destination before the spell ends, the message is lost, and the beast makes its way back to where you cast this spell.

At Higher Levels: If you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the duration of the spell increases by 48 hours for each slot level above 2nd.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Healing Spirit</name>
				<school>2</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You call forth a nature spirit to soothe the wounded. The intangible spirit appears in a space that is a 5-foot cube you can see within range. The spirit looks like a transparent beast or fey (your choice).

Until the spell ends, whenever you or a creature you can see moves into the spirit's space for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, you can cause the spirit to restore ld6 hit points to that creature (no action required). The spirit can't heal constructs or undead.

As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the Spirit up to 30 feet to a space you can see.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 2nd.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<roll>1d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Flame Blade</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>leaf of sumac</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>You evoke a fiery blade in your free hand. The blade is similar in size and shape to a scimitar, and it lasts for the duration. If you let go of the blade, it disappears, but you can evoke the blade again as a bonus action.

You can use your action to make a melee spell attack with the fiery blade. On a hit, the target takes 3d6 fire damage.

The flaming blade sheds bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 4th level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for every two slot levels above 2nd.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>1d20+%0+%8</roll>
				<roll>3d6</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Dust Devil</name>
				<school>2</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a pinch of dust</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Choose an unoccupied 5-foot cube of air that you can see within range. An elemental force that resembles a dust devil appears in the cube and lasts for the spell's duration.

Any creature that ends its turn within 5 feet of the dust devil must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 1d8 bludgeoning damage and is pushed 10 feet away. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn't pushed.

As a bonus action, you can move the dust devil up to 30 feet in any direction. If the dust devil moves over sand, dust, loose dirt, or small gravel, it sucks up the material and forms a 10-foot-radius cloud of debris around itself that lasts until the start of your next turn. The cloud heavily obscures its area.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 3rd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 2nd.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<roll>1d8</roll>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Lesser Restoration</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You touch a creature and can end either one disease or one condition afflicting it. The condition can be blinded, deafened, paralyzed, or poisoned.</text>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Skywrite</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>2</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Sight</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
				<text>You cause up to ten words to form in a part of the sky you can see. The words appear to be made of cloud and remain in place for the spell's duration. The words dissipate when the spell ends. A strong wind can disperse the clouds and end the spell early.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<filter>1</filter>
		</class>
		<background>
			<id>3942</id>
			<name>Folk Hero</name>
			<align>Neutral good</align>
			<personality>You judge people by their actions, testing them with strong words</personality>
			<ideals>Traditional ways, when wise and good, should be upheld</ideals>
			<bonds>Everything you do is to serve and protect the common folk</bonds>
			<flaws>COnvinced of the import of your destiny, you are blind to your shortcomings and the risk of failure</flaws>
			<feat>
				<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Animal Handling, Survival</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
				<text>One type of artisan's tools, vehicles (land)</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Equipment</name>
				<text>A set of artisan's tools (one of your choice), a shovel, an iron pot, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Feature: Rustic Hospitality</name>
				<text>Since you come from the ranks of the common folk, you fit in among them with ease. You can find a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other commoners, unless you have shown yourself to be a danger to them. They will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives for you.</text>
			</feat>
			<proficiency>101</proficiency>
			<proficiency>117</proficiency>
		</background>
		<xp>2700</xp>
		<unarmed>1</unarmed>
		<abilities>8,15,13,10,15,13,</abilities>
		<hpMax>31</hpMax>
		<hpCurrent>31</hpCurrent>
		<item>
			<name>Backpack</name>
			<text>A backpack can hold one cubic foot or 30 pounds of gear. You can also strap items, such as a bedroll or a coil of rope, to the outside of a backpack.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Bedroll</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<value>1.0</value>
			<weight>7.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Common Clothes</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Dagger</name>
			<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 149</text>
			<type>5</type>
			<slot>2</slot>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d4</damage1H>
			<damageType>2</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>138</weaponProperty>
			<weaponRange>20</weaponRange>
			<weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Harp</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Healer's Kit</name>
			<text>This kit is a leather pouch containing bandages, salves, and splints. The kit has ten uses. As an action, you can expend one use of the kit to stabilize a creature that has 0 hit points, without needing to make a Wisdom (Medicine) check.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 151</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Herbalism Kit</name>
			<text>This kit contains a variety of instruments such as clippers, mortar and pestle, and pouches and vials used by herbalists to create remedies and potions. Proficiency with this kit lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make to identify or apply herbs. Also, proficiency with this kit is required to create antitoxin and potions of healing.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 154</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Mess Kit</name>
			<text>This tin box contains a cup and simple cutlery. The box clamps together, and one side can be used as a cooking pan and the other as a plate or shallow bowl.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 152</text>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Pouch</name>
			<text>A cloth or leather pouch can hold up to 20 sling bullets or 50 blowgun needles, among other things. A compartmentalized pouch for holding spell components is called a component pouch. A pouch can hold up to 1/5 cubic foot or 6 pounds of gear.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Rations (1 day)</name>
			<text>Rations consist of dry foods suitable for extended travel, including jerky, dried fruit, hardtack, and nuts.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<quantity>10</quantity>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scimitar</name>
			<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.

Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 149</text>
			<type>5</type>
			<quantity>2</quantity>
			<value>25.0</value>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d6</damage1H>
			<damageType>3</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>10</weaponProperty>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Tinderbox</name>
			<text>This small container holds flint, fire steel, and tinder (usually dry cloth soaked in light oil) used to kindle a fire. Using it to light a torch - or anything else with abundant, exposed fuel - takes an action. Lighting any other fire takes 1 minute.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Waterskin</name>
			<text>A waterskin can hold up to 4 pints of liquid.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Yew Wand</name>
			<text>A druid can use such a druidic focus as a spellcasting focus, using it in place of any material component that does not have a cost.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 151</text>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Studded Leather Armor</name>
			<text>Made from tough but flexible leather, studded leather is reinforced with close-set rivets or spikes.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 144</text>
			<type>1</type>
			<slot>5</slot>
			<value>45.0</value>
			<weight>13.0</weight>
			<ac>12</ac>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Potion of Healing</name>
			<text>Rarity: Common
You regain 2d4 + 2 hit points when you drink this potion.	The potion's red liquid glimmers when agitated.

Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 187</text>
			<type>12</type>
			<quantity>2</quantity>
			<weight>0.5</weight>
			<magic>1</magic>
			<roll>2d4+2</roll>
		</item>
		<container>
			<name>Money</name>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Copper (cp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.01</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Silver (sp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.1</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Electrum (ep)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.5</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Gold (gp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>1.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Platinum (pp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>10.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
		</container>
		<note>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Common, Draconic, Druidic</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Faction</name>
			<text>You are a member of the Emerald Enclave, wilderness survivalists who preserve the natural order while rooting out unnatural threats.</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Background</name>
			<text>"All things have a spirit within. My spirit is my strength."
You were born in a sacred natural place, and you were marked from birth with supernatural gifts. Although your parents were farmers, your presence was a blessing to them and your village. The Druids of the circle overseeing the land near your home tutored you from a young age, allowing you to eschew the normal life a farm child. You became to shift your form when you entered puberty. Although the your build is slight, your powers of spirit grant you all the might you need.</text>
		</note>
	</character>
</pc>
