<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<baseclass UA="UA">
		<name>Ranger (Revised) (UA)</name>
		<hd>10</hd>
		<proficiency>Strength, Dexterity, Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, Survival</proficiency>
		<numSkills>3</numSkills>
		<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
		<armor>light armor, medium armor, shields</armor>
		<weapons>simple weapons, martial weapons</weapons>
		<tools>none</tools>
		<wealth>5d10x4</wealth>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>0,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>0,4,2,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>0,4,2,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>0,4,3,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>0,4,3,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,2,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,2,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,3,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,3,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,3,2</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,3,2</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Ranger (Revised)</name>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
				<text>Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
				<text>Tools: none</text>
				<text>Skills: Choose three from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You begin play with the following equipment, in addition to any equipment provided by your background.</text>
				<text>• (a) scale mail or (b) leather armor</text>
				<text>• (a) two shortswords or (b) two simple melee weapons</text>
				<text>• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d10 x 4 gp and choose your own equipment.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This class is from Unearthed Arcana: The Ranger, Revised, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this class.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Favored Enemy</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you have significant experience studying, tracking, hunting, and even talking to a certain type of enemy commonly encountered in the wilds. Choose a type of favored enemy: beasts, fey, humanoids, monstrosities, or undead. You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with weapon attacks against creatures of the chosen type. Additionally, you have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.</text>
				<text>	When you gain this feature, you also learn one language of your choice, typically one spoken by your favored enemy or creatures associated with it. However, you are free to pick any language you wish to learn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Natural Explorer</name>
				<text>You are a master of navigating the natural world, and you react with swift and decisive action when attacked. This grants you the following benefits:</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• You ignore difficult terrain.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• You have advantage on initiative rolls.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• On your first turn during combat, you have advantage on attack rolls against creatures that have not yet acted.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>	In addition, you are skilled at navigating the wilderness. You gain the following benefits when traveling for an hour or more:</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• Your group can't become lost except by magical means.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Fighting Style</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Fighting Style: Archery</name>
				<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
				<special>Fighting Style: Archery</special>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooter</name>
				<text>You are trained in making ranged attacks at close quarters. When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. Finally, you have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</text>
				<modifier category="bonus">ranged attacks +1</modifier>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
				<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
				<special>Fighting Style: Defense</special>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
				<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
				<special>Fighting Style: Dueling</special>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Fighting Style: Mariner</name>
				<text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name>
				<text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
				<special>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</special>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Fighting Style: Tunnel Fighter</name>
				<text>You excel at defending narrow passages, doorways, and other tight spaces. As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>By the time you reach 2nd level, you have learned to use the magical essence of nature to cast spells, much as a druid does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the ranger spell list.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spell Slots:</text>
				<text>	The Ranger table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell animal friendship and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast animal friendship using either slot.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher:</text>
				<text>	You know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the ranger spell list.</text>
				<text>	At each odd level, you learn an additional ranger spell of your choice. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 5th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the ranger spells you know and replace it with another spell from the ranger spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability:</text>
				<text>	Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your ranger spells, since your magic draws on your attunement to nature. You use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a ranger spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature>
				<name>Primeval Awareness</name>
				<text>Beginning at 3rd level, your mastery of ranger lore allows you to establish a powerful link to beasts and to the land around you.</text>
				<text>	You have an innate ability to communicate with beasts, and they recognize you as a kindred spirit. Through sounds and gestures, you can communicate simple ideas to a beast as an action, and can read its basic mood and intent. You learn its emotional state, whether it is affected by magic of any sort, its short-term needs (such as food or safety), and actions you can take (if any) to persuade it to not attack.</text>
				<text>	You cannot use this ability against a creature that you have attacked within the past 10 minutes.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you can attune your senses to determine if any of your favored enemies lurk nearby. By spending 1 uninterrupted minute in concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), you can sense whether any of your favored enemies are present within 5 miles of you. This feature reveals which of your favored enemies are present, their numbers, and the creatures' general direction and distance (in miles) from you.</text>
				<text>	If there are multiple groups of your favored enemies within range, you learn this information for each group.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Ranger Conclave</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you choose to emulate the ideals and training of a ranger conclave: the Beast Conclave, the Hunter Conclave, or the Stalker Conclave, all detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 5th, 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Greater Favored Enemy</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you are ready to hunt even deadlier game. Choose a type of greater favored enemy: aberrations, celestials, constructs, dragons, elementals, fiends, or giants. You gain all the benefits against this chosen enemy that you normally gain against your favored enemy, including an additional language. Your bonus to damage rolls against all your favored enemies increases to +4.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you have advantage on saving throws against the spells and abilities used by a greater favored enemy.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
			<feature>
				<name>Fleet of Foot</name>
				<text>Beginning at 8th level, you can use the Dash action as a bonus action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Hide in Plain Sight</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can remain perfectly still for long periods of time to set up ambushes.</text>
				<text>	When you attempt to hide on your turn, you can opt to not move on that turn. If you avoid moving, creatures that attempt to detect you take a -10 penalty to their Wisdom (Perception) checks until the start of your next turn. You lose this benefit if you move or fall prone, either voluntarily or because of some external effect. You are still automatically detected if any effect or action causes you to no longer be hidden.</text>
				<text>	If you are still hidden on your next turn, you can continue to remain motionless and gain this benefit until you are detected.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Vanish</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can't be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Feral Senses</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can't see. When you attack a creature you can't see, your inability to see it doesn't impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it.</text>
				<text>	You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn't hidden from you and you aren't blinded or deafened.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Foe Slayer</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you become an unparalleled hunter. Once on each of your turns, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</baseclass>
</compendium>
