<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Ranger (Revised) (UA)" UA="UA">
		<name>Ranger (Revised Hunter)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Ranger Conclave: Hunter (UA)</name>
				<text>Some rangers seek to master weapons to better protect civilization from the terrors of the wilderness. Members of the Hunter Conclave learn specialized fighting techniques for use against the most dire threats, from rampaging ogres and hordes of orcs to towering giants and terrifying dragons.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hunter: Hunter's Prey</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you gain one of the following features of your choice: Colossus Slayer, Giant Killer, or Horde Breaker.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hunter's Prey: Colossus Slayer</name>
				<text>Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it's below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hunter's Prey: Giant Killer</name>
				<text>When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hunter's Prey: Horde Breaker</name>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you make a weapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES" HB="HB">
				<name>Hunter's Prey: Zombie Killer</name>
				<text>When you damage an enemy with a weapon attack, that enemy has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes before the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hunter: Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hunter: Defensive Tactics</name>
				<text>At 7th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice: Escape the Horde, Multiattack Defense, or Steel Will.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Defensive Tactics: Escape the Horde</name>
				<text>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Defensive Tactics: Multiattack Defense</name>
				<text>When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Defensive Tactics: Steel Will</name>
				<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES" HB="HB">
				<name>Defensive Tactics: Resist Death</name>
				<text>You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid being cursed or paralyzed and you have resistance to necrotic damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hunter: Multiattack</name>
				<text>At 11th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice: Volley or Whirlwind Attack</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Multiattack: Volley</name>
				<text>You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon's range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Multiattack: Whirlwind Attack</name>
				<text>You can use your action to make melee attacks against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES" HB="HB">
				<name>Multiattack: Skirmish Attack</name>
				<text>You can use your action to choose up to 3 creatures within 30 feet of you that you can see and make a melee attack against each of them. Each creature must be within your reach to attack it, though you can use your movement before and after each attack to put those creatures within your reach.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hunter: Superior Hunter's Defense</name>
				<text>At 15th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice: Evasion, Stand Against the Tide, and Uncanny Dodge.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Superior Hunter's Defense: Evasion</name>
				<text>When you are subjected to an effect, such as a red dragon's fiery breath or a lightning bolt spell, that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on a saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Superior Hunter's Defense: Stand Against the Tide</name>
				<text>When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Superior Hunter's Defense: Uncanny Dodge</name>
				<text>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES" HB="HB">
				<name>Superior Hunter's Defense: Superior Resilience</name>
				<text>When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Constitution saving throw, such as a ghast's stench or a wraith's life drain, you can use a 20 instead of the number you rolled on the die for that saving throw.</text>
				<text>	You can use this feature up to three times. You regain all expended uses of this feature when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
