<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Monk">
		<name>Monk (Four Elements)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Four Elements</name>
                <text>You follow a monastic tradition that teaches you to harness the elements. When you focus your ki, you can align yourself with the forces of creation and bend the four elements to your will, using them as an extension of your body. Some members of this tradition dedicate themselves to a single element, but others weave the elements together.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Many monks of this tradition tattoo their bodies with representations of their ki powers, commonly imagined as coiling dragons, but also as phoenixes, fish, plants, mountains, and cresting waves.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Disciple of the Elements</name>
                <text>You learn magical disciplines that harness the power of the four elements. A discipline requires you to spend ki points each time you use it.</text>
                <text />
                <text>You know the Elemental Attunement discipline and one other elemental discipline of your choice. You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Casting Elemental Spells. Some elemental disciplines allow you to cast spells. To cast one of these spells, you use its casting time and other rules, but you don't need to provide material components for it.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Once you reach 5th level in this class, you can spend additional ki points to increase the level of an elemental discipline spell that you cast, provided that the spell has an enhanced effect at a higher level, as burning hands does. The spell's level increases by 1 for each additional ki point you spend. For example, if you are a 5th-level monk and use Sweeping Cinder Strike to cast burning hands, you can spend 3 ki points to cast it as a 2nd-level spell (the discipline's base cost of 2 ki points plus 1).</text>
                <text />
                <text>The maximum number of ki points you can spend to cast a spell in this way (including its base ki point cost and any additional ki points you spend to increase its level) is determined by your monk level. At 5th level, you may spend up to 3 ki points; this increases to 4 ki points at 9th level, 5 at 13th level, and 6 at 17th level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 2 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 3 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 4 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
