<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Sorcerer" HB="HB">
		<name>Sorcerer (Spell Surge)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Sorcerous Origin: Spell Surge</name>
				<text>The Spellsurge is an individual suffused by vast amounts of raw arcane power, typically from birth, as a result of powerful outside magic weaving itself into their DNA. A lich's dark phylactery, a djinni's golden lamp, or the storied Bluestones of Tremahia are all examples of objects capable of infusing an individual with the magic they radiate. Arcana comes easily to these seeming savants, and without the rigorous study of wizards, or the guiding patron of warlocks, the Spellsurge's magic can manifest in a myriad of unpredictable and often dangerous forms. But unlike Wild Magic sorcerers, who seek to harness their magic by twisting the threads of fate, a Spellsurge accepts the consequences of their sheer, unbridled power--and sets it free. Without control, these individuals often fall victim to themselves. But through a combination of talent, grit, and determination, a Spellsurge can learn to channel that might, and unleash it in ways that ba e even the greatest mages.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Spell Surge: Untamed Power</name>
				<text>The Spellsurge's approach to magic is direct and powerful--garnering these sorcerers reputations as "brutes" of the arcane world. Starting when you choose this origin at 1st level, your veins course with wild, surging magic, increasing the damage of your spells by an amount equal to one third of your Sorcerer level (rounded down).</text>
				<text>	In addition, whenever you cast a spell of Level 1 or higher, roll a d10: on a critical hit, a 10 on the d10, or at the DM's discretion, you must roll on the Surge table to create an additional random magical effect. Upon rolling a critical failure with a spell, or a 1 on the d10, you must roll specifically on the Backfire spell table, and the random magical effect replaces the initial spell. Spells with multiple attack rolls trigger only once. You may spend 1 Sorcery Point to quell a surge or backfire, but you must choose to do so before rolling on the table.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Backfire Table</name>
				<text>1. You cast Confusion centered on yourself</text>
				<text>2. You cast Grease and Fog Cloud centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>3. You cast Slow centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>4. A blast of force erupts from you--you are stunned for one round, and all creatures within 30 feet of you must succeed a Strength saving throw equal to your Spell Save DC, or be thrown 10 feet away and knocked Prone.</text>
				<text>5. You electrocute yourself, causing 1d8 lightning damage every time you touch another creature or metallic object for 1 hour. Your singed eyebrows and hair stand on end.</text>
				<text>6. You turn into a potted plant until the end of your next turn. While a plant, you are incapacitated and have vulnerability to all damage. If you drop to 0 hit points, your pot breaks, and your unconscious form reverts.</text>
				<text>7. For the next hour, any flammable object you touch not being worn or carried by a creature bursts into flame.</text>
				<text>8. You hiccup uncontrollably for 1 hour. You gain disadvantage to Stealth and Intimidation checks, and must succeed at a DC 12 Constitution saving throw before casting spells with a verbal component.</text>
				<text>9. Your clothing is banished to the Void for 1 minute.</text>
				<text>10. You cast a reverse version of Blink on yourself, where you roll the d20 at the start of your, and reappear at the end of your turn if sent to the Astral Plane.</text>
				<text>11. A burst of radiant sunlight erupts from your body, and all creatures within 30 feet of you becomes Blinded for the next minute, making saves against your Spell DC.</text>
				<text>12. All creatures within 10 feet of you are affected by the Hold Monster spell, making saves against your Spell DC.</text>
				<text>13. Flip a coin: on heads, you change genders for 24 hours. On tails, you are transformed into a talking beast of the DM's choosing for 24 hours, keeping your mental stats.</text>
				<text>14. You and all creatures within 30 feet of you gain vulnerability to physical damage for the next minute.</text>
				<text>15. You cast Gaseous Form centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>16. You cast Fireball at 3rd level centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>17. You cast Otto's Irresistable Dance centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>18. You cast Reverse Gravity centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>19. Your mind is pulled into a dark labyrinth, as you become affected by the Maze spell.</text>
				<text>20. Roll a d10: on a roll of 10, you are afflicted with vampirism; on a 1, you are cursed with lycanthropy.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Surge Table</name>
				<text>1. Maximize the damage of one damaging spell you cast within the next minute.</text>
				<text>2. You cast Reverse Gravity centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>3. You glitterbomb the surrounding area, casting Faerie Fire centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>4. You cast magic missile as a 5th-level spell.</text>
				<text>5. For the next minute, you can only speak in Halo-esque Gregorian chants.</text>
				<text>6. A target you choose immediately takes an extra Action.</text>
				<text>7. You cast Gaseous Form centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>8. You cast Otto's Irresistable Dance centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>9. You gain temporary hit points equal to your level.</text>
				<text>10. A spectral shield hovers near you for the next minute, granting you a +2 to AC and immunity to Magic Missile.</text>
				<text>11. For one minute, you can cast Misty Step without expending a spell slot.</text>
				<text>12. You cast Mirror Image on yourself.</text>
				<text>13. For 24 hours, you get a six-pack and gain the Monk's Martial Arts feature at Level 1. Additionally, your mouth does not appear to match your words when you speak.</text>
				<text>14. Regain one expended spell slot (max 5th level).</text>
				<text>15. A tyrannosaurus controlled by the DM appears in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of you, then disappears 1 minute later.</text>
				<text>16. A unicorn controlled by the DM appears in a space within 5 feet of you, then disappears 1 minute later.</text>
				<text>17. You summon Bigby's Hand, which uses its first action to flick you in the groin. You are stunned for one round, but the hand is then placed under your control. The hand lasts for 1 minute, and does not require concentration.</text>
				<text>18. 1d6 pixies controlled by the DM appear in unoccupied spaces within 60 feet of you. THey consider you an ally unless you are fighting Beasts or Fey creatures, and cast spells on random targets. The pixies vanish after 1 minute.</text>
				<text>19. You are immune to the effects of alcohol for 24 hours.</text>
				<text>20. For 24 hours, small, white rabbits inexplicably seem to appear at random inside your clothing, pockets, bags, and any other containers you interact with.</text>
				<text>21. You grow a long beard and mane made of feathers that remain until you sneeze, at which point the feathers explode from your face and head.</text>
				<text>22. All creatures within 30 feet of you heal 2d8 hit points.</text>
				<text>23. For one hour, you are affected by the Detect Thoughts spell. If a creature resists probing, you maintain the spell--but the creature becomes immune for the remainder.</text>
				<text>24. A burst of radiant sunlight erupts from your body, and all creatures within 30 feet of you become Blinded for the next minute, making saves against your Spell DC.</text>
				<text>25. You are encircled by a 4th Level Wall of Fire with a 10-foot-radius. The ring of fire lasts for 1 minute, and it burns burns burns...</text>
				<text>26. For the next minute, all your spells with a casting time of 1 action can be cast as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>27. Illusory butterflies and flower petals flutter in the air within 10 feet of you for the next 24 hours.</text>
				<text>28. You are surrounded by faint, ethereal music for the next minute, and it accurately reflects your inner thoughts.</text>
				<text>29. Flip a coin: if heads, your size increases by one size category for 24 hours--if tails, it decreases.</text>
				<text>30. You cast Hunger of Hadar at a point you choose, as you accidentally tear a rift into extradimensional space.</text>
				<text>31. Cats are inexplicably drawn to you for 24 hours. Roll a d20--your roll determines the number of stray cats that follow you around for the duration. Cats act as temporary followers, and you can attempt to give them basic commands as a bonus action. Flip a coin: if heads, they obey your command--if tails, they attack you for 1 round.</text>
				<text>32.1d6 flumphs controlled by the DM appear in unoccupied spaces within 60 feet of you and are frightened of you.  ey vanish after 1 minute.</text>
				<text>33. A 3rd Level thunderstep triggers immediately the next time you take damage. Lasts for 1 minute.</text>
				<text>34. You become really, really, ridiculously good looking. You gain advantage on Charisma checks for 24 hours, and must fend off suitors by force.</text>
				<text>35. An exquisite gemstone worth 3d10 x 10 gold pieces coalesces in front of you.</text>
				<text>36. You cast Grease and Fog Cloud centered on yourself.</text>
				<text>37. A Simulacrum of yourself appears beside you. It can only cast Cantrips, and has completely free will.</text>
				<text>38. Another target within 5 feet of you is affected by Haste. If no creature is within 5 feet, you are affected by it.</text>
				<text>39. For the next hour, any flammable object you touch not being worn or carried by a creature bursts into  ame.</text>
				<text>40. Your clothing is banished to the Void for 1 minute.</text>
				<text>41. Choose one energy type: for one minute, you deal [1d4] extra damage of that type every time you deal damage.</text>
				<text>42. You can't speak for the next minute. Whenever you try, pink bubbles  oat out of your mouth.</text>
				<text>43. An Otiluke's Freezing Sphere appears in your hand. 44. For one hour, you gain a hover speed of 20.</text>
				<text>45. Each creature within 30 feet of you takes 2d10 necrotic damage. You regain hit points equal to the sum of the necrotic damage dealt.</text>
				<text>46. You instantly regain 3d4 Sorcery Points.</text>
				<text>47. For the next minute, you regain 10 hit points at the start of each of your turns.</text>
				<text>48. Up to three creatures you choose within 30 feet of you instantly take 5d10 lightning or fire damage.</text>
				<text>49. You gain resistance to all damage for the next minute.</text>
				<text>50. Your age changes by 2d20 years in a direction of your choosing, bringing you to a minimum of 1 year old.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Spell Surge: Arcane Anomaly</name>
				<text>Though lacking the in-depth knowledge of studied wizards, you are naturally gifted in the arcane arts, manifesting and manipulating magics beyond your understanding. At 1st level, you gain the ability to cast one spell as an "Arcane Anomaly" once per Long Rest. This must be a spell from the Bard, Warlock, or Wizard lists, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. In order to cast your Anomaly, you must use the spell's appropriate cast time to make a Charisma (Performance) check, with DC equal to 10 + the spell level. On a success, the spell is immediately cast using the appropriate slot; on a failure, neither the ability nor the spell slot activate, but you can reattempt on future turns. You can take Disadvantage to roll on the Surge Table, or Advantage by rolling on the Backfire table (if successful, the spell is not replaced). Your Spellcasting Ability for these spells is Charisma.</text>
				<text>	You gain one additional use of Arcane Anomaly at 5th, 9th, 13th, and 17th levels. Whenever you do so, you may take one more qualified spell as an Arcane Anomaly. Once chosen, spells cannot be changed.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Spell Surge: Synergy</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you are able to weave some of your untamed magic into the spells you cast. Once per Long Rest, you can tap into pockets of your simmering power, and pair a spell with a Surge or Back re option of your choosing, excluding #45-50 on the Surge Table. You can make the decision after casting the spell, but before the effect takes place.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Spell Surge: Cry Havoc</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you have opened the floodgates of your incredible, raw power, allowing it to surge through you and pour into the spells that you cast. At the start of your turn, you may choose to forgo movement and activate this feature, entering a supercharged magical state. While channeling this ability, your spell attacks are made with advantage, and saving throws against your spells are made with disadvatage. However, attacks targeting you are also made with advantage, and you automatically fail Dexterity saving throws. The effect lasts for 1 minute, and ends early if you use movement, lose control of your character, or leave the current plane.</text>
				<text>	You can use Cry Havoc a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1) without penalty, replenishing on a Long Rest--for each additional use, you suffer one level of Exhaustion.
				</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Spell Surge: Transcendence</name>
				<text>By 18th level, you discover a means to fully unleash your magic, and allow it to flow freely through you. The ebbing tide of arcana has altered your body, subtly enhancing your mental and physical fortitude. Becoming more and more a being of energy incarnate, magic itself begins bending to your will. You gain the following:</text>
				<text>• Your Constitution Score and Cap both increase by 2.</text>
				<text>• You gain access to #45-50 on the Surge Table when using your "Synergy"feature.</text>
				<text>• You are able to cast the Thaumaturgy cantrip, and without a verbal component.</text>
				<text>• You can use your Reaction to force a creature within 60 feet to make a Constitution saving throw against your Spell Save DC in order to maintain Concentration.</text>
				<text>In addition, you gain up to three distinctive physical traits that serve as manifestations of your surging power: glowing white eyes, crackling electricity, or billowing blue flame are all examples of potential trait options. You are able to activate these traits at will, and the DM can choose to grant Advantage or Disadvantage on specific Charisma checks while they are active, depending on the trait and situation.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
