<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
<subclass baseclass="Barbarian" HB="HB">
	<name>Barbarian (Courageous Heart)</name>
  <autolevel level="3">
    <feature optional="YES">
      <name>Matter at Hand</name>
      <text>When you choose this path at 3rd level, you gain prociency with improvised weapons and unarmed strikes. The damage for these attacks is 1d4 + your Strength modifier. If your improvised weapon is similar in shape and function to another weapon, you can use that weapon’s statistics instead.</text>
    </feature>
    <feature optional="YES">
      <name>Favor the Bold</name>
      <text>At 3rd level, when the adrenaline kicks in, primal instinct propels certain heroes to awe-inspiring feats, seeming to add just a smidge of luck at the right moment.</text>
      <text>	While raging, whenever you make a saving throw, or an attack roll with an unarmed strike or improvised weapon, you can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the total.</text>
    </feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Hearty Blow</name>
      <text>At 6th level, when you hit with an unarmed or improvised weapon attack while raging, roll 1d4 and add its total to the attack’s damage. This feature increases in potency as you gain barbarian levels to 2d4 at 10th, and 3d4 at 14th level.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Stroke of Inspiration</name>
      <text>At 10th level, you seem to stumble upon the right clue, connection, or words, even when you have no idea what is going on. When you fail a Charisma, Intelligence, or Wisdom-based ability check, you expend a use of your rage to reroll the check with advantage.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Tenacious Heart</name>
      <text>At 14th level, whenever you make a Constitution saving throw to remain conscious because of your Relentless Rage feature, you can use one of the following Tenacious Heart options of your choice. You can use only one Tenacious Heart option per round and must decide before you make the roll.</text>
      <text>	Inspiring. You inspiring last stand fills your allies with renewed vigor. Allies within 30 feet of you that can see or hear you gain 10 temporary hit points.</text>
      <text>	Persistent. You won’t quit without a fight. The DC of your Relentless Rage feature is reduced by 5 until the end of your turn.</text>
      <text>	Rallying. Your heroic refusal to die fills your allies with confidence. All allies within 30 feet of you that can see or hear you gain advantage on the next attack roll they make within the next 1 minute.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</subclass>
</compendium>
