<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Barbarian" HB="HB">
		<name>Barbarian (Sacred Kin)</name>
		<spellAbility>Constitution</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots optional="YES">2,2,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Primal Path: Path of Sacred Kin</name>
				<text>As in all civilizations, stories of life's origin are intertwined with the path of mythical beings consorting among them out of grand purpose or boredom. These stories, told since the first sunrise, act as guiding parables when a tribe or people faces a crucial juncture in their fate. They tell of times of great peril, when a powerful individual emerges from their number, led by a forbear's spirit, to lead them to their destiny—for good or ill. The circumstances surrounding the event could be as simple as the death of a clan's chieftain, as great as the threat of slavery, or even extinction.</text>
				<text>	With most tribes, the elders are aware of a spirit's affinity to their people but other times they are just as surprised by the mark themselves. When the gift manifests itself it is easily recognized often celebrated. There are instances, however, when it is perceived as an omen.</text>
				<text>In battle, your ancestor's spirit courses through you, imbuing your frenzy with the supernatural fury of the spirit, be they celestial, demonic, draconic, or even aberrant in nature.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Spellcasting</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, you channel your ancient blood to harness the power of your forbearer. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the sorcerer spell list.</text>
				<text />
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>You learn three cantrips of your choice from the sorcerer spell list. You learn an additional sorcerer cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</text>
				<text />
				<text>Spell Slots</text>
				<text>The Sacred Kin Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell fog cloud and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast fog cloud using either slot.</text>
				<text />
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>You know three 1st-level sorcerer spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the conjuration and divination spells on the sorcerer spell list.</text>
				<text>	The Spells Known column of the Sacred Kin Spellcasting table shows when you learn more sorcerer spells of 1st level or higher. Each of these spells must be a conjuration or divination spell of your choice, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
				<text>	The spells you learn at 8th, 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic on the sorcerer's spell list.</text>
				<text>	Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the sorcerer spells you know with another spell of your choice from the sorcerer spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, and it must be a conjuration or divination spell, unless you're replacing the spell you gained at 8th, 14th, or 20th level.</text>
				<text />
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Constitution is your spellcasting ability for your sorcerer spells, since the power of your magic relies on your ability to harness the magic in your blood. You use your Constitution whenever a spell refers to your spell casting ability. In addition, you use your Constitution modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a spell you cast or when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Ancestral Origins</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, when you choose this path, you choose the origin of your ancestor, either celestial, demonic, draconic, or aberrant.</text>
				<text>Choose one ancestor type from the Ancestral Origins Table. The chosen ancestor associated with your origin is used by features you gain later.</text>
				<text>You can speak, read, and write the language of your ancestor and can weave their curses and oaths into your battle-cries. Additionally, whenever you make a Charisma check when interacting with a creature of your ancestors' type, your proficiency bonus is doubled if it applies to the check.</text>
				<text>Ancestor    Damage Type                 Language</text>
				<text>Celestial   Thunder or Radiant          Celestial</text>
				<text>Demonic     Necrotic or Poison          Abyssal</text>
				<text>Draconic    Cold, Fire, or Lightning    Draconic</text>
				<text>Aberrant    Psychic or Force            Deep Speech</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Mythic Manifestation</name>
				<text>As ancient magic flows through you, physical traits of your lineage emerge. Starting at 3rd level, whenever you cast a spell, you regain hit points equal to three times spell slot's level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Supernatural Fury</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you can focus on the magic in your blood, allowing you to concentrate your rage into the ancient magic of your bloodline and enter a Supernatural Fury. You gain the ability to cast and concentrate on spells, even while raging, at the expense of your physical resistances.</text>
				<text>	When you enter your Supernatural Fury and you aren't wearing heavy armor, the following benefits replace the bene ts of the Rage feature:</text>
				<text>	• You gain a bonus to your AC equal to your Strength modifier (minimum of +1).</text>
				<text>	• You have advantage on Constitution checks and saving throws made to maintain concentration on a spell.</text>
				<text>	• You have resistance to magical damage and are immune to the damage type you chose from your Ancestral Origin.</text>
				<text>Your Supernatural Fury lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you're knocked unconscious or if your turn ends and you haven't attacked a hostile creature, cast a spell, or taken damage since your last turn. You can end your Supernatural Fury on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Ancestry Points</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you have 4 ancestry points, and you gain more as you reach higher levels, as shown in the Ancestry Points column of the Bloodline Spellcasting table. You regain all spent ancestry points when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Metamagic</name>
				<text>As represented by ancestry points, you're able to create a variety of magical effects. You gain the ability to twist your spells to suit your needs. You gain two of the metamagic options of your choice from the sorcerer's list of available options. You gain another one at 10th and 17th level.</text>
				<text>You can use only one metamagic option when you cast a spell, unless otherwise noted.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Transcendent Legacy</name>
				<text>At 6th level, when you enter your rage, you can spend 1 ancestry point to imbue your weapons with the damage type you chose from your Ancestral Origin. For 1 hour, your weapon attacks deal magical damage of that type instead of bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage.</text>
				<text>	At 14th level, weapon attacks with this feature ignore resistance, but not immunity, to the damage type of your Ancestral Origin.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Ancestral Guidance</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, when you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action. If the cantrip dealt damage, you make this attack with advantage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of Sacred Kin: Immortal Birthright</name>
				<text>Beginning at 14th level, you gain the ability to sprout a pair of wings from your back, gaining a flying speed equal to your current speed. The wings, either feathered, dragon-scaled, leathery, or nightmarish, take the form your ancestor. You can create these wings as a bonus action on your turn. They last until you dismiss them as a bonus action on your turn. You can't manifest your wings while wearing armor unless the armor is made to accommodate them, and clothing not made to accommodate your wings might be destroyed when you manifest them.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you have advantage on saving throws against spells and other magical effects.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
