<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Rogue" HB="HB">
		<name>Rogue (Scout BotR)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Roguish Archetype: Scout</name>
				<text>You focus your training on travel and exploration. As a scout, you might be a guide, a hunter, a messenger, an explorer, or even a commando in service to an army, sabotaging the enemy encampments while gathering crucial intelligence about their numbers and movements. Being successful as a scout requires speed, sharp senses, and the ability to move unseen and unheard. Mastering these techniques will help you stay alive as you venture ahead into the most dangerous areas.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Scout: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
				<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Nature and Survival skills if you don't already have it. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those proficiencies.</text>
				<proficiency>Nature, Survival</proficiency>
				<modifier category="skills">Nature +PROF +PROF</modifier>
				<modifier category="skills">Survival +PROF +PROF</modifier>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Scout: Forward Observer</name>
				<text>Beginning at 3rd level, whenever no other creature is within 30 feet of you, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks and on Dexterity checks made to roll initiative.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Scout: Fleet-Footed</name>
				<text>At 9th level, while you wear light or no armor, your speed increases by 10 feet and neither climbing nor swimming costs you extra movement. In addition, you have advantage on saving throw made to avoid gaining level of exhaustion from forced march.</text>
				<modifier category="bonus">speed +10</modifier>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Scout: Pathfinder</name>
				<text>Upon reaching 13th level, you become a master at overland travel. Fot any destination you have visited at least once, you always know how far it is away from you and in what direction the destination lies from your current position. When traveling one hour or longer to such a destination, you gain the following benefits:</text>
				<text>	• Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel.</text>
				<text>	• You cannot be lost except by magical means.</text>
				<text>	• You are always considered alert to danger regardless other activities you engage in while traveling.</text>
				<text>	• Finally, if you travel alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Scout: Skirmisher</name>
				<text>Beginning at 17th level, whenever you move half your speed or farther before you take the Attack action, you have advantage on your attack roll, and your movement after the attack does not provoke opportunity attacks.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
