<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<background>
		<name>Emissary</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Persuasion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Persuasion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of fine clothes, a badge of office, papers identifying you as an agent of an institution (such as the great church), and a purse containing 25 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Access</name>
			<text>You have free access to movers and shakers with whom your patron organization has connections. You can petition for and usually receive an audience from a noble, guild head, or crime lord, provided they are amenable to the group you represent. While you are on official business, your host will usually provide you with accommodations, sustenance, and entertainment, provided you remain on good terms.
			</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Reborn</name>
		<proficiency>History, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Your choice of two from among Arcana, History, and Persuasion.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiency</name>
			<text>One type of artisan’s tools or musical instrument</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A walking staff (quarterstaff), a list containing items that you must do to right the crimes of your prior life, a set of ragged traveler’s clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Echoes of Another Life</name>
			<text>As one of the reborn, you have an entire previous life’s worth of memories and experiences to draw on, and sometimes you come across people or places you recognize from that past life. When you select this background, choose a single organization that is relatively widespread; for example, you might choose the religious orders of a faith from your past, the military forces of a kingdom, an order of monks, or the cabal of cultists that once served you. In your past life, you had a strong relationship with that organization—whether friendly or antagonistic, as you choose when you select this background. You have a strong familiarity with the traditions, practices, hierarchies, and trappings of that organization, enough so that you can convincingly converse with a member of that organization and pass yourself off as a member. You can draw upon your knowledge of that organization at will.
			</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Variant Hermit (Friar)</name>
		<proficiency>Medicine, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Medicine, Religion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Herbalism Kit</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A holy symbol, a winter blanket, a set of common clothes, an herbalism kit, and 5 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Wanderer</name>
			<text>You have an excellent memory for maps and geography, and you can always recall the general layout of terrain, settlements, and other features around you. In addition, you can find food and fresh water for yourself and up to five other people each day, provided that the land offers berries, small game, water, and so forth.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Variant Soldier (Churchguard)</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, Intimidation, Perception, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Athletics, Intimidation, Perception, Religion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>An insignia of rank, a churchguard uniform, a holy symbol, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Military Rank</name>
			<text>You have a military rank from your career as a soldier. Soldiers loyal to your former military organization still recognize your authority and influence, and they defer to you if they are of a lower rank. You can invoke your rank to exert influence over other soldiers and requisition simple equipment or horses for temporary use. You can also usually gain access to friendly military encampments and fortresses where your rank is recognized.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
</compendium>
