<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<!--Plane Shift: Amonkhet-->
	<background>
		<name>Initiate</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Athletics, Intimidation</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set, vehicles (land)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A simple puzzle box, a scroll containing the basic teachings of the  ve gods, a gaming set, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp. If you have completed any trials before the start of the campaign, you also have any cartouches you have earned.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Trials of the Five Gods</name>
			<text>Your life is oriented around your participation in the five trials that will determine your worthiness in the afterlife. While you prepare for and undergo those trials, you have constant access to training. A comfortable place to live and regular meals are provided to you by servitor mummies (the anointed) under the supervision of viziers. You can enjoy these benefits only as long as you obey the societal norms of Naktamun—training for the trials (with or without your crop), obeying the orders of the gods, and following the instructions of their viziers. If you violate these norms, you risk being treated as a dissenter. See "Trials of the Five Gods" for more information about undertaking the trials and their rewards.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Vizier</name>
		<proficiency>History, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>History, Religion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of artisan's tools, one type of musical instrument</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of artisan's tools or a musical instrument (one of your choice), a scroll of your god's teachings, a vizier's cartouche, a set of fine clothes, and a pouch containing 25 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Voice of Authority</name>
			<text>Your voice is the voice of your god, at least in theory. Your job might include training and instructing initiates, and they are required to obey you. In any circumstance, an initiate is expected to defer to your voice and obey your commands. If you abuse this authority, though, your god might personally punish you.
		</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Dissenter(Initiate)</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Athletics, Intimidation</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set, vehicles (land)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A simple puzzle box, a scroll containing the basic teachings of the  ve gods, a gaming set, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp. If you have completed any trials before the start of the campaign, you also have any cartouches you have earned.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Shelter of Dissenters</name>
			<text>If they wish to have any hope of survival, whether hiding within the city or cast out into the desert, dissenters must help each other. You canfind a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other dissenters. They will help shield you from those who hunt you, possibly even risking their lives for you.
		</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Dissenter(Vizier)</name>
		<proficiency>History, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>History, Religion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of artisan's tools, one type of musical instrument</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of artisan's tools or a musical instrument (one of your choice), a scroll of your god's teachings, a vizier's cartouche, a set of fine clothes, and a pouch containing 25 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Shelter of Dissenters</name>
			<text>If they wish to have any hope of survival, whether hiding within the city or cast out into the desert, dissenters must help each other. You canfind a place to hide, rest, or recuperate among other dissenters. They will help shield you from those who hunt you, possibly even risking their lives for you.
		</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
</compendium>
