<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
<!--Tal'dorei Campaign Setting-->
<background>
	<name>Clasp Member</name>
	<proficiency>Deception</proficiency>
	<trait>
		<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
		<text>Deception, plus your choice of one between Sleight of Hand or Stealth.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
		<text>Your choice of one from Thieves' Tools, Forgery Kit, or Disguise Kit.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Languages</name>
		<text>Thieves' Cant</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Equipment</name>
		<text>A set of dark common clothes including a hood, a set of tools to match your choice of tool proficiency, and a belt pouch containing 10g.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Feature: A Favor In Turn</name>
		<text>You have gained enough clout within the Clasp that you can call in a favor from your contacts, should you be close enough to a center of Clasp activity. A request for a favor can be no longer than 20 words, and is passed up the chain to an undisclosed Spireling for approval.This favor can take a shape up to the DM's discretion depending on the request, with varying speeds of fulfillment: If muscle is requested, an NPC Clasp minion can temporarily aid the party. If money is needed, a small loan can be provided. If you've been imprisoned, they can look into breaking you free, or paying off the jailer.
		</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The turn comes when a favor is asked to be repaid. The favor debt can be called in without warning, and many times with intended immediacy. Perhaps the player is called to commit a specific burglary without the option to decline. Maybe they must press a dignitary for a specific secret at an upcoming ball. The Clasp could even request a hit on an NPC, no questions asked or answered. The DM is to provide a debt call proportionate to the favor fulfilled. If a favor is not repaid within a reasonable period of time, membership to the Clasp can be revoked, and if the debt is large enough, the player may become the next hit contract to make the rounds.
		</text>
	</trait>
</background>
<background>
	<name>Lyceum Student</name>
	<proficiency/>
	<trait>
		<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
		<text>Your choice of two from among Arcana, History, and Persuasion.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Languages</name>
		<text>Two of your choice</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Equipment</name>
		<text>A set of fine clothes, a lyceum student uniform, a writing kit (small pouch with a quill, ink, folded parchment, and a small penknife), and a belt pouch containing 10g.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Feature: Student Privilege</name>
		<text>You've cleared enough lessons, and gained an ally or two on staff, to have access to certain chambers within the Lyceum (and some other allied universities) that outsid-ers would not. This allows use of any Tool Kit, so long as the Tool Kit is used on the grounds of the Lyceum and is not removed from its respective chamber (each tool kit is magically marked and will sound an alarm if removed). More dangerous kits and advanced crafts (such as use of a Poisoner's Kit, or the enchanting of a magical item) might require staff supervision. You may also have access to free crafting materials and enchanting tables, so long as they are relatively inexpensive, or your argument for them is convincing (up to the staff's approval and DM's discretion).
		</text>
	</trait>
</background>
<background>
	<name>Ashari</name>
	<proficiency>Nature</proficiency>
	<trait>
		<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
		<text>Nature, plus your choice of one between Arcana or Survival.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
		<text>Herbalism Kit</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Languages</name>
		<text>One of your choice.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Equipment</name>
		<text>A staff, hunting gear (a shortbow with 20) arrows, or a hunting trap), a set of traveler's clothes, a belt pouch containing 10 gp.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Feature: Elemental Harmony</name>
		<text>Your upbringing surrounded by such strong, wild elemental magics has attuned your senses to the very nature of their chaotic forces, enabling you to subtly bend them to your will in small amounts. You learn the Prestidigitation Cantrip, but can only produce the extremely minor eff??ects below that involve the element of your chosen Ashari tribe:
		• You create an instantaneous puff of wind strong enough to blow papers off a desk, or mess up someone's hair (Zephrah).
		• You instantaneously create and control a burst of flame small enough to light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire. (Pyrah).
		• You instantaneously create a small rock within your hand, no larger than a gold coin, that turns to dust after a minute (Terrah).
		• You instantaneously create enough hot or cold water to fill a small glass (Vesrah).
		</text>
	</trait>
</background>
<background>
	<name>Recovered Cultist</name>
	<proficiency>Religion, Deception</proficiency>
	<trait>
		<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
		<text>Nature, plus your choice of one between Arcana or Survival.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Languages</name>
		<text>One of your choice.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Equipment</name>
		<text>Vestments and a holy symbol of your previous cult, a set of common clothes, a belt pouch containing 15 gp.
		</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Feature: Wicked Awareness</name>
		<text>Your time worshipping in secrecy and shadow at the altar of malevolent forces has left you with insight and keen awareness to those who still operate in such ways. You can often spot hidden signs, messages, and signals left in populated places. If actively seeking signs of a cult or dark following, you have an easier time locating and decoding the signs or social interactions that signify cult activity, gaining advantage on any ability checks to discover such details.</text>
	</trait>
</background>
<background>
	<name>Fate-Touched</name>
	<proficiency/>
	<trait>
		<name>Feature: Fortune's Grace</name>
		<text>Your fate-touched essence occasionally leads surrounding events to shift in your favor. You gain 1 Luck point, as per the Lucky feat outlined within the Player's Handbook pg 167. This luck point is used in the same fashion as the feat, and you regain this expended luck point when you finish a long rest. If you already have the Lucky feat, you add this luck point to your total for the feat.</text>
	</trait>
</background>
</compendium>
