<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<background>
		<name>Dead</name>
		<proficiency>History, Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>History, Intimidation</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>50 feet of rope, a bit of dirt from your grave in a sacred vial, a set of common clothes, two rare coins with which you were buried, and a belt pouch with 5 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Spirit Talk</name>
			<text>You can connect with the souls of the dead thanks to the long time you spent dead. You may spend a day of downtime communicating with the souls to learn a piece of information by asking a question. The quality and specifics of the information you get is up to the DM.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Heretic</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Deception, Religion</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A holy symbol (subtly modified to represent your own heretical belief), a prayer book or prayer wheel, vestments, a bottle of invisible ink, a quill, a set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 10 gp.
			</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Heretical Belief</name>
			<text>d8 Belief</text>
			<text>1  Dark Moon. A doctrine that ascribes Selûne and Shar as two aspects of the same deity</text>
			<text>2  Fatemakers. Tymorans who believe mortals can influence and control luck.</text>
			<text>3  Threefold God. A belief that Tyr, Helm and Torm are all the same god.</text>
			<text>4  Forsaken One. A conspiracy that Savras and Leira conceived and abandoned a god child.</text>
			<text>5  Three-Faced Sun. The sun is a tripartite deity, with divine aspects of dawn, noon and dusk.</text>
			<text>6  Shared Suffering. Flagellant Ilmatari who say all mortals must share their god’s suffering.</text>
			<text>7  Entropy. Belief that dying gods sent a divine sphere of annihilation to Toril to kill wizards.</text>
			<text>9  Harlot’s Coin. Belief that Waukeen sold her divinity to Graz’zt and he receives her prayers.
			</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Heretical Contacts</name>
			<text>You know where to find heretics in settlements where your faith is represented. If no heretics are present, you can indoctrinate weak-willed souls if you spend a day preaching. Where heretics are present, you can always find a place to hide, rest and recuperate. If needed, they can help you escape the settlement on a cart or through a secret tunnel.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Legendary Lineage</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, History</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Athletics, History</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Vehicles (land)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A set of traveler's clothes, a wood figure made in the likeness of an ancestor, a signet ring, a gaming set in which you are proficient, and a belt pouch containing 15 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Good Reputation</name>
			<text>Since your family name is known, you can reap many benefits by flying the flag of your heritage. People in positions of power and privilege are willing to take a meeting with you and grant you favors. The DM decides the extent and effect of these favors, but they shouldn't involve lavish gifts or great personal risk to the granter.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Polymorphed</name>
		<proficiency>Survival, Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Survival and choose one additional from either Animal Handling or Deception.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A bag of caltrops, a realistic ink drawing of your polymorphed form, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch with 5 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Kindred Spirit</name>
			<text>Nonhostile creatures of the same type as your polymorphed form are inclined to like you. These creatures might help guide you to a place if they know its location, provide you with shelter, or shield you from danger, provided they aren't put directly into harm’s way.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<background>
		<name>Retired Adventurer</name>
		<proficiency>History, Insight</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>History, Insight</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>An old map to a secret dungeon you never got around to visiting, a set of common clothes, a set of bone dice or a deck of cards, and a purse containing 25 gp</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: C-List Celebrity</name>
			<text>Whenever you are in a civilized area that knows of you past adventures, you can live a aristocratic life style for free as people wish to honor your past deeds. You can also use your influence to gain audiences with important political figures and get random gifts from admiring fans. However if you choose to use your influence in this way, it also alerts anyone in the area looking for you of your location and draws attention to your party.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
</compendium>
