<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<spell>
		<name>Anwyn's Elysian Palace</name>
		<level>9</level>
		<school>C</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Touch</range>
		<components>V, S, M (ash from the central hearth of a site consecrated to Anwyn)</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Cleric</classes>
		<text>You and one creature you touch are transported to the great palace of Anwyn on the plane of Elysium. The palace is one of her many homes, though she is rarely present there. There is, however, a 1 percent chance for Anwyn to be in residence. If so, and if you are Anwynian, you might be granted an audience with the god, with the effects of such an audience determined by the GM. In any event, five solars—Atteretix the body servant, Miallira the handmaid, Rigar the door warden, Ayalla the chamberlain, and Yovarra the chef—staff the place. You and your companion arrive in the palace's atrium. If your companion is hostile, the solars immediately attack.</text>
		<text>	You can use a bonus action to return to the spot where you cast this spell at any time. Each hour you remain in the palace after 24 hours, you take a permanent and cumulative –1 penalty to your Constitution score. If your Constitution score drops to 0, you die and your soul moves to its proper destination.</text>
		<text>	Anyone spending 8 hours or longer in the palace enjoys splendid feats and perfect restfulness, conferring the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• A creature regains all hit points and Hit Dice. 8 hours in the palace also cures the creature of all diseases, removes all poisons, and lifts all curses other than those bestowed by a god or a being of similar status.</text>
		<text>• A dead creature is restored to life as by the true resurrection spell.</text>
		<text>• A creature can ask the solars questions that can be answered with a yes or a no as if the creature cast the commune spell. A creature can ask up to twenty questions and has no chance of receiving no answer.</text>
		<text>• For 24 hours after leaving the palace, a creature benefits as if under the effect of the bless spell and is immune to the frightened condition.</text>
		<text>	Once you cast this spell, you cannot cast it again until one year, one month, and one day pass.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Armor of Earth</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>A</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Self</range>
		<components>V, S, M (a bit of dirt)</components>
		<duration>8 hours</duration>
		<classes>Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer</classes>
		<text>You rub dirt into your skin, causing it to assume the appearance of earth that lasts for the duration or until you don any armor or you become immersed in liquid. Until the spell ends, your base AC becomes 11 + your spellcasting modifier and you ignore the effects of moving across difficult terrain made from earth, stone, or plants.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Fair Light</name>
		<level>5</level>
		<school>Ev</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Self</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>1 hour</duration>
		<classes>Cleric</classes>
		<text>A 60-foot-radius sphere of sparkling light spreads out from you. The sphere is made of bright light, and sheds dim light for an additional 60 feet.</text>
		<text>	Golden halos form around the heads of good creatures illuminated by the spell, while shadowy halos form around the heads of evil creatures. Furthermore, good creatures illuminated by the light roll a d4 and add the resulting number to the number rolled on the d20 when making attack rolls or saving throws. Conversely, evil creatures illuminated by the light must roll a d4 whenever they make attack rolls or saving throws and subtract that number from the number rolled on the d20.</text>
		<text>	If any of this spell's area overlaps with an area of dark- ness created by a spell of 5th level or lower, the spell that created the darkness is dispelled.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Fist of Air</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>Ev</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>30 ft.</range>
		<components>V,S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Sorcerer, Wizard</classes>
		<text>You strike at a creature or object in range with a sudden concentrated blast of air, impacting it with incredible force. The target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failure, the target takes 1d6 bludgeoning damage and is pushed 5 feet in a direction you choose.</text>
		<text>	This spell's damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Judgment of Maal</name>
		<level>9</level>
		<school>N</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<ritual>YES</ritual>
		<range>30 ft</range>
		<components>V, S, M (black sapphire gem worth at least 1,000 gp)</components>
		<duration>Permanent</duration>
		<classes>Cleric</classes>
		<text>You draw forth the soul of one evil creature that has been dead no longer than one hour and is within the spells range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be sent to the land of the dead to be judged by Maal, and be imprisoned in that place for the duration of the spell. The creature's corpse remains, but is now an empty soulless shell.</text>
		<text>	While imprisoned, the creature to whom the soul belongs cannot be restored to life by any means. Shattering the black sapphire gem ends the spell and enables the soul to escape the land of the dead.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Light of the Moon</name>
		<level>5</level>
		<school>Ev</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Self (60-foot line)</range>
		<components>V, S, M (an opaque lens of white glass)</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
		<classes>Cleric, Druid</classes>
		<text>A beam of soft light flashes from your hand in a 5-foot wide, 60-foot-long line. Each creature in the line must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature gains one level of exhaustion and must then suc- ceed on a Wisdom saving throw or fall unconscious until it takes damage or someone uses an action to shake or slap the sleeping creature awake. Shapechangers make their saving throws with disadvantage and if they fail, they instantly revert to their original form and cannot assume a different form until the spell ends. Undead and creatures immune to being charmed are immune to this effect.</text>
		<text>	Undead creatures in the line must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 4d8 radiant damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
		<text>	For the duration, a mote of soft light shines from your hand, shedding dim light in a 30-foot radius. This light is moonlight.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Power of the Earth</name>
		<level>4</level>
		<school>T</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Touch</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>1 hour</duration>
		<classes>Cleric, Druid, Sorcerer</classes>
		<text>You touch a willing creature in contact with an earthen or stone surface. For the duration, the target gains a number of benefits while it remains in contact with such a surface:</text>
		<text>	The target cannot be moved against its will by any means and has advantage on any check or saving throw made to avoid being knocked prone.</text>
		<text>	The target gains tremorsense out to a range of 60 feet. See MM for details on this special sense.</text>
		<text>	The target gains 3d6 temporary hit points. If the target breaks contact with an earthen or stone surface, any remaining temporary hit points disappear until the target resumes contact with such a surface.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Shooting Stars</name>
		<level>9</level>
		<school>Ev</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>1 mile</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Druid, Sorcerer, Wizard</classes>
		<text>Tiny motes of cold radiance fall to the ground at eight different points you can see within range. Each creature directly below a falling mote must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be struck by the mote. On a failure, you decide whether the creature takes 12d6 cold damage or regains 12d6 hit points.</text>
		<text>	Then, center a 30-foot-radius sphere on each point you chose. The sphere spreads around corners. For each creature in an area other than one struck by the mote, you decide whether the creature takes 3d6 cold damage or regains 3d6 hit points.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Test of Souls</name>
		<level>4</level>
		<school>D</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<ritual>YES</ritual>
		<range>Touch</range>
		<components>V</components>
		<duration>1 hour</duration>
		<classes>Cleric</classes>
		<text>You touch a creature to test their heart. The target must be willing, or the spell has no effect. When you cast the spell, you and the target are transported in your minds' eyes to a testing ground, where the target undergoes a series of tests of a metaphysical and metaphorical nature to reveal their attitudes toward life, the gods, death, and more. You observe these tests and can put the target to tests of your own devising.</text>
		<text>	The testing lasts for the duration, during which time you and the target are unconscious. If either of you take any damage or are slapped or shaken, the spell ends.</text>
		<text>	At the end of the hour, you learn all the following information about the target:</text>
		<text>	• Alignment</text>
		<text>	• Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma scores</text>
		<text>	• Religious affiliation and degree of piety</text>
		<text>	• Race</text>
		<text>	• Whether the target has told you any lies during the preceding 24 hours and what those lies, if any, were.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Ward Against Undeath</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>N</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Touch</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>10 days</duration>
		<classes>Cleric</classes>
		<text>You touch a corpse, or other remains. For the duration, the target can't become undead.</text>
	</spell>
</compendium>
