<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="YES">
<!--Barbarian-->
<class>
	<name>Barbarian (Path of the Berserker)</name>
	<hd>12</hd>
	<proficiency>Strength, Constitution</proficiency>
	<spellAbility></spellAbility>
	<autolevel level="1">
		<feature>
			<name>Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Armor: Light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
			<text>Weapons: Simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
			<text>Tools: None</text>
			<text>Saving Throws: Strength, Constitution</text>
			<text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Intimidation, Nature, Perception, and Survival</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Starting Equipment</name>
			<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
			<text>• (a) a greataxe or (b) any martial melee weapon </text>
			<text>• (a) two handaxes or (b) any simple weapon </text>
			<text>• 2d4 x 10 gp, an explorer's pack, and four javelins</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Rage</name>
			<text>In battle, you fight with primal ferocity. On your turn, you can enter a rage as a bonus action.</text>
			<text>While raging, you gain the following benefits if you aren't wearing heavy armor:</text>
			<text>• You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</text>
			<text>• When you make a melee weapon attack using Strength, you gain a +2 bonus to the damage roll. This bonus increases as you level.</text>
			<text>• You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</text>
			<text>If you are able to cast spells, you can't cast them or concentrate on them while raging.</text>
			<text>Your rage lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are knocked unconscious or if your turn ends and you haven't attacked a hostile creature since your last turn or taken damage since then. You can also end your rage on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
			<text>Once you have raged twice, you must finish a long rest before you can rage again. The number of times you can rage between rages goes up as you level.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Unarmored Defense</name>
			<text>While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="2">
		<feature>
			<name>Reckless Attack</name>
			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can throw aside all concern for defense to attack with fierce desperation. When you make your first attack on your turn, you can decide to attack recklessly. Doing so gives you advantage on melee attack rolls using Strength during this turn, but attack rolls against you have advantage until your next turn.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Danger Sense</name>
			<text>At 2nd level, you gain an uncanny sense of when things nearby aren't as they should be, giving you an edge when you dodge away from danger.</text>
			<text>You have advantage on Dexterity saving throws against effects that you can see, such as traps and spells. To gain this benefit, you can't be blinded, deafened, or incapacitated.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<feature>
			<name>Primal Path (Path of the Berserker)</name>
			<text>For some barbarians, rage is a means to an end -- that end being violence. The Path of the Berserker is a path of untrammeled fury, slick with blood. As you enter the berserker's rage, you thrill in the chaos of battle, heedless of your own health or well-being.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Frenzy</name>
			<text>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, you can go into a frenzy when you rage. If you do so, for the duration of your rage you can make a single melee weapon attack as a bonus action on each of your turns after this one. When your rage ends, you suffer one level of exhaustion.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Increased Rages</name>
			<text>You can now rage up to 3 times between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">
		<feature>
			<name>Extra Attack</name>
			<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Fast Movement</name>
			<text>Starting at 5th level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you aren't wearing heavy armor.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
		<feature>
			<name>Mindless Rage</name>
			<text>Beginning at 6th level, you can't be charmed or frightened while raging. If you are charmed or frightened when you enter your rage, the effect is suspended for the duration of the rage.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Increased Rages</name>
			<text>You can now rage up to 4 times between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
		<feature>
			<name>Feral Instinct</name>
			<text>By 7th level, your instincts are so honed that you have advantage on initiative rolls.</text>
			<text>Additionally, if you are surprised at the beginning of combat and aren't incapacitated, you can act normally on your first turn, but only if you enter your rage before doing anything else on that turn.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">
		<feature>
			<name>Brutal Critical</name>
			<text>Beginning at 9th level, you can roll one additional weapon damage die when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.</text>
			<text>This increases to two additional dice at 13th level and three additional dice at 17th level.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Rage Damage Increase</name>
			<text>Your bonus to the damage rolls of melee attacks increases to +3.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">
		<feature>
			<name>Intimidating Presence</name>
			<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can use your action to frighten someone with your menacing presence. When you do so, choose one creature that you can see within 30 feet of you. If the creature can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8+your proficiency bonus+your Charisma modifier) or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn. On subsequent turns, you can use your action to extend the duration of this effect on the frightened creature until the end of your next turn. This effect ends if the creature ends its turn out of line of sight or more than 60 feet away from you.</text>
			<text>If the creature succeeds on its saving throw, you can't use this feature on that creature again for 24 hours.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
		<feature>
			<name>Relentless Rage</name>
			<text>Starting at 11th level, your rage can keep you fighting despite grievous wounds. If you drop to 0 hit points while you're raging and don't die outright, you can make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw. If you succeed, you drop to 1 hit point instead.</text>
			<text>Each time you use this feature after the first, the DC increases by 5. When you finish a short or long rest, the DC resets to 10.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Increased Rages</name>
			<text>You can now rage up to 5 times between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">
		<feature>
			<name>Retaliation</name>
			<text>Starting at 14th level, when you take damage from a creature that is within 5 feet of you. you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
		<feature>
			<name>Persistent Rage</name>
			<text>Beginning at 15th level, your rage is so fierce that it ends early only if you fall unconscious or if you choose to end it.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Rage Damage Increase</name>
			<text>Your bonus to the damage rolls of melee attacks increases to +4.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Increased Rages</name>
			<text>You can now rage up to 5 times between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
		<feature>
			<name>Indomitable Might</name>
			<text>Beginning at 18th level, if your total for a Strength check is less than your Strength score, you can use that score in place of the total.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">
		<feature>
			<name>Primal Champion</name>
			<text>At 20th level, you embody the power of the wilds. Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 4. Your maximum for those scores is now 24.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Unlimited Rages</name>
			<text>You have unlimited rages between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</class>
<class>
	<name>Barbarian (Path of the Totem Warrior)</name>
	<hd>12</hd>
	<proficiency>Strength, Constitution</proficiency>
	<spellAbility></spellAbility>
	<autolevel level="1">
		<feature>
			<name>Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Armor: Light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
			<text>Weapons: Simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
			<text>Tools: None</text>
			<text>Saving Throws: Strength, Constitution</text>
			<text>Skills: Choose two from Animal Handling, Athletics, Intimidation, Nature, Perception, and Survival</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Starting Equipment</name>
			<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
			<text>• (a) a greataxe or (b) any martial melee weapon </text>
			<text>• (a) two handaxes or (b) any simple weapon </text>
			<text>• 2d4 x 10 gp, an explorer's pack, and four javelins</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Rage</name>
			<text>In battle, you fight with primal ferocity. On your turn, you can enter a rage as a bonus action.</text>
			<text>While raging, you gain the following benefits if you aren't wearing heavy armor:</text>
			<text>• You have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</text>
			<text>• When you make a melee weapon attack using Strength, you gain a +2 bonus to the damage roll. This bonus increases as you level.</text>
			<text>• You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</text>
			<text>If you are able to cast spells, you can't cast them or concentrate on them while raging.</text>
			<text>Your rage lasts for 1 minute. It ends early if you are knocked unconscious or if your turn ends and you haven't attacked a hostile creature since your last turn or taken damage since then. You can also end your rage on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
			<text>Once you have raged twice, you must finish a long rest before you can rage again. The number of times you can rage between rages goes up as you level.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Unarmored Defense</name>
			<text>While you are not wearing any armor, your Armor Class equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Constitution modifier. You can use a shield and still gain this benefit.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="2">
		<feature>
			<name>Reckless Attack</name>
			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can throw aside all concern for defense to attack with fierce desperation. When you make your first attack on your turn, you can decide to attack recklessly. Doing so gives you advantage on melee attack rolls using Strength during this turn, but attack rolls against you have advantage until your next turn.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Danger Sense</name>
			<text>At 2nd level, you gain an uncanny sense of when things nearby aren't as they should be, giving you an edge when you dodge away from danger.</text>
			<text>You have advantage on Dexterity saving throws against effects that you can see, such as traps and spells. To gain this benefit, you can't be blinded, deafened, or incapacitated.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<feature>
			<name>Primal Path (Path of the Totem Warrior)</name>
			<text>The Path of the Totem Warrior is a spiritual journey, as the barbarian accepts a spirit animal as guide, protector, and inspiration. In battle, your totem spirit fills you with supernatural might, adding magical fuel to your barbarian rage.</text>
			<text>Most barbarian tribes consider a totem animal to be kin to a particular clan. In such cases, it is unusual for an individual to have more than one totem animal spirit, though exceptions exist.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Spirit Seeker</name>
			<text>Yours is a path that seeks attunement with the natural world, giving you a kinship with beasts. At 3rd level when you adopt this path, you gain the ability to cast the beast sense and speak with animals spells, but only as rituals, as described in chapter 10.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Totem Spirit</name>
			<text>At 3rd level, when you adopt this path, you choose a totem spirit and gain its feature. You must make or acquire a physical totem object- an amulet or similar adornment - that incorporates fur or feathers, claws, teeth, or b ones of the totem animal. At your option, you also gain minor physical attributes that are reminiscent of your totem spirit. For example, if you have a bear totem spirit, you might be unusually hairy and thick-skinned, or if your totem is the eagle, your eyes turn bright yellow.</text>
			<text>Your totem animal might be an animal related to those listed here but more appropriate to your homeland. For example, you could choose a hawk or vulture in place of an eagle.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Bear. While raging, you have resistance to all damage except psychic damage. The spirit of the bear makes you tough enough to stand up to any punishment.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Eagle. While you're raging and aren't wearing heavy armor, other creatures have disadvantage on opportunity attack rolls against you, and you can use the Dash action as a bonus action on your turn. The spirit of the eagle makes you into a predator who can weave through the fray with ease.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Wolf. While you're raging, your friends have advantage on melee attack rolls against any creature within 5 feet of you that is hostile to you. The spirit of the wolf makes you a leader of hunters.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Increased Rages</name>
			<text>You can now rage up to 3 times between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">
		<feature>
			<name>Extra Attack</name>
			<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Fast Movement</name>
			<text>Starting at 5th level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you aren't wearing heavy armor.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
		<feature>
			<name>Aspect of the Beast</name>
			<text>At 6th level, you gain a magical benefit based on the totem animal of your choice. You can choose the same animal you selected at 3rd level or a different one.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Bear. You gain the might of a bear. Your carrying capacity (including maximum load and maximum lift) is doubled, and you have advantage on Strength checks made to push, pull, lift, or break objects.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Eagle. You gain the eyesight of an eagle. You can see up to 1 mile away with no difficulty, able to discern even fine details as though looking at something no more than 100 feet away from you. Additionally, dim light doesn't impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Wolf. You gain the hunting sensibilities of a wolf. You can track other creatures while traveling at a fast pace, and you can move stealthily while traveling at a normal pace (see chapter 8 for rules on travel pace).</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Increased Rages</name>
			<text>You can now rage up to 4 times between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
		<feature>
			<name>Feral Instinct</name>
			<text>By 7th level, your instincts are so honed that you have advantage on initiative rolls.</text>
			<text>Additionally, if you are surprised at the beginning of combat and aren't incapacitated, you can act normally on your first turn, but only if you enter your rage before doing anything else on that turn.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">
		<feature>
			<name>Brutal Critical</name>
			<text>Beginning at 9th level, you can roll one additional weapon damage die when determining the extra damage for a critical hit with a melee attack.</text>
			<text>This increases to two additional dice at 13th level and three additional dice at 17th level.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Rage Damage Increase</name>
			<text>Your bonus to the damage rolls of melee attacks increases to +3.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">
		<feature>
			<name>Spirit Walker</name>
			<text>At 10th level, you can cast the commune with nature spell, but only as a ritual. When you do so, a spiritual version of one of the animals you chose for Totem Spirit or Aspect of the Beast appears to you to convey the information you seek.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
		<feature>
			<name>Relentless Rage</name>
			<text>Starting at 11th level, your rage can keep you fighting despite grievous wounds. If you drop to 0 hit points while you're raging and don't die outright, you can make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw. If you succeed, you drop to 1 hit point instead.</text>
			<text>Each time you use this feature after the first, the DC increases by 5. When you finish a short or long rest, the DC resets to 10.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Increased Rages</name>
			<text>You can now rage up to 5 times between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">
		<feature>
			<name>Totemic Attunement</name>
			<text>At 14th level, you gain a magical benefit based on a totem animal of your choice. You can choose the same animal you selected previously or a different one.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Bear. While you're raging, any creature within 5 feet of you that's hostile to you has disadvantage on attack rolls against targets other than you or another character with this feature. An enemy is immune to this effect if it can't see or hear you or if it can't be frightened.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Eagle. While raging, you have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed. This benefit works only in short bursts; you fall if you end your turn in the air and nothing else is holding you aloft.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Wolf. While you're raging, you can use a bonus action on your turn to knock a Large or smaller creature prone when you hit it with melee weapon attack.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
		<feature>
			<name>Persistent Rage</name>
			<text>Beginning at 15th level, your rage is so fierce that it ends early only if you fall unconscious or if you choose to end it.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Increased Rages</name>
			<text>You can now rage up to 5 times between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Rage Damage Increase</name>
			<text>Your bonus to the damage rolls of melee attacks increases to +4.</text>
		</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
		<feature>
			<name>Indomitable Might</name>
			<text>Beginning at 18th level, if your total for a Strength check is less than your Strength score, you can use that score in place of the total.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">
		<feature>
			<name>Primal Champion</name>
			<text>At 20th level, you embody the power of the wilds. Your Strength and Constitution scores increase by 4. Your maximum for those scores is now 24.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Unlimited Rages</name>
			<text>You have unlimited rages between long rests.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</class>
<!--Bard-->
<class>
	<name>Bard (College of Lore)</name>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<proficiency>Dexterity, Charisma</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: Light armor</text>
				<text>Weapons: Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</text>
				<text>Tools: Three musical instruments of your choice</text>
				<text>Saving Throws: Dexterity, Charisma</text>
				<text>Skills: Choose any three</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a rapier, (b) a longsword, or (c) any simple weapon </text>
				<text>• (a) a diplomat's pack  or (b) an entertainer's pack </text>
				<text>• (a) a lute or (b) any other musical instrument </text>
				<text>• 5d4 x 10 gp, leather armor, and a dagger</text>
			</feature>
		<slots>2, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Spellcasting</name>
			<text>You have learned to untangle and reshape the fabric of reality in harmony with your wishes and music. Your spells are part of your vast repertoire, magic that you can tune to different situations.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Cantrips</text>
			<text>You know two cantrips of your choice from the bard spell list. You learn an additional Bard cantrip at 4th and 10th level.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Spell Slots</text>
			<text>You have two first level spell slots You gain additional spell slots as you level up..</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher</text>
			<text>You know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the bard spell list.</text> 
			<text>You learn an additional bard spell for which you have a spell slot for at 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 5th, 6th, 7th 8th, 9th, 11th, 13th, 15th, and 17th levels.</text>
			<text>Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the bard spells you know and replace it with another spell from the bard spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
			<text>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your bard spells. Your magic comes from the heart and soul you pour into the performance of your music or oration. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a bard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
			<text>Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
			<text>Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Ritual Casting</text>
			<text>You can cast any bard spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
			<text>You can use a musical instrument as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Bardic Inspiration</name>
			<text>You can inspire others through stirring words or music. To do so, you use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than yourself within 60 feet of you who can hear you. That creature gains one Bardic Inspiration die, a d6.</text>
			<text>Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Bardic Inspiration die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once the Bardic Inspiration die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one Bardic Inspiration die at a time.</text>
			<text>You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
			<text>Your Bardic Inspiration die changes when you reach certain levels in this class. The die becomes a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="2">
		<slots>2, 3</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Jack of All Trades</name>
			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can add half your proficiency bonus, rounded down, to any ability check you make that doesn't already include your proficiency bonus.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Song of Rest</name>
			<text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can use soothing music or oration to help revitalize your wounded allies during a short rest. If you or any friendly creatures who can hear your performance regain hit points at the end of the short rest, each of those creatures regains an extra 1d6 hit points.</text>
			<text>The extra hit points increase when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d8 at 9th level, to 1d10 at 13th level, and to 1d12 at 17th level.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<slots>2, 4, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Bard College (Lore)</name>
			<text>Bards of the College of Lore know something about most things, collecting bits of knowledge from sources as diverse as scholarly tomes and peasant tales. Whether singing folk ballads in taverns or elaborate compositions in royal courts, these bards use their gifts to hold audiences spellbound. When the applause dies down, the audience members might find themselves questioning everything they held to be true, from their faith in the priesthood of the local temple to their loyalty to the king.</text>
			<text>The loyalty of these bards lies in the pursuit of beauty and truth, not in fealty to a monarch or following the tenets of a deity. A noble who keeps such a bard as a herald or advisor knows that the bard would rather be honest than politic.</text>
			<text>The college's members gather in libraries and sometimes in actual colleges, complete with classrooms and dormitories, to share their lore with one another. They also meet at festivals or affairs of state, where they can expose corruption, unravel lies, and poke fun at self-important figures of authority.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Bonus Proficiencies</name>
			<text>When you join the College of Lore at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with three skills of your choice.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Expertise</name>
			<text>At 3rd level, choose two of your skill proficiencies. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Cutting Words</name>
			<text>Also at 3rd level, you learn how to use your wit to distract, confuse, and otherwise sap the confidence and competence of others. When a creature that you can see within 60 feet of you makes an attack roll, an ability check, or a damage roll, you can use your reaction to expend one of your uses of Bardic Inspiration, rolling a Bardic Inspiration die and subtracting the number rolled from the creature's roll. You can choose to use this feature after the creature makes its roll, but before the DM determines whether the attack roll or ability check succeeds or fails, or before the creature deals its damage. The creature is immune if it can't hear you or if it's immune to being charmed.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">
		<slots>3, 4, 3</slots> 
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Font of Inspiration</name>
			<text>Beginning when you reach 5th level, you regain all of your expended uses of Bardic Inspiration when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Bardic Inspiration</name>
			<text>Your Bardic Inspiration die becomes a d8</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Countercharm</name>
			<text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to use musical notes or words of power to disrupt mind-influencing effects. As an action, you can start a performance that lasts until the end of your next turn. During that time, you and any friendly creatures within 30 feet of you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed. A creature must be able to hear you to gain this benefit. The performance ends early if you are incapacitated or silenced or if you voluntarily end it (no action required).</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Additional Magical Secrets</name>
			<text>At 6th level, you learn two spells of your choice from any class. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip. The chosen spells count as bard spells for you but don't count against the number of bard spells you know.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Song of Rest</name>
			<text>The extra hit points increase to 1d8.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Magical Secrets</name>
			<text>By 10th level, you have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines. Choose two spells from any class, including this one. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip.</text>
			<text>The chosen spells count as bard spells for you and are included in the number in the Spells Known column of the Bard table.</text>
			<text>You learn two additional spells from any class at 14th level and again at 18th level.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Expertise</name>
			<text>At 10th level, choose two of your skill proficiencies. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Bardic Inspiration</name>
			<text>Your Bardic Inspiration die becomes a d10</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="13">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Song of Rest</name>
			<text>The extra hit points increase to 1d8.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Magical Secrets</name>
			<text>By 14th level, you have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines. Choose two spells from any class, including this one. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip.</text>
			<text>The chosen spells count as bard spells for you and are included in the number in the Spells Known column of the Bard table.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Peerless Skill</name>
			<text>Starting at 14th level, when you make an ability check, you can expend one use of Bardic Inspiration. Roll a Bardic Inspiration die and add the number rolled to your ability check. You can choose to do so after you roil the die for the ability check, but before the DM tells you whether you succeed or fail.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Bardic Inspiration</name>
			<text>Your Bardic Inspiration die becomes a d12</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="17">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Song of Rest</name>
			<text>The extra hit points increase to 1d8.</text>
		</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Magical Secrets</name>
			<text>By 18th level, you have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines. Choose two spells from any class, including this one. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip.</text>
			<text>The chosen spells count as bard spells for you and are included in the number in the Spells Known column of the Bard table.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Superior Inspiration</name>
			<text>At 20th level, when you roll initiative and have no uses of Bardic Inspiration left, you regain one use.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</class>
<class>
	<name>Bard (College of Valor)</name>
	<hd>8</hd>
	<proficiency>Dexterity, Charisma</proficiency>
	<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: Light armor</text>
				<text>Weapons: Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords</text>
				<text>Tools: Three musical instruments of your choice</text>
				<text>Saving Throws: Dexterity, Charisma</text>
				<text>Skills: Choose any three</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a rapier, (b) a longsword, or (c) any simple weapon </text>
				<text>• (a) a diplomat's pack  or (b) an entertainer's pack </text>
				<text>• (a) a lute or (b) any other musical instrument </text>
				<text>• 5d4 x 10 gp, leather armor, and a dagger</text>
			</feature>
		<slots>2, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Spellcasting</name>
			<text>You have learned to untangle and reshape the fabric of reality in harmony with your wishes and music. Your spells are part of your vast repertoire, magic that you can tune to different situations.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Cantrips</text>
			<text>You know two cantrips of your choice from the bard spell list. You learn an additional Bard cantrip at 4th and 10th level.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Spell Slots</text>
			<text>You have two first level spell slots You gain additional spell slots as you level up..</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher</text>
			<text>You know four 1st-level spells of your choice from the bard spell list.</text> 
			<text>You learn an additional bard spell for which you have a spell slot for at 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 5th, 6th, 7th 8th, 9th, 11th, 13th, 15th, and 17th levels.</text>
			<text>Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the bard spells you know and replace it with another spell from the bard spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
			<text>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your bard spells. Your magic comes from the heart and soul you pour into the performance of your music or oration. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a bard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
			<text>Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
			<text>Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Ritual Casting</text>
			<text>You can cast any bard spell you know as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag.</text>
			<text> </text>
			<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
			<text>You can use a musical instrument as a spellcasting focus for your bard spells.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Bardic Inspiration</name>
			<text>You can inspire others through stirring words or music. To do so, you use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature other than yourself within 60 feet of you who can hear you. That creature gains one Bardic Inspiration die, a d6.</text>
			<text>Once within the next 10 minutes, the creature can roll the die and add the number rolled to one ability check, attack roll, or saving throw it makes. The creature can wait until after it rolls the d20 before deciding to use the Bardic Inspiration die, but must decide before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails. Once the Bardic Inspiration die is rolled, it is lost. A creature can have only one Bardic Inspiration die at a time.</text>
			<text>You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain any expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
			<text>Your Bardic Inspiration die changes when you reach certain levels in this class. The die becomes a d8 at 5th level, a d10 at 10th level, and a d12 at 15th level.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="2">
		<slots>2, 3</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Jack of All Trades</name>
			<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can add half your proficiency bonus, rounded down, to any ability check you make that doesn't already include your proficiency bonus.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Song of Rest</name>
			<text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can use soothing music or oration to help revitalize your wounded allies during a short rest. If you or any friendly creatures who can hear your performance regain hit points at the end of the short rest, each of those creatures regains an extra 1d6 hit points.</text>
			<text>The extra hit points increase when you reach certain levels in this class: to 1d8 at 9th level, to 1d10 at 13th level, and to 1d12 at 17th level.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<slots>2, 4, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Bard College (Valor)</name>
			<text>Bards of the College of Lore know something about most things, collecting bits of knowledge from sources as diverse as scholarly tomes and peasant tales. Whether singing folk ballads in taverns or elaborate</text>			
			<text>Bards of the College of Valor are daring skalds whose tales keep alive the memory of the great heroes of the past, and thereby inspire a new generation of heroes. These bards gather in mead halls or around great bonfires to sing the deeds of the mighty, both past and present. They travel the land to witness great events firsthand and to ensure that the memory of those events doesn't pass from the world. With their songs, they inspire others to reach the same heights of accomplishment as the heroes of old.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Bonus Proficiencies</name>
			<text>When you join the College of Lore at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with medium armor, shields, and martial weapons.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Expertise</name>
			<text>At 3rd level, choose two of your skill proficiencies. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Cutting Words</name>
			<text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to inspire others in battle. A creature that has a Bardic Inspiration die from you can roll that die and add the number rolled to a weapon damage roll it just made. Alternatively, when an attack roll is made against the creature, it can use its reaction to roll the Bardic Inspiration die and add the number rolled to its AC against that attack, after seeing the roll but before knowing whether it hits or misses.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">
		<slots>3, 4, 3</slots> 
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Font of Inspiration</name>
			<text>Beginning when you reach 5th level, you regain all of your expended uses of Bardic Inspiration when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Bardic Inspiration</name>
			<text>Your Bardic Inspiration die becomes a d8</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Countercharm</name>
			<text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to use musical notes or words of power to disrupt mind-influencing effects. As an action, you can start a performance that lasts until the end of your next turn. During that time, you and any friendly creatures within 30 feet of you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened or charmed. A creature must be able to hear you to gain this benefit. The performance ends early if you are incapacitated or silenced or if you voluntarily end it (no action required).</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
		<name>Extra Attack</name>
		<text>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 1</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">
		<slots>3, 4, 3, 3, 3, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Song of Rest</name>
			<text>The extra hit points increase to 1d8.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Magical Secrets</name>
			<text>By 10th level, you have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines. Choose two spells from any class, including this one. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip.</text>
			<text>The chosen spells count as bard spells for you and are included in the number in the Spells Known column of the Bard table.</text>
			<text>You learn two additional spells from any class at 14th level and again at 18th level.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Expertise</name>
			<text>At 10th level, choose two of your skill proficiencies. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Bardic Inspiration</name>
			<text>Your Bardic Inspiration die becomes a d10</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="13">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Song of Rest</name>
			<text>The extra hit points increase to 1d8.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Magical Secrets</name>
			<text>By 14th level, you have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines. Choose two spells from any class, including this one. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip.</text>
			<text>The chosen spells count as bard spells for you and are included in the number in the Spells Known column of the Bard table.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Battle Magic </name>
			<text>At 14th level, you have mastered the art of weaving spellcasting and weapon use into a single harmonious act. When you use your action to cast a bard spell, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Bardic Inspiration</name>
			<text>Your Bardic Inspiration die becomes a d12</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="17">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Improved Song of Rest</name>
			<text>The extra hit points increase to 1d8.</text>
		</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 1, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Magical Secrets</name>
			<text>By 18th level, you have plundered magical knowledge from a wide spectrum of disciplines. Choose two spells from any class, including this one. A spell you choose must be of a level you can cast, as shown on the Bard table, or a cantrip.</text>
			<text>The chosen spells count as bard spells for you and are included in the number in the Spells Known column of the Bard table.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 1, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
			<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">
		<slots>4, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 1, 1</slots>
		<feature>
			<name>Superior Inspiration</name>
			<text>At 20th level, when you roll initiative and have no uses of Bardic Inspiration left, you regain one use.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</class>
<class>
		<name>Paladin (Vengeance)</name>
		<hd>10</hd>
		<proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>0,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>0,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>0,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>0,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>0,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: All armor, Shields
Weapons: Simple weapons, martial weapons
Tools: None
					
Saving Throws: Wisdom, Charisma
Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</text>
				<text>• (a) five javelins or (b) any simple melee weapon</text>
				<text>• (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• 5d4 x 10 gp, Chain mail, and a holy symbol</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Divine Sense</name>
				<text>The presence of strong evil registers on your senses like a noxious odor, and powerful good rings like heavenly music in your ears. As an action, you can open your awareness to detect such forces. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any celestial, fiend, or undead within 60 feet of you that is not behind total cover. You know the type (celestial, fiend, or undead) of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity (the vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich, for instance). Within the same radius, you also detect the presence of any place or object that has been consecrated or desecrated, as with the hallow spell.</text>
				<text>You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1+ your Charisma modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Lay on Hands</name>
				<text>Your blessed touch can heal wounds. You have a pool of healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your paladin level x 5.</text>
				<text>As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.</text>
				<text>Alternatively, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multi pIe poisons with a single use of Lay on Hands, expending hit points separately
for each one.</text>
				<text>This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Fighting Style</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your speciality. Choose one of the following options. You can't take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.
				</text>
				<text>DEFENSE: While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.
				</text>
				<text>DUELING: When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.
				</text>
				<text>GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING:
When you roll a 1or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.
</text>
				<text>PROTECTION:
When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the paladin spell list.</text>
				<text>
PREPARING AND CASTING SPELLS
The Paladin table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain ali expended spell slots when you finish a long rest</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of paladin spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list. When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>For example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least I minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</text>
				<text>
SPELLCASTING ABILITY
Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin spells, since their power derives from the strength of your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one. </text>
				<text>Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma Modifier</text>
				<text>Spell attack Modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma Modifier</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus
You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your paladin spells. </text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Divine Smite</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one paladin spell slot to deal radiant damage to the target, in addition to the weapon's damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus ld8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by ld8 if the target is an undead or a fiend.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature>
				<name>Divine Health</name>
				<text>By 3rd level, the divine magic flowing through you makes you immune to disease</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Tenents of Vengeance</name>
				<text>The tenets of the Oath of Vengeance vary by paladin, but all the tenets revolve around punishing wrongdoers by any means necessary. Paladins who uphold these tenets are willing to sacrifice even their own righteousness to mete out justice upon those who do evil, so the paladins are often neutral or lawful neutral in alignment. The core principles of the tenets are brutally simple.</text>
				<text>Fight the Greater Evil. Faced with a choice of fighting my sworn foes or combating a lesser evil, I choose the greater evil.</text>
				<text>No Mercy for the Wicked. Ordinary foes might win my mercy, but my sworn enemies do not.</text>
				<text>By Any Means Necessary. My qualms can't get in the way of exterminating my foes.</text>
				<text>Restitution. If my foes wreak ruin on the world, it is because I failed to stop them. I must help those harmed by their misdeeds.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Channel Divinity (Vengeance)</name>
				<text>When you take this oath at 3rd level, you gain the following two Channel Divinity options.</text>
				<text>Abjure Enemy. As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer of denunciation, using your Channel Divinlty. Choose one creature within 60 feet of you that you can see. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw, unless it is immune to being frightened. Fiends and undead have disadvantage on this saving throw.
On a failed save, the creature is frightened for 1 minute or until it takes any damage. While frightened, the creature's speed is 0, and It can't benefit from any bonus to its speed.</text>
				<text>On a successful save, the creature's speed is halved for 1 minute or until the creature takes any damage.</text>
				<text>Vow of Enmity. As a bonus action, you can utter a vow of enmity against a creature you can see within 10 feet of you, using your Channel Divinity. You gain advantage on attack rolls against the creature for 1 minute or until it drops to O hit points or falls unconscious.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Oath of Vengeance Spells (Level 3)</name>
				<text>You gain access to the following spells: bane, and hunter's mark.</text>
				<text>Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
				<text>If you gain an oath spell that doesn't appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<feature>
				<name>Extra Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Oath of Vengeance Spells (Level 5)</name>
				<text>You gain access to the following spells: hold person, misty step.</text>
				<text>Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
				<text>If you gain an oath spell that doesn't appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Aura of Protection</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</text>
				<text>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature>
				<name>Relentless Avenger</name>
				<text>By 7th level, your supernatural focus helps you close off a foe's retreat. When you hit a creature with an opportunity attack, you can move up to half your speed immediately after the attack and as part of the same reaction. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
			</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<feature>
				<name>Oath of Vengeance Spells (Level 9)</name>
				<text>You gain access to the following spells: haste, protection from energy.</text>
				<text>Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
				<text>If you gain an oath spell that doesn't appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Aura of Courage</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level. you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be frightened while you are conscious.</text>
				<text>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature>
				<name>Improved Divine Smite</name>
				<text>By 11th level, you are so suffused with righteous might that all your melee weapon strikes carry divine power with them. Whenever you hit a creature with a melee weapon, the creature takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage. If you also use your Divine Smite with an attack, you add this damage to the extra damage of your Divine Smite.
				</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
			</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<feature>
				<name>Oath of Vengeance Spells (Level 13)</name>
				<text>You gain access to the following spells: banishment, dimension door.</text>
				<text>Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
				<text>If you gain an oath spell that doesn't appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Cleansing Touch</name>
				<text>Beginning at 14th level, you can use your action to end one spell on yourself or on one willing creature that you touch.</text>
				<text>You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature>
				<name>Soul of Vengeance</name>
				<text>Starting at 15th level, the authority with which you speak your Vow of Enmity gives you greater power over your foe. When a creature under the effect of your Vow of Enmity makes an attack, you can use your reaction to make a melee weapon attack against that creature if it is within range.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature>
				<name>Oath of Vengeance Spells (Level 17)</name>
				<text>You gain access to the following spells: hold monster, scrying.</text>
				<text>Each oath has a list of associated spells. You gain access to these spells at the levels specified in the oath description. Once you gain access to an oath spell, you always have it prepared. Oath spells don't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
				<text>If you gain an oath spell that doesn't appear on the paladin spell list, the spell is nonetheless a paladin spell for you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Aura of Protection (Range Increase)</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.</text>
				<text>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Aura of Courage (Range Increase)</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be frightened while you are conscious.</text>
				<text>At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Avenging Angel</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you ean assume the form of an angelic avenger. Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 hour, you gain the following benefits:</text>
				<text>Wings sprout from your back and grant you a flying speed of 60 feet.</text>
				<text>You emanate an aura of menace in a 30-foot radius. The first time any enemy creature enters the aura or starts its turn there during a battle, the creature must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for 1 minute or unti it takes any damage. Attack rolls against the frightened creature have advantage.</text>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>

	<class>
		<name>Rogue (Thief)</name>
		<hd>8</hd>
		<proficiency>Dexterity, Intelligence</proficiency>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: Light Armor
Weapons: Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords
Tools: Thieves' tools
					
Saving Throws: Dexterity, Intelligence
Skills: Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>• You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword </text>
				<text>• (a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword </text>
				<text>• (a) a burglar's pack or (b) a dungeoneer's pack or (c) an explorer's pack </text>
				<text>• 4d4 x 10 gp, Leather armor, two daggers, and thieves'</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>Choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves' tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe's distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.</text>
				<text>You don't need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn't incapacitated, and you don't have disadvantage on the attack roll.</text>
				<text>The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as shown below.
				</text>
				<text>3rd level - 2d6</text>
				<text>5th level - 3d6</text>
				<text>7th level - 4d6</text>
				<text>9th level - 5d6</text>
				<text>11th level - 6d6</text>
				<text>13th level - 7d6</text>
				<text>15th level - 8d6</text>
				<text>17th level - 9d6</text>
				<text>19th level - 10d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Thieves' Cant</name>
				<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves' cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves' cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.</text>
				<text>In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves' guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
				</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Cunning action</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level,  quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Rogueish Archetype (Thief)</name>
				<text>You hone your skills in the larcenous arts. Burglars, bandits, cutpurses, and other criminals typically follow this archetype, but so do rogues who prefer to think of themselves as professional treasure seekers, explorers, delvers, and investigators. In addition to improving your agility and stealth, you learn skills useful for delving into ancient ruins, reading unfamiliar languages, and using magic items you normally couldn't employ.</text>
				<text>Your archetype grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Fast Hands</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, use your thieves' tools to disarm a trap or open a lock, or take the Use an Object action.
				</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Second-Story Work</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you gain the ability to climb faster than normal; climbing no longer costs you extra movement.</text>
				<text>In addition, when you make a running jump, the distance you cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Dexterity modifier.</text>
			</feature>				
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
				<text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>Choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves' tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Evasion</name>
				<text>Starting at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon's fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Supreme Sneak</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on a Dexterity (Stealth) check if you move no more than half your speed on the same turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Reliable Talent</name>
				<text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
			</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Use Magic Device</name>
				<text>By 13th level, you have learned enough about the workings of magic that you can improvise the use of items even when they are not intended for you. You ignore all class, race, and level requirements on the use of magic items.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Blindsense</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Slippery Mind</name>
				<text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
			</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Thief's Reflexes</name>
				<text>When you reach 17th level, you have become adept at laying ambushes and quickly escaping danger. You can take two turns during the first round of any combat. You take your first turn at your normal initiative and your second turn at your initiative minus 10. You can't use this feature when you are surprised.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Elusive</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has advantage against you while you aren't incapacitated.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
			</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Stroke of Luck</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.</text>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>

	<class>
		<name>Rogue (Assassin)</name>
		<hd>8</hd>
		<proficiency>Dexterity, Intelligence</proficiency>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: Light Armor
Weapons: Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords
Tools: Thieves' tools
					
Saving Throws: Dexterity, Intelligence
Skills: Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>• You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword </text>
				<text>• (a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword </text>
				<text>• (a) a burglar's pack or (b) a dungeoneer's pack or (c) an explorer's pack </text>
				<text>• 4d4 x 10 gp, Leather armor, two daggers, and thieves'</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>Choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves' tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe's distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.</text>
				<text>You don't need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn't incapacitated, and you don't have disadvantage on the attack roll.</text>
				<text>The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as shown below.
				</text>
				<text>3rd level - 2d6</text>
				<text>5th level - 3d6</text>
				<text>7th level - 4d6</text>
				<text>9th level - 5d6</text>
				<text>11th level - 6d6</text>
				<text>13th level - 7d6</text>
				<text>15th level - 8d6</text>
				<text>17th level - 9d6</text>
				<text>19th level - 10d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Thieves' Cant</name>
				<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves' cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves' cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.</text>
				<text>In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves' guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Cunning action</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level,  quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Rogueish Archetype (Assassin)</name>
				<text>You focus your training on the grim art of the death. Those who adhere to this archetype are diverse: hired killers, spies, bounty hunters, and even specially anointed priests trained to exterminate the enemies of their deity. Stealth, poison, and disguise help you eliminate your foes with deadly efficiency.</text>
				<text>Your archetype grants you features at 3rd level and then again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Bonus Proficiencies</name>
				<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with the disguise kit and the poisoner's kit.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Assassinate</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you are at your deadliest when you get the drop on your enemies. You have advantage on attack rolls against any creature that hasn't taken a turn in the combat yet. In addition, any hit you score against a creature that is surprised is a critical hit.</text>
				</feature>				
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
				<text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>Choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves' tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Evasion</name>
				<text>Starting at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon's fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Supreme Sneak</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, you can unfailingly create false identities for yourself. You must spend seven days and 25 gp to establish the history, profession, and affiliations for an identity. You can't establish an identity that belongs to someone else. For example, you might acquire appropriate clothing, letters of introduction, and official-looking certification to establish yourself as a member of a trading house from a remote city so you can insinuate yourself into the company of other wealthy merchants.</text>
				<text>Thereafter, if you adopt the new identity as a disguise, other creatures believe you to be that person until given an obvious reason not to.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Reliable Talent</name>
				<text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Imposter</name>
				<text>At 13th level, you gain the ability to unerringly mimic another person's speech, writing, and behavior. You must spend at least three hours studying these three components of the person's behavior, listening to speech, examining handwriting, and observing mannerism.</text>
				<text>Your ruse is indiscernible to the casual observer. If a wary creature suspects something is amiss, you have advantage on any Charisma (Deception) check you make to avoid detection.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Blindsense</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Slippery Mind</name>
				<text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Death Strike</name>
				<text>Starting at 17th level, you become a master of instant death. When you attack and hit a creature that is surprised, it must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your Dexterity modifier + your proficiency bonus). On a failed save, double the damage of your attack against the creature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Elusive</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has advantage against you while you aren't incapacitated.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Stroke of Luck</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.</text>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>	

	<class>
		<name>Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</name>
		<hd>8</hd>
		<proficiency>Dexterity, Intelligence</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: Light Armor
Weapons: Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, shortswords
Tools: Thieves' tools
					
Saving Throws: Dexterity, Intelligence
Skills: Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, and Stealth</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a rapier or (b) a shortsword </text>
				<text>• (a) a shortbow and quiver of 20 arrows or (b) a shortsword </text>
				<text>• (a) a burglar's pack or (b) a dungeoneer's pack or (c) an explorer's pack </text>
				<text>• 4d4 x 10 gp, Leather armor, two daggers, and thieves'</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>Choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves' tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe's distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.</text>
				<text>You don't need advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn't incapacitated, and you don't have disadvantage on the attack roll.</text>
				<text>The amount of the extra damage increases as you gain levels in this class, as shown below.
				</text>
				<text>3rd level - 2d6</text>
				<text>5th level - 3d6</text>
				<text>7th level - 4d6</text>
				<text>9th level - 5d6</text>
				<text>11th level - 6d6</text>
				<text>13th level - 7d6</text>
				<text>15th level - 8d6</text>
				<text>17th level - 9d6</text>
				<text>19th level - 10d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Thieves' Cant</name>
				<text>During your rogue training you learned thieves' cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in seemingly normal conversation. Only another creature that knows thieves' cant understands such messages. It takes four times longer to convey such a message than it does to speak the same idea plainly.</text>
				<text>In addition, you understand a set of secret signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages, such as whether an area is dangerous or the territory of a thieves' guild, whether loot is nearby, or whether the people in an area are easy marks or will provide a safe house for thieves on the run.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Cunning action</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level,  quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can be used only to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Rogueish Archetype (Arcane Trickster)</name>
				<text>Some rogues enhance their fine-honed skills of stealth and agility with magic, learning tricks of enchantment and illusion. These rogues include pickpockets and burglars, but also pranksters, mischief-makers, and a significant number of adventurers.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, you gain the ability to cast spells.</text>
				<text>Cantrips. You learn three cantrips: mage hand and two other cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn another wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</text>
				<text>Spell Slots. The Arcane Trickster Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher. You know three 1st level wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the enchantment and illusion spells on the wizard spell list.</text>
				<text>You learn a new spell from the enchantment or illusion schools of magic on the wizard spell list at 4th, 7th, 10th, 11th, 13th, 16th, and 19th level. The spell must be for a level which you have spell slots for.</text>
				<text>You learn a new spell from any school of magic on the wizard spell list at 8th, 14th, and 20th level. The spell must be for a level which you have spell slots for.</text>
				<text>In addition, whenever you gain a level in this class, you may replace one of the wizard spells you know with with a different one. The new spell must be for a level for which you have spell slots, and it must be an enchantment or illusion spell, unless you gained it at 8th, 14th, or 20th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Mage Hand Legerdemain</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, when you cast mage hand, you can make the spectral hand invisible, and you can perform the following additional tasks with it:
				</text>
				<text>• You can stow one object the hand is holding in a container worn or carried by another creature.</text>
				<text>• You can retrieve an object in a container worn or carried by another creature.</text>
				<text>• You can use thieves' tools to pick lock and disarm traps at range.</text>
				<text> You can perform one of these tasks without being noticed by a creature if you succeed on a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check contested by the creature's Wisdom (Perception) check.</text>
				<text>In addition, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to control the hand.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st level spell from the wizard spell list. It must be from the enchantment or illusion schools of magic.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
				<text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Expertise</name>
				<text>Choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your proficiency with thieves' tools. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Evasion</name>
				<text>Starting at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon's fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st or 2nd level spell from the wizard spell list. It must be from the enchantment or illusion schools of magic.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st or 2nd level spells from the wizard spell list. They can be from any school of magic.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Magical Ambush</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, if you are hidden from a creature when you cast a spell on it, the creature has disadvantage on any saving throw it makes against the spell this turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st or 2nd level spells from the wizard spell list. It must be from the enchantment or illusion schools of magic.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Reliable Talent</name>
				<text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st or 2nd level spell from the wizard spell list. It must be from the enchantment or illusion schools of magic.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Versatile Trickster</name>
				<text>At 13th level, you gain the ability to distract targets with your mage hand. As a bonus action on your turn, you can designate a creature within 5 feet of the spectral hand created by the spell. Doing so gives you advantage on attack rolls against that creature until the end of the turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level spell from the wizard spell list. It must be from the enchantment or illusion schools of magic.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Blindsense</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level spell from the wizard spell list. It can be from any school of magic.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Slippery Mind</name>
				<text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>	
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level spell from the wizard spell list. It must be from the enchantment or illusion schools of magic.</text>
			</feature>
			</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Thief</name>
				<text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to magically steal the knowledge of how to cast a spell from another spellcaster.</text>
				<text>Immediately after a creature casts a spell that targets you or includes you in its area of effect, you can use your reaction to force the creature to make a saving throw with its spellcasting ability modifier. The DC equals your spell save DC. On a failed save, you negate the spell's effect against you, and you steal the knowledge of the spell if it is at least 1st level and of a level you can cast (it doesn't need to be a wizard spell). For the next 8 hours, you know the spell and can cast it using your spell slots. The creature can't cast that spell until the 8 hours have passed.
				</text>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Elusive</name>
				<text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has advantage against you while you aren't incapacitated.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Sneak Attack Improvement</name>
				<text>Your sneak attack damage increases by 1d6</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spells Known</name>
				<text>You learn one additional 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level spell from the wizard spell list. It can be from any school of magic.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Stroke of Luck</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.</text>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="YES">
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (Artificer)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. 
				</text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier 
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Infuse Potions</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can produce magic potions. You spend 10 minutes focusing your magic on a vial of mundane water and expend a spell slot to transform it into a potion. Once you have expended a spell slot to create a potion, you cannot regain that slot until the potion is consumed or after 1 week, at which time the potion loses its effectiveness. You can create up to three potions at a time; creating a fourth potion causes the oldest currently active one to immediately lose its potency. If that potion has been consumed, its effects immediately end. </text>
				<text>The spell slot you expend determines the type of potion you can create.</text>
				<text>1st - Climbing, growth, or healing</text>
				<text>2nd - Mind reading or greater healing</text>
				<text>3rd - Invisibility, superior healing, or water breathing</text>
				<text>4th - Resistance</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Infuse Scrolls</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you can also tap into your reserves of magical energy to create spell scrolls. You can use your Arcane Recovery ability to create a scroll instead of regaining expended spell slots.</text>
				<text>You must finish a short rest, then spend 10 minutes with parchment, quill, and ink to create a spell scroll containing one spell chosen from those you know. Subtract the spell's level from the total levels worth of slots you regain using Arcane Recovery. This reduction to your Arcane Recovery applies until you use the scroll and then finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Infuse Weapons and Armor</name>
				<text>Beginning at 6th level, you can produce magic weapons and armor. You spend 10 minutes focusing your magic on a mundane weapon, suit of armor, shield, or bundle of twenty pieces of ammunition, and expend a spell slot to infuse it with magical energy. The magic item retains its enhancement for 8 hours or until used (in the case of magic ammunition). You can infuse only one item at a time; if you infuse a second one, the first immediately loses its potency. Once you have expended a spell slot to create such an item, you cannot regain that slot until the item becomes nonmagical.</text>
				<text>The spell slot you expend determines the type of weapon, armor, or shield you can create.</text>
				<text>2nd - +1 ammunition (20 pieces)</text>
				<text>3rd - +1 weapon or +1 shield</text>
				<text>4th - +1 armor</text>
				<text>5th - +2 weapon or +2 ammunition (20 pieces)</text>
				<text>6th - +2 armor</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Superior Artificer</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can create a second magic weapon, suit of armor, shield, or bundle of ammunition using your Infuse Weapons and Armor ability. Attempting to infuse a third item causes the oldest one to immediately lose its potency.</text>
				<text>You can also create one additional potion or scroll using Infuse Potions or Infuse Scrolls.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Master Artificer</name>
				<text>On reaching 14th level, your mastery of arcane magic allows you to produce a variety of magic items. You can create a single item chosen from the lists below. It takes you 1 week to produce such an item, and you must rest for 1 month before using this ability to craft another item.</text>
				<text>d1OO Magic Item (List A)
	01-50 Potion of healing
	51-60 Spell scroll (cantrip)
	61-70 Potion of climbing
	71-90 Spell scroll (1st level)
	91-94 Spell scroll (2nd level)
	95-98 Potion of greater healing
	99 Bag of holding
	00 Driftglobe
</text>
				<text>d1OO Magic Item (List B)
	01-15 Potion of greater healing
	16-22 Potion of fire breath
	23-29 Potion of resistance
	30-34 Ammunition , +1
	35-39 Potion of animal friendship
	40-44 Potion of hill giant strength
	45-49 Potion of growth
	50-54 Potion of water breathing
	55-59 Spell scroll (2nd level)
	60-64 Spell scroll (3rd level)
	65-67 Bag of holding
	68-70 Keoghtom's ointment
	71-73 Oil of slipperiness
	74-75 Dust of disappearance
	76-77 Dust of dryness
	78-79 Dust of sneezing and choking
	80-81 Elemental gem
	82-83 Philter of love
	84 Alchemy jug
	85 Cap of water breathing
	86 Cloak of the manta ray
	87 Driftglobe
	88 Goggles of night
	89 Helm of comprehending languages
	90 Immovable rod
	91 Lantern of revealing
	92 Mariner's armor
	93 Mithral armor
	94 Potion of poison
	95 Ring of swimming
	96 Robe of useful items
	97 Rope of climbing
	98 Saddle of the cavalier
	99 Wand of magic detection
	00 Wand of secrets
</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 1, 1</slots>
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (School of Abjuration)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. 
				</text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier 
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>School of Abjuration</name>
				<text>The School of Abjuration emphasizes magic that blocks, banishes, or protects. Detractors of this school say that its tradition is about denial, negation rather than positive assertion. You understand, however, that ending harmful effects, protecting the weak, and banishing evil influences is anything but a philosophical void. It is a proud and respected vocation. </text>
				<text>Called abjurers, members of this school are sought when baleful spirits require exorcism, when important locations must be guarded against magical spying, and when portals to other planes of existence must be closed.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Abjuration Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an abjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Ward</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can weave magic around yourself for protection. When you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, you can simultaneously use a strand of the spell's magic to create a magical ward on yourself that lasts until you finish a long rest. The ward has hit points equal to twice your wizard level+your Intelligence modifier. Whenever you take damage, the ward takes the damage instead. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, you take any remaining damage.</text>
				<text>While the ward has 0 hit points, it can't absorb damage, but its magic remains. Whenever you cast an abjuration spell of 1st level or higher, the ward regains a number of hit points equal to twice the level of the spell.</text>
				<text>Once you create the ward, you can't create it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Projected Ward</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you takes damage, you can use your reaction to cause your Arcane Ward to absorb that damage. If this damage reduces the ward to 0 hit points, the warded creature takes any remaining damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Improved Abjuration</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, when you cast an abjuration spell that requires you to make an ability check as a part of casting that spell (as in counterspell and dispel magic), you add your proficiency bonus to that ability check.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Resistance</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you have advantage on saving throws against spells.</text>
				<text>Furthermore, you have resistance against the damage of spells.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 1, 1</slots>
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (School of Conjuration)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. 
				</text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier 
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>School of Conjuration</name>
				<text>As a conjurer, you favor spells that produce objects and creatures out of thin air. You can conjure billowing clouds of killing fog or summon creatures from elsewhere to fight on your behalf. As your mastery grows, you learn spells of transportation and can teleport yourself across vast distances, even to other planes of existence, in an instant.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Conjuration Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a conjuration spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Minor Conjuration</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can use your action to conjure up an inanimate object in your hand or on the ground in an unoccupied space that you can see within 10 feet of you. This object can be no larger than 3 feet on a side and weigh no more than 10 pounds, and its form must be that of a nonmagical object that you have seen. The object is visibly magical, radiating dim light out to 5 feet.</text>
				<text>The object disappears after 1 hour, when you use this feature again, or if it takes any damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Benign Transposition</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your action to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space that you can see. Alternatively, you can choose a space within range that is occupied by a Small or Medium creature. If that creature is willing, you both teleport, swapping places.</text>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest or you cast a conjuration spell of 1st level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Focused Conjuration</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, while you are concentrating on a conjuration spell, your concentration can't be broken as a result of taking damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Durable Summons</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, any creature that you summon or create with a conjuration spell has 30 temporary hit points.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (School of Divination)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. 
				</text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>School of Divination</name>
				<text>The counsel of a diviner is sought by royalty and commoners alike, for all seek a clearer understanding of the past, present, and future. As a diviner, you strive to part the veils of space, time, and consciousness so that you can see clearly. You work to master spells of discernment, remote viewing, supernatural knowledge, and foresight.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Divination Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a divination spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Portent</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level when you choose this school, glimpses of the future begin to press in on your awareness. When you finish a long rest, roll two d20s and record the numbers rolled. You can replace any attack roll, saving throw, or ability check made by you or a creature that you can see with one of these foretelling rolls. You must choose to do so before the roll, and you can replace a roll in this way only once per turn.</text>
				<text>Each foretelling roll can be used only once. When you finish a long rest, you lose any unused foretelling rolls.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Expert Divination</name>
				<text>Beginning at 6th level, casting divination spells comes so easily to you that it expends only a fraction of your spellcasting efforts. When you cast a divination spell of 2nd level or higher using a spell slot, you regain one expended spell slot. The slot you regain must be of a level lower than the spell you cast and can't be higher than 5th level.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>The Third Eye</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can use your action to increase your powers of perception. When you do so, choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you are incapacitated or you take a short or long rest. You can't use the feature again until you finish a rest.</text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Darkvision.</text>
				<text>You gain darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ethereal Sight.</text>
				<text>You can see into the Ethereal Plane within 60 feet of you. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Greater Comprehension.</text>
				<text>You can read any language. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>See Invisibility.</text>
				<text>You can see invisible creatures and objects within 10 feet of you that are within line of sight.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Greater Portent</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, the visions in your dreams intensify and paint a more accurate picture in your mind of what is to come. You roll three d20s for your Portent feature, rather than two.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5, 4, 3, 3, 3, 3, 2, 2, 1, 1</slots>
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (School of Enchantment)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. 
				</text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>School of Enchantment</name>
				<text>As a member of the School of Enchantment, you have honed your ability to magically entrance and beguile other people and monsters. Some enchanters are peacemakers who bewitch the violent to lay down their arms and charm the cruel into showing mercy. Others are tyrants who magically bind the unwilling into their service. Most enchanters fall somewhere in between.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Enchantment Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an enchantment spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Hypnotic Gaze</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level when you choose this school, your soft words and enchanting gaze can magically enthrall another creature. A s an action, choose one creature that you can see within 5 feet of you. If the target can see or hear you, it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or be charmed by you until the end of your next turn. The charmed creature's speed drops to 0, and the creature is incapacitated and visibly dazed.</text>
				<text>On subsequent turns, you can use your action to maintain this effect, extending its duration until the end of your next turn. However, the effect ends if you move more than 5 feet away from the creature, if the creature can neither see nor hear you, or if the creature takes damage.</text>
				<text>Once the effect ends, or if the creature succeeds on its initial saving throw against this effect, you can't use this feature on that creature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Instinctive Charm</name>
				<text>Beginning at 6th level, when a creature you can see within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to divert the attack, provided that another creature is within the attack's range. The attacker must make a Wisdom saving throw against your wizard spell save DC. On a failed save, the attacker must target the creature that is closest to it, not including you or itself. If multiple creatures are closest, the attacker chooses which one to target. On a successful save, you can't use this feature on the attacker again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You must choose to use this feature before knowing whether the attack hits or misses. Creatures that can't be charmed are immune to this effect.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Split Enchantment</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, when you cast an enchantment spell of 1st level or higher that targets only one creature, you can have it target a second creature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Alter Memories</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you gain the ability to make a creature unaware of your magical influence on it. When you cast an enchantment spell to charm one or more creatures, you can alter one creature's understanding so that it remains unaware of being charmed.</text>
				<text>Additionally, once before the spell expires, you can use your action to try to make the chosen creature forget some of the time it spent charmed. The creature must succeed on an Intelligence saving throw against your wizard spell save DC or lose a number of hours of its memories equal to 1+your Charisma modifier (minimum 1). You can make the creature forget less time, and the amount of time can't exceed the duration of your enchantment spell.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (School of Evocation)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. 
				</text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>School of Evocation</name>
				<text>You focus your study on magic that creates powerful elemental effects such as bitter cold, searing flame, rolling thunder, crackling lightning, and burning acid. Some evokers find employment in military forces, serving as artillery to blast enemy armies from afar. Others use their spectacular power to protect the weak, while some seek their own gain as bandits, adventurers, or aspiring tyrants.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Evocation Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an evocation spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Sculpt Spells</name>
				<text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can create pockets of relative safety within the effects of your evocation spells. When you cast an evocation spell that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose a number of them equal to 1+the spell's level. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws against the spell, and they take no damage if they would normally take half damage on a successful save.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Potent Cantrip</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, your damaging cantrips affect even creatures that avoid the brunt of the effect. When a creature succeeds on a saving throw against your cantrip, the creature takes half the cantrip's damage (if any) but suffers no additional effect from the cantrip.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Empowered Evocation</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can add your Intelligence modifier to the damage roll of any wizard evocation spell you cast</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Overchannel</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can increase the power of your simpler spells. When you cast a wizard spell of 5th level or lower that deals damage, you can deal maximum damage with that spell.</text>
				<text>The first time you do so, you suffer no adverse effect. If you use this feature again before you finish a long rest, you take 2d12 necrotic damage for each level of the spell, immediately after you cast it. Each time you use this feature again before finishing a long rest, the necrotic damage per spell level increases by 1d 12. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (School of Illusion)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. </text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier 
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>School of Illusion</name>
				<text>You focus your studies on magic that dazzles the senses, befuddles the mind, and tricks even the wisest folk. Your magic is subtle, but the illusions crafted by your keen mind make the impossible seem real. Some illusionists - including many gnome wizards - are benign tricksters who use their spells to entertain. Others are more sinister masters of deception, using their illusions to frighten and fool others for their personal gain.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Illusion Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an illusion spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Improved Minor Illusion</name>
				<text>When you choose this school at 2nd level, you learn the minor illusion cantrip. If you already know this cantrip, you learn a different wizard cantrip of your choice. The cantrip doesn't count against your number of cantrips known.</text>
				<text>When you cast minor illusion, you can create both a sound and an image with a single casting of the spell.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Malleable Illusions</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you cast an illusion spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can use your action to change the nature of that illusion (using the spell's normal parameters for the illusion), provided that you can see the illusion.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Illusory Step</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can create an illusory duplicate of yourself as an instant, almost instinctual reaction to danger. When a creature makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to interpose the illusory duplicate between the attacker and yourself. The attack automatically misses you, then the illusion dissipates.</text>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Illusory Reality</name>
				<text>By 14th level, you have learned the secret of weaving shadow magic into your illusions to give them a semireality. When you cast an illusion spell of 1st level or higher, you can choose one inanimate, nonmagical object that is part of the illusion and make that object real. You can do this on your turn as a bonus action while the spell is ongoing. The object remains real for 1 minute. For example, you can create an illusion of a bridge over a chasm and then make it real long enough for your allies to cross.</text>
				<text>The object can't deal damage or otherwise directly harm anyone.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (School of Transmutation)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. </text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier 
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>School of Transmutation</name>
				<text>You are a student of spells that modify energy and matter. To you, the world is not a fixed thing, but eminently mutable, and you delight in being an agent of change. You wield the raw stuff of creation and learn to alter both physical forms and mental qualities. Your magic gives you the tools to become a smith on reality's forge.</text>
				<text>Some transmuters are tinkerers and pranksters, turning people into toads and transforming copper into silver for fun and occasional profit. Others pursue their magical studies with deadly seriousness, seeking the power of the gods to make and destroy worlds.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Transmutation Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a transmutation spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Minor Alchemy</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level when you select this school, you can temporarily alter the physical properties of one nonmagical object, changing it from one substance into another. You perform a special alchemical procedure on one object composed entirely of wood, stone (but not a gemstone), iron, copper, or silver, transforming it into a different one of those materials. For each 10 minutes you spend performing the procedure, you can transform up to 1 cubic foot of material. After 1 hour, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell), the material reverts to its original substance.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Transmuter's Stone</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can spend 8 hours creating a transmuter's stone that stores transmutation magic. You can benefit from the stone yourself or give it to another creature. A creature gains a benefit of your choice as long as the stone is in the creature's possession. When you create the stone, choose the benefit from the following options:</text>
				<text>• Darkvision out to a range of 60 feet, as described in chapter 8</text>
				<text>• An increase to speed of 10 feet while the creature is unencumbered</text>
				<text>• Proficiency in Constitution saving throws</text>
				<text>• Resistance to acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage (your choice whenever you choose this benefit)</text>
				<text>Each time you cast a transmutation spell of 1st level or higher, you can change the effect of your stone if the stone is on your person.</text>
				<text>If you create a new transmuter's stone, the previous one ceases to function.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Shapechanger</name>
				<text>At 10th level, you add the polymorph spell to your spellbook, if it is not there already. You can cast polymorph without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can target only yourself and transform into a beast whose challenge rating is 1 or lower.</text>
				<text>Once you cast polymorph in this way, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest, though you can still cast it normally using an available spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Master Transmuter</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use your action to consume the reserve of transmutation magic stored within your transmuter's stone in a single burst. When you do so, choose one of the following effects. Your transmuter's stone is destroyed and can't be remade until you finish a long rest. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Major Transformation.</text>
				<text>You can transmute one nonmagical object - no larger than a 5-foot cube - into another nonmagical object of similar size and mass and of equal or lesser value. You must spend 10 minutes handling the object to transform it. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Panacea.</text>
				<text>You remove all curses, diseases, and poisons affecting a creature that you touch with the transmuter's stone. The creature also regains all its hit points. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Restore Life.</text>
				<text>You cast the raise dead spell on a creature you touch with the transmuter's stone, without expending a spell slot or needing to have the spell in your spellbook. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Restore Youth. </text>
				<text>You touch the transmuter's stone to a willing creature, and that creature's apparent age is reduced by 3 d 10 years, to a minimum of 13 years. This effect doesn't extend the creature's lifespan.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
	<class>
		<name>Wizard (School of Necromancy)</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Intelligence, Wisdom</proficiency>
		<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Armor: None
Weapons: Daggers, darts, slings, quarterstaffs, light crossbows
Tools: None

Saving Throws: Intelligence, Wisdom
Skills: Choose two from Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Medicine, Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</text>
				<text>• (a) a quarterstaff or (b) a dagger</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholars pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• A spellbook</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>As a student of arcane magic, you have a spellbook containing spells that show the first glimmerings of your true power.
						</text>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn additional wizard cantrips of your choice at higher levels.
						</text>
				<text>Spellbook</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you have a spellbook containing six 1st-level wizard spells of your choice. 
						</text>
				<text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
				<text>To cast one of your spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>You prepare the list of wizard spells that are available for you to cast. To do so. choose a number of wizard spells from your spellbook equal to your Intelligence modifier+your wizard level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of wizard spells requires time spent studying your spellbook and memorizing the incantations and gestures you must make to cast the spell: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list. 
						</text>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your spells. </text>
				<text>Spell save DC 
	  • 8+proficiency bonus+Int modifier
				  </text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier 
	  • proficiency bonus+your int modifier </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Ritual Casting</text>
				<text>You can cast a wizard spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell in your spellbook. You don't need to have the spell prepared. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus as a spellcasting focus for your wizard spells. </text>
				<text> </text>
				<text>Learning Spells of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>Each time you gain a wizard level, you can add two wizard spells of your choice to your spellbook. Each of these spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots, as shown on the Wizard table. On your adventures, you might find other spells that you can add to your spellbook.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Recovery</name>
				<text>You have learned to regain some of your magical energy by studying your spellbook. Once per day when you finish a short rest, you can choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your wizard level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Arcane Tradition</name>
				<text>When you reach 2nd level, you choose an arcane tradition, shaping your practice of magic through one of eight schools:
		• Abjuration
		• Conjuration
		• Divination
		• Enchantment
		• Evocation
		• Illusion
		• Necromancy
		• Transmutation.
		</text>
				<text>Your choice grants you features at 2nd level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>School of Necromancy</name>
				<text>The School of Necromancy explores the cosmic forces of life, death, and undeath. As you focus your studies in this tradition, you learn to manipulate the energy that animates all living things. As you progress, you learn to sap the life force from a creature as your magic destroys its body, transforming that vital energy into magical power you can manipulate.</text>
				<text>Most people see necromancers as menacing, or even villainous, due to the close association with death. Not all necromancers are evil, but the forces they manipulate are considered taboo by many societies.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Necromancy Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy a necromancy spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Grim Harvest</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to reap life energy from creatures you kill with your spells. Once per turn when you kill one or more creatures with a spell of 1st level or higher, you regain hit points equal to twice the spell's level, or three times its level if the spell belongs to the School of Necromancy. You don't gain this benefit for killing constructs or undead.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature>
				<name>Undead Thralls</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you add the animate dead spell to your spellbook if it is not there already. When you cast animate dead, you can target one additional corpse or pile of bones, creating another zombie or skeleton, as appropriate.</text>
				<text>Whenever you create an undead using a necromancy spell, it has additional benefits:</text>
				<text>• The creature's hit point maximum is increased by an amount equal to your wizard level.</text>
				<text>• The creature adds your proficiency bonus to its weapon damage rolls.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Inured to Undeath</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you have resistance to necrotic damage, and your hit point maximum can't be reduced. You have spent so much time dealing with undead and the forces that animate them that you have become inured to some of their worst effects.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Command Undead</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can use magic to bring undead under your control, even those created by other wizards. As an action, you can choose one undead that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Charisma saving throw against your wizard spell save DC. If it succeeds, you can't use this feature on it again. If it fails, it becomes friendly to you and obeys your commands until you use this feature again.</text>
				<text>Intelligent undead are harder to control in this way. If the target has an Intelligence of 8 or higher, it has advantage on the saving throw. If it fails the saving throw and has an Intelligence of 12 or higher, it can repeat the saving throw at the end of every hour until it succeeds and breaks free.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Spell Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have achieved such mastery over certain spells that you can cast them at will. Choose a 1st-level wizard spell and a 2nd-level wizard spell that are in your spellbook. You can cast those spells at their lowest level without expending a spell slot when you have them prepared. If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
				<text>By spending 8 hours in study, you can exchange one or both of the spells you chose for different spells of the same levels.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<feature>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1, or you can take a feat (if your DM allows it). As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Signature Spell</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you gain mastery over two powerful spells and can cast them with little effort. Choose two 3rd-level wizard spells in your spellbook as your signature spells. You always have these spells prepared, they don't count against the number of spells you have prepared, and you can cast each of them once at 3rd level without expending a spell slot. When you do so, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>If you want to cast either spell at a higher level, you must expend a spell slot as normal.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class>
</compendium>	