<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<notes version="5" auto_indent="YES">
	<note>
		<title>Metamagic Options</title>
		<text>Careful Spell</text>
		<text>When you cast a spell that forces other creatures to make a saving throw, you can protect some of those creatures from the spell's full force. To do so, you spend 1 sorcery point and choose a number of those creatures up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one creature). A chosen creature automatically succeeds on its saving throw against the spell. </text>
		<text> </text>
		<text>Distant Spell</text>
		<text>When you cast a spell that has a range of 5 feet or greater, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double the range of the spell.</text>
		<text>When you cast a spell that has a range of touch, you can spend 1 sorcery point to make the range of the spell 30 feet. </text>
		<text> </text>
		<text>Empowered Spell</text>
		<text>When you roll damage for a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to reroll a number of the damage dice up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). You must use the new rolls.</text>
		<text>You can use Empowered Spell even if you have already used a different Metamagic option during the casting of the spell. </text>
		<text> </text>
		<text>Extended Spell</text>
		<text>When you cast a spell that has a duration of 1 minute or longer, you can spend 1 sorcery point to double its duration, to a maximum duration of 24 hours. </text>
		<text> </text>
		<text>Heightened Spell</text>
		<text>When you cast a spell that forces a creature to make a saving throw to resist its effects, you can spend 3 sorcery points to give one target of the spell disadvantage on its first saving throw made against the spell. </text>
		<text> </text>
		<text>Quickened Spell</text>
		<text>When you cast a spell that has a casting time of 1 action, you can spend 2 sorcery points to change the casting time to 1 bonus action for this casting. </text>
		<text> </text>
		<text>Subtle Spell</text>
		<text>When you cast a spell, you can spend 1 sorcery point to cast it without any somatic or verbal components. </text>
		<text> </text>
		<text>Twinned Spell</text>
		<text>When you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn't have a range of self, you can spend a number of sorcery points equal to the spell's level to target a second creature in range with the same spell (1 sorcery point if the spell is a cantrip).</text>
	</note>
</notes>			