<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
	<character>
		<version>32</version>
		<uid>3702</uid>
		<name>Cleric Dwarf Soldier</name>
		<race>
			<source>1</source>
			<name>Hill Dwarf</name>
			<speed>25</speed>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Dwarvish. Dwarvish is full of hard consonants and guttural sounds, and those characteristics spill over into whatever other language a dwarf might speak.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Darkvision</name>
				<text>Accustomed to life underground, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Dwarven Resilience</name>
				<text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Dwarven Combat Training</name>
				<text>You have proficiency with the battleaxe, handaxe, light hammer, and warhammer.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Tool Proficiency</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency with the artisan's tools of your choice: smith's tools, brewer's supplies, or mason's tools.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Stonecunning</name>
				<text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (History) check related to the origin of stonework, you are considered proficient in the History skill and add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Dwarven Toughness</name>
				<text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
			</feat>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>2</type>
				<value>2</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>4</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
		</race>
		<class>
			<source>1</source>
			<id>3691</id>
			<name>Cleric</name>
			<hd>2</hd>
			<wealth>5d4x10</wealth>
			<proficiency>109</proficiency>
			<proficiency>4</proficiency>
			<proficiency>5</proficiency>
			<proficiency>114</proficiency>
			<numClassSkills>2</numClassSkills>
			<armor>Light armor, medium armor, shields</armor>
			<weapons>All simple weapons</weapons>
			<tools>None</tools>
			<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			<slotsCurrent>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Life Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
				<text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Life Domain: Disciple of Life</name>
				<text>Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2+the spell's level.</text>
			</feat>
			<autolevel>
				<slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Life Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
					<text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Life Domain: Disciple of Life</name>
					<text>Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2+the spell's level.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>2</level>
				<slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Channel Divinity</name>
					<text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as noted in the domain description.
    When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.
    Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell save DC.
    Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests, and beginning at 18th level. you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead</name>
					<text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.
    A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Life Domain Channel Divinity: Preserve Life</name>
					<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to heal the badly injured.
    As an action, you present your holy symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore a number of hit points equal to five times your cleric level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. You can't use this feature on an undead or a construct.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>3</level>
				<slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>4</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>5</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Destroy Undead</name>
					<text>Starting at 5th level, when an undead fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed if its challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold, as shown in the Destroy Undead table.

Cleric Level Destroys Undead of CR
5th 1/2 or lower
8th 1 or lower
11th 2 or lower
14th 3 or lower
17th 4 or lower</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>6</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Life Domain: Blessed Healer</name>
					<text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others heal you as well. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hit points to a creature other than you, you regain hit points equal to 2+the spell's level.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>7</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>8</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Life Domain: Divine Strike</name>
					<text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>9</level>
				<slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>10</level>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Divine Intervention</name>
					<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can call on your deity to intervene on your behalf when your need is great.
    Imploring your deity's aid requires you to use your action. Describe the assistance you seek, and roll percentile dice. If you roll a number equal to or lower than your cleric level, your deity intervenes. The DM chooses the nature of the intervention; the effect of any cleric spell or cleric domain spell would be appropriate. If your deity intervenes, you can't use this feature again for 7 days. Otherwise, you can use it again after you finish a long rest.
    At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>11</level>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>12</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>13</level>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>14</level>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>15</level>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>16</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>17</level>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Life Domain: Supreme Healing</name>
					<text>Starting at 17th level, when you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hit points to a creature, you restore 12.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>18</level>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>19</level>
				<scoreImprovement>1</scoreImprovement>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>20</level>
				<slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<spellAbility>4</spellAbility>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Cure Wounds</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A creature you touch regains a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Detect Poison and Disease</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a yew leaf</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you can sense the presence and location of poisons, poisonous creatures, and diseases within 30 feet of you. You also identify the kind of poison, poisonous creature, or disease in each case.
    The spell can penetrate most barriers, but it is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Guiding Bolt</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>120 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>1 round</duration>
				<text>A flash of light streaks toward a creature of your choice within range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 4d6 radiant damage, and the next attack roll made against this target before the end of your next turn has advantage, thanks to the mystical dim light glittering on the target until then.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Protection from Evil and Good</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>holy water or powdered silver and iron, which the spell consumes</materials>
				<duration>Concentration up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>Until the spell ends, one willing creature you touch is protected against certain types of creatures: aberrations, celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead.
    The protection grants several benefits. Creatures of those types have disadvantage on attack rolls against the target. The target also can't be charmed, frightened, or possessed by them. If the target is already charmed, frightened, or possessed by such a creature, the target has advantage on any new saving throw against the relevant effect.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Sacred Flame</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Flame like radiance descends on a creature that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take 1d8 radiant damage. The target gains no benefit from cover for this saving throw.
    The spell's damage increases by 1d8 when you reach 5th level (2d8), 11th level (3d8), and 17th level (4d8).</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Inflict Wounds</name>
				<school>7</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>Make a melee spell attack against a creature you can reach. On a hit, the target takes 3d10 necrotic damage.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the damage increases by 1d10 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Create or Destroy Water</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a drop of water if creating water or a few grains of sand if destroying it</materials>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>You either create or destroy water.
    Create Water. You create up to 10 gallons of clean water within range in an open container. Alternatively, the water falls as rain in a 30 foot cube within range, extinguishing exposed flames in the area.
    Destroy Water. You destroy up to 10 gallons of water in an open container within range. Alternatively, you destroy fog in a 30 foot cube within range.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you create or destroy 10 additional gallons of water, or the size of the cube increases by 5 feet, for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Detect Magic</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.
    The spell can penetrate most barriers, but it is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Purify Food and Drink</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>10 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>All nonmagical food and drink within a 5 foot radius sphere centered on a point of your choice within range is purified and rendered free of poison and disease.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Healing Word</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A creature of your choice that you can see within range regains hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d4 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Light</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a firefly or phosphorescent moss</materials>
				<duration>1 hour</duration>
				<text>You touch one object that is no larger than 10 feet in any dimension. Until the spell ends, the object sheds bright light in a 20 foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. The light can be colored as you like. Completely covering the object with something opaque blocks the light. The spell ends if you cast it again or dismiss it as an action.
    If you target an object held or worn by a hostile creature, that creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw to avoid the spell.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Thaumaturgy</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You manifest a minor wonder, a sign of supernatural power, within range. You create one of the following magical effects within

• Your voice booms up to three times as loud as normal for 1 minute.
• You cause flames to flicker, brighten, dim, or change color for 1 minute.
• You cause harmless tremors in the ground for 1 minute.
• You create an instantaneous sound that originates from a point of your choice within range, such as a rumble of thunder, the cry of a raven, or ominous whispers.
• You instantaneously cause an unlocked door or window to fly open or slam shut.
• You alter the appearance of your eyes for 1 minute.

    If you cast this spell multiple times, you can have up to three of its 1 minute effects active at a time, and you can dismiss such an effect as an action.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Detect Evil and Good</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you know if there is an aberration, celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead within 30 feet of you, as well as where the creature is located. Similarly, you know if there is a place or object within 30 feet of you that has been magically consecrated or desecrated.
    The spell can penetrate most barriers, but it is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Sanctuary</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a small silver mirror</materials>
				<duration>1 minute</duration>
				<text>You ward a creature within range against attack. Until the spell ends, any creature who targets the warded creature with an attack or a harmful spell must first make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or lose the attack or spell. This spell doesn't protect the warded creature from area effects, such as the explosion of a fireball.
    If the warded creature makes an attack or casts a spell that affects an enemy creature, this spell ends.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Bless</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a sprinkling of holy water</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You bless up to three creatures of your choice within range. Whenever a target makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or saving throw.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Shield of Faith</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a small parchment with a bit of holy text written on it</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>A shimmering field appears and surrounds a creature of your choice within range, granting it a +2 bonus to AC for the duration.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Command</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>1 round</duration>
				<text>You speak a one word command to a creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or follow the command on its next turn. The spell has no effect if the target is undead, if it doesn't understand your language, or if your command is directly harmful to it.
    Some typical commands and their effects follow. You might issue a command other than one described here. If you do so, the GM determines how the target behaves. If the target can't follow your command, the spell ends.
    Approach. The target moves toward you by the shortest and most direct route, ending its turn if it moves within 5 feet of you.
    Drop. The target drops whatever it is holding and then ends its turn.
    Flee. The target spends its turn moving away from you by the fastest available means.
    Grovel. The target falls prone and then ends its turn.
    Halt. The target doesn't move and takes no actions. A flying creature stays aloft, provided that it is able to do so. If it must move to stay aloft, it flies the minimum distance needed to remain in the air.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can affect one additional creature for each slot level above 1st. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<source>1</source>
				<name>Bane</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a drop of blood</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Up to three creatures of your choice that you can see within range must make Charisma saving throws. Whenever a target that fails this saving throw makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the spell ends, the target must roll a d4 and subtract the number rolled from the attack roll or saving throw.
    At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
			</spell>
		</class>
		<background>
			<name>Soldier</name>
			<align>Neutral Good</align>
			<personality>I'm always polite and respectful. Also, I don't trust my gut feelings, so I tend to wait for others to act.</personality>
			<ideals>Respect. People deserve to be treated with dignity and courtesy.</ideals>
			<bonds>I have three cousins-Gundren, Tharden, and Nundro Rockseeker-who are my friends and cherished clan members</bonds>
			<flaws>I secretly wonder whether the gods care about mortal affairs at all</flaws>
			<feat>
				<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
				<text>Athletics, Intimidation</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
				<text>One type of gaming set, vehicles (land)</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Equipment</name>
				<text>An insignia of rank, a trophy taken from a fallen enemy (a dagger, broken blade, or piece of a banner), a set of bone dice or deck of cards, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Feature: Military Rank</name>
				<text>You have a military rank from your career as a soldier. Soldiers loyal to your former military organization still recognize your authority and influence, and they defer to you if they are of a lower rank. You can invoke your rank to exert influence over other soldiers and requisition simple equipment or horses for temporary use. You can also usually gain access to friendly military encampments and fortresses where your rank is recognized.</text>
			</feat>
			<proficiency>117</proficiency>
			<proficiency>105</proficiency>
		</background>
		<unarmed>1</unarmed>
		<abilities>14,8,13,10,15,12,</abilities>
		<hpMax>11</hpMax>
		<hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent>
		<item>
			<source>1</source>
			<name>Chain mail</name>
			<type>3</type>
			<slot>5</slot>
			<value>75.0</value>
			<weight>55.0</weight>
			<ac>16</ac>
			<strength>13</strength>
			<stealth>1</stealth>
		</item>
		<item>
			<source>1</source>
			<name>Shield</name>
			<type>4</type>
			<slot>4</slot>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>6.0</weight>
			<ac>2</ac>
		</item>
		<item>
			<source>1</source>
			<name>Warhammer</name>
			<type>5</type>
			<slot>2</slot>
			<value>15.0</value>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d8</damage1H>
			<damage2H>1d10</damage2H>
			<damageType>1</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>1536</weaponProperty>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<source>1</source>
			<name>Handaxe</name>
			<type>5</type>
			<quantity>2</quantity>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d6</damage1H>
			<damageType>3</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>136</weaponProperty>
			<weaponRange>20</weaponRange>
			<weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Holy Symbol (Amulet)</name>
			<text>A holy symbol is a representation of a god or pantheon

A cleric or paladin can use a holy symbol as a spellcasting focus, using it in place of any material components which do not list a cost. To use the symbol in this way, the caster must hold it in hand, wear it visibly, or bear it on a shield.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 151</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Backpack</name>
			<text>A backpack can hold one cubic foot or 30 pounds of gear. You can also strap items, such as a bedroll or a coil of rope, to the outside of a backpack.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Crowbar</name>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Hammer</name>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Piton</name>
			<quantity>10</quantity>
			<weight>0.25</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Torch</name>
			<quantity>10</quantity>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Tinderbox</name>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Rations (1 day)</name>
			<quantity>10</quantity>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Waterskin</name>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Rope, hempen (50 feet)</name>
			<weight>10.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<source>1</source>
			<name>Mason's tools</name>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>8.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Dagger taken from a fallen enemy as a trophy</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Playing Card Set</name>
			<text>If you are proficient with a gaming set, you can add your proficiency bonus to ability checks you make to play a game with that set. Each type of gaming set requires a separate proficiency.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 154</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Common Clothes</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Pouch</name>
			<text>A cloth or leather pouch can hold up to 20 sling bullets or 50 blowgun needles, among other things. A compartmentalized pouch for holding spell components is called a component pouch. A pouch can hold up to 1/5 cubic foot or 6 pounds of gear.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>rank insignia (sergeant)</name>
		</item>
		<container>
			<name>Money</name>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Copper (cp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.01</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Silver (sp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.1</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Electrum (ep)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.5</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Gold (gp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>10</quantity>
				<value>1.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Platinum (pp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>10.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
		</container>
		<note>
			<name>Dwarf</name>
			<text>Kingdoms rich in ancient grandeur, halls carved into the roots of mountains, the echoing of picks and hammers in mines and blazing forges, a commitment to clan and tradition, and hatred of goblins and orcs—these common threads are the heritage of every dwarf.
	Bold and hardy, dwarves are known as skilled warriors, miners, and workers of stone and metal. They can live to be more than 400 years old, so the oldest living dwarves often remember a very different world.
	Dwarves are solid and enduring like the mountains they love, weathering the centuries with stoic endurance. Individual dwarves are determined and loyal, true to their word and committed in action, sometimes to the point of stubbornness.
	In the Forgotten Realms, your people are called gold dwarves. They have remote kingdoms in the south and typically keep their distance from human affairs. Their brethren are the shield dwarves of the north, who are strong, hardy, and accustomed to a difficult life in rugged terrain. Years ago, you moved to that northern realm.

Male Dwarf Names: Adrik, Baern, Brottor, Dain, Darrak, Eberk, Einkil, Fargrim, Gardain, Harbek, Kildrak, Morgran, Orsik, Rurik, Taklinn, Thoradin, Tordek, Traubon, Travok, Veit, Vondal

Female Dwarf Names: Amber, Artin, Bardryn, Dagnal, Diesa, Eldeth, Finellen, Gunnloda, Gurdis, Helja, Hlin, Kathra, Kristryd, Ilde, Liftrasa, Mardred, Riswynn, Sannl, Torbera, Torgga, Vistra

Dwarf Clan Names: Battlehammer, Brawnanvil, Dankil, Frostbeard, Gorunn, Ironfist, Loderr, Strakeln, Torunn, Ungart</text>
			<expanded>0</expanded>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Cleric</name>
			<text>Clerics are intermediaries between the mortal world and the distant planes of the gods. As varied as the gods they serve, clerics strive to embody the handiwork of their deities. No ordinary priest or temple servant, a cleric is imbued with divine magic.
	Divine Domain. You draw magic from a divine domain—a sphere of magical influence—associated with your deity. Your domain lets you have certain spells, such as bless and cure wounds, always prepared.
	Your domain is Life, which is affiliated with many gods of good. Your god, Marthammor Duin, is the dwarf god of wanderers, travelers, and outcasts—those who move among strange lands and foreign peoples. Dwarves who honor him wear his holy symbol, a boot overlaid by an upright mace, on a necklace often made of silver and iron.</text>
			<expanded>0</expanded>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Soldier</name>
			<text>Trained as a soldier on the island of Mintarn, you traveled to Neverwinter as part of a mercenary company that serves as both army and city watch. You grew disillusioned with your fellow soldiers, who seem to enjoy their authority at the expense of the people they're supposed to protect. Everything came to a head recently, when you disobeyed an order and followed your conscience. You were suspended from active duty, though you kept your rank and your connection to the mercenaries. Since then, you have devoted yourself to your deity.
	Personal Goal: Teach the Redbrands a Lesson. You've heard that Daran Edermath in the town of Phandalin is looking for people of courage and principle to teach some bullies a lesson. These thugs, the Redbrands, have been throwing their weight around in Phandalin, much as your compatriots did in Neverwinter. Putting a stop to their villainy is a worthy goal.
	Alignment: Neutral Good. Your conscience, not law and authority, will guide you to do the right thing. Power is meant to be used for the benefit of all, not to oppress the weak.</text>
			<expanded>0</expanded>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Common, Dwarvish</text>
		</note>
	</character>
</pc>
