<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Bard" UA="Bard">
		<name>Bard (Glamour)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Bard College: College of Glamour (UA)</name>
                <text>The College of Glamour is open to those bards who mastered their craft in the vibrant, deadly realm of the Feywild. Tutored by satyrs, eladrin, and other fey, these bards learn to use their magic to delight and captivate others. </text>
                <text>	The bards of this college are regarded with a mixture of awe and fear. Their performances are the stuff of legend. The bards of this college are so eloquent that a speech or song that one of them performs can cause captors to release the bard unharmed and can lull a furious dragon into complacency. The same magic that allows them to quell beasts can also bend minds. Villainous bards of this college can leech off a community for weeks, abusing their magic to turn their hosts into thralls.</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Bard College is from Unearthed Arcana: Bard Colleges, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>College of Glamour: Mantle of Inspiration</name>
                <text>When you join the College of Glamour at 3rd level, you gain the ability to weave a song of fey magic that enthralls your allies with vigor and speed. </text>
                <text>	As a bonus action, you can expend a use of Bardic Inspiration to grant yourself a wondrous, otherworldly appearance. When you do so, choose a number of allies you can see and who can see you within 60 feet of you, up to a number of them equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Each target gains 2d6 temporary hit points. </text>
                <text>	When a target gains these temporary hit points, it can also use its reaction to move up to its speed toward you, without provoking opportunity attacks. It must take the shortest, safest path to you. </text>
                <text>	The number of temporary hit points increases when you reach certain levels in this class, increasing to 2d8 at 5th level, 2d10 at 10th level, and 2d12 at 15th level.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>College of Glamour: Enthralling Performance</name>
                <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can charge your performance with seductive fey magic. </text>
                <text>	If you perform for at least 10 minutes, you can attempt to inspire wonder in your audience by singing, reciting a poem, or dancing. At the end of the performance, choose a number of humanoids within 60 feet of you who watched and listened to all of it, up to a number of them equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of one). Each target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or be charmed by you. While charmed in this way, the target idolizes you, it speaks glowingly of you to anyone who speaks to it, and it hinders anyone who opposes you, avoiding violence unless it was already inclined to fight on your behalf. This effect ends on a target after 1 hour, if it takes any damage, if you attack it, or if it witnesses you attacking or damaging any of its allies. </text>
                <text>	If a target succeeds on its save against this effect, the target has no hint that you tried to charm it. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>College of Glamour: Mantle of Majesty</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to cloak yourself in a fey magic that makes others want to serve you. As a bonus action, you take on an appearance of unearthly beauty for 1 minute. During this time, you can cast command as a bonus action on each of your turns, without using a spell slot. This effect lasts for 1 minute, and any creature charmed by you automatically fails its saving throw against the spell. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="14">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>College of Glamour: Unbreakable Majesty</name>
                <text>At 14th level, you gain an otherworldly aspect to your appearance that makes you look more fierce and lovely. </text>
                <text>	In addition, through this feature, you can cast sanctuary on yourself. If a creature fails its saving throw against the spell, you also gain advantage on all Charisma checks against the creature for 1 minute, and it has disadvantage on any saving throw it makes against your spells on your next turn. </text>
                <text>	Once you cast sanctuary using this feature, you can't do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

	</subclass>
</compendium>