<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!-- Updated 2018/07/30 (rootwo62) -->
<compendium version='0.5' versionBoBH="1.8" authorBoBH='Nathan Haslè' BoBHDownload='https://www.reddit.com/r/UnearthedArcana/comments/80i3p6/book_of_beautiful_horrors_update_18_170_pages_of/'>
	<monster>
		<name>Botchling</name>
		<size>S</size>
		<type>undead, book of beautiful horrors</type>
		<alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
		<ac>12</ac>
		<hp>40 (9d6 + 9)</hp>
		<speed>15 ft.</speed>
		<str>5</str>
		<dex>15</dex>
		<con>12</con>
		<int>6</int>
		<wis>12</wis>
		<cha>5</cha>
		<skill>Stealth +6</skill>
		<passive>11</passive>
		<senses>darkvision 60ft.</senses>
		<resist>cold, necrotic</resist>
		<conditionImmunities>exhaustion, prone</conditionImmunities>
		<languages>-</languages>
		<cr>2</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Deathly Echoes</name>
			<text>After the botchling uses its Wail, there is a 50 percent chance that it will summon 1d3 specters or one shade. A summoned creature materializes within 30 feet of the botchling in an unoccupied space. The creature acts as an ally of the botchling. The creature vanishes when it drops to 0 hit points.</text>
		</trait>
		<action>
			<name>Feverish Hunger</name>
			<text>As a bonus action, the botchling can target one creature it can see within 5 feet of it that is unconscious. The target must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw against this magic or gain 1 level of exhaustion.</text>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Bite</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage plus 13 (3d8) necrotic damage. The botchling regains a number of hit points equal to the amount of necrotic damage dealt. If the target is a humanoid, it must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or fall unconscious for 1 minute. The target awakens if it takes damage or another creature takes an action to wake it.</text>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Wail (Recharges 4-6)</name>
			<text>The botchling lets out a horrific wail. Any creature within 60 feet of the botchling that can hear the wail must succeed on a DC 16 Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of the botchling's next turn.</text>
		</action>
	</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Lubberkin</name>
		<size>S</size>
		<type>undead, book of beautiful horrors</type>
		<alignment>neutral good</alignment>
		<ac>12</ac>
		<hp>40 (9d6 + 9)</hp>
		<speed>0 ft., fly 40 ft. (hover)</speed>
		<str>1</str>
		<dex>15</dex>
		<con>12</con>
		<int>6</int>
		<wis>16</wis>
		<cha>5</cha>
		<passive>13</passive>
		<senses>darkvision 60ft.</senses>
		<resist>acid, cold, fire, necrotic; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical weapons</resist>
		<conditionImmunities>charmed, exhaustion, grappled, paralyzed, petrified, poisoned, prone, restrained, unconscious</conditionImmunities>
		<languages>-</languages>
		<cr>2</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Ephemeral</name>
			<text>The lubberkin can’t wear or carry anything.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Glow</name>
			<text>The lubberkin sheds bright light in a 5-to 20- foot radius and dim light for an additional number of feet equal to the chosen radius. The lubberkin can alter the radius as a bonus action. While inside the radius of bright light, a friendly creature gains a +3 bonus to its saving throws.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Incorporeal Movement</name>
			<text>The lubberkin can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. It takes 5 (1d10) force damage if it ends its turn inside an object.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Kin Awareness</name>
			<text>The lubberkin knows the distance to and direction of any creature part of its family, even if the creature and the lubberkin are on different planes of existence. If a creature that is part of the family dies, the lubberkin knows.</text>
		</trait>
		<action>
			<name>Glowing Touch</name>
			<text>Melee Spell Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5ft., one creature. Hit: 20 (5d6 + 3) radiant damage and the next attack roll made against this target before the end of the lubberkin's next turn has advantage, thanks to the mystical dim light glittering on the target until then.</text>
			<attack>Glowing Touch|20|5d6+3</attack>
		</action>
	</monster>
</compendium>