<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<!--Ghosts of Saltmarsh-->
<monster>
	<name>Amphisbaena</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<type>monstrosity</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
	<ac>14</ac>
	<hp>11 (2d8 + 2)</hp>
	<speed>30 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>
	<str>14</str>
	<dex>18</dex>
	<con>12</con>
	<int>3</int>
	<wis>10</wis>
	<cha>3</cha>
	<save></save>
	<skill>Perception +2</skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist></resist>
	<immune></immune>
	<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
	<senses>blindsight 10 ft.</senses>
	<passive>12</passive>
	<languages>—</languages>
	<cr>1/2</cr>
	<trait>
		<name>Two Heads</name>
		<text>The amphisbaena has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks and on saving throws against being blinded, charmed, deafened, frightened, stunned, and knocked unconscious.</text>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Multiattack</name>
		<text>The amphisbaena makes two bite attacks.</text>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Bite</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d4 + 4) piercing damage, and the target must make a DC 11 Constitution saving throw, taking 3 (1d6) poison damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
		<attack>Bite|6|1d4+4</attack>
		<attack>Poison||1d6</attack>
	</action>
</monster>
<monster>
	<name>Assassin Vine</name>
	<size>L</size>
	<type>plant</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
	<ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
	<hp>85 (10d10 + 30)</hp>
	<speed>5 ft., climb 5 ft.</speed>
	<str>18</str>
	<dex>10</dex>
	<con>16</con>
	<int>1</int>
	<wis>10</wis>
	<cha>1</cha>
	<save></save>
	<skill></skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist>cold, fire</resist>
	<immune></immune>
	<conditionImmune>blinded, deafened, exhaustion, prone</conditionImmune>
	<senses>blindsight 30 ft.</senses>
	<passive>10</passive>
	<languages>—</languages>
	<cr>3</cr>
	<trait>
		<name>False Appearance</name>
		<text>While the assassin vine remains motionless, it is indistinguishable from a normal plant.</text>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Constrict</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 20 ft., one creature. Hit: The target takes 11 (2d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage, and it is grappled (escape DC 14). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and it takes 21 (6d6) poison damage at the start of each of its turns. The vine can constrict only one target at a time.</text>
		<attack>Constrict|6|2d6+4</attack>
		<attack>Poison||6d6</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Entangling Vines</name>
		<text>The assassin vine can animate normal vines and roots on the ground in a 15-foot square within 30 feet of it. These plants turn the ground in that area into difficult terrain. A creature in that area when the effect begins must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be restrained by entangling vines and roots. A creature restrained by the plants can use its action to make a DC 13 Strength (Athletics) check, freeing itself on a successful check. The effect ends after 1 minute or when the assassin vine dies or uses Entangling Vines again.</text>
	</action>
</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Bard</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<type>humanoid (any race)</type>
		<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
		<alignment>any alignment</alignment>
		<ac>15 (chain shirt)</ac>
		<hp>44 (8d8+8)</hp>
		<speed>30 ft.</speed>
		<str>11</str>
		<dex>14</dex>
		<con>12</con>
		<int>10</int>
		<wis>13</wis>
		<cha>14</cha>
		<save>Dex +4, Wis +3</save>
		<skill>Acrobatics +4, Perception +5, Performance +6</skill>
		<resist />
		<vulnerable />
		<immune />
		<conditionImmune />
		<senses />
		<passive>15</passive>
		<languages>any two languages</languages>
		<cr>2</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Spellcasting</name>
			<text>The bard is a 4th-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Charisma (spell save DC 12, +4 to hit with spell attacks). It has the following bard spells prepared:</text>
			<text>Cantrips (at will): friends, mage hand, vicious mockery</text>
			<text>1st level (4 slots): charm person, healing word, heroism, sleep, thunderwave</text>
			<text>2nd level (3 slots): invisibility, shatter</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Song of Rest</name>
			<text>The bard can perform a song while taking a short rest. Any ally who hears the song regains an extra ld6 hit points if it spends any Hit Dice to regain hit points at the end of that rest. The bard can confer this benefit on itself as well.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Taunt (2/day)</name>
			<text>The bard can use a bonus action on its turn to target one creature within 30 feet of it. If the target can hear the bard, the target must succeed on a DC 12 Charisma saving throw or have disadvantage on ability checks, attack rolls, and saving throws until the start of the bard's next turn.</text>
		</trait>
		<action>
			<name>Shortsword</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6+2) piercing damage.</text>
			<attack>Shortsword|4|1d6+2</attack>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Shortbow</name>
			<text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, range 80/320 ft., one: target. Hit: 5 (1d6+2) piercing damage.</text>
			<attack>Shortbow|4|1d6+2</attack>
		</action>
		<spells>friends, mage hand, vicious mockery, charm person, healing word, heroism, sleep, thunderwave, invisibility, shatter</spells>
		<slots>4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
	</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Bodak</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<type>undead</type>
		<description>Source: Volo's Guide to Monsters</description>
		<alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
		<ac>15 (natural armor)</ac>
		<hp>58 (9d8+18)</hp>
		<speed>30 ft.</speed>
		<str>15</str>
		<dex>16</dex>
		<con>15</con>
		<int>7</int>
		<wis>12</wis>
		<cha>12</cha>
		<save />
		<skill>Perception +4, Stealth +6</skill>
		<resist>cold, fire, necrotic; bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
		<vulnerable />
		<immune>lightning, poison</immune>
		<conditionImmune>charmed, frightened, poisoned</conditionImmune>
		<senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
		<passive>14</passive>
		<languages>Abyssal, the languages it knew in life</languages>
		<cr>6</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Aura of Annihilation</name>
			<text>The bodak can activate or deactivate this feature as a bonus action. While active, the aura deals 5 necrotic damage to any creature that ends its turn within 30 feet of the bodak. Undead and fiends ignore this effect.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Death Gaze</name>
			<text>When a creature that can see the bodak's eyes starts its turn within 30 feet of the bodak, the bodak can force it to make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw if the bodak isn't incapacitated and can see the creature. If the saving throw fails by 5 or more, the creature is reduced to 0 hit points, unless it is immune to the frightened condition. Otherwise, a creature takes 16 (3d10) psychic damage on a failed save.</text>
			<text>	Unless surprised, a creature can avert its eyes to avoid the saving throw at the start of its turn. If the creature does so. it has disadvantage on attack rolls against the bodak until the start of its next turn. If the creature looks at the bodak in the meantime, it must immediately make the saving throw.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Sunlight Hypersensitivity</name>
			<text>The bodak takes 5 radiant damage when it starts its turn in sunlight. While in sunlight, it has disadvantage on attack rolls and ability checks.</text>
		</trait>
		<action>
			<name>Fist</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4+2) bludgeoning damage plus 9 (2d8) necrotic damage.</text>
			<attack>Fist|5|1d4+2+2d8</attack>
			<attack />
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Withering Gaze</name>
			<text>One creature that the bodak can see within 60 feet of it must make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw, taking 22 (4d10) necrotic damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
			<attack>Withering Gaze||4d10</attack>
		</action>
		<spells />
	</monster>
<monster>
	<name>BUllywug Croaker</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<type>humanoid (bullywug)</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
	<ac>15 (hide armor, shield)</ac>
	<hp>33 (6d8 + 6)</hp>
	<speed>20 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
	<str>14</str>
	<dex>12</dex>
	<con>12</con>
	<int>7</int>
	<wis>15</wis>
	<cha>10</cha>
	<save>Con +3</save>
	<skill>Perception +4, Stealth +3</skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist></resist>
	<immune></immune>
	<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
	<senses></senses>
	<passive>14</passive>
	<languages>Bullywug</languages>
	<cr>2</cr>
	<trait>
		<name>Amphibious</name>
		<text>The croaker can breathe air and water.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Speak with Frogs and Toads</name>
		<text>The croaker can communicate simple concepts to frogs and toads when it speaks in Bullywug.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Standing Leap</name>
		<text>The croaker's long jump is up to 20 feet and its high jump is up to 10 feet, with or without a running start.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Swamp Camouflage</name>
		<text>The croaker has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide in swampy terrain.</text>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Spear</name>
		<text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage, or 6 (1d8 + 2) piercing damage if used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<attack>Spear (1H)|4|1d6+2</attack>
		<attack>Spear (2H)|4|1d8+2</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Bite</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage.</text>
		<attack>Bite|4|1d6+2</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Glaaar-pat (3/Day)</name>
		<text>The croaker sings a song of marshy doom. Each chosen creature within 30 feet of the croaker that can hear the song must make a DC 12 Wisdom saving throw. taking 9 (2d8) psychic damage on a failed save. or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that fails this saving throw also has disadvantage on Constitution saving throws until the end of its next turn.</text>
		<attack>Psychic Damage||2d8</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Rooooo-glog (1/Day)</name>
		<text>The croaker sings an ode to an elder froghemoth. Each bullywug within 30 feet of the croaker that can hear the song gains 10 temporary hit points.</text>
	</action>
</monster>
<monster>
	<name>Bullywug Royal</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<type>humanoid (bullywug)</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
	<ac>15 (hide armor, shield)</ac>
	<hp>52 (8d8 + 16)</hp>
	<speed>20 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>
	<str>16</str>
	<dex>12</dex>
	<con>14</con>
	<int>10</int>
	<wis>11</wis>
	<cha>14</cha>
	<save>Str +5, Dex +3</save>
	<skill>Athletics +5, Intimidation +4, Stealth +3</skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist></resist>
	<immune></immune>
	<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
	<senses></senses>
	<passive>10</passive>
	<languages>Bullywug</languages>
	<cr>3</cr>
	<trait>
		<name>Amphibious</name>
		<text>The royal can breathe air and water.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Brute</name>
		<text>A melee weapon deals one extra die of its damage when the royal hits with it (included in the attack).</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Frog Rider</name>
		<text>The royal has advantage on melee attacks made while riding a frog mount.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Speak with Frogs and Toads</name>
		<text>The royal can communicate simple concepts to frogs and toads when it speaks in Bullywug.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Standing Leap</name>
		<text>The royal's long jump is up to 20 feet and its high jump is up to 10 feet, with or without a running start.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Swamp Camouflage</name>
		<text>The royal has advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks made to hide in swampy terrain.</text>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Multiattack</name>
		<text>The royal makes two attacks: one with its royal spear and one with its bite.</text>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Royal Spear</name>
		<text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 10ft. or range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6+ 3) piercing damage, or 12 (2d8 + 3) piercing damage if used with two hands to make a melee attack. If the target is a Medium or smaller creature, it must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
		<attack>Royal Spear (1H)|5|2d6+3</attack>
		<attack>Royal Spear (2H)|5|2d8+3</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Bite</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) piercing damage.</text>
		<attack>Bite|5|1d6+3</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Croaked Degree (1/Day)</name>
		<text>The royal makes a loud pronouncement. Each bullywug within 60 feet of the royal that can hear the pronouncement has advantage on its next attack roll.</text>
	</action>
</monster>
<monster>
	<name>Deep Scion</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<type>humanoid (shapechanger)</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>neutral evil</alignment>
	<ac>11</ac>
	<hp>67 (9d8 + 27)</hp>
	<speed>30 ft. (20 ft. and swim 40 ft. in hybrid form)</speed>
	<str>18</str>
	<dex>13</dex>
	<con>16</con>
	<int>10</int>
	<wis>12</wis>
	<cha>14</cha>
	<save>Wis +3, Cha +4</save>
	<skill>Deception +6, Insight +3, Sleight of Hand +3, Stealth +3</skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist></resist>
	<immune></immune>
	<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
	<senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses>
	<passive>11</passive>
	<languages>Aquan, Common, thieves' cant</languages>
	<cr>3</cr>
	<trait>
		<name>Shapechanger</name>
		<text>The deep scion can use its action to polymorph into a humanoid-piscine hybrid form, or back into its true form. Its statistics, other than its speed, are the same in each form. Any equipment it is wearing or carrying isn't transformed. The deep scion reverts to its true form if it dies.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Amphibious (Hybrid Form Only)</name>
		<text>The deep scion can breathe air and water.</text>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Multiattack</name>
		<text>In humanoid form, the deep scion makes two melee attacks. In hybrid form, the deep scion makes three attacks: one with its bite and two with its claws.</text>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Battleaxe (Humanoid Form Only)</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8 + 4) slashing damage, or 9 (1d10 + 4) slashing damage 1f used with two hands.</text>
		<attack>Battleaxe (1H)|6|1d8+4</attack>
		<attack>Battleaxe (2H)|6|1d10+4</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Bite (Hybrid Form Only)</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 6 (1d4 + 4) piercing damage.</text>
		<attack>Bite|6|1d4+4</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Claw (Hybrid Form Only)</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d6 + 4) slashing damage.</text>
		<attack>Claw|6|1d6+4</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Psychic Screech (Hybrid Form Only; Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
		<text>The deep scion emits a terrible scream audible within 300 feet. Creatures within 30 feet of the deep scion must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be stunned until the end of the deep scion's next turn. In water, the psychic screech also telepathically transmits the deep scion's memories of the last 24 hours to its master, regardless of distance, so long as it and its master are 1n the same body of water.</text>
	</action>
</monster>
<monster>
	<name>Drowned Ascetic</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<type>undead</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
	<ac>13</ac>
	<hp>75 (10d8 + 30)</hp>
	<speed>30 ft.</speed>
	<str>12</str>
	<dex>16</dex>
	<con>16</con>
	<int>3</int>
	<wis>9</wis>
	<cha>5</cha>
	<save>Dex +5</save>
	<skill></skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist></resist>
	<immune>poison</immune>
	<conditionImmune>poisoned</conditionImmune>
	<senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
	<passive>9</passive>
	<languages>understands the languages it knew in life but can't speak</languages>
	<cr>3</cr>
	<trait>
		<name>Bottom Treader</name>
		<text>The drowned ascetic cannot swim, and it sinks to the bottom of any body of water. It takes no penalties to its movement or attacks underwater. It is immune to the effects of being underwater at a depth greater than 100 feet.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Bound Together</name>
		<text>The drowned ascetic shares its mind with every other drowned one within 1 mile of it, and can communicate its thoughts and observations to them instantaneously and without limitation.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Undead Fortitude</name>
		<text>If damage reduces the drowned ascetic to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success. the drowned ascetic drops to 1 hit point instead.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Bluerot</name>
		<text>This disease target humanoids. While afflicted with bluerot, a victim grows grotesque blue boils on their face and back. This disease is carried by undead (including the drowned ones in Tammeraut's Fate), and victims most often acquire it through wounds caused by infected creatures.</text>
		<text>	The disease's boils manifest in 1d4 hours, causing the victim's Constitution and Charisma scores to decrease by 1d4 each, to a minimum of 3. This is quickly followed by a fever and tingling in the extremities. An infected creature is vulnerable to radiant damage and gains the ability to breathe underwater.</text>
		<text>	At the end of each long rest, an infected creature makes a DC 12 Constitution saving throw. On a success, the victim regains 1 point of Constitution and 1 point of Charisma lost to the disease. If the infected creature regains all the points lost to the disease, it is cured. Other effects that raise the victim's ability scores do not cure the disease. On a failed saving throw, the victim takes 18 (4d8) necrotic damage as the boils burst and spread. A creature reduced to 0 hit points by this damage cannot regain hit points until the disease is cured, though it can be stabilized as normal.</text>
		<roll>4d8</roll>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Multiattack</name>
		<text>The drowned ascetic makes three unarmed strikes.</text>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Unarmed Strike</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8 + 3) bludgeoning damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or contract bluerot (see the" Bluerot" sidebar).</text>
		<attack>Unarmed Strike|5|1d8+3</attack>
	</action>
</monster>
<monster>
	<name>Drowned Assassin</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<type>undead</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
	<ac>14 (leather armor)</ac>
	<hp>67 (9d8 + 27)</hp>
	<speed>30 ft.</speed>
	<str>15</str>
	<dex>16</dex>
	<con>16</con>
	<int>9</int>
	<wis>9</wis>
	<cha>16</cha>
	<save>Dex +5, Con +5</save>
	<skill>Intimidation +5, Stealth +5</skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist></resist>
	<immune>poison</immune>
	<conditionImmune>poisoned</conditionImmune>
	<senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
	<passive>9</passive>
	<languages>understands the languages it knew in life but can't speak</languages>
	<cr>4</cr>
	<trait>
		<name>Bottom Treader</name>
		<text>The drowned assassin cannot swim, and it sinks to the bottom of any body of water. It takes no penalties to its movement or attacks underwater. It is immune to the effects of being underwater at a depth greater than 100 feet.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Bound Together</name>
		<text>The drowned assassin shares its mind with every other drowned one within 1 mile of it, and can communicate its thoughts and observations to them instantaneously and without limitation.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Undead Fortitude</name>
		<text>If damage reduces the drowned assassin to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, the drowned assassin drops to 1 hit point instead.</text>
	</trait>
		<trait>
		<name>Bluerot</name>
		<text>This disease target humanoids. While afflicted with bluerot, a victim grows grotesque blue boils on their face and back. This disease is carried by undead (including the drowned ones in Tammeraut's Fate), and victims most often acquire it through wounds caused by infected creatures.</text>
		<text>	The disease's boils manifest in 1d4 hours, causing the victim's Constitution and Charisma scores to decrease by 1d4 each, to a minimum of 3. This is quickly followed by a fever and tingling in the extremities. An infected creature is vulnerable to radiant damage and gains the ability to breathe underwater.</text>
		<text>	At the end of each long rest, an infected creature makes a DC 12 Constitution saving throw. On a success, the victim regains 1 point of Constitution and 1 point of Charisma lost to the disease. If the infected creature regains all the points lost to the disease, it is cured. Other effects that raise the victim's ability scores do not cure the disease. On a failed saving throw, the victim takes 18 (4d8) necrotic damage as the boils burst and spread. A creature reduced to 0 hit points by this damage cannot regain hit points until the disease is cured, though it can be stabilized as normal.</text>
		<roll>4d8</roll>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Multiattack</name>
		<text>The drowned assassin makes two hand crossbow attacks or two dagger attacks. It can then take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Hand Crossbow</name>
		<text>Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit , range 30/120 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) piercing damage plus 3 (1d6) poison damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or contract bluerot (see the "Bluerot" sidebar).</text>
		<attack>Hand Crossbow|5|1d6+3+1d6</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Dagger</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d4+3) piercing damage plus 9 (2d8)poison damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or contract bluerot (see the "Bluerot" sidebar).</text>
		<attack>Dagger|5|1d4+3+2d8</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Reveal (1/Day)</name>
		<text>The drowned assassin removes its mask, revealing its rotting face. Each creature of the assassin's choice within 30 feet of it that can see the assassin must succeed on a DC 13 Wisdom saving throw or be frightened until the end of its next turn.</text>
	</action>
</monster>
<monster>
	<name>Drowned Blade</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<type>undead</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
	<ac>10 (leather armor)</ac>
	<hp>45 (6d8 + 18)</hp>
	<speed>30 ft.</speed>
	<str>16</str>
	<dex>8</dex>
	<con>16</con>
	<int>3</int>
	<wis>9</wis>
	<cha>5</cha>
	<save></save>
	<skill></skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist></resist>
	<immune>poison</immune>
	<conditionImmune>poisoned</conditionImmune>
	<senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
	<passive>9</passive>
	<languages>understands the languages 1t knew in life but can't speak</languages>
	<cr>2</cr>
	<trait>
		<name>Bottom Treader</name>
		<text>The drowned blade cannot swim, and it sinks to the bottom of any body of water. It takes no penalties to its movement or attacks underwater. It is immune to the effects of being underwater at a depth greater than 100 feet.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Bound Together</name>
		<text>The drowned blade shares its mind with every other drowned one within 1 mile of it, and can communicate its thoughts and observations to them instantaneously and without limitation.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Undead Fortitude</name>
		<text>If damage reduces the drowned blade to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, the drowned blade drops to 1 hit point instead.</text>
	</trait>
<trait>
		<name>Bluerot</name>
		<text>This disease target humanoids. While afflicted with bluerot, a victim grows grotesque blue boils on their face and back. This disease is carried by undead (including the drowned ones in Tammeraut's Fate), and victims most often acquire it through wounds caused by infected creatures.</text>
		<text>	The disease's boils manifest in 1d4 hours, causing the victim's Constitution and Charisma scores to decrease by 1d4 each, to a minimum of 3. This is quickly followed by a fever and tingling in the extremities. An infected creature is vulnerable to radiant damage and gains the ability to breathe underwater.</text>
		<text>	At the end of each long rest, an infected creature makes a DC 12 Constitution saving throw. On a success, the victim regains 1 point of Constitution and 1 point of Charisma lost to the disease. If the infected creature regains all the points lost to the disease, it is cured. Other effects that raise the victim's ability scores do not cure the disease. On a failed saving throw, the victim takes 18 (4d8) necrotic damage as the boils burst and spread. A creature reduced to 0 hit points by this damage cannot regain hit points until the disease is cured, though it can be stabilized as normal.</text>
		<roll>4d8</roll>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Multiattack</name>
		<text>The drowned blade makes two rusted longsword attacks</text>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Rusted Longsword</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8 + 3) slashing damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or contract bluerot (see the "Bluerot" sidebar).</text>
		<attack>Rusted Longsword|5|1d8+3</attack>
	</action>
</monster>
<monster>
	<name>Drowned Master</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<type>undead</type>
	<description>Source: Ghosts of Saltmarsh</description>
	<alignment>chaotic evil</alignment>
	<ac>14 (natural armor)</ac>
	<hp>157 (21d8 + 63)</hp>
	<speed>30 ft.</speed>
	<str>17</str>
	<dex>12</dex>
	<con>16</con>
	<int>9</int>
	<wis>14</wis>
	<cha>12</cha>
	<save>Con +7, Wis +6</save>
	<skill>Perception +10</skill>
	<vulnerable></vulnerable>
	<resist></resist>
	<immune>poison</immune>
	<conditionImmune>poisoned</conditionImmune>
	<senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses>
	<passive>20</passive>
	<languages>understands the languages it knew in life but can't speak</languages>
	<cr>9</cr>
<trait>
		<name>Bound Together</name>
		<text>The drowned blade shares its mind with every other drowned one within 1 mile of it, and can communicate its thoughts and observations to them instantaneously and without limitation.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Cold Aura</name>
		<text>At the start of each of the drowned master's turns, each creature within 5 feet of it takes 5 (1d10) cold damage. A creature that touches the drowned master or hits it with a melee attack while within 5 feet of it takes 5 (1d10) cold damage.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Undead Fortitude</name>
		<text>If damage reduces the drowned blade to 0 hit points, it must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 + the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, the drowned blade drops to 1 hit point instead.</text>
	</trait>
<trait>
		<name>Bluerot</name>
		<text>This disease target humanoids. While afflicted with bluerot, a victim grows grotesque blue boils on their face and back. This disease is carried by undead (including the drowned ones in Tammeraut's Fate), and victims most often acquire it through wounds caused by infected creatures.</text>
		<text>	The disease's boils manifest in 1d4 hours, causing the victim's Constitution and Charisma scores to decrease by 1d4 each, to a minimum of 3. This is quickly followed by a fever and tingling in the extremities. An infected creature is vulnerable to radiant damage and gains the ability to breathe underwater.</text>
		<text>	At the end of each long rest, an infected creature makes a DC 12 Constitution saving throw. On a success, the victim regains 1 point of Constitution and 1 point of Charisma lost to the disease. If the infected creature regains all the points lost to the disease, it is cured. Other effects that raise the victim's ability scores do not cure the disease. On a failed saving throw, the victim takes 18 (4d8) necrotic damage as the boils burst and spread. A creature reduced to 0 hit points by this damage cannot regain hit points until the disease is cured, though it can be stabilized as normal.</text>
		<roll>4d8</roll>
	</trait>
	<action>
		<name>Multiattack</name>
		<text>The drowned master makes two attacks: one with its greatsword and one with its Life-Draining Tentacle.</text>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Greatsword</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) slashing damage plus 14 (4d6) cold damage, and the target must succeed on a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or contract bluerot (see the" Bluerot" sidebar).</text>
		<attack>Greatsword|7|2d6+3+4d6</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Life-Draining Tentacle</name>
		<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 15 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) necrotic damage. The target must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or have its hit point maximum reduced by an amount equal to the damage taken. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0. This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. On a failed save, the target also contracts bluerot (see the "Bluerot" sidebar).</text>
		<attack>Life-Draining Tentacle|7|2d6+3</attack>
	</action>
	<action>
		<name>Necrotic Ink (Recharge 5-6)</name>
		<text>The drowned master discharges foul ink in front of itself in a 30-foot cone. Each creature caught in the ink must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw, taking 27 (6d8) necrotic damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that fails this saving throw 1s blinded until the end of its next turn and contracts bluerot (see the "Bluerot" sidebar).</text>
		<attack>Necrotic Ink (Recharge 5-6)||6d8</attack>
	</action>
</monster>
</compendium>