<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
<character><name>Rogue (class template)</name>
	<race>
	</race>
	<class><name>Rogue</name><hd>2</hd><hdCurrent>1</hdCurrent><slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
		<feat><name>Armor Proficiencies</name><text>Light armor.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Weapon Proficiencies</name><text>Simple weapons, hand crossbows, longswords, rapiers, &#38; shortswords.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Tool Proficiencies</name><text>Thieves&#39; tools.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Saving Throw Proficiencies</name><text>Dexterity &#38; Intelligence.</text><expanded>0</expanded><mod><category>3</category><type>1</type></mod><mod><category>3</category><type>3</type></mod></feat>
		<feat><name>Skill Proficiencies</name><text>Choose four from Acrobatics, Athletics, Deception, Insight, Intimidation, Investigation, Perception, Performance, Persuasion, Sleight of Hand, &#38; Stealth.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Expertise</name><text>At 1st level, choose two of your skill proficiencies, or one of your skill proficiencies and your thieves&#39; tool proficiency. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies.
	At 6th level, you can choose two more of your proficiencies to gain this benefit.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Sneak Attack</name><text>Beginning at 1st level, you know how to strike subtly and exploit a foe&#39;s distraction. Once per turn, you can deal an extra 1d6 damage to one creature you hit with an attack if you have Advantage on the attack roll. The attack must use a finesse or a ranged weapon.
	You don&#39;t need Advantage on the attack roll if another enemy of the target is within 5 feet of it, that enemy isn&#39;t incapacitated, and you don&#39;t have Disadvantage on the attack roll.
	The amount of extra damage increases as shown on the table below:
Level	Damage Die
1st		1d6	
2nd		1d6
3rd		2d6
4th		2d6
5th		3d6
6th		3d6
7th		4d6
8th		4d6
9th		5d6
10th	5d6
11th	6d6
12th	6d6
13th	7d6
14th	7d6
15th	8d6
16th	8d6
17th	9d6
18th	9d6
19th	10d6
20th	10d6</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Thieves&#39; Cant</name><text>During your rogue training you learned Thieves&#39; Cant, a secret mix of dialect, jargon, and code that allows you to hide messages in normal conversation. Only another creature that knows Thieves&#39; Cant understands such messages. It takes four times as long to convey such a message than it takes to speak the message plainly.
	In addition you understand a secret set of signs and symbols used to convey short, simple messages.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Cunning Action</name><text>Starting at 2nd level, your quick thinking and agility allow you to move and act quickly. You can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat. This action can only be used to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Roguish Archetype</name><text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you emulate in the exercise of your roguish abilities.
	Your choice gives you features again at 9th, 13th, and 17th level.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Ability Score Improvement</name><text>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 10th, 12th, 16th, 19th level, you can increase one of your ability scores by 2, or two of your ability scores by 1. As normal you cannot raise an ability score above 20 with this feature.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Uncanny Dodge</name><text>Starting at 5th level, when an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attacks damage against you.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Evasion</name><text>Beginning at 7th level, you can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon&#39;s fiery breath or an ice storm spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Reliable Talent</name><text>By 11th level, you have refined your chosen skills until they approach perfection. Whenever you make an ability check that lets you add your proficiency bonus, you can treat a d20 roll of 9 or lower as a 10.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Blindsense</name><text>Starting at 14th level, if you are able to hear, you are aware of the location of any hidden or invisible creature within 10 feet of you.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Slippery Mind</name><text>By 15th level, you have acquired greater mental strength. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Elusive</name><text>Beginning at 18th level, you are so evasive that attackers rarely gain the upper hand against you. No attack roll has Advantage against you while you aren&#39;t incapacitated.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Stroke of Luck</name><text>At 20th level, you have an uncanny knack for succeeding when you need to. If your attack misses a target within range, you can turn the miss into a hit. Alternatively, if you fail an ability check, you can treat the d20 roll as a 20.
	Once you use this feature, you can&#39;t use it again until you find a short or long rest.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Thief (Roguish Archetype)</name><text>You hone your skills in the larcenous arts. Burglars, bandits, cutpurses, and other criminals typically follow this archetype, but so do rogues who prefer to think of themselves as professional treasure seekers, explorers, delvers, and investigators.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Fast Hands (Thief)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use the bonus action granted by Cunning Action to make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check, use your Thieves&#39; Tools to disarm a trap or open a lock, or take the Use Object action.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Second-Story Work (Thief)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the ability to climb faster than normal; climbing no longer costs you extra movement.
	In addition, when you make a running jump, the distance you cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Dexterity modifier.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Supreme Sneak (Thief)</name><text>Starting at 9th level you have Advantage on a Dexterity (Stealth) check if you move no more than half your speed on the same turn.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Use Magic Device (Thief)</name><text>By 13th level, you have learned enough about the workings of magic that you can improvise the use of items even when they are not intended for you. You ignore all class, race, and level requirements on the use of magic items.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Thief&#39;s Reflexes (Thief)</name><text>When you reach 17th level, you have become adept at laying ambushes and quickly escaping danger. You can take two turns during the first round of any combat. You take your first turn at your normal initiative and your second turn at a minus 10. You can&#39;t use this feature when you are surprised.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Assassin (Roguish Archetype)</name><text>You focus your training on the grim art of death.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Bonus Proficiencies (Assassin)</name><text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with the Disguise Kit and the Poisoner&#39;s Kit.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Assassinate (Thief)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, you are at you deadliest when you get the drop on your enemies. You have Advantage on attack rolls against any creature that hasn&#39;t taken a turn in the combat yet. In addition, any hit you score against a creature that is surprised is a critical hit.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Infiltration Expertise (Assassin)</name><text>Starting at 9th level, you can unfailingly create false identities for yourself. You must spend seven days and 25 gp to establish the history, profession, and affiliations for an identity. You can&#39;t establish an identity that belongs to someone else. 
	For example, you might acquire appropriate clothing, letters of introduction, and official-looking certification to establish yourself as a member of a trading house from a remote city so you can insinuate yourself into the company of wealthy merchants.
	Thereafter, if you adopt the new identity as a disguise, other creatures believe you to be that person until given an obvious reason not to.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Impostor (Assassin)</name><text>At 13th level, you gain the ability to unerringly mimic another person&#39;s speech, writing, and behavior.
	You must spend at least three hours studying these three basic components of the person&#39;s behavior.
	Your ruse is indiscernible to the casual observer. If a wary creature suspects something is amiss, you have Advantage on any Charisma (Deception) check you make to avoid detection.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Death Strike (Assassin)</name><text>Starting at 17th level, you become a master of instant death. 
	When you attack and hit a creature that is surprised, it must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your Dexterity modifier + your proficiency bonus). On a failed save, double the damage of your attack against the creature.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Arcane Trickster (Roguish Archetype)</name><text>Some rogues enhance their fine-honed skills of stealth and agility with magic, learning tricks of enchantment and illusion.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Spellcasting (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>At 3rd level you gain the ability to cast wizard spells.

• Cantrips – You learn three cantrips: Mage Hand, and two other cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level

•Spells – The Arcane Trickster table shows you how many cantrips, spells known, and how many spell slots you have per level. You know three 1st level wizard spells, that must be chosen from the enchantment and illusion school at 3rd level through 7th level.
	At 8th through 20th level these spells can be learned from any school of magic on the wizard spell list.
	Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the wizard spells you know with another spell you can learn at that level. 
	  You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.

• Arcane Trickster Table
		Spells	Slots per level
Level	Known	1st 2nd 3rd 4th
1st		3		2	–	–	–
2nd		4		3	–	–	–
3rd		4		3	–	–	–
4th		4		3	–	–	–
5th		5		4	2	–	–
6th		6		4	2	–	–
7th		6		4	2	–	–
8th		7		4	3	–	–
9th		8		4	3	–	–
10th	8		4	3	–	–
11th	9		4	3	–	–
12th	10		4	3	–	–
13th	10		4	3	2	–
14th	11		4	3	2	–
15th	11		4	3	2	–
16th	11		4	3	3	–
17th	11		4	3	3	–
18th	11		4	3	3	–
19th	12		4	3	3	1
20th	13		4	3	3	1

•Spellcasting Ability
	Intelligence is your spellcasting ability.
	• Spell Save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier.
	• Spell Attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier.
</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Mage Hand Legerdemain (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>Starting at 3rd level, when you cast mage hand, you can make the spectral hand invisible, and you can perform the following additional tasks with it.
	
	• You can stow one object the hand is holding in a container worn or carried by another creature
	• You can retrieve an object in a container worn or carried by another creature.
	• You can use thieves&#39; tools to pick locks and disarm traps at range.

	You can perform one of these tasks without being noticed by a creature if you succeed on a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check contested by the creature&#39;s Wisdom (Perception) check.
	In addition, you can use the bonus action granted by your Cunning Action to control the hand.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Magical Ambush (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>Starting at 9th level, if you are hidden from a creature when you cast a spell on it, the creature has Disadvantage on any saving throw it makes against the spell this turn.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Versatile Trickster (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>At 13th level, you gain the ability to distract targets with your mage hand. 
	As a bonus action on your turn, you can designate a creature within 5 feet of the spectral hand created by the spell. Doing so gives you advantage on attack rolls against that creature until the end of the turn.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Spell Thief (Arcane Trickster)</name><text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to magically steal the knowledge of how to cast a spell from another spellcaster.
	Immeadiately after a creature casts a spell that targets you or includes you in it&#39;s area of effect, you can use your reaction to force the creature to make a saving throw with it&#39;s spellcasting ability modifier. The DC equals your spell save DC. On a failed save, you negate the spell&#39;s effect on you, and you steal the knowledge of the spell if it is at least 1st level and of a level you can cast (it doesn&#39;t need to be a wizard spell). For the next 8 hours, you  know the spell and can cast it using your spell slots. The creature can&#39;t cast the spell until the 8 hours have passed.
	Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
	</class>
	<background>
	</background>	<xp>0</xp>
	<abilities>10,10,10,10,10,10,</abilities>
	<hpMax>0</hpMax><hpCurrent>0</hpCurrent><hpTemp>0</hpTemp>
<imageData><uniqueID>1023</uniqueID></imageData></character></pc>