<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Cleric">
		<name>Cleric (Balance)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Divine Domain: Balance</name>
				<text>There cannot be good without evil, law without chaos, light without dark. These forces act in the cosmos, striving for dominance, but always checked by their opposite. Their conflict creates stability in the universe—a stability that must be preserved so existence can continue. Gods of balance preserve the delicate equilibrium between cosmic forces to ensure all things work as they should. They tend to be impartial gods, moved to action only when the scales tip toward one side or the other. They then throw their weight behind the weaker force until balance is restored. Most gods of balance focus on one of good versus evil or law versus chaos.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Balance Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>1st - detect evil and good, sanctuary</text>
				<text/>
				<text>3rd - calm emotions, warding bond</text>
				<text/>
				<text>5th - dispel magic, tongues</text>
				<text/>
				<text>7th - banishment, freedom of movement</text>
				<text/>
				<text>9th - dispel evil and good, geas</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Balance Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
				<text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor and Insight.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Balance Domain: Servant oF Balance</name>
				<text>Also starting at 1st level, you can use your action to touch a willing creature other than yourself and spend 1 Hit Die. Roll the die and the creature touched regains hit points equal to the number rolled.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Balance Domain Channel Divinity: Divine Retribution</name>
				<text>Beginning at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to restore balance on the battlefield.</text>
				<text>	When a creature other than you hits you or a creature within your reach, you can use a reaction to make one weapon attack with advantage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Balance Domain: Even the Field</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when a creature within 30 feet of you becomes blinded, charmed, deafened, frightened, invisible, paralyzed, poisoned, restrained, or stunned, you can use your reaction and use your Channel Divinity to force one creature you can see within 30 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, you bestow the same condition on that creature. The condition lasts until the triggering condition is removed.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Balance Domain: Divine Strike</name>
				<text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Balance Domain: Paragon of Balance</name>
				<text>Beginning at 17th level, you cannot be charmed or frightened. In addition, once per round, when you take damage, a creature you choose within 30 feet of you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC or take psychic damage equal to the amount of damage you took.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Cleric (Balance)">
		<index name="Detect Evil and Good"/>
		<index name="Sanctuary"/>
		<index name="Calm Emotions"/>
		<index name="Warding Bond"/>
		<index name="Dispel Magic"/>
		<index name="Tongues "/>
		<index name="Banishment"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Dispel Evil and Good"/>
		<index name="Geas"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
