<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<subclass baseclass="Cleric" source="PS:A">
		<name>Cleric (Rhonas Strength)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Divine Domain: Strength</name>
				<text>It falls to Rhonas to instill this teaching in those who would enter the afterlife—but to his mind, the words themselves don't matter. Strength can't be taught. It must be built through practice and training. Rhonas demonstrates his teachings by his example, rather than by giving his students any kind of academic instruction. He welcomes the people of Naktamun to stand by the Hekma and watch him as he storms into the desert to battle the greatest horrors. He encourages them to observe his indomitable strength, for though they will never equal it, they can aspire to mimicry. He invites them to scrutinize every move and practice what they see</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Strength Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>1st - divine favor, shield of faith</text>
				<text/>
				<text>3rd - enhance ability, protection from poison</text>
				<text/>
				<text>5th - haste, protection from energy</text>
				<text/>
				<text>7th - dominate beast, stoneskin</text>
				<text/>
				<text>9th - destructive wave, insect plague</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Strength Domain: Acolyte of Strength</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you learn one druid cantrip of your choice. You also gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Athletics, Nature, or Survival.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Strength Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
				<text>Also at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Strength Domain Channel Divinity: Feat of Strength</name>
				<text>At 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to enhance your physical might. When you make an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw using Strength, you can use your Channel Divinity to gain a +10 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fails.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Strength Domain Channel Divinity: Rhonas's Blessing</name>
				<text>At 6th level, when a creature within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw using Strength, you can use your reaction to grant that creature a +10 bonus to the roll, using your Channel Divinity. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the roll succeeds or fail.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Strength Domain: Divine Strike</name>
				<text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 damage of the same type dealt by the weapon to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.
			</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Strength Domain: Avatar of Battle</name>
				<text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Cleric (Strength)">
		<index name="Divine Favor"/>
		<index name="Shield of Faith"/>
		<index name="Enhance Ability"/>
		<index name="Protection from Poison"/>
		<index name="Haste"/>
		<index name="Protection from Energy"/>
		<index name="Dominate Beast"/>
		<index name="Stoneskin"/>
		<index name="Destructive Wave"/>
		<index name="Insect Plague"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
