<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Cleric">
		<name>Cleric (Earth)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Divine Domain: Earth</name>
				<text>The gods of the earth have dominion over the solid foundations upon which the world is built. These gods not only command stones and move mountains, but also hold sway over the fertile soil in which plants grow, the precious gems and metals mortal races draw from mines deep beneath the ground, and the deep caverns and subterranean realms that form the pillars upon which the surface world rests. There is a strong bond between the Earth domain and the mortal races; it is in the earth that farmers work to grow the crops needed to feed their families, and in the earth that miners delve to retrieve the stones and metals necessary to build the fundamental structures of civilization. Clerics bestowed with the powers of the Earth domain carry with them the strength and immovability of stone, and use their divinely-granted gifts to protect those around them from harm.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Earth Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>1st - entangle, heroism</text>
				<text/>
				<text>3rd - acid arrow, shatter</text>
				<text/>
				<text>5th - meld into stone, plant growth</text>
				<text/>
				<text>7th - conjure minor elementals, stoneskin</text>
				<text/>
				<text>9th - conjure elemental, wall of stone</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Earth Domain: Strength of the Mountain</name>
				<text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor. Additionally, you have advantage on Strength saving throws.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Earth Domain: Endurance of Stone</name>
				<text>Also starting at 1st level, your hit point maximum increases by 1, and increases by 1 again whenever you gain a level in this class.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Earth Domain Channel Divinity: Shelter of the Land</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to shield your allies against harm.</text>
				<text>	As an action, you present your holy symbol and lay a protective blessing upon your allies that radiates outward from you. For 1 minute, whenever a creature other than you that is within 60 feet of you and that you can see takes bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, you can choose to reduce that damage by an amount equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Earth Domain: Potency of the Soil</name>
				<text>Beginning at 6th level, when you cast a spell that targets only one creature and doesn't have a range of self, if that spell causes the target to regain hit points, you can choose for a different creature in range to also regain the same number of hit points.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Earth Domain: Divine Strike</name>
				<text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Earth Domain: Foundations of the Deep Earth</name>
				<text>Starting at 17th level, you become immune to petrification and, if you are not incapacitated, you cannot be moved against your will.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Cleric (Earth)">
		<index name="Entangle"/>
		<index name="Heroism"/>
		<index name="Acid Arrow"/>
		<index name="Shatter"/>
		<index name="Meld into Stone"/>
		<index name="Plant Growth"/>
		<index name="Conjure Minor Elementals"/>
		<index name="Stoneskin"/>
		<index name="Conjure Elemental"/>
		<index name="Wall of Stone"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
