<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Druid">
		<name>Druid (Land)</name>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Druid Circle: Circle of the Land</name>
				<text>The Circle of the Land is made up of mystics and sages who safeguard ancient knowledge and rites through a vast oral tradition. These druids meet within sacred circles of trees or standing stones to whisper primal secrets in Druidic. The circle's wisest members preside as the chief priests of communities that hold to the Old Faith and serve as advisors to the rulers of those folk. As a member of this circle, your magic is influenced by the land where you were initiated into the circle's mysterious rites.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Circle of Land: Bonus Cantrip</name>
				<text>You learn one additional druid cantrip of your choice.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Circle of Land: Natural Recovery</name>
				<text>Starling at 2nd level, you can regain some of your magical energy by sitting in meditation and communing with nature. During a short rest, you choose expended spell slots to recover. The spell slots can have a combined level that is equal to or less than half your druid level (rounded up), and none of the slots can be 6th level or higher. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest</text>
				<text>	For example, when you are a 4th-level druid, you can recover up to two levels worth of spell slots. You can recover either a 2nd-level slot or two 1st-level slots.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Circle of Land: Circle Spells</name>
				<text>Your mystical connection to the land infuses you with the ability to cast certain spells. At 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th level you gain access to circle spells connected to the land where you became a druid. Choose that land - arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or Underdark - and consult the associated list of spells.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once you gain access to a circle spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day. If you gain access to a spell that doesn't appear on the druid spell list, the spell is nonetheless a druid spell for you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Circle of Land: Land's Stride</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the entangle spell.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Circle of Land: Nature's Ward</name>
				<text>When you reach 10th level, you can't be charmed or frightened by elementals or fey, and you are immune to poison and disease.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Circle of Land: Nature's Sanctuary</name>
				<text>When you reach 14th level, creatures of the natural world sense your connection to nature and become hesitant to attack you. When a beast or plant creature attacks you, that creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your druid spell save DC. On a failed save, the creature must choose a different target, or the attack automatically misses. On a successful save, the creature is immune to this effect for 24 hours.</text>
				<text>	The creature is aware of this effect before it makes its attack against you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Druid (Tree of Life)" HB="HB">
		<index name="Aid"/>
		<index name="Calm Emotions"/>
		<index name="Beacon of Hope"/>
		<index name="Revivify"/>
		<index name="Conjure Woodland Beings"/>
		<index name="Death Ward"/>
		<index name="Dispel Evil and Good"/>
		<index name="Hallow"/>
	</spellList>
	<spellList class="Druid (Arctic)">
		<index name="Commune with Nature"/>
		<index name="Cone of Cold"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Hold Person"/>
		<index name="Ice Storm"/>
		<index name="Sleet Storm"/>
		<index name="Slow"/>
		<index name="Spike Growth"/>
	</spellList>
	<spellList class="Druid (Coast)">
		<index name="Conjure Elemental"/>
		<index name="Control Water"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Mirror Image"/>
		<index name="Misty Step"/>
		<index name="Scrying"/>
		<index name="Water Breathing"/>
		<index name="Water Walk"/>
	</spellList>
	<spellList class="Druid (Desert)">
		<index name="Blight"/>
		<index name="Blur"/>
		<index name="Create Food and Water"/>
		<index name="Hallucinatory Terrain"/>
		<index name="Insect Plague"/>
		<index name="Protection from Energy"/>
		<index name="Silence"/>
		<index name="Wall of Stone"/>
	</spellList>
	<spellList class="Druid (Forest)">
		<index name="Barkskin"/>
		<index name="Call Lightning"/>
		<index name="Commune with Nature"/>
		<index name="Divination"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Plant Growth"/>
		<index name="Spider Climb"/>
		<index name="Tree Stride"/>
	</spellList>
	<spellList class="Druid (Grassland)">
		<index name="Daylight"/>
		<index name="Divination"/>
		<index name="Dream"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Haste"/>
		<index name="Insect Plague"/>
		<index name="Invisibility"/>
		<index name="Pass Without Trace"/>
	</spellList>
	<spellList class="Druid (Mountain)">
		<index name="Lightning Bolt"/>
		<index name="Meld into Stone"/>
		<index name="Passwall"/>
		<index name="Spider Climb"/>
		<index name="Spike Growth"/>
		<index name="Stone Shape"/>
		<index name="Stoneskin"/>
		<index name="Wall of Stone"/>
	</spellList>
	<spellList class="Druid (Swamp)">
		<index name="Darkness"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Insect Plague"/>
		<index name="Locate Creature"/>
		<index name="Melf's Acid Arrow"/>
		<index name="Scrying"/>
		<index name="Stinking Cloud"/>
		<index name="Water Walk"/>
	</spellList>
	<spellList class="Druid (Underdark)">
		<index name="Cloudkill"/>
		<index name="Gaseous Form"/>
		<index name="Greater Invisibility"/>
		<index name="Insect Plague"/>
		<index name="Spider Climb"/>
		<index name="Stinking Cloud"/>
		<index name="Stone Shape"/>
		<index name="Web"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
