<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Paladin" UA="Paladin">
		<name>Paladin (Conquest)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Sacred Oath: Oath of Conquest</name>
				<text>The Oath of Conquest calls to paladins who seek glory in battle and the subjugation of their enemies. It isn't enough for these paladins to establish order. They must crush the forces of chaos. </text>
				<text>	Sometimes called knight tyrants or iron mongers, those who swear this oath gather into grim orders that serve gods or philosophies of war and well-ordered might. Some of these paladins go so far as to consort with the powers of the Nine Hells. </text>
				<text>	The archdevil Bel, warlord of Avernus, counts many of these paladins-called hell knights-as his most ardent supporters. Hell knights cover their armor with trophies taken from fallen enemies, a grim warning to any who dare oppose them and the decrees of their lords. </text>
				<text />
				<text>Tenets of Conquest: </text>
				<text>	A paladin who takes this oath has the tenets of conquest seared on the upper arm. A hell knight's oath appears in Infernal runes, a brutal reminder of vows to the Lords of Hell. </text>
				<text />
				<text>Douse the Flame of Hope: It is not enough to merely defeat an enemy in battle. Your victory must be so overwhelming that your enemies' will to fight is shattered forever. A blade can end a life. Fear can end an empire. </text>
				<text />
				<text>Rule with an Iron Fist: Once you have conquered, tolerate no dissent. Your word is law. Those who obey it shall be favored. Those who defy it shall be punished as an example to all who might follow. </text>
				<text />
				<text>Strength Above All: You shall rule until a stronger one arises. Then you must grow mightier and meet the challenge, or fall to your own ruin. </text>
				<text />
				<text>Oath Spells:</text>
				<text>	You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.</text>
				<text />
				<text>3rd - armor of Agathys, command </text>
				<text>5th - hold person, spiritual weapon </text>
				<text>9th - bestow curse, fear </text>
				<text>13th - blight, dominate beast </text>
				<text>17th - dominate person, insect plague</text>
				<text />
				<text>This Sacred Oath is from Unearthed Arcana: Paladin Sacred Oaths, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of Conquest Channel Divinity: Conquering Strike (Oath of Conquest)</name>
				<text>You can use your Channel Divinity to break a foe's will. When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack as part of the Attack action, you can also use your Channel Divinity to force the target to make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target becomes frightened of you for 1 minute. The frightened creature can repeat this saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of Conquest Channel Divinity: Guided Strike (Oath of Conquest)</name>
				<text>You can use your Channel Divinity to strike with supernatural accuracy. When you make an attack roll, you can use your Channel Divinity to gain a +10 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of Conquest: Aura of Conquest (Oath of Conquest)</name>
				<text>Starting at 7th level, you emanate a menacing aura while you're not incapacitated. The aura includes your space, extends 10 feet from you in every direction, and is blocked by total cover. Any enemy in the aura has disadvantage on saving throws against being frightened. </text>
				<text>	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of Conquest: Implacable Spirit (Oath of Conquest)</name>
				<text>Once you reach 15th level, you can no longer be charmed.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oath of Conquest: Invincible Conquerer (Oath of Conquest)</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you gain the ability to harness extraordinary martial prowess. As an action, you can magically become an avatar of conquest, gaining the following benefits for 1 minute: </text>
				<text />
				<text>• You have resistance to all damage. </text>
				<text />
				<text>• When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can make one additional attack as part of that action. </text>
				<text />
				<text>• Your melee weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. </text>
				<text />
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>