<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
	<character>
		<version>32</version>
		<uid>4081</uid>
		<name>Human Paladin</name>
		<race>
			<name>Human</name>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice. Humans typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects. They are fond of sprinkling their speech with words borrowed from other tongues: Orc curses, Elvish musical expressions, Dwarvish military phrases, and so on.</text>
			</feat>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>1</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>2</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>3</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>4</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
			<mod>
				<category>1</category>
				<type>5</type>
				<value>1</value>
			</mod>
		</race>
		<class>
			<id>3911</id>
			<name>Paladin</name>
			<level>4</level>
			<hd>3</hd>
			<hdCurrent>4</hdCurrent>
			<proficiency>114</proficiency>
			<proficiency>5</proficiency>
			<proficiency>109</proficiency>
			<proficiency>4</proficiency>
			<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			<slotsCurrent>0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields
Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons
Tools: none
Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.

• (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons
• (a) five javelins or (b) any simple melee weapon
• (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack
• Chain mail and a holy symbol

Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Divine Sense</name>
				<text>The presence of strong evil registers on your senses like a noxious odor, and powerful good rings like heavenly music in your ears. As an action, you can open your awareness to detect such forces. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any celestial, fiend, or undead within 60 feet of you that is not behind total cover. You know the type (celestial, fiend, or undead) of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity (the vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich, for instance). Within the same radius, you also detect the presence of any place or object that has been consecrated or desecrated, as with the hallow spell.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Lay on Hands</name>
				<text>Your blessed touch can heal wounds. You have a pool of healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your paladin level x 5.
	As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.
	Alternatively, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multiple poisons with a single use of Lay on Hands, expending hit points separately for each one.
	This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Divine Smite</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal radiant damage to the target, in addition to the weapon's damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is an undead or a fiend.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Fighting Style: Protection</name>
				<text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Spellcasting</name>
				<text>By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the paladin spell list.

Preparing and Casting Spells
The Paladin table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of paladin spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list. When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.

Spellcasting Ability
Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin spells, since their power derives from the strength of your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier

Spellcasting Focus
You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your paladin spells.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Divine Health</name>
				<text>By 3rd level, the divine magic flowing through you makes you immune to disease.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Sacred Oath</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, you swear the oath that binds you as a paladin forever. Up to this time you have been in a preparatory stage, committed to the path but not yet sworn to it. Now you choose the Oath of Devotion, the Oath of the Ancients, the Oath of the Crown, or the Oath of Vengeance, all detailed at the end of the c1ass description.
	Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 15th, and 20th level. Those features include oath spells and the Channel Divinity feature.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Sacred Oath: Oath of Devotion</name>
				<text>The Oath of Devotion binds a paladin to the loftiest ideals of justice, virtue, and order. Sometimes called cavaliers, white knights, or holy warriors, these paladins meet the ideal of the knight in shining armor, acting with honor in pursuit of justice and the greater good. They hold themselves to the highest standards of conduct, and some, for better or worse, hold the rest of the world to the same standards. Many who swear this oath are devoted to gods of law and good and use their gods' tenets as the measure of their devotion. They hold angels - the perfect servants of good - as their ideals, and incorporate images of angelic wings into their helmets or coats of arms.

Tenets of Devotion

Though the exact words and strictures of the Oath of Devotion vary, paladins of this oath share these tenets.
	Honesty. Don't lie or cheat. Let your word be your promise.
	Courage. Never fear to act, though caution is wise.
	Compassion. Aid others, protect the weak, and punish those who threaten them. Show mercy to your foes, but temper it with wisdom.
	Honor. Treat others with fairness, and let your honorable deeds be an example to them. Do as much good as possible while causing the least amount of harm.
	Duty. Be responsible for your actions and their consequences, protect those entrusted to your care, and obey those who have just authority over you.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Oath of Devotion Channel Divinity: Sacred Weapon</name>
				<text>As an action, you can imbue one weapon that you are holding with positive energy, using your Channel Divinity. For 1 minute, you add your Charisma modifier to attack rolls made with that weapon (with a minimum bonus of +1). The weapon also emits bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light 20 feet beyond that. If the weapon is not already magical, it becomes magical for the duration.
	You can end this effect on your turn as part of any other action. If you are no longer holding or carrying this weapon, or if you fall unconscious, this effect ends.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Oath of Devotion Channel Divinity: Turn the Unholy</name>
				<text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring fiends and undead, using your Channel Divinity. Each fiend or undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.
	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<optional>1</optional>
				<name>Oath of Devotion: Oath Spells</name>
				<text>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.

3rd - protection from evil and good, sanctuary

5th - lesser restoration, zone of truth

9th - beacon of hope, dispel magic

13th - freedom of movement, guardian of faith

17th - commune, flame strike</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
				<text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
			</feat>
			<autolevel>
				<slots>0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
					<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields
Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons
Tools: none
Skills: Choose two from Athletics, Insight, Intimidation, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Starting Equipment</name>
					<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.

• (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons
• (a) five javelins or (b) any simple melee weapon
• (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack
• Chain mail and a holy symbol

Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Divine Sense</name>
					<text>The presence of strong evil registers on your senses like a noxious odor, and powerful good rings like heavenly music in your ears. As an action, you can open your awareness to detect such forces. Until the end of your next turn, you know the location of any celestial, fiend, or undead within 60 feet of you that is not behind total cover. You know the type (celestial, fiend, or undead) of any being whose presence you sense, but not its identity (the vampire Count Strahd von Zarovich, for instance). Within the same radius, you also detect the presence of any place or object that has been consecrated or desecrated, as with the hallow spell.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to 1 + your Charisma modifier. When you finish a long rest, you regain all expended uses.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Lay on Hands</name>
					<text>Your blessed touch can heal wounds. You have a pool of healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your paladin level x 5.
	As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in your pool.
	Alternatively, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multiple poisons with a single use of Lay on Hands, expending hit points separately for each one.
	This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>2</level>
				<slots>0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Divine Smite</name>
					<text>Starting at 2nd level, when you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one spell slot to deal radiant damage to the target, in addition to the weapon's damage. The extra damage is 2d8 for a 1st-level spell slot, plus 1d8 for each spell level higher than 1st, to a maximum of 5d8. The damage increases by 1d8 if the target is an undead or a fiend.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooter</name>
					<text>When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
					<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
					<special>1</special>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
					<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
					<special>2</special>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name>
					<text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Fighting Style: Mariner</name>
					<text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Fighting Style: Protection</name>
					<text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Fighting Style: Tunnel Fighter</name>
					<text>As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Spellcasting</name>
					<text>By 2nd level, you have learned to draw on divine magic through meditation and prayer to cast spells as a cleric does. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the paladin spell list.

Preparing and Casting Spells
The Paladin table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells. To cast one of your paladin spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.
	You prepare the list of paladin spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the paladin spell list. When you do so, choose a number of paladin spells equal to your Charisma modifier + half your paladin level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.
	For example, if you are a 5th-level paladin, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Charisma of 14, your list of prepared spells can include four spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or a 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.
	You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of paladin spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.

Spellcasting Ability
Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your paladin spells, since their power derives from the strength of your convictions. You use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a paladin spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.
	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier
	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier

Spellcasting Focus
You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your paladin spells.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>3</level>
				<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Divine Health</name>
					<text>By 3rd level, the divine magic flowing through you makes you immune to disease.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<name>Sacred Oath</name>
					<text>When you reach 3rd level, you swear the oath that binds you as a paladin forever. Up to this time you have been in a preparatory stage, committed to the path but not yet sworn to it. Now you choose the Oath of Devotion, the Oath of the Ancients, the Oath of the Crown, or the Oath of Vengeance, all detailed at the end of the c1ass description.
	Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 15th, and 20th level. Those features include oath spells and the Channel Divinity feature.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Sacred Oath: Oath of Devotion</name>
					<text>The Oath of Devotion binds a paladin to the loftiest ideals of justice, virtue, and order. Sometimes called cavaliers, white knights, or holy warriors, these paladins meet the ideal of the knight in shining armor, acting with honor in pursuit of justice and the greater good. They hold themselves to the highest standards of conduct, and some, for better or worse, hold the rest of the world to the same standards. Many who swear this oath are devoted to gods of law and good and use their gods' tenets as the measure of their devotion. They hold angels - the perfect servants of good - as their ideals, and incorporate images of angelic wings into their helmets or coats of arms.

Tenets of Devotion

Though the exact words and strictures of the Oath of Devotion vary, paladins of this oath share these tenets.
	Honesty. Don't lie or cheat. Let your word be your promise.
	Courage. Never fear to act, though caution is wise.
	Compassion. Aid others, protect the weak, and punish those who threaten them. Show mercy to your foes, but temper it with wisdom.
	Honor. Treat others with fairness, and let your honorable deeds be an example to them. Do as much good as possible while causing the least amount of harm.
	Duty. Be responsible for your actions and their consequences, protect those entrusted to your care, and obey those who have just authority over you.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Oath of Devotion Channel Divinity: Sacred Weapon</name>
					<text>As an action, you can imbue one weapon that you are holding with positive energy, using your Channel Divinity. For 1 minute, you add your Charisma modifier to attack rolls made with that weapon (with a minimum bonus of +1). The weapon also emits bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light 20 feet beyond that. If the weapon is not already magical, it becomes magical for the duration.
	You can end this effect on your turn as part of any other action. If you are no longer holding or carrying this weapon, or if you fall unconscious, this effect ends.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Oath of Devotion Channel Divinity: Turn the Unholy</name>
					<text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring fiends and undead, using your Channel Divinity. Each fiend or undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes damage.
	A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>
				</feat>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Oath of Devotion: Oath Spells</name>
					<text>You gain oath spells at the paladin levels listed.

3rd - protection from evil and good, sanctuary

5th - lesser restoration, zone of truth

9th - beacon of hope, dispel magic

13th - freedom of movement, guardian of faith

17th - commune, flame strike</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>4</level>
				<slots>0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>5</level>
				<slots>0,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Extra Attack</name>
					<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>6</level>
				<slots>0,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Aura of Protection</name>
					<text>Starting at 6th level, whenever you or a friendly creature within 10 feet of you must make a saving throw, the creature gains a bonus to the saving throw equal to your Charisma modifier (with a minimum bonus of +1). You must be conscious to grant this bonus.
	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>7</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Oath of Devotion: Aura of Devotion</name>
					<text>Starting at 7th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be charmed while you are conscious.
	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>8</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>9</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>10</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Aura of Courage</name>
					<text>Starting at 10th level, you and friendly creatures within 10 feet of you can't be frightened while you are conscious.
	At 18th level, the range of this aura increases to 30 feet.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>11</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Improved Divine Smite</name>
					<text>By 11th level, you are so suffused with righteous might that all your melee weapon strikes carry divine power with them. Whenever you hit a creature with a melee weapon, the creature takes an extra 1d8 radiant damage. If you also use your Divine Smite with an attack, you add this damage to the extra damage of your Divine Smite.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>12</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>13</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>14</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Cleansing Touch</name>
					<text>Beginning at 14th level, you can use your action to end one spell on yourself or on one willing creature that you touch.
	You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Charisma modifier (a minimum of once). You regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>15</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Oath of Devotion: Purity of Spirit</name>
					<text>Beginning at 15th level, you are always under the effects of a protection from evil and good spell.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>16</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>17</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>18</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Aura of Protection Improvement</name>
					<text>At 18th level, the range of your Aura of Protection increases to 30 feet.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>19</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
					<text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
	If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<autolevel>
				<level>20</level>
				<slots>0,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,</slots>
				<feat>
					<optional>1</optional>
					<name>Oath of Devotion: Holy Nimbus</name>
					<text>At 20th level, as an action, you can emanate an aura of sunlight. For 1 minute, bright light shines from you in a 30-foot radius, and dim light shines 30 feet beyond that.
	Whenever an enemy creature starts its turn in the bright light, the creature takes 10 radiant damage.
	In addition, for the duration, you have advantage on saving throws against spells cast by fiends or undead.
	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				</feat>
			</autolevel>
			<spellAbility>5</spellAbility>
			<spell>
				<name>Ceremony</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 hour</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>25 gp worth of powdered silver, which the spell consumes</materials>
				<duration>Instantaneous </duration>
				<text>You perform a special religious ceremony that is infused with magic. When you cast the spell, choose one of the following rites, the target of which must be within 10 feet of you throughout the casting.

Atonement. You touch one willing creature whose alignment has changed, and you make a DC 20 Wisdom (Insight) check. On a successful check, you restore the target to its original alignment

Bless Water. You touch one vial of water and cause it to become holy water.

Coming of Age. You touch one humanoid who is a young adult. For the next 24 hours, whenever the target makes an ability check, it can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check. A creature can benefit from this rite only once.

Dedication. You touch one humanoid who wishes to be dedicated to your god's service. For the next 24 hours, whenever the target makes a saving throw, it can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the save. A creature can benefit from this rite only once.

Funeral Rite. You touch one corpse, and for the next 7 days, the target can't become undead by any means short of a wish spell.

Wedding. You touch adult humanoids willing to be bonded together in marriage. For the next 7 days, each target gains a +2 bonus to AC while they are within 30 feet of each other. A creature can benefit from this rite again only if widowed.

This spell can be found in Xanathar's Guide to Everything</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Sanctuary</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a small silver mirror</materials>
				<duration>1 minute</duration>
				<text>You ward a creature within range against attack. Until the spell ends, any creature who targets the warded creature with an attack or a harmful spell must first make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or lose the attack or spell. This spell doesn't protect the warded creature from area effects, such as the explosion of a fireball.

If the warded creature makes an attack or casts a spell that affects an enemy creature, this spell ends.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Bless</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a sprinkling of holy water</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You bless up to three creatures of your choice within range. Whenever a target makes an attack roll or a saving throw before the spell ends, the target can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the attack roll or saving throw.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Purify Food and Drink</name>
				<school>8</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>10 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>All nonmagical food and drink within a 5-foot-radius sphere centered on a point of your choice within range is purified and rendered free of poison and disease.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Wrathful Smite</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>The next time you hit with a melee weapon attack during this spell's duration, your attack deals an extra 1d6 psychic damage. Additionally, if the target is a creature, it must make a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you until the spell ends. As an action, the creature can make a Wisdom check against your spell save DC to steel its resolve and end this spell.</text>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Thunderous Smite</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>The first time you hit with a melee weapon attack during this spell's duration, your weapon rings with thunder that is audible within 300 feet of you, and the attack deals an extra 2d6 thunder damage to the target. Additionally, if the target is a creature, it must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 10 feet away from you and knocked prone.</text>
				<roll>2d6</roll>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Divine Favor</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>Your prayer empowers you with divine radiance. Until the spell ends, your weapon attacks deal an extra 1d4 radiant damage on a hit.</text>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Searing Smite</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>The next time you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack during the spell's duration, your weapon flares with white-hot intensity, and the attack deals an extra 1d6 fire damage to the target and causes the target to ignite in flames. At the start of each of its turns until the spell ends, the target must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, it takes 1d6 fire damage. On a successful save, the spell ends. If the target or a creature within 5 feet of it uses an action to put out the flames, or if some other effect douses the flames (such as the target being submerged in water), the spell ends.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the initial extra damage dealt by the attack increases by 1d6 for each slot above the 1st.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<roll>1d6</roll>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Shield of Faith</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a small parchment with a bit of holy text written on it</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>A shimmering field appears and surrounds a creature of your choice within range, granting it a +2 bonus to AC for the duration.</text>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Compelled Duel</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 bonus action</time>
				<range>30 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>You attempt to compel a creature into a duel. One creature that you can see within range must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature is drawn to you, compelled by your divine demand. For the duration, it has disadvantage on attack rolls against creatures other than you, and must make a Wisdom saving throw each time it attempts to move to a space that is more than 30 feet away from you, if it succeeds on this saving throw, this spell doesn't restrict the target's movement for that turn.

The spell ends if you attack any other creature, if you cast a spell that targets a hostile creature other than the target, if a creature friendly to you damages the target or casts a harmful spell on it, or if you end your turn more than 30 feet away from the target.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Protection from Evil and Good</name>
				<school>1</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>holy water or powdered silver and iron, which the spell consumes</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>Until the spell ends, one willing creature you touch is protected against certain types of creatures - aberrations, celestials, elementals, fey, fiends, and undead.

The protection grants several benefits. Creatures of those types have disadvantage on attack rolls against the target. The target also can't be charmed, frightened, or possessed by them. If the target is already charmed, frightened, or possessed by such a creature, the target has advantage on any new saving throw against the relevant effect.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Warlock</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Heroism</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
				<text>A willing creature you touch is imbued with bravery. Until the spell ends, the creature is immune to being frightened and gains temporary hit points equal to your spellcasting ability modifier at the start of each of its turns. When the spell ends, the target loses any remaining temporary hit points from this spell.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can target one additional creature for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<prepared>1</prepared>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Cure Wounds</name>
				<school>5</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Touch</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
				<text>A creature you touch regains a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + your spellcasting ability modifier. This spell has no effect on undead or constructs.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, the healing increases by 1d8 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
				<roll>1d8+%0</roll>
				<sclass>Artificer</sclass>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Detect Evil and Good</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you know if there is an aberration, celestial, elemental, fey, fiend, or undead within 30 feet of you, as well as where the creature is located. Similarly, you know if there is a place or object within 30 feet of you that has been magically consecrated or desecrated. The spell can penetrate most barriers, but it is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Command</name>
				<school>4</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>60 feet</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<duration>1 round</duration>
				<text>You speak a one-word command to a creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or follow the command on its next turn. The spell has no effect if the target is undead, if it doesn't understand your language, or if your command is directly harmful to it.

Some typical commands and their effects follow. You might issue a command other than one described here. If you do so, the DM determines how the target behaves. If the target can't follow your command, the spell ends.

Approach: The target moves toward you by the shortest and most direct route, ending its turn if it moves within 5 feet of you.

Drop: The target drops whatever it is holding and then ends its turn.

Flee: The target spends its turn moving away from you by the fastest available means.

Grovel: The target falls prone and then ends its turn.

Halt: The target doesn't move and takes no actions. A flying creature stays aloft, provided that it is able to do so. If it must move to stay aloft, it flies the minimum distance needed to remain in the air.

At Higher Levels: When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you can affect one additional creature for each slot level above 1st. The creatures must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Detect Magic</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<ritual>1</ritual>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you sense the presence of magic within 30 feet of you. If you sense magic in this way, you can use your action to see a faint aura around any visible creature or object in the area that bears magic, and you learn its school of magic, if any.

The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
				<sclass>Bard</sclass>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
				<sclass>Sorcerer</sclass>
				<sclass>Wizard</sclass>
			</spell>
			<spell>
				<name>Detect Poison and Disease</name>
				<school>3</school>
				<level>1</level>
				<time>1 action</time>
				<range>Self</range>
				<v>1</v>
				<s>1</s>
				<m>1</m>
				<materials>a yew leaf</materials>
				<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
				<text>For the duration, you can sense the presence and location of poisons, poisonous creatures, and diseases within 30 feet of you. You also identify the kind of poison, poisonous creature, or disease in each case.

The spell can penetrate most barriers, but is blocked by 1 foot of stone, 1 inch of common metal, a thin sheet of lead, or 3 feet of wood or dirt.</text>
				<sclass>Cleric</sclass>
				<sclass>Druid</sclass>
				<sclass>Paladin</sclass>
				<sclass>Ranger</sclass>
			</spell>
			<filter>1</filter>
		</class>
		<background>
			<id>3958</id>
			<name>Noble</name>
			<align>Lawful good</align>
			<personality>You are convinced that the common folk love you for your kindness and generosity</personality>
			<ideals>It is your duty to protect and care for those beneath you</ideals>
			<bonds>Your loyalty to your sovereign is unswerving</bonds>
			<flaws>You have an insatiable desire for carnal pleasures</flaws>
			<feat>
				<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
				<text>History, Persuasion</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
				<text>One type of gaming set</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Languages</name>
				<text>One of your choice</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Equipment</name>
				<text>A set of fine clothes, a signet ring, a scroll of pedigree, and a purse containing 25 gp</text>
			</feat>
			<feat>
				<name>Feature: Position of Privilege</name>
				<text>Thanks to your noble birth, people are inclined to think the best of you. You are welcome in high society, and people assume you have the right to be wherever you are. The common folk make every effort to accommodate you and avoid your displeasure, and other people of high birth treat you as a member of the same social sphere. You can secure an audience with a local noble if you need to.</text>
			</feat>
			<proficiency>113</proficiency>
			<proficiency>105</proficiency>
		</background>
		<xp>2700</xp>
		<unarmed>1</unarmed>
		<abilities>15,8,13,10,13,15,</abilities>
		<hpMax>36</hpMax>
		<hpCurrent>36</hpCurrent>
		<item>
			<name>Longsword</name>
			<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 149</text>
			<type>5</type>
			<slot>2</slot>
			<value>15.0</value>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d8</damage1H>
			<damage2H>1d10</damage2H>
			<damageType>3</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>512</weaponProperty>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Javelin</name>
			<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.

Thrown: If a weapon has the thrown property, you can throw the weapon to make a ranged attack. If the weapon is a melee weapon, you use the same ability modifier for that attack roll and damage roll that you would use for a melee attack with the weapon. For example, if you throw a handaxe, you use your Strength, but if you throw a dagger, you can use either your Strength or your Dexterity, since the dagger has the finesse property.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 149</text>
			<type>5</type>
			<quantity>5</quantity>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>2.0</weight>
			<damage1H>1d6</damage1H>
			<damageType>2</damageType>
			<weaponProperty>128</weaponProperty>
			<weaponRange>30</weaponRange>
			<weaponLongRange>120</weaponLongRange>
			<mod>
				<type>1</type>
			</mod>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Chain Mail</name>
			<text>Made of interlocking metal rings, chain mail includes a layer of quilted fabric worn underneath the mail to prevent chafing and to cushion the impact of blows. The suit includes gauntlets.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 145</text>
			<type>3</type>
			<slot>5</slot>
			<value>75.0</value>
			<weight>55.0</weight>
			<ac>16</ac>
			<strength>13</strength>
			<stealth>1</stealth>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Shield</name>
			<text>A shield is made from wood or metal and is carried in one hand. Wielding a shield increases your Armor Class by 2. You can benefit from only one shield at a time.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 144</text>
			<type>4</type>
			<slot>4</slot>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>6.0</weight>
			<ac>2</ac>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Bell</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<value>1.0</value>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Dragonchess Set</name>
			<text>If you are proficient with a gaming set, you can add your proficiency bonus to ability checks you make to play a game with that set. Each type of gaming set requires a separate proficiency.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 154</text>
			<value>1.0</value>
			<weight>0.5</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Engraved tankard</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Signet Ring</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Sealing Wax</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Scroll of Pedigree</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Holy Symbol (Amulet)</name>
			<text>A holy symbol is a representation of a god or pantheon

A cleric or paladin can use a holy symbol as a spellcasting focus, using it in place of any material components which do not list a cost. To use the symbol in this way, the caster must hold it in hand, wear it visibly, or bear it on a shield.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 151</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Fine Clothes</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<value>15.0</value>
			<weight>6.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Traveler's Clothes</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<value>2.0</value>
			<weight>4.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Perfume</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Soap</name>
			<text>Source: Player's Handbook, page 150</text>
			<quantity>2</quantity>
			<value>2.0</value>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Waterskin with fine wine</name>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Healer's Kit</name>
			<text>This kit is a leather pouch containing bandages, salves, and splints. The kit has ten uses. As an action, you can expend one use of the kit to stabilize a creature that has 0 hit points, without needing to make a Wisdom (Medicine) check.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 151</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>3.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Pouch</name>
			<text>A cloth or leather pouch can hold up to 20 sling bullets or 50 blowgun needles, among other things. A compartmentalized pouch for holding spell components is called a component pouch. A pouch can hold up to 1/5 cubic foot or 6 pounds of gear.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 153</text>
			<value>5.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<item>
			<name>Holy Water (flask)</name>
			<text>As an action, you can splash the contents of this flask onto a creature within 5 feet of you or throw it up to 20 feet, shattering it on impact. In either case, make a ranged attack against a target creature, treating the holy water as an improvised weapon. If the target is a fiend or undead, it takes 2d6 radiant damage.
	A cleric or paladin may create holy water by performing a special ritual. The ritual takes 1 hour to perform, uses 25 gp worth of powdered silver, and requires the caster to expend a 1st-level spell slot.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 151</text>
			<value>25.0</value>
			<weight>1.0</weight>
		</item>
		<container>
			<label>Explorer's Pack</label>
			<name>Backpack</name>
			<value>10.0</value>
			<weight>5.0</weight>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Bedroll</name>
				<weight>7.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Mess kit</name>
				<weight>1.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Tinderbox</name>
				<weight>1.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Torch</name>
				<quantity>10</quantity>
				<weight>1.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Rations (1 day)</name>
				<quantity>10</quantity>
				<weight>2.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Waterskin</name>
				<weight>5.0</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Rope, hempen (50 feet)</name>
				<weight>10.0</weight>
			</item>
		</container>
		<container>
			<name>Money</name>
			<carried>1</carried>
			<item>
				<name>Copper (cp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.01</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Silver (sp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.1</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Electrum (ep)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>0.5</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Gold (gp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>1.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
			<item>
				<name>Platinum (pp)</name>
				<text>Common coins come in several different denominations based on the relative worth of the metal from which they are made. The three most common coins are the gold piece (gp), the silver piece (sp), and the copper piece (cp).

With one gold piece, a character can buy a belt pouch, 50 feet of good rope, or a goat. A skilled (but not exceptional) artisan can earn one gold piece a day. The gold piece is the standard unit of measure for wealth, even if the coin itself is not commonly used. When merchants discuss deals that involve goods or services worth hundreds or thousands of gold pieces, the transactions don't usually involve the exchange of individual coins. Rather, the gold piece is a standard measure of value, and the actual exchange is in gold bars, letters of credit, or valuable goods.

One gold piece is worth ten silver pieces, the most prevalent coin among commoners. A silver piece buys a laborer's work for a day, a flask of lamp oil, or a night's rest in a poor inn.

One silver piece is worth ten copper pieces, which are common among laborers and beggars. A single copper piece buys a candle, a torch, or a piece of chalk.

In addition, unusual coins made of other precious metals sometimes appear in treasure hoards. The electrum piece (ep) and the platinum piece (pp) originate from fallen empires and lost kingdoms, and they sometimes arouse suspicion and skepticism when used in transactions. An electrum piece is worth five silver pieces, and a platinum piece is worth ten gold pieces.

A standard coin weighs about a third of an ounce, so fifty coins weigh a pound.

Source: Player's Handbook, page 143</text>
				<type>15</type>
				<quantity>0</quantity>
				<value>10.0</value>
				<weight>0.02</weight>
			</item>
		</container>
		<note>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Common, Dwarvish, Elvish</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Faction</name>
			<text>You belong to the Lords' Alliance, whose members ensure the safety and prosperity of civilized folk by standing United against the forces that threaten civilization</text>
		</note>
		<note>
			<name>Background</name>
			<text>"No thanks are necessary. I am but a humble servant of the gods. Well, perhaps just one drink."
You follow the path of righteousness, and everyone knows it. Your family built chapels to the gods of light and life throughout their lands, and you spread the good word as you travel.
	You move in the highest circles of the ruling classes and among the simple folk, bringing salvation wherever you go. You vigorously proclaim the virtues of an honorable life, though sometimes your audience doesn't seem to share your enthusiasm. But you're no stick-in-the-mud, and you enjoy the worldly rewards for a job well done.</text>
		</note>
	</character>
</pc>
