<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<pc version="5">
<character><name>Cuag Stormhammer</name>
	<race><id>2</id><name>Mountain Dwarf</name><speed>25</speed>
		<feat><name>Description</name><text>Male dwarf, 4&#39;4&#34;, approx 150lbs, red hair and beard, amber eyes</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Languages</name><text>Common, Draconic, Druidic, Dwarvish, Goblin, Primordial</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Darkvision</name><text>You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Dwarven Resilience</name><text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage (explained in chapter 9).</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Dwarven Combat Training</name><text>You have proficiency with the battleaxe, handaxe, throwing hammer, and warhammer.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Tool Proficiency</name><text>You gain proficiency with the artisan’s tools of your choice: smith’s tools, brewer’s supplies, or mason’s tools.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Stonecunning</name><text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (History) check related to the origin of stonework, you are considered proficient in the History skill and add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</text></feat>
	</race>
	<class><id>7</id><weight>3</weight><name>Druid</name><level>12</level><hd>2</hd><spellAbility>4</spellAbility><hdCurrent>12</hdCurrent><slots>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slots><slotsCurrent>4,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0,</slotsCurrent>
		<feat><name>(2) Wild Shape</name><text>You can use your action to magically assume the shape of a beast you have seen before. Challenge rating up to lvl/3, minimum CR of 1.

You can use this feature twice. You can regain expended uses who you complete a short or long rest.

You can stay in a beast shape for a number of hours equal to half your Druid level (rounded down). You can revert to your normal form using a bonus action.

Retain alignment, personality, INT, WIS, CHA. Retain all skill and saving proficiencies, and gain those of animal. Take spillover damage past 0 into regular HP pool. Transforming doesn&#39;t break concentration.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>(2) Combat Wild Shape</name><text>You gain the ability to use Wild Shape as a bonus action.

While you are transformed by Wild Shape, you can use a bonus action to expend one spell slot to regain 1d8 hit points per level of the spell slot expended.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>(6) Primal Strike</name><text>Your attacks in beast form count as magical for the purpose of oncoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>(10) Elemental Wild Shape</name><text>You can expend two uses of Wild Shape at the same time to transform into an air, earth, fire, or water elemental.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>(14) Thousand Forms</name><text>You can cast the Alter Self spell at will.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>(18) Beast Spells</name><text>You can cast many of your Druid spells in any shape you assume using Wild Shape. You can perform the somatic and verbal components of a Druid spell while in beast shape, but you aren&#39;t able to provide martial components.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>(18) Timeless Body</name><text>The primal magic that you wield causes you to age more slowly. For every 10 years that pass, your body only ages one year.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>(20) Archdruid</name><text>You can use your Wild Shape an unlimited amount of times.

You can ignore the verbal and somatic components of your Druid spells, as well as any material components that lack a cost and aren&#39;t consumed by a spell. You gain this benefit in both your normal shape and your beast shape from Wild Shape.</text><expanded>0</expanded></feat>
		<feat><name>Weapon Proficiencies </name><text>battle axe, darts, javelins, hand axe, mace, quarterstaff, scimitar, sickle, sling, spear, throwing hammer, war hammer</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Preparing And Casting Spells</name><text>Prepare WIS + LVL number of spells</text></feat>
		<mod><name>Intelligence Saving Throw Proficiency</name><category>3</category><type>3</type></mod>
		<mod><name>Wisdom Saving Throw Proficiency</name><category>3</category><type>4</type></mod>
		<mod><name>Nature Proficiency</name><category>4</category><type>10</type></mod>
		<mod><name>Search Proficiency</name><category>4</category><type>8</type></mod>
	</class>
	<background><id>4</id><name>Sage</name>
		<feat><name>Lost Band Of Ancestry</name><text>Able to smell copper and silver, affinity for emeralds.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Researcher</name><text>When you attempt to learn or recall a piece of lore, if you do not know that information, you often know where and from whom you can obtain it. Usually, this information comes from a library, scriptorium, university, or a sage or other learned person or creature. Your DM might rule that the knowledge you seek is secreted away in an almost inaccessible place, or that it simply cannot be found. Unearthing the deepest secrets of the multiverse can require an adventure or even a whole campaign.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Background</name><text>I wear a copper and silver band on my left arm above the elbow. I was left at a monastery deep in the forest as a toddler. I have no information of my family except for the family crest on the band. There are runes on the inside of the band that I&#39;ve been unable to translate. Because the band is my only link to my family I have a strong attachment to it. So strong that I can smell the metals it&#39;s made from, due to a traumatic loss of the band when I was young. Until this event, the Druids at the monastery called me &#34;Dwarf.&#34; This earned me the name &#34;Cog,&#34; spelled Cuag for the runes of the metals in the band. </text></feat>
		<feat><name>Personality Trait</name><text>I&#39;m used to helping out those who aren&#39;t as smart as I am, and I don&#39;t mind explaining things to others. </text></feat>
		<feat><name>Ideal</name><text>The path to power and self-improvement is through knowledge.</text></feat>
		<feat><name>Bond</name><text>I&#39;ve been searching my whole life to find information about my family. </text></feat>
		<feat><name>Flaw</name><text>I have a fear of abandonment.</text></feat>
		<mod><name>Arcana Proficiency</name><category>4</category><type>2</type></mod>
		<mod><name>History Proficiency</name><category>4</category><type>5</type></mod>
	</background>	<xp>112360</xp>
	<abilities>16,18,16,17,20,12,</abilities>
	<hpMax>93</hpMax><hpCurrent>92</hpCurrent><hpTemp>0</hpTemp>
<inspiration>2</inspiration>
	<feat><name>Polearm Master</name><text>You can keep your enemies at bay with reach weapons. You gain the following benefits.

When you take the Attack action and attack with only a glaive, halberd, or quarterstaff, you can use a bonus action to make an attack with the opposite end of the weapon. The weapon&#39;s damage die for this attack is a d4, and the attack deals bludgeoning damage.

While you are wielding a glaive, halberd, pike, or quarterstaff, other creatures provoke an opportunity attack from you who they enter your reach.</text></feat>
	<item><name>Staff Of The Uncrowned King</name><text>Requires attunement</text><type>5</type><slot>2</slot><weight>4</weight><damage1H>1d6</damage1H><damage2H>1d8</damage2H><damageType>1</damageType><weaponProperty>512</weaponProperty><mod><type>1</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><type>2</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><type>7</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><type>8</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><name>Used As Magic Focus</name><type>8</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><type>1</type></mod></item>
	<item><name>Mask Of The Braxat</name><text>Mask, very rare, requires attunment

This mask is made from the brownish-orange facial chitin of a large insect, including the foremost of his cranial protrusions.

When activated, this mask enables the wearer to spit a globe of acid at an opponent up to 40 ft away.

DC is 10 + spell casting ability or DC + DEX if wearer doesn&#39;t cast spells.

The opponent takes 4d6 points of Acid damage on a hit and half on a successful save.

This ability functions three times per day.

</text><slot>1</slot><weight>0</weight><roll>4d6</roll></item>
	<item><name>Cloak Of Elvenkind</name><text>Hide in any natural environment. Looks super bad ass.

This long cloak is fashioned from gray cloth, expertly crafted, and is half the weight of a normal cloak.

An elf who sees a non-elf wearing a cloak of this sort might assume the cloak is stolen. In some cases, however, cloaks of elvenkind are presented as gifts to the elves&#39; most trusted and valued allies.  

Property: While you wear a cloak of elvenkind with the hood up, you can attempt to hide in any natural environment, as long as no creatures are within 20 feet of you. You do not have to be obscured to make the attempt, but you must stay quiet.</text><slot>1</slot><quantity>4</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Cursed Cave Walker Boots</name><text>1/encounter, wearer can ignore effect that will change their position
1/day, traverse the wall or ceiling at half your speed
Have a preference for being upside down when idle

Requires attunement</text><slot>1</slot><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Magic Rune Stone</name><text>1/encounter, lasts 5 min, chaotic effect, weapon +1
01-20 - additional +1 to weapon
21-40 - weap gains energy type of choice, +1D6
41-60 - 50% chance to add 1D12 damage
61-80 - weapon uses next damage die (6&#62;8&#62;10)
81-00 - reroll one miss</text><slot>1</slot><quantity>3</quantity><weight>0</weight><roll>1n100</roll><mod><name>Attack +1</name><type>1</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><type>2</type><value>1</value></mod></item>
	<item><name>Eleven Ring Of Defense</name><text>1/encounter reduce damage by 5</text><slot>1</slot><quantity>4</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Ring Of Corners</name><text>Able to see out of emerald if ring worn in the last hour. Won from stone-crushing contest.

Require attunment  </text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Lost Longsword Of The Northern King</name><text>Gives Sight Beyond Sight - 1/day can cast True Seeing for five minutes 

Requires attunement </text><type>5</type><weight>3</weight><damage1H>1d8</damage1H><damage2H>1d10</damage2H><damageType>3</damageType><weaponProperty>512</weaponProperty><roll>1d6</roll><mod><type>1</type></mod></item>
	<item><name>Boots Of Curb Stomping</name><text>1d6 against enemy on the first round of damage if you charged</text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Dagger Of Venom +1</name><text>You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls and damage rolls for attacks you make with this magic weapon. If you apply poison to the dagger, other than its own poison, its saving throw DC increases by 2. 

Once per day, you can use an action to cause thick, black poison to coat the blade. The poison remains for 1 minute or until you hit with an attack using this weapon. When you hit acreature with the poisoned dagger, the target must make a DC 15 Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target becomes poisoned for 1 minute and takes 2d10 poison damage.</text><type>5</type><weight>1</weight><damage1H>1d4</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>138</weaponProperty><weaponRange>20</weaponRange><weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange><roll>2d10</roll><mod><type>1</type></mod><mod><type>1</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><type>2</type><value>1</value></mod></item>
	<item><name>Starlight Light Crossbow +2</name><text>ATK d20+prof+dx+2
DMG d8+Dex+2</text><type>6</type><weight>5</weight><damage2H>1d8</damage2H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>273</weaponProperty><weaponRange>80</weaponRange><weaponLongRange>320</weaponLongRange><mod><type>1</type><value>2</value></mod><mod><type>1</type></mod><mod><type>2</type><value>2</value></mod></item>
	<item><name>Erebus Hand Wraps (Shadow Ribbons)</name><text>Makes you want to do slight of hand, always busy

Requires attunement</text><weight>0</weight><mod><category>4</category><type>16</type><value>2</value></mod><mod><name>Sneak Attack Bonus</name><type>1</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><name>Sneak Attack Bonus</name><type>2</type><value>1</value></mod></item>
	<item><name>Cursed Ageis</name><text>Strike to light shield
1/day 1 hit dice used gives max roll

Requires attunement </text><type>4</type><weight>0</weight><mod><type>10</type><value>1</value></mod><mod><type>13</type><value>-10</value></mod></item>
	<item><name>Amulet Of Health</name><text>CON is 19 while wearing

Wondrous, requires attunement</text><slot>1</slot><weight>0</weight><mod><category>1</category><type>2</type><value>3</value></mod><mod><type>9</type><value>10</value></mod></item>
	<item><name>Dagger</name><type>5</type><weight>1</weight><damage1H>1d4</damage1H><damageType>2</damageType><weaponProperty>138</weaponProperty><weaponRange>20</weaponRange><weaponLongRange>60</weaponLongRange><mod><type>1</type></mod></item>
	<item><name>Gold (gp)</name><type>15</type><quantity>4126</quantity><weight>0.02</weight></item>
	<item><name>Leather Armor +1</name><text>Enchanted by Krystoval
Have a slight blue hue</text><type>1</type><slot>5</slot><weight>10</weight><ac>11</ac><mod><type>10</type><value>1</value></mod></item>
	<item><name>Shield</name><type>4</type><weight>6</weight><ac>2</ac></item>
	<item><name>Spider Leg, 6&#39;</name><text>Taken from giant spider killed in theater</text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Abacus</name><weight>2</weight></item>
	<item><name>Backpack</name><weight>5</weight></item>
	<item><name>Bedroll</name><weight>7</weight></item>
	<item><name>Book Of Teaching And Maps</name><text>Given to me by the Druids when I set off to find my history.</text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Candle</name><text>For 1 hour, a candle sheds bright light in a 5-foot radius and dim light for an additional 5 feet.</text><quantity>10</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Cartographer&#39;s tools</name><weight>6</weight></item>
	<item><name>Component pouch</name><text>A component pouch is a small, watertight leather belt pouch that has compartments to hold all the material components and other special items you need to cast your spells, except for those components that have a specific cost (as indicated in a spell’s description).</text><weight>2</weight></item>
	<item><name>Consecration Kit</name><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Crowbar</name><text>Using a crowbar grants advantage to Strength checks where the crowbar’s leverage can be applied.</text><weight>5</weight></item>
	<item><name>Crystoval&#39;s Book, Front Page</name><text>Torn out of the book before we destroyed it after killing the Lich Queen</text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Crystoval&#39;s Book, Random Page</name><quantity>3</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Emerald</name><text>30g</text><type>15</type><quantity>2</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Gems</name><type>15</type><quantity>13</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Hempen rope (50 feet)</name><text>Rope, whether made of hemp or silk, has 2 hit points and can be burst with a DC 17 Strength check.</text><weight>10</weight></item>
	<item><name>Herbalism kit</name><text>This kit contains a variety of instruments such as clippers, mortar and pestle, and pouches and vials used by herbalists to create remedies and potions. Proficiency with this kit lets you add your proficiency bonus to any ability checks you make to identify or apply herbs. Also, proficiency with this kit is required to create antitoxin and potions of healing.</text><weight>3</weight></item>
	<item><name>Ink (1 ounce bottle)</name><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Ink pen</name><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Knife, small</name><weight>1</weight></item>
	<item><name>Mess kit</name><text>This tin box contains a cup and simple cutlery. The box clamps together, and one side can be used as a cooking pan and the other as a plate or shallow bowl.</text><weight>1</weight></item>
	<item><name>Rations (1 day)</name><text>Rations consist of dry foods suitable for extended travel, including jerky, dried fruit, hardtack, and nuts.</text><quantity>10</quantity><weight>2</weight></item>
	<item><name>Parchment (one sheet)</name><quantity>10</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Sand (1 small bag)</name><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Tinderbox</name><text>This small container holds flint, fire steel, and tinder (usually dry cloth soaked in light oil) used to kindle a fire. Using it to light a torch—or anything else with abundant, exposed fuel—takes an action. Lighting any other fire takes 1 minute.</text><weight>1</weight></item>
	<item><name>Tiny Cage With No Door</name><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Torch</name><text>A torch burns for 1 hour, providing bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an additional 20 feet. If you make a melee attack with a burning torch and hit, it deals 1 fire damage.</text><quantity>10</quantity><weight>1</weight></item>
	<item><name>Vial Of Book Blood</name><text>Taken from the Lich Queen&#39;s book when destroyed by priestesses</text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Waterskin</name><weight>5</weight></item>
	<item><name>Potions Of Inspiration</name><text>Gain advantage on rolls</text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Studded Armor +1</name><type>1</type><weight>0</weight><mod><type>10</type><value>1</value></mod></item>
	<item><name>Gems</name><type>15</type><quantity>400</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Potion Of Longevity</name><text>Potion, very rare When you drink this potion, your physical age is reduced by 1d6 + 6 years, to a minimum of 13 years. Each time you subsequently drink a potion of longevity, there is 10 percent cumulative chance that you instead age by 1d6 + 6 years. Suspended in this amber liquid are a scorpion’s tail, an adder’s fang, a dead spider, and a tiny heart that, against all reason, is still beating. These ingredients vanish when the potion is opened.</text><quantity>2</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Bag Of Holding</name><text>Wondrous item, uncommon This bag has an interior space considerably larger than its outside dimensions, roughly 2 feet in diameter at the mouth and 4 feet deep. The bag can hold up to 500 pounds, not exceeding a volume of 64 cubic feet. The bag weighs 15 pounds, regardless of its contents. Retrieving an item from the bag requires an action. If the bag is overloaded, pierced, or torn, it ruptures and is destroyed, and its contents are scattered in the Astral Plane. If the bag is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, but the bag must be put right before it can be used again. Breathing creatures inside the bag can survive up to a number of minutes equal to 10 divided by the number of creatures (minimum 1 minute), after which time they begin to suffocate. Placing a bag of holding inside an extradimensional space created by a Heward’s handy haversack, portable hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10 feet of the gate is sucked through it to a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can’t be reopened.</text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Scrimshaw Pipe With Copper Inlay</name><text>In the shape of Maradin&#39;s hammer</text><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Glass Mirror</name><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Platinum (pp)</name><type>15</type><quantity>33</quantity><weight>0.02</weight></item>
	<item><name>Vial Of Black Sizzle Water</name><text>Sizzle when pours in the ground</text><quantity>5</quantity><weight>0</weight></item>
	<item><name>Potion Of Healing</name><text>2d4+2</text><quantity>29</quantity><weight>0</weight><roll>2n4+2</roll></item>
	<attack><name>[M] Q.Staff + Cant. &#38; Rune (20)</name><type>1</type><attackBonus>%8+%5+1+1+1</attackBonus><damage>1d8+%5+1+1+1</damage><damageType>1</damageType></attack>
	<attack><name>[M] Q.Staff + Cant. &#38; Rune (40)</name><type>1</type><attackBonus>%8+%5+1+1</attackBonus><damage>1d8+%5+1+1+1d6</damage><damageType>1</damageType></attack>
	<attack><name>[M] Q.Staff + Cant. &#38; Rune (60)</name><type>1</type><attackBonus>%8+%5+1+1</attackBonus><damage>1d8+%5+1+1+1n12</damage><damageType>1</damageType></attack>
	<attack><name>[M] Q.Staff + Cant. &#38; Rune (60 !)</name><type>1</type><attackBonus>%8+%5+1+1</attackBonus><damage>1d8+%5+1+1</damage><damageType>1</damageType></attack>
	<attack><name>[M] Q.Staff + Cant. &#38; Rune (80)</name><type>1</type><attackBonus>%8+%5+1+1</attackBonus><damage>1d10+%5+1+1</damage><damageType>1</damageType></attack>
	<attack><name>ATTACK AGAIN W/ BUTT</name><type>1</type></attack>
	<tracker><label>Hit Dice</label><value>5</value><formula>8</formula></tracker>
	<tracker><label>Wild Shape</label><resetType>1</resetType><value>2</value><formula>2</formula></tracker>
	<tracker><label>Prepared Spells</label><type>0</type><value>16</value><formula>16</formula></tracker>
	<tracker><label>Mask Acid</label><resetType>2</resetType><value>3</value><formula>3</formula></tracker>
	<note><name>2014-09-02</name><text>First time using this app, hopefully everything is set correctly.  Working on switching character from Next to 5e. </text><expanded>1</expanded></note>
	<note><name>Back notes before switching to app</name><text>Kelani the singer, &#34;more than what she seems,&#34; spy for concordium.
elf queen embassy, stark gold, booby trapped
captain &#34;eye patch&#34; Mandelbrot
malin&#39;tor spy master, Russian accent
elf queen pendant
ambassador Syra &#34;Mrs Scissors&#34;
the wolf book in the spotlight room in the theatre
Zanafer was zombie lady we killed
Kelani stole cristoval&#39;s spell book (used to cause all kinds of problems)
-day of morning, red waste
haris of dragonhall is a spy!
saiden boromor owns Lucky Lady, Vink&#39;s cousin
Half a neckless, shifty eyes
thora tarkanen, important and looked down upon
unicorns are real
2nd down on right, straight through double door, middle door in round room then across the hallway

catholic power runes &#34;pineapple&#34;
chipmunk, spoon, sugar, barefoot
rustic rooster, capt william t portabel, loves seahorses, wants to protect sea life, fish tacos
arlan twackdinger was a slave, kender, trained by same dude as Gav
seafaring dwarf, tourtalina loved, rival dan corngrinder
giant castle ship
found lady aristine delborn, elvish, 100 years in captivity 
sank the ship with the bomb
got cursed cave weaver boots

court of stars in elftown, captain william t portabel, smuggling us into the city.
lady elf 200 years old moonshadow, ruler of the high elves
dearborn, king of the 12th age
loved the sizard king
city of the coast, concord
pack lord inn, say hi to breanna
general thuram, giving to axis and publicly killing his daughter kelanie
bounty for oni - demon spirits
we killed a green drake!
took two big fucking pointy teeth
ben got snuck up on &#34;dont move or i&#39;ll slit your throat&#34;
she is using a power
&#34;gav, you need to be on your guard
my father is trying to kill you to steal the book, get to queens wood to be safe&#34;

shannon gets to use his arm crystals for his casting focus
ryan reworked sarah&#39;s character sheet
heading to twisp, right side of hill, filled with halflings
master sheply
made 35 health potions
fertile soils. well maintained, quiet atmosphere
ancient waterfall
cooking, blacksmithing, farming, rare animal husbandry
familiar face &#34;bob&#34; female elf mage, met 7 years ago, while an engineer
been desecration of local temple, work of diabloist, learn what it means
enter the temple, crumbling, creepy disappear
non human chanting - druid recognize as bullywog (frogs)
dark unholy ritual, not arcana, peaceful
dusk, normal weather
have a good feeling the town might be okay
we have achieved the court of stars
a ring! elven ring of defense, broad silver band with emerald
general therum takes a knee before king
sister casts invisibility to hide from general
beheaded his own daughter kelanie (after we brought her back from the dead) to make destroy book
go see private performance from bard who mesmerized The Green Dragon, seen at The Badgers Harp. Connie Saltemie
</text><expanded>0</expanded></note>
	<note><name>Custom Attack Explanation</name><text>Attack: d20 + Prof + WIS + 1 + 1
D20 roll to hit, plus proficiency, plus WIS instead of STR because Cantrip, plus 1 for active rune, plus 1 for &#34;+1 quarterstaff&#34;, plus rune effect (only on 1-20)

Damage:  d8 + WIS + 1 + 1 + 1
Weapon die (boosted by Cantrip), plus WIS instead of STR because Cantrip, plus 1 for active rune, plus 1 for &#34;+1 quarterstaff&#34;, plus rune effect</text><expanded>1</expanded></note>
	<monster><label>Bat</label><name>Bat</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac>	<hpMax>1</hpMax><hpCurrent>1</hpCurrent><speed>5 ft., fly 30 ft.</speed>	<abilities>2,15,8,2,12,4,</abilities>
<senses>blindsight 60 ft.</senses><passive>11</passive><cr>-3</cr>	<trait><name>Echolocation</name><text>The bat can’t use its blindsight while deafened.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Keen Hearing</name><text>The bat has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +0 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 1 piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>0</attackBonus><damage>1</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Boar</label><name>Boar</name><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>11</ac><armor>natural armor</armor>	<hpMax>11</hpMax><hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent><speed>40 ft.</speed>	<abilities>13,11,12,2,9,5,</abilities>
<passive>9</passive><cr>-1</cr>	<trait><name>Charge</name><text>If the boar moves at least 20 feet straight toward a target and then hits it with a tusk attack on the same turn, the target takes an extra 3 (1d6) slashing damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 11 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Relentless (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name><text>If the boar takes 7 damage or less that would reduce it to 0 hit points, it is reduced to 1 hit point instead.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Tusk</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d6 + 1) slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>3</attackBonus><damage>1d6+1</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Brown Bear</label><name>Brown Bear</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>11</ac><armor>natural armor</armor>	<hpMax>34</hpMax><hpCurrent>34</hpCurrent><speed>40 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>	<abilities>19,10,16,2,13,7,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>3</modifier></skill>
<passive>13</passive>	<trait><name>Keen Smell</name><text>The bear has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Multiattack</name><text>The bear makes two attacks: one with its bite and one with its claws.</text></action>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d8 + 4) piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>1d8+4</damage></attack>
</action>
	<action><name>Claws</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>2d6+4</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Cat</label><name>Cat</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac>	<hpMax>2</hpMax><hpCurrent>2</hpCurrent><speed>40 ft., climb 30 ft.</speed>	<abilities>3,15,10,3,12,7,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>3</modifier></skill>
<passive>13</passive><cr>-3</cr>	<trait><name>Keen Smell</name><text>The cat has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Claws</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +0 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>0</attackBonus><damage>1</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Constrictor Snake</label><name>Constrictor Snake</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac>	<hpMax>13</hpMax><hpCurrent>13</hpCurrent><speed>30 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>	<abilities>15,14,12,1,10,3,</abilities>
<senses>blindsight 10 ft.</senses><cr>-1</cr>	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>1d6+2</damage></attack>
</action>
	<action><name>Constrict</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 6 (1d8 + 2) bludgeoning damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 14). Until this grapple ends, the creature is restrained, and the snake can’t constrict another target.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>1d8+2</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Crocodile</label><name>Crocodile</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac><armor>natural armor</armor>	<hpMax>19</hpMax><hpCurrent>19</hpCurrent><speed>20 ft., 30 ft.</speed>	<abilities>15,10,13,2,10,5,</abilities>
	<skill><id>16</id><modifier>2</modifier></skill>
<cr>0</cr>	<trait><name>Hold Breath</name><text>The crocodile can hold its breath for 15 minutes.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one creature. Hit: 7 (1d10 + 2) piercing damage, and the target is grappled (escape DC 12). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and the crocodile can’t bite another target.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>1d10+2</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Dire Wolf</label><name>Dire Wolf</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>14</ac><armor>natural armor</armor>	<hpMax>37</hpMax><hpCurrent>37</hpCurrent><speed>50 ft.</speed>	<abilities>17,15,15,3,12,7,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>3</modifier></skill>
<passive>13</passive>	<trait><name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name><text>The wolf has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Pack Tactics</name><text>The wolf has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the wolf’s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) piercing damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>2d6+3</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Frog</label><name>Frog</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>11</ac>	<hpMax>1</hpMax><hpCurrent>1</hpCurrent><speed>20 ft., swim 20 ft.</speed>	<abilities>1,13,8,1,8,3,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>1</modifier></skill>
<senses>darkvision 30 ft.</senses><passive>11</passive><cr>-4</cr>	<trait><name>Amphibious</name><text>The frog can breathe air and water.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Standing Leap</name><text>The frog’s long jump is up to 10 feet and its high jump is up to 5 feet, with or without a running start.</text></trait>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Giant Eagle</label><name>Giant Eagle</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>13</ac>	<hpMax>26</hpMax><hpCurrent>26</hpCurrent><speed>10 ft., fly 80 ft.</speed>	<abilities>16,17,13,8,14,10,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>4</modifier></skill>
<passive>14</passive><languages>Giant Eagle, understands Common and Auran but can’t speak them</languages>	<trait><name>Keen Sight</name><text>The eagle has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Multiattack</name><text>The eagle makes two attacks: one with its beak and one with its talons.</text></action>
	<action><name>Beak</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>1d6+3</damage></attack>
</action>
	<action><name>Talons</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 10 (2d6 + 3) slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>2d6+3</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Hawk</label><name>Hawk</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>13</ac>	<hpMax>1</hpMax><hpCurrent>1</hpCurrent><speed>10 ft., fly 60 ft.</speed>	<abilities>5,16,8,2,14,6,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>4</modifier></skill>
<passive>14</passive><cr>-3</cr>	<trait><name>Keen Sight</name><text>The hawk has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Talons</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>1</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Lion</label><name>Lion</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac>	<hpMax>26</hpMax><hpCurrent>26</hpCurrent><speed>50 ft.</speed>	<abilities>17,15,13,3,12,8,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>3</modifier></skill>
<passive>13</passive>	<trait><name>Keen Smell</name><text>The lion has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Pack Tactics</name><text>The lion has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the lion’s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Pounce</name><text>If the lion moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a claw attack on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the target is prone, the lion can make one bite attack against it as a bonus action.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Running Leap</name><text>With a 10-foot running start, the lion can long jump up to 25 feet.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8 + 3) piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>1d8+3</damage></attack>
</action>
	<action><name>Claw</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>1d6+3</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Owl</label><name>Owl</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>11</ac>	<hpMax>1</hpMax><hpCurrent>1</hpCurrent><speed>5 ft., fly 60 ft.</speed>	<abilities>3,13,8,2,12,7,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>3</modifier></skill>
<senses>darkvision 120 ft.</senses><passive>13</passive><cr>-3</cr>	<trait><name>Flyby</name><text>The owl doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy’s reach.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Keen Hearing and Sight</name><text>The owl has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or sight.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Talons</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +3 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>3</attackBonus><damage>1</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Panther</label><name>Panther</name><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac>	<hpMax>13</hpMax><hpCurrent>13</hpCurrent><speed>50 ft., climb 40 ft.</speed>	<abilities>14,15,10,3,14,7,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>4</modifier></skill>
<passive>14</passive><cr>-1</cr>	<trait><name>Keen Smell</name><text>The panther has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Pounce</name><text>If the panther moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a claw attack on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 12 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the target is prone, the panther can make one bite attack against it as a bonus action.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>1d6+2</damage></attack>
</action>
	<action><name>Claw</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 4 (1d4 + 2) slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>1d4+2</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Poisonous Snake</label><name>Poisonous Snake</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>13</ac>	<hpMax>2</hpMax><hpCurrent>2</hpCurrent><speed>30 ft., swim 30 ft.</speed>	<abilities>2,16,11,1,10,3,</abilities>
<senses>blindsight 10 ft.</senses><cr>-2</cr>	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 piercing damage, and the target must make a DC 10 Constitution saving throw, taking 5 (2d4) poison damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>1</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Rat</label><name>Rat</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment>	<hpMax>1</hpMax><hpCurrent>1</hpCurrent><speed>20 ft.</speed>	<abilities>2,11,9,2,10,4,</abilities>
<senses>darkvision 30 ft.</senses><cr>-3</cr>	<trait><name>Keen Smell</name><text>The rat has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +0 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>0</attackBonus><damage>1</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Raven</label><name>Raven</name><size>0</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac>	<hpMax>1</hpMax><hpCurrent>1</hpCurrent><speed>10 ft., fly 50 ft.</speed>	<abilities>2,14,8,2,12,6,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>3</modifier></skill>
<passive>13</passive><cr>-3</cr>	<trait><name>Mimicry</name><text>The raven can mimic simple sounds it has heard, such as a person whispering, a baby crying, or an animal chittering. A creature that hears the sounds can tell they are imitations with a successful DC 10 Wisdom (Insight) check.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Beak</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 1 piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>1</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Reef Shark</label><name>Reef Shark</name><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac><armor>natural armor</armor>	<hpMax>22</hpMax><hpCurrent>22</hpCurrent><speed>0 ft., swim 40 ft.</speed>	<abilities>14,13,13,1,10,4,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>2</modifier></skill>
<senses>blindsight 30 ft.</senses><passive>12</passive><cr>0</cr>	<trait><name>Pack Tactics</name><text>The shark has advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of the shark’s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Water Breathing</name><text>The shark can breathe only underwater.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d8 + 2) piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>1d8+2</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Riding Horse</label><name>Riding Horse</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment>	<hpMax>13</hpMax><hpCurrent>13</hpCurrent><speed>60 ft.</speed>	<abilities>16,10,12,2,11,7,</abilities>
<cr>-1</cr>	<action><name>Hooves</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +2 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (2d4 + 3) bludgeoning damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>2</attackBonus><damage>2d4+3</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Tiger</label><name>Tiger</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>12</ac>	<hpMax>37</hpMax><hpCurrent>37</hpCurrent><speed>40 ft.</speed>	<abilities>17,15,14,3,12,8,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>3</modifier></skill>
<senses>darkvision 60 ft.</senses><passive>13</passive>	<trait><name>Keen Smell</name><text>The tiger has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on smell.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Pounce</name><text>If the tiger moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a claw attack on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the target is prone, the tiger can make one bite attack against it as a bonus action.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d10 + 3) piercing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>1d10+3</damage></attack>
</action>
	<action><name>Claw</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d8 + 3) slashing damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>5</attackBonus><damage>1d8+3</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Warhorse</label><name>Warhorse</name><size>3</size><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>11</ac>	<hpMax>19</hpMax><hpCurrent>19</hpCurrent><speed>60 ft.</speed>	<abilities>18,12,13,2,12,7,</abilities>
<passive>11</passive><cr>0</cr>	<trait><name>Trampling Charge</name><text>If the horse moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a hooves attack on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the target is prone, the horse can make another attack with its hooves against it as a bonus action.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Hooves</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>2d6+4</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster>
	<monster><label>Wolf</label><name>Wolf</name><type>beast</type><alignment>unaligned</alignment><ac>13</ac><armor>natural armor</armor>	<hpMax>11</hpMax><hpCurrent>11</hpCurrent><speed>40 ft.</speed>	<abilities>12,15,12,3,12,6,</abilities>
	<skill><id>11</id><modifier>3</modifier></skill>
<passive>13</passive><cr>-1</cr>	<trait><name>Keen Hearing and Smell</name><text>The wolf has advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text></trait>
	<trait><name>Pack Tactics</name><text>The wolf has advantage on attack rolls against a creature if at least one of the wolf’s allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</text></trait>
	<action><name>Bite</name><text>Melee Weapon Attack: +4 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (2d4 + 2) piercing damage. If the target is a creature, it must succeed on a DC 11 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>	<attack><attackBonus>4</attackBonus><damage>2d4+2</damage></attack>
</action>
</monster><imageData><uniqueID>1001</uniqueID></imageData></character></pc>