<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Wizard" HB="HB">
		<name>Wizard (Artifice)</name>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Arcane Tradition: Artifice</name>
				<text>The magic taught by the School of Artifice encompasses a broad spectrum of schools of magic, but all of it is concentrated on transferring that magical power into magic items. Students of the School of Artifice can accurately identify magic items and their properties as a matter of course, and are among the most skilled magical craftsmen in existence. Beyond that, the School of Artifice teaches its students how to enchant magic items with a speed unmatched by other wizards. Though the magic imbued in such items often does not last long, they produce magical devices in hours that it would take other wizards days, weeks, or longer to produce. Wizards that study in the School of Artifice are sometimes called artificers, and are frequently hired by adventuring companies looking to gain some magical support.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Artifice: Artifice Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, you halve the amount of time it takes you to craft a magic item. Additionally, you add detect magic and identify to your spellbook, if they are not already there.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Artifice: Arcane Relics</name>
				<text>Also at 2nd level, you gain the ability to create temporary magic items that your companions can use, known as arcane relics. These can be held in one hand, and you determine the actual shape of the object, as fits the item's powers. You can spend the time during a short or long rest to create a single arcane relic and explain its use to any creatures that are nearby and can hear and understand you during that time. When you create the relic, you choose a single wizard spell of 1st level or higher from your spellbook that requires 1 action to cast, and use a spell slot equal to that spell's level. From that point on, the arcane relic is a magic item, and any creatures to whom you explained the relic's use can, while holding the relic, use an action to cast the spell you chose (following the same rules as magic items that allow you to cast spells). If the spell requires an attack roll or saving throw, it uses your spell attack bonus or spell save DC. Once the spell has been cast, the arcane relic loses all its magical power and crumbles into shards and dust.</text>
				<text>	The arcane relic's magic persists for only a short period of time, and the magical energy that you use to create the relic can only maintain a single arcane relic at a time. If you create another arcane relic, or if 24 hours pass and the relic has not been used, it loses its magic and crumbles to dust.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Artifice: Rapid Enchantment</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you add the magic weapon spell to your spellbook, if it is not already there. When you cast magic weapon, you can target up to two weapons.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Artifice: The Way of the Heirophants</name>
				<text>To join the Hierophants of Tinel (see p. 84-85), you must be an arcane spellcaster and a devout follower of the god. Membership in the hierophants confers the following benefits. Note that these benefits are maintained even if the hierophant leaves or even betrays the order, since they are matters of special training. Characters who learn hierophant secrets and then leave the order are widely despised by followers of the Gods of the Tree, and especially by loyal followers of Tinel himself.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Artifice (Heirophants): Comprehend Magic</name>
				<text>At 7th level, you learn the secrets of magic as a divine power of the universe mastered by Tinel. You become so in tune with the very power of magic that you are always under the effects of the detect magic and see invisibility spells.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Artifice: Improved Artifice</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, you can create two arcane relics during a short or long rest, and can maintain up to two relics at a time, instead of just one.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Artifice (Heirophants): Mastery of Magic</name>
				<text>You may become one of  e Five when another one dies or "retires" (vanishes into mystery, usually), provided you are at least 12th level—though you may be required to be of higher level to outshine competitors for the position. The Five possess ancient tomes of wisdom written when the world was young and the mortal races first learned to use magic from Tinel himself. These secrets are considered exceptionally dangerous and none but the Five may study them. This feature confers the following benefits: You have a +10 bonus on Intelligence (arcana) checks. You either add counterspell and dispel magic to the list of spells you know, or count as if you always have them prepared. In addition, you have advantage on ability checks made because of casting either spell.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Artifice: Supreme Artifice</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can create three arcane relics during a short or long rest, and can maintain up to three relics at a time, instead of two.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
