<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<!-- Guildmaster's Guide to Ravnica backgrounds and guild spells -->
	<background>
		<name>Azorius Functionary</name>
		<proficiency>Insight, Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Skill Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Nature, plus your choice of one between Arcana or Survival.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>An Azorius insignia, a scroll containing the text of a law important to you, a bottle of blue ink, a pen, a set of fine clothes. and a belt pouch containing 10 gp (Azorius-minted 1-zino coins)
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Legal Authority</name>
			<text>You have the authority to enforce the laws of Ravnica, and that status inspires a certain amount of respect and even fear in the populace. People mind their manners in your presence and avoid drawing your attention; they assume you have the right to be wherever you are. Showing your Azorius insignia gets you an audience with anyone you want to talk to (though it might cause more problems than it solves when you're dealing with incorrigible lawbreakers). If you abuse this privilege, though, you can get in serious trouble with your superiors and even be stripped of your position.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Azorius Guild">
		<index name="Friends"/>
		<index name="Message"/>
		<index name="Command"/>
		<index name="Ensnaring Strike"/>
		<index name="Arcane Lock"/>
		<index name="Calm Emotions"/>
		<index name="Hold Person"/>
		<index name="Clairvoyance"/>
		<index name="Counterspell"/>
		<index name="Compulsion"/>
		<index name="Divination"/>
		<index name="Dominate Person"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Boros Legionnaire</name>
		<proficiency>Athletics, Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of gaming set</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Choose one of Celestial, Draconic, Goblin, or Minotaur</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A Boros insignia, a feather from an angel's wing, a tattered piece of a Boros banner (a souvenir from a famous battle), a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 2 gp (Boros-minted 1-zino coins)
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Legion Station</name>
			<text>You have an established place in the hierarchy of the Boros Legion. You can requisition simple equipment for temporary use, and you can gain access to any Boros garrison in Ravnica, where you can rest in safety and receive the attention of medics. You are also paid a salary of 1 gp (a Boros-minted 1-zino coin) per week, which (combined with free lodging in your garrison) enables you to maintain a poor lifestyle between adventures.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Boros Guild">
		<index name="Fire Bolt"/>
		<index name="Sacred Flame"/>
		<index name="Guiding Bolt"/>
		<index name="Heroism"/>
		<index name="Aid"/>
		<index name="Scorching Ray"/>
		<index name="Beacon of Hope"/>
		<index name="Blinding Smite"/>
		<index name="Death Ward"/>
		<index name="Wall of Fire"/>
		<index name="Flame Strike"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Dimir Operative</name>
		<proficiency>Deception, Stealth</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Disguise kit</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>One of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A Dimir insignia, three small knives, a set of dark-colored common clothes, and the starting equipment of the background described in this chap- ter for your secondary guild
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: False Identity</name>
			<text>You have more than one identity. The one you wear most of the time makes you appear to bea member of a guild other than House Dimir. You have documentation, established acquaintances, and disguises that allow you to assume that persona and fit into the secondary guild.</text>
			<text>	Whenever you choose, you can drop this identity and blend into the guildless masses of the city.</text>
			<text>	Consider why you're embedded in the secondary guild. Create a story with your DM, inspired by rolling on the following table or choosing a reason that suits you.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>d8  Reason for Infiltration</text>
			<text>1   My parents belong to this guild, and I let them think I'm following in their footsteps.</text>
			<text>2   I've been assigned to track this guild's activities.</text>
			<text>3   I've been assigned to get close to an individual in this guild and learn their secrets.</text>
			<text>4   I've been assigned to recruit a new Dimir spy from the ranks of this guild.</text>
			<text>5   I was a member of this guild before the Dimir recruited me.</text>
			<text>6   I don't like what this guild stands for and want to destroy it from within.</text>
			<text>7   I secretly wish I could leave the Dimir and join this guild, but there is no escaping the Dimir.</text>
			<text>8   I chose this guild at random or on a lark.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Dimir Guild">
		<index name="Encode Thoughts"/>
		<index name="Mage Hand"/>
		<index name="Disguise Self"/>
		<index name="Sleep"/>
		<index name="Detect Thoughts"/>
		<index name="Pass without Trace"/>
		<index name="Gaseous Form"/>
		<index name="Meld into Stone"/>
		<index name="Nondetection"/>
		<index name="Arcane Eye"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Modify Memory"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Golgari Agent</name>
		<proficiency>Nature, Survival</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Poisoner's kit</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Choose one of Elvish, Giant, or Kraut</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A Golgari insignia, a poisoner's kit, a pet beetle or spider, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp worth of mixed coins
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Undercity Paths</name>
			<text>You know hidden, underground pathways that you can use to bypass crowds, obstacles, and observation as you move through the city. When you aren't in combat, you and companions you lead can travel between any two lo- cations in the city twice as fast as your speed would normally allow. The paths of the undercity are haunted by dangers that rarely brave the light of the surface world, so your journey isn't guaranteed to be safe.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Golgari Guild">
		<index name="Dancing Lights"/>
		<index name="Spare the Dying"/>
		<index name="Entangle"/>
		<index name="Ray of Sickness"/>
		<index name="Protection from Poison"/>
		<index name="Ray of Enfeeblement"/>
		<index name="Spider Climb"/>
		<index name="Animate Dead"/>
		<index name="Plant Growth"/>
		<index name="Giant Insect"/>
		<index name="Grasping Vine"/>
		<index name="Cloudkill"/>
		<index name="Insect Plague"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Gruul Anarch</name>
		<proficiency>Animal Handling, Athletics</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Herbalism kit</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Choose one of Draconic, Giant, Goblin, or Sylvan</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A Gruul insignia. a hunting trap, an herbalism kit, the skull of a boar, a beast-hide cloak, a set of traveler·s clothes. and a belt pouch containing 10 gp (Azorius 1-zino coins)
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Rubblebelt Refuge</name>
			<text>You are intimately familiar with areas of the city that most people shun: ruined neighborhoods where wurms rampaged, overgrown parks that no hand has tended in decades, and the vast. sprawling rubblebelts of broken terrain that civilized folk have long abandoned. You can find a suitable place for you and your allies to hide or rest in these areas. In addition, you can find food and fresh water in these areas for yourself and up to five other people each day.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Gruul Guild">
		<index name="Fire Bolt"/>
		<index name="Produce Flame"/>
		<index name="Compelled Duel"/>
		<index name="Speak with Animals"/>
		<index name="Thunderwave"/>
		<index name="Beast Sense"/>
		<index name="Shatter"/>
		<index name="Conjure Animals"/>
		<index name="Conjure Barrage"/>
		<index name="Dominate Beast"/>
		<index name="Stoneskin"/>
		<index name="Destructive Wave"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Izzet Engineer</name>
		<proficiency>Arcana, Investigation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of artisan's tools</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Choose one of Draconic, Goblin, or Vedalken</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>An Izzet insignia, one set of artisan's tools, the charred and twisted remains of a failed experiment, a hammer, a block and tackle, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 5 gp (Azorius 1-zino coins)
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Urban Infrastructure</name>
			<text>The popular conception of the Izzet League is based on mad inventions, dangerous experiments, and ex- plosive blasts. Much of that perception is accurate, but the league is also involved with mundane tasks of construction and architecture- primarily in crafting the infrastructure that allows Ravnicans to enjoy running water, levitating platforms, and other magical and technological wonders.</text>
			<text>	You have a basic knowledge of the structure of buildings, including the stuff behind the walls. You can also find blueprints of a specific building in order to learn the details of its construction. Such blueprints might provide knowledge of entry points, structural weaknesses, or secret spaces. Your access to such information isn't unlimited. If obtaining or using the information gets you in trouble with the law, the guild can't shield you from the repercussions.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Izzet Guild">
		<index name="Produce Flame"/>
		<index name="Shocking Grasp"/>
		<index name="Chaos Bolt"/>
		<index name="Create or Destroy Water"/>
		<index name="Unseen Servant"/>
		<index name="Heat Metal"/>
		<index name="Rope Trick"/>
		<index name="Call Lightning"/>
		<index name="Elemental Weapon"/>
		<index name="Glyph of Warding"/>
		<index name="Conjure Minor Elementals"/>
		<index name="Divination"/>
		<index name="Otiluke's Resilient Sphere"/>
		<index name="Animate Objects"/>
		<index name="Conjure Elemental"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Orzhov Representative</name>
		<proficiency>Intimidation, Religion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>An Orzhov insignia, a foot-long chain made of ten gold coins, vestments, a set of fine clothes, and a belt pouch containing 1 pp (an Orzhov-minted 10-zino coin)
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Leverage</name>
			<text>You can exert leverage over one or more individuals below you in the guild's hierarchy and demand their help as needs warrant. For example, you can have a message carried across a neighborhood, procure a short carriage ride without paying, or have others clean up a bloody mess you left in an alley. The DM decides if your demands are reasonable and if there are subordinates available to fulfill them. As your status in the guild improves, you gain influence over more people, including ones in greater positions of power.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Orzhov Guild">
		<index name="Friends"/>
		<index name="Guidance"/>
		<index name="Command"/>
		<index name="Illusory Script"/>
		<index name="Enthrall"/>
		<index name="Ray of Enfeeblement"/>
		<index name="Zone of Truth"/>
		<index name="Bestow Curse"/>
		<index name="Speak with Dead"/>
		<index name="Spirit Guardians"/>
		<index name="Blight"/>
		<index name="Death Ward"/>
		<index name="Leomund's Secret Chest"/>
		<index name="Geas"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Rakdos Cultist</name>
		<proficiency>Acrobatics, Performance</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Choose either Abyssal or Giant</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of musical instrument</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A Rakdos insignia, a musical instrument (one ofyour choice), a costume, a hooded lantern made of wrought iron, a 10-foot length of chain with sharply spiked links, a tinderbox, 10 torches, a set of common clothes, a belt pouch containing 10 gp (a mix of Azorius and Boros 1-zino coins), and a bottle of sweet, red juice
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Fearsome Reputation</name>
			<text>People recognize you as a member of the Cult of Rakdos, and they're careful not to draw your anger or ridicule. You can get away with minor criminal offenses, such as refusing to pay for food at a restaurant or breaking down a door at a local shop, if no legal authorities witness the crime. Most people are too daunted by you to report your wrongdoing to the Azorius.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Rakdos Guild">
		<index name="Fire Bolt"/>
		<index name="Vicious Mockery"/>
		<index name="Burning Hands"/>
		<index name="Dissonant Whispers"/>
		<index name="Hellish Rebuke"/>
		<index name="Crown of Madness"/>
		<index name="Enthrall"/>
		<index name="Flaming Sphere"/>
		<index name="Fear"/>
		<index name="Haste Confusion"/>
		<index name="Wall of Fire"/>
		<index name="Dominate Person"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Selesnya Initiate</name>
		<proficiency>Nature, Persuasion</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Choose one of Elvish, Loxodon, or Sylvan</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Tool Proficiencies</name>
			<text>One type of artisan's tools or one musical instrument</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A Selesnya insignia, a healer's kit, robes, a set of common clothes, and a belt pouch containing 5 gp (Azorius 1-zino coins)
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Conclave Shelter</name>
			<text>As a member of the Selesnya Conclave, you can count on your guild mates to provide shelter and aid. You and your companions can find a place to hide or rest in any Selesnya enclave in the city, unless you have proven to be a danger to them. The members of the enclave will shield you from the law or anyone else searching for you, though they will not risk their lives in this effort.</text>
			<text>	In addition, as a guild member you can receive free healing and care at a Selesnya enclave, though you must provide any material components needed for spells.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Selesnya Guild">
		<index name="Druidcraft"/>
		<index name="Friends"/>
		<index name="Aid"/>
		<index name="Animal Friendship"/>
		<index name="Charm Person"/>
		<index name="Animal Messenger"/>
		<index name="Calm Emotions"/>
		<index name="Warding Bond"/>
		<index name="Plant Growth"/>
		<index name="Speak with Plants"/>
		<index name="Aura of Life"/>
		<index name="Conjure Minor Elementals"/>
		<index name="Awaken"/>
		<index name="Commune with Nature"/>
	</spellList>
	<background>
		<name>Simic Scientist</name>
		<proficiency>Arcana, Medicine</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>Two of your choice</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Equipment</name>
			<text>A Simic insignia, a set of commoner's clothes, a book of research notes, an ink pen, a bottle of squid ink, a flask of oil (made from blubber), a vial of acid (derived from digestive juices), a vial of fish scales, a vial of seaweed, a vial of jellyfish stingers, a glass bottle ofunidentified slime, and a belt pouch containing 10 gp (Azorius 1-zino coins)
		</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feature: Researcher</name>
			<text>When you attempt to learn or recall a magical or scientific fact, if you don't know that information, you know where and from whom you can obtain it. Usually, this information comes from a Simic laboratory, or sometimes from an Izzet facility, a library, a university, or an independent scholar or other learned person or creature. Knowing where the information can be found doesn't automatically enable you to learn it; you might need to offer bribes, favors, or other incentives to induce people to reveal their secrets.</text>
			<text>	Your DM might rule that the knowledge you seek is secreted away in an inaccessible place, or that it simply can't be found. Unearthing the deepest secrets of the multiverse can require an adventure or even a whole campaign.</text>
		</trait>
	</background>
	<spellList class="Simic Guild">
		<index name="Acid Splash"/>
		<index name="Druidcraft"/>
		<index name="Detect Poison and Disease"/>
		<index name="Expeditious Retreat"/>
		<index name="Jump"/>
		<index name="Alter Self"/>
		<index name="Enhance Ability"/>
		<index name="Enlarge/Reduce"/>
		<index name="Gaseous Form"/>
		<index name="Water Breathing"/>
		<index name="Wind Wall"/>
		<index name="Freedom of Movement"/>
		<index name="Polymorph"/>
		<index name="Creation"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
