<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Blood Hunter" HB="HB">
		<name>Blood Hunter (Ghostslayer)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>`Blood Hunter Order: Order of the Ghostslayer</name>
				<text>The Order of the Ghostslayer is the oldest and most driven of the orders, having rediscovered the secrets of blood magic and refined them for combat against the scourge of undeath. Ghostslayers seek out and study the moment of the death, obsessing over the mysteries of the transition. Some will sit with the terminally diseased to closely witness their passing, while others go so far as to deliberately have a near-death experience, allowing them to tune to their body and senses to the ethereal realms beyond.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Ghostslayer: Rite of the Dawn</name>
				<text>When you join this order at 3rd level, you learn the esoteric rite Rite of the Dawn.</text>
				<text>  • Rite of the Dawn. Your rite damage is radiant type.</text>
				<text>	If you hit an Undead creature with your Rite of the Dawn, it suffers additional radiant damage equal to your Wisdom modifier.</text>
				<text>	Upon reaching 11th level, any creature you hit with your Rite of the Dawn suffers this additional radiant damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Ghostslayer: Hallowed Veins</name>
				<text>Beginning at 7th level, your blood curses become honed to the fabric of a creature's essence. Your blood curses can now affect any creature, regardless of their form or lack of blood.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Ghostslayer: Supernal Surge</name>
				<text>Upon reaching 11th level, you can spend a bonus action to allow your body to take on a swift, ghostly form. This effect lasts a number of rounds equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1). While this surge lasts, you can make a single weapon attack as a bonus action on each of your turns.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you become spectral for the duration, allowing you to move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You take 1d10 force damage if you end your turn inside an object. If this surge ends while you are inside an object, you are immediately shunted to the nearest unoccupied space that you can occupy and take force damage equal to twice the number of feet you moved.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Ghostslayer: Gravesight</name>
				<text>At 15th level, you can see in normal darkness, as well as see invisible creatures and objects, up to 30 feet.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Ghostslayer: Vengeful Spirit</name>
				<text>Upon reaching 18th level, you learn to project your spirit to fight on while on the edge of death. Whenever your hit points drop to 0, you can choose to let your soul emerge from your body to fight on. Your body remains unconscious and subject to death saving throws per normal. At the beginning of your next turn, you manifest a spirit form in your space that picks up your weapons and continues fighting on, acting on your turn and every one of your subsequent turns under your control. Your spirit form has your physical attributes and armor class, as well as your weapons and ammunition, and can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. This form is immune to cold, necrotic, and non-magical weapon damage. Your spirit form has access to all of your abilities other than your blood maledict feature.</text>
				<text>	If your spirit form takes any damage, your body dies, or you regain any hit points, your spirit form vanishes. If your spirit form vanishes, it drops your weapons in its space.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
