<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<subclass baseclass="Blood Hunter">
		<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots optional="YES">2,1,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots optional="YES">2,1,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots optional="YES">2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots optional="YES">2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots optional="YES">2,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots optional="YES">2,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots optional="YES">2,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots optional="YES">2,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots optional="YES">2,0,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots optional="YES">3,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<name>Blood Hunter (Profane Soul)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Blood Hunter Order: Order of the Profane Soul</name>
				<text>The magics adopted by the wayward blood hunter prove formidable against many an evil across the realm. However, the darkest of abominations draw from an ancient well of cruel, unfathomable power. These terrors can control shadows to do their bidding, hide in plain sight among the noblest of nobles, and bend the minds of the most stalwart warrior with but a glance. These fiends are far trickier to hunt, and many lost their lives in pursuit of such wickedness.</text>
				<text>	A small sect of blood hunters had finally had enough and delved into the same well of corrupting arcane knowledge, making pacts with lesser evils to better combat the greater. While they may have lost a part of themselves, the power gained far outweighed the price, for even devils now quake when they know they've drawn the attention of the Order of the Profane Soul.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Profane Soul: Otherworldly Patron</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, you strike a bargain with an otherworldly being of your choice: the Archfey, the Fiend, or the Great Old One, each detailed on page 109 of the PHB or the Undying on page 139 of the Sword Coast Adventurer's Guide. Your choice augments some of your order features.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Profane Soul: Pact Magic</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, you can augment your combat techniques with the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 of the PHB for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 of the PHB for the Warlock spell list.</text>
				<text>	Cantrips. You learn two cantrips of your choice from the Warlock spell list. You learn an additional Warlock cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</text>
				<text>	Spell Slots. The Profane Soul Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your Warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, when you are 8th level, you have two 2nd level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell thunderwave, you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 2nd-level spell.</text>
				<text>	Spell Known of 1st Level and Higher. At 3rd level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the Warlock spell list.</text>
				<text>	The total spell known are equal to the Warlock level divided by 2, rounded up. A spell you choose to learn must be of a level no higher than what's shown in the table's (listed at the beginning of this class description) Slot Level column for our level. When you reach 11th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally when you get a level in this class and order, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace is with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text>	Spellcasting Ability. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells, so you use your Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a warlock spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Profane Soul: Rite Focus</name>
				<text>Beginning at 3rd level, your weapon becomes a core to your pact with your chosen dark patron. While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus (found in chapter 5 of the PHB) for your spells. Your chosen pact also enhances your rite (outlined below).</text>
				<text>  • The Archfey. If you deal rite damage to a creature, that creature loses any half or three-quarters cover bonuses, as well as invisibility, until the beginning of your next turn.</text>
				<text>  • The Fiend. While using the Rite of the Flame, if you roll a 1 on your rite damage die, you may reroll the die. You may reroll only once per attack.</text>
				<text>  • The Great Old One. Whenever you deal a critical hit to a creature, that creature must make a Wisdom saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</text>
				<text>  • The Undying. Whenever you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points with a weapon attack, and kill it, you regain hit points equal to your crimson rite damage die.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Profane Soul: Mystic Frenzy</name>
				<text>Beginning at 7th level, when you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Profane Soul: Revealed Arcana</name>
				<text>At 7th level, your dark patron grants you the rare use of a dangerous arcane spell based on your pact.</text>
				<text>  • The Archfey. You can cast blur once using a profane soul spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>  • The Fiend. You can cast scorching ray once using a profane soul spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>  • The Great Old One. You can cast detect thoughts once using a profane soul spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>  • The Undying. You can cast blindness/deafness once using a profane soul spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Profane Soul: Diabolic Channel</name>
				<text>At 11th level, you can temporarily infuse your rite with the seed of a powerful spell. As an action, you can imbue your rite-enhanced weapon with one spell you can cast or is already active, then make a single attack with that weapon. If that attack hits, all spell attack rolls for the imbued spell hit the target automatically and are considered part of the single weapon attack. The target takes weapon damage, and is subject to the effects of the spell, expending a spell slot accordingly. If the attack has advantage, the target's initial saving throw against the spell has disadvantage. If the attack misses, the spell has no effect. Area spells originate from the target's space.</text>
				<text>	The spell must be of 1st level or higher, having a casting time of 1 action, or require an action to activate an already active concentration spell.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Profane Soul: Unsealed Arcana</name>
				<text>At 15th level, your dark patron grants you the rare use of an additional arcane spell based on your pact.</text>
				<text>  • The Archfey. You can cast slow once using a profane soul spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>  • The Fiend. You can cast fireball once using a profane spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>  • The Great Old One. You can cast haste once using a profane soul spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>  • The Undying. You can cast bestow curse once using a profane soul spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Order of the Profane Soul: Soul Siphon</name>
				<text>When you reach 18th level, you learn to sacrifice the souls of powerful foes to your dark patron in exchange for immediate power. When you reduce a creature to 0 hit points with an attack, kill the creature, and they have a challenge rating of 15 or above, you recover an expended spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<borrowSpells fromClass="Warlock" class="Blood Hunter (Profane Soul)"/>
</compendium>
