<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
<subclass baseclass="Blood Hunter" HB="HB">
	<name>Blood Hunter (Mutant)</name>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Blood Hunter Order: Order of the Mutant</name>
			<text>The process of consuming the Hunter's Bane is a painful, scarring, and often fatal experience. Those that survive find themselves irrevocably changed, enhanced. Some found this experience exalting, embracing the ability to alter one's own physiology through corrupted alchemy.</text>
			<text>	Over generations of experimentation, a splinter order of blood hunters began to emerge, one that focused on brewing toxic elixirs to modify their capabilities in battle, altering their blood and, over time become something beyond human. They called themselves the Order of the Mutant.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Mutant: Formulas</name>
			<text>You begin to uncover forbidden alchemical formulas that temporarily alter your mental and physical abilities.</text>
			<text>	Beginning at 3rd level, you choose to learn three mutagen formulas. Your formula options are detailed at the end of this order description. You gain an additional formula at 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.</text>
			<text>Additionally, when you gain a new mutagen formula, you can choose one of the formulas you already know and replace it with another mutagen formula.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Mutant: Mutagen Craft</name>
			<text>At 3rd level, you can take a short rest to concoct a single mutagen. Consuming a single mutagen requires a bonus action, and the effects (including side effects) last until you take a short or long rest to mediate and flush the toxins from your system.</text>
			<text>Mutagens are designed for your biology. They have no effect on large or larger creatures, and only impart the side effects on other medium or smaller creatures that drink the entire mutagen. They are also unstable by nature, losing their potency over time and becoming inert if not swallowed before you finish your next short or long rest.</text>
			<text>Your body will begin to better utilize the toxins you instill it with as you grow in power and experience. These advancing mutations may be signified by a Mutation score.</text>
			<text>	Mutation Score = your blood hunter level divided by 4, rounded up.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Mutant: Mutagen List</name>
			<text>These mutagens are presented in alphabetical order. You can learn a mutagen at the same time you meet its prerequisites.</text>
			<text>  • Aether. Prerequisite: 11th level. You gain a flying speed of 20 feet. Side effect: you have disadvantage on all Strength and Dexterity ability checks.</text>
			<text>  • Celerity. Your Dexterity score increases by an amount equal to your mutation score, as does your Dexterity maximum. Side effect: Your Wisdom score decreases by amount equal to your mutation score.</text>
			<text>  • Conversant. You gain advantage on Intelligence ability checks. Side effect: You have disadvantage on Charisma ability checks.</text>
			<text>  • Cruelty. Prerequisite: 11th level. You can make a single weapon attack as a bonus action on each of your turns. Side effect: You gain vulnerability to slashing damage.</text>
			<text>  • Impermeable. You gain resistance to piercing damage. Side effect: You gain vulnerability to slashing damage.</text>
			<text>  • Mobility. You gain immunity to the grappled and restrained conditions. At 11th level, you also are immune to the paralyzed condition. Side effect: You gain a penalty to initiative equal to 2 times your mutation score.</text>
			<text>  • Nighteye. You gain darkvision for up to 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, this increases its range by 60 additional feet. Side effect: You gain sunlight sensitivity. (PHB 24)</text>
			<text>  • Potency. Your Strength score increases by an amount equal to your mutation score, as does your Strength maximum. Side effect: Your Dexterity score decreases by an amount equal to your mutation score.</text>
			<text>  • Precision. Prerequisite: 11th level. Your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20. Side effect: All healing you receive is halved.</text>
			<text>  • Rapidity. Your speed increases by 10 feet. At 15th level, your speed increases by 15 feet instead. Side effect: You have disadvantage on Dexterity ability checks.</text>
			<text>  • Reconstruction. Prerequisite: 7th level. While conscious and in combat, you regenerate hit points equal to 2 times your mutation score (rounded down) at the start of your turn as long as you are above 0 hit points. Side effect: Your speed decreases by 10 feet.</text>
			<text>  • Sagacity. Your Wisdom score increases by an amount equal to your mutation score, as does your Wisdom maximum. Side effect: Your armor class is reduced by an amount equal to your mutation score.</text>
			<text>  • Shielded. You gain resistance to slashing damage. Side effect: You gain vulnerability to bludgeoning damage.</text>
			<text>  • Unbreakable. You gain resistance to bludgeoning damage. Side effect: You gain vulnerability to piercing damage.</text>
			<text>  • Wariness. You gain a bonus to initiative equal to 2 times your mutation score. Side effect: You have disadvantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Mutant: Advanced Mutagen Craft</name>
			<text>Upon reaching 7th level, when you take a short rest to concoct a mutagen, you can now create two. Mutagens must be different formulas, and can be ingested with overlapping effects that last until you finish your next short or long rest. Each mutagen still takes a separate bonus action to imbibe.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Mutant: Strange Metabolism</name>
			<text>Beginning at 11th level, you can use a bonus action to install a burst of adrenaline to temporarily resist the negative effects of a mutagen. You can choose to ignore the side effect of a mutagen affecting you for 1 minute.</text>
			<text>	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Mutant: Robust Physiology</name>
			<text>At 15th level, your body has begun to adapt to toxins and venoms, ignoring their corroding effects. You gain immunity to poison damage and the poisoned condition.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Mutant: Advanced Mutagen Craft (2)</name>
			<text>Upon reaching 15th level, you can now create three mutagens during a short rest.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Mutant: Exalted Mutation</name>
			<text>At 18th level, your body has begun producing one of your toxins naturally. Choose one of your known mutagen formulas. You gain the benefits and side effects of this mutagen permanently, at all times. You cannot change this choice of formula after this feature is acquired.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</subclass>
</compendium>
