<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
<subclass baseclass="Mist Walker" HB="HB">
	<name>Mist Walker (Mind)</name>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Conviction of the Mind</name>
			<text>Some Mist Walkers believe that only by strengthening their allies, can they achieve total dominance over their opponents. These Mist Walkers spend countless hours perfecting their ability to walk the Mist— so much so that they gain the ability to guide their allies through the Mist, and eventually their foes as well. For these Mist Walkers, the key to swift victory, is understanding the battlefield in its entirety, and controlling the positioning and flow of combat.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Conviction of the Mind: Additional Shroud Abilities</name>
			<text>Starting at 3rd level, you gain the following additional Shroud Abilities:</text>
			<text />
			<text>Oppressive Haze (Shroud Ability)</text>
			<text>As bonus action, you may spend 3 Shroud Points to choose one creature you can see within 10 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or else it is surrounded in an oppressive gray mist, which lasts for 1 minute.</text>
			<text>	An affected target's speed is halved, it takes a −2 penalty to AC and Dexterity saving throws, and it can't use reactions. On its turn, it can use either an action or a bonus action, not both. Regardless of the creature's abilities or magic items, it can't make more than one melee or ranged attack during its turn.</text>
			<text>	If the creature attempts to cast a spell with a casting time of 1 action, roll a d20. On an 11 or higher, the spell doesn't take effect until the creature's next turn, and the creature must use its action on that turn to complete the spell. If it can't, the spell is wasted.</text>
			<text>	A creature affected by this ability makes another Wisdom saving throw at the end of its turn. On a successful save, the effect ends for it.</text>
			<text></text>
			<text>Disarming Mist (Shroud Ability)</text>
			<text>As a bonus action, whenever you hit a creature with an attack, you may spend 2 Shroud Points to attempt to disarm your opponent using the Mist to aid you. The target makes a Dexterity (Acrobatics) check to avoid having a weapon that it is currently wielding be teleported through the Mist to a space of your choosing within 30 feet. If the target succeeds its saving throw, nothing happens.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>Obstructing Shroud (Shroud Ability)</text>
			<text>As a bonus action, you may spend 2 Shroud Points to choose one large size or smaller creature you can see within 10 feet of you. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or else it has disadvantage on attacks until the end of its next turn.</text>
			<text/>
			<text>Swift Guidance</text>
			<text>As a bonus action, choose any number of creatures you can see within your Mist Walk Distance. You may spend 1 Shroud Point per target to give them an additional 15 feet of movement speed until the end of their next turn.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Conviction of the Mind: Tenacious Mind</name>
			<text>Beginning at 3rd level, you can now recuperate your expended Shroud Points after a short rest once per day.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Conviction of the Mind: Calculated Exchange</name>
			<text>Beginning at 3rd Level, as an action, choose two willing medium sized or smaller creatures that you can see within half your Mist Walk Distance. Those creatures swap places. This does not provoke an opportunity attack for the moved creatures.
			</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Conviction of the Mind: Veiled Ferry</name>
			<text>Beginning at 7th level, you touch a willing creature and can have them accompany you when you Mist Walk. The target must be medium size or smaller, and appears in an unoccupied square next to your target square. If there isn't an unoccupied space within 5 feet of your arrival point, the target is moved to the nearest unoccupied square and takes 2d6 points of force damage, for every 5 feet it is forced to move.
			</text>
			<text>	The creature has advantage on the next attack it makes before the end of its next turn. You can use this ability a number of times per day equal to your Intelligence modifier.</text>
			<text>	When you reach 13th level in this class, you can use this ability a number of times per day equal to twice your Intelligence modifier.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Conviction of the Mind: Vigilant Response</name>
			<text>At 11th level, your ability to track multiple enemies on the battlefield is uncanny. Whenever a creature within 30 feet of you, that you can see and hear, begins to cast a spell, you can use your reaction to teleport to an unoccupied space next to the target and make a single attack against them. If you hit, the target must make a Constitution saving throw as normal or lose the spell.</text>
			<text>	You cannot use this ability again until you complete a short rest.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Conviction of the Mind: Vigilant Subterfuge</name>
			<text>Beginning at 15th level, whenever an ally that you can see that is within your Mist Walk Distance is the target of an attack, after the die is rolled, but before the Dungeon Master declares whether the hit was successful, you can, as a reaction attempt to swap the places of that ally and another creature of your choice— potentially having the new creature take the attack instead.</text>
			<text>	Choose one medium sized or smaller creature within your Mist Walk Distance that you can see. If the target is a willing target, switch the target's position with your ally. Then, apply the original attack to the new creature, using its AC to determine the success or failure of the attack. If it hits, the attack deals damage to the new creature and applies any additional abilities, conditions, saving throws, etc. to the new creature as normal.</text>
			<text>	If the target is an unwilling creature, it must succeed a Wisdom saving throw or be forced to swap places with your ally and take the attack. Once you have used this ability, you cannot use it again until you complete a short rest.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</subclass>
</compendium>
