<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Fighter">
		<name>Fighter (Hospitaler)</name>
		<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots optional="YES">2,2,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,1</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Martial Archetype: Hospitaler</name>
				<text>The hospitaler archetype stands at the crossroads of martial mastery and devotion to one or more gods. Hospitalers approach their faith much as clerics do, but draw on their religious convictions to help them overcome their enemies in battle. Where paladins are called to  ght in the name of righteousness, hospitalers use their devotion to the divine to advance the cause of their patron deities in the world and might serve as combat healers, chaplains, or simply devout warriors who took up arms in the name of the gods. Hospitalers pray for and receive a small number of cleric spells, and most focus their spell selection on healing magic.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hospitaler: Spellcasting</name>
				<text>When you reach 3rd level, the gods infuse you with divine power, which augments your combat capabilities. See the PH for rules of spell casting and for the cleric spell list.</text>
				<text>	• Cantrips: Choose two cantrips to learn from the cleric spell list. You learn another cleric cantrip of your choice when you reach 10th level.</text>
				<text>	• Preparing and Casting Spells: The Hospitaler spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells. When you would cast a spell of 1st level or higher, you must expend a slot of the spell’s level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	You prepare the list of cleric spells available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Charisma modifier + half your fighter level, rounded down (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots. You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest, though doing so requires you to spend at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list in prayer and meditation.</text>
				<text>	• Spellcasting Ability: Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells, since the power you draw to cast them comes from your devotion and understanding of the deity you serve. You use Wisdom whenever a spell refers to your Charisma modi er when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
				<text>	Spellcasting Focus: You can use a holy symbol as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hospitaler: Devoted Healer</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you learn to how to channel your faith, which is represented by special dice called faith dice, into healing. You have two faith dice, which are d6s. Whenever you cast a 1st-level or higher spell that restores hit points to a creature, you can expend a faith die, roll it, and add the number rolled to the total number of hit points the creature regains. You regain all your expended faith dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	You gain another faith die at 7th level and another one at 15th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hospitaler: Improved Devoted Healer</name>
				<text>Starting at 7th level, your faith dice turn into d8s. At 18th level, they turn into d10s.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hospitaler: Healing Surge</name>
				<text>When you reach 10th level, any time you use your Action Surge, you can expend one faith die. Roll the die and each creature you choose within 30 feet of you gains temporary hit points equal to the number rolled. After 1 minute, any remaining temporary hit points are lost.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hospitaler: Flanking Maneuvers</name>
				<text>At 10th level, your battlefield awareness allows you to sense a retreat and cut it off as it happens. When you hit a creature with an opportunity attack, you can move up to half your speed immediately after the attack as part of the same reaction. This movement doesn't provoke opportunity attacks.</text>
				<text>	Starting at 18th level, if you make a melee attack against a creature, that creature can't make an opportunity attack against you for the rest of your turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Hospitaler: Burgeoning Faith</name>
				<text>Beginning at 15th level, when you roll initiative and you have no faith dice remaining, you regain one faith die.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<borrowSpells fromClass="Cleric" class="Fighter (Hospitaler)" />
</compendium>
