<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="YES" HB="HB">
	<race name="Changling">
		<name>Changeling</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Cha 2</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and either your Dexterity or your Intelligence increases by 1 (your choice).</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Change Appearance</name>
			<text>As an action, you can transform your appearance or revert to your natural form. You can’t duplicate the appearance of a creature you’ve never seen, and you revert to your natural form if you die.</text>
			<text>	You decide what you look like, including your height, weight, facial features, the sound of your voice, coloration, hair length, sex, and any other distinguishing characteristics. You can make yourself appear as a member of another race, though none of your game statistics change. You also can’t appear as a creature of a different size than you, and your basic shape stays the same; if you’re bipedal, you can’t use this trait to become quadrupedal, for instance. Your clothing and other equipment don’t change in appearance, size, or shape to match your new form, requiring you to keep a few extra out ts on hand to make the most compelling disguise possible.</text>
			<text>	Even to the most astute observers, your ruse is usually indiscernible. If you rouse suspicion, or if a wary creature suspects something is amiss, you have advantage on any Charisma (Deception) check you make to avoid detection.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Changeling Instincts</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Deception, Intimidation, Insight, and Persuasion.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Unsettling Visage</name>
			<text>When a creature you can see makes an attack roll against you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the roll. You must use this feature before knowing whether the attack hits or misses.
			</text>
			<text>	Using this trait reveals your shapeshifting nature to any creature within 30 feet that can see you. Once you use this trait, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Divergent Persona</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency with one tool of your choice. De ne a unique identity associated with that proficiency; establish the name, race, gender, age, and other details. While you are in the form of this persona, the related proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses that proficiency.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and two other languages of your choice.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Kalashtar">
		<name>Kalashtar</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Wis 1, Cha 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text> Your Wisdom and Charisma scores both increase by 1. In addition, one ability score of your choice increases by 1.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Dual Mind</name>
			<text>When you make a Wisdom saving throw, you can use your reaction to gain advantage on the roll. You can use this trait immediately before or after you roll, but before any of the roll’s effects occur.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Mental Discipline</name>
			<text>You have resistance to psychic damage.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Mind Link</name>
			<text>You can speak telepathically to any creature you can see within 60 feet of you. You don’t need to share a language with the creature for it to understand your telepathic messages, but the creature must be able to understand at least one language or be telepathic itself.
			</text>
			<text>	As a bonus action when you’re speaking telepathically to a creature, you can give that creature the ability to speak telepathically to you until the start of your next turn. To use this ability, the creature must be within 60 feet of you and be able to see you.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Psychic Glamour</name>
			<text>Choose one of the following skills: Insight, Intimidation, Performance, or Persuasion. You have advantage on all ability checks you make with that skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Severed from Dreams</name>
			<text>Kalashtar sleep, but they don’t connect to the plane of dreams as other creatures do. Instead, their minds draw from the memories of their otherworldly spirit while they sleep. As such, you are immune to magical spells and effects that require you to dream, like the dream spell, but not to spells and effects that put you to sleep, like the sleep spell.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Quori, and one other language of your choice.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
</compendium>
