<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="YES" HB="HB">
<race name="Feyblood (Skyborn)" source="XLNtEE">
	<name>Feyblood (Sylphi/Skyborn)</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<speed>30</speed>
	<ability>Cha 2, Wis 1</ability>
	<trait>
		<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
		<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Fey Charm</name>
		<text>You can target one humanoid or beast that you can see within 30 feet. It must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be magically charmed. The charmed creature regards you as a trusted friend to be heeded and protected. Although the target isn't under your control, it takes your requests or actions in the most favorable way it can.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Fey Resistance</name>
		<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed and against illusion magic.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Faerie Wings</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you can use your wings to glide at a rate of 60 feet per round as if under the effects of a feather fall spell. At 6th level, once per long rest, you can fly as if under the effect of the fly spell for up to 10 minutes.
		</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Languages</name>
		<text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Sylvan, and one extra language of your choice.</text>
	</trait>
</race>
<race name="Feyblood (Earthborn)" source="XLNtEE">
	<name>Feyblood (Dryashi/Earthborn)</name>
	<size>M</size>
	<speed>30</speed>
	<ability>Cha 2, Con 1</ability>
	<trait>
		<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
		<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Fey Charm</name>
		<text>You can target one humanoid or beast that you can see within 30 feet. It must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be magically charmed. The charmed creature regards you as a trusted friend to be heeded and protected. Although the target isn't under your control, it takes your requests or actions in the most favorable way it can.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Fey Resistance</name>
		<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed and against illusion magic.</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Earthen Upbringing</name>
		<text>While perfectly still, you are invisible when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena. At 6th level, when you are hidden in this way, you can use your action to cast invisibility with no material components, and you can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.
		</text>
	</trait>
	<trait>
		<name>Languages</name>
		<text>You can speak, read, and write Common, Sylvan, and one extra language of your choice.</text>
	</trait>
</race>
</compendium>