<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="YES" HB="HB">
	<!--Plane Shift: Amonkhet-->
	<race name="Human (Amonkhet)" source="PS:A">
		<name>Human (Amonkhet)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text>Two different ability scores of your choice increase by 1.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Skills</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency in one skill of your choice.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feat</name>
			<text>You gain one feat of your choice.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one extra language of your choice. Humans typically learn the languages of other peoples they deal with, including obscure dialects. They are fond of sprinkling their speech with words borrowed from other tongues: Orc curses, Elvish musical expressions, Dwarvish military phrases, and so on.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Aven (Ibis-Headed)" source="PS:A">
		<name>Aven (Ibis-Headed)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>25</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Int 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Speed</name>
			<text>Your base walking speed is 25 feet. You have a flying speed of 30 feet. You can't use your flying speed while you wear medium or heavy armor. (If your campaign uses the variant rule for encumbrance, you can't use your flying speed if you are encumbered.)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Kefnet's Blessing</name>
			<text>You can add half your proficiency bonus, rounded down, to any Intelligence check you make that doesn't already include your proficiency bonus.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Aven.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Aven (Hawk-Headed)" source="PS:A">
		<name>Aven (Hawk-Headed)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>25</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Wis 2</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Speed</name>
			<text>Your base walking speed is 25 feet. You have a flying speed of 30 feet. You can't use your flying speed while you wear medium or heavy armor. (If your campaign uses the variant rule for encumbrance, you can't use your flying speed if you are encumbered.)</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Hawkeyed</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill. In addition, attacking at long range doesn't impose disadvantage on your ranged weapon attack rolls.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Aven.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Khenra" source="PS:A">
		<name>Khenra</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>35</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Str 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Khenra Weapon Training</name>
			<text>You have proficiency with the khopesh, spear, and javelin.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Khenra Twins</name>
			<text>If your twin is alive and you can see your twin, whenever you roll a 1 on an attack roll, ability check, or saving throw, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll. If your twin is dead (or if you were born without a twin), you can't be frightened.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Khenra</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Minotaur (Amonkhet)" source="PS:A">
		<name>Minotaur (Amonkhet)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Str 2, Con 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Natural Weapon</name>
			<text>You can use your horns as a natural weapon to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with your horns, you deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Menacing</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Relentless Endurance</name>
			<text>When you are reduced to 0 hit points but not killed outright, you can drop to 1 hit point instead. You can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Savage Attacks</name>
			<text>When you score a critical hit with a melee weapon attack, you can roll one of the weapon's damage dice one additional time and add it to the extra damage of the critical hit.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Minotaur.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Naga" source="PS:A">
		<name>Naga</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Con 2, Int 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Speed Burst</name>
			<text>By lowering your body to the ground and propelling yourself with your arms, you can move more quickly for a time. As a bonus action on your turn, if you have both hands free, you can increase your walking speed by 5 feet until the end of your turn.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Natural Weapons</name>
			<text>Your fanged maw and constricting serpentine body are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with your bite, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, and your target must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Constitution modifier). On a failed save, the target takes 1d4 poison damage.</text>
			<text>	If you hit with your constrict attack, you deal bludgeoning damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, and the target is grappled (escape DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier). Until this grapple ends, the target is restrained, and you can't constrict another target.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Poison Immunity</name>
			<text>You are immune to poison damage and can't be poisoned.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Poison Affinity</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency with the poisoner's kit.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Naga.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
</compendium>
