<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" auto_indent="YES" HB="HB">
	<!--Plane Shift: Kaladesh-->
	<race name="Aetherborn" source="PS:K">
		<name>Aetherborn</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Cha 2</ability>
		<proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text>Your Charisma score increases by 2, and two other ability scores of your choice increase by 1.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to the night, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Born of Aether</name>
			<text>You have resistance to necrotic damage.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Menacing</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and two other languages of your choice.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Dwarf (Kaladesh)" source="PS:K">
		<name>Dwarf (Kaladesh)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>25</speed>
		<ability>Con 2, Wis 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Survival</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to the night, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Dwarven Resilience</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against poison, and you have resistance against poison damage.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Dwarven Toughness</name>
			<text>Your hit point maximum increases by 1, and it increases by 1 every time you gain a level.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Artisan's Expertise</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency with two kinds of artisan's tools of your choice. Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of the chosen proficiencies. In addition, whenever you make an Intelligence (History) check related to the origin of any architectural construction (including buildings, public works such as canals and aqueducts, and the massive cogwork that underlies much of the construction of Ghirapur), you are considered proficient in the History skill and add double your proficiency bonus to the check, instead of your normal proficiency bonus.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Dwarvish. Dwarvish is full of hard consonants and guttural sounds, and those characteristics spill over into whatever other language a dwarf might speak.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Elf (Kaladesh Bishtahar/Tirahar)" source="PS:K">
		<name>Elf (Kaladesh Bishtahar/Tirahar)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>35</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Wis 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text>Your Intelligence and Charisma scores each increase by 1.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to the night, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Elf Weapon Training</name>
			<text>You have proficiency with the longsword, shortsword, shortbow, and longbow.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fleet of Foot</name>
			<text>Your base walking speed increases to 35 feet.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Mask of the Wild</name>
			<text>You can attempt to hide even when you are only lightly obscured by foliage, heavy rain, falling snow, mist, and other natural phenomena.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Elf (Kaladesh Vahadar)" source="PS:K">
		<name>Elf (Kaladesh Vahadar)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2, Wis 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Perception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text>Your Intelligence and Charisma scores each increase by 1.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Accustomed to the night, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Keen Senses</name>
			<text>You have proficiency in the Perception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Elf Weapon Training</name>
			<text>You have proficiency with the longsword, shortsword, shortbow, and longbow.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Fey Ancestry</name>
			<text>You have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, and magic can't put you to sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Trance</name>
			<text>Elves don't need to sleep. Instead, they meditate deeply, remaining semiconscious, for 4 hours a day. (The Common word for such meditation is "trance.") While meditating, you can dream after a fashion; such dreams are actually mental exercises that have become reflexive through years of practice. After resting in this way, you gain the same benefit that a human does from 8 hours of sleep.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Elvish. Elvish is fluid, with subtle intonations and intricate grammar. Elven literature is rich and varied, and their songs and poems are famous among other races. Many bards learn their language so they can add Elvish ballads to their repertoires.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Cantrip</name>
			<text>You know one cantrip of your choice from the druid spell list. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for it.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Extra Language</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write one extra language of your choice.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race name="Vedalken (Kaladesh)" source="PS:K">
		<name>Vedalken (Kaladesh)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Int 2, Wis 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Intimidation</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text>Your ability scores each increase by 1.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Vedalken Cunning</name>
			<text>You have advantage on all Intelligence, Wisdom, and Charisma saving throws against magic.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Aether Lore</name>
			<text>Whenever you make an Intelligence (History) check related to magic items or aether-powered technological devices, you can add twice your proficiency bonus, instead of any proficiency bonus you normally apply.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Vedalken. The Vedalken language is renowned for its technical treatises and its catalogs of knowledge about the natural world and the aether that pervades it.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
</compendium>
