<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--Tal'dorei-->
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<monster>
		<name>Plainscow</name>
		<size>L</size>
		<type>beast, Tal'dorei Campaign Setting</type>
		<alignment>unaligned</alignment>
		<ac>13 (natural armor)</ac>
		<hp>42 (5d10 + 15)</hp>
		<speed>40 ft.</speed>
		<str>18</str>
		<dex>8</dex>
		<con>16</con>
		<int>2</int>
		<wis>10</wis>
		<cha>6</cha>
		<save></save>
		<skill>Insight +2</skill>
		<resist>bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing from nonmagical attacks</resist>
		<immune></immune>
		<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
		<vulnerable></vulnerable>
		<senses></senses>
		<passive>10</passive>
		<languages>—</languages>
		<cr>2</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Trampling Charge</name>
			<text>If the plainscow moves at least 20 feet straight toward a creature and then hits it with a hooves attack on the same turn, that target must succeed on a DC 14 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. If the target is prone, the plainscow can make another attack with its hooves as a bonus action.</text>
		</trait>
		<action>
			<name>Hooves</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage.</text>
			<attack>Hooves|6|2d6+4</attack>
		</action>
	</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Ashari Firetamer</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<type>humanoid (any race), Tal'dorei Campaign Setting</type>
		<alignment>neutral good</alignment>
		<ac>17 (red dragon scale mail)</ac>
		<hp>92 (16d8 + 20)</hp>
		<speed>30 ft.</speed>
		<str>8</str>
		<dex>15</dex>
		<con>14</con>
		<int>12</int>
		<wis>18</wis>
		<cha>11</cha>
		<save></save>
		<skill>Arcana +5, Nature +9</skill>
		<resist>fire</resist>
		<immune></immune>
		<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
		<vulnerable></vulnerable>
		<senses></senses>
		<passive>14</passive>
		<languages>Common, Druidic, Primordial (Ignan)</languages>
		<cr>7</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Flameform</name>
			<text>As a bonus action, the firetamer can transform into a  re elemental. While in this form, the firetamer cannot cast spells, but can expend a spell slot as a bonus action to regain 1d8 hit points per level of the spell slot expended. When the firetamer is reduced to 0 hit points, falls unconscious, or dies in this form, it reverts to its humanoid form. It can remain in flameform for up to 5 hours, and can enter  flameform twice, regaining expended uses after completing a short or long rest.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Spellcasting</name>
			<text>The firetamer is a 9th-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 16, +8 to hit with spell attacks). It has the following druid spells prepared:</text>
			<text>Cantrips (at will): druidcraft, mending, produce flame</text>
			<text>1st level (4 slots): cure wounds, faerie fire, longstrider, jump</text>
			<text>2nd level (3 slots): flame blade, heat metal, lesser restoration</text>
			<text>3rd level (3 slots): daylight, dispel magic, protection from energy</text>
			<text>4th level (3 slots): blight, freedom of movement, wall of fire</text>
			<text>5th level (1 slot): conjure elemental</text>
		</trait>
		<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
		<slots>4,3,3,3,1</slots>
		<spells>Druidcraft, Mending, Produce Flame, Cure Wounds, Faerie Fire, Longstrider, Jump, Flame Blade, Heat Metal, Lesser Restoration, Daylight, Dispel Magic, Protection from Energy, Blight, Freedom of Movement, Wall of Fire, Conjure Elemental</spells>
		<action>
			<name>Scimitar</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) slashing damage plus 14 (4d6) fire damage.</text>
			<attack>Scimitar|6|1d6+2+4d6</attack>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Flamecharm (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
			<text>The firetamer can cast dominate monster (save DC 16) on a fire elemental or other fire elemental creature. If the elemental has 150 or more hit points, it has advantage on the saving throw.</text>
		</action>
	</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Ashari Stoneguard</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<type>humanoid (any race), Tal'dorei Campaign Setting</type>
		<alignment>lawful neutral</alignment>
		<ac>15 (granite half plate)</ac>
		<hp>152 (16d8 + 80)</hp>
		<speed>30 ft.</speed>
		<str>18</str>
		<dex>10</dex>
		<con>20</con>
		<int>10</int>
		<wis>14</wis>
		<cha>9</cha>
		<save>Str +8, Con +9, Wis +6</save>
		<skill>Athletics +8, Intimidation +3</skill>
		<resist></resist>
		<immune></immune>
		<conditionImmune>petrified</conditionImmune>
		<vulnerable></vulnerable>
		<senses>tremorsense 30 ft.</senses>
		<passive>12</passive>
		<languages>Common, Druidic, Primordial (Terran)</languages>
		<cr>7</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Spellcasting</name>
			<text>The stoneguard is a 3rd-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 14, +6 to hit with spell attacks). It has the following druid spells prepared:</text>
			<text>Cantrips (at will): druidcraft, resistance</text>
			<text>1st level (4 slots): goodberry, speak with animals, thunderwave</text>
			<text>2nd level (2 slots): hold person, spike growth</text>
		</trait>
		<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
		<slots>4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		<spells>Druidcraft, Mending, Produce Flame, Cure Wounds, Faerie Fire, Longstrider, Jump, Flame Blade, Heat Metal, Lesser Restoration, Daylight, Dispel Magic, Protection from Energy, Blight, Freedom of Movement, Wall of Fire, Conjure Elemental</spells>
		<action>
			<name>Multiattack</name>
			<text>The stoneguard makes three granite maul attacks.</text>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Granite Maul</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +8 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 11 (2d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage. If the attack hits, the stoneguard may also immediately cast thunderwave as a bonus action. This casting uses a spell slot, but no material components.</text>
			<attack>Granite Maul|8|2d6+4</attack>
		</action>
		<reaction>
			<name>Sentinel</name>
			<text>When a creature within 5 feet of the stoneguard attacks a target other than the stoneguard, it can make a single attack roll against the attacker.</text>
		</reaction>
		<reaction>
			<name>Skin to Stone</name>
			<text>When the stoneguard is attacked, it may gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks until the end of the attacker’s turn.</text>
		</reaction>
	</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Ashari Waverider</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<type>humanoid (any race), Tal'dorei Campaign Setting</type>
		<alignment>neutral good</alignment>
		<ac>14 (hide armor of cold resistance)</ac>
		<hp>77 (14d8 + 14)</hp>
		<speed>30 ft.</speed>
		<str>15</str>
		<dex>14</dex>
		<con>12</con>
		<int>10</int>
		<wis>16</wis>
		<cha>13</cha>
		<save>Con +4, Wis +6</save>
		<skill>Athletics +8, Nature +3</skill>
		<resist>cold</resist>
		<immune></immune>
		<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
		<vulnerable></vulnerable>
		<senses></senses>
		<passive>13</passive>
		<languages>Common, Druidic, Primordial (Aquan)</languages>
		<cr>4</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Fishform</name>
			<text>As a bonus action, the waverider can transform into a hunter shark or giant octopus. While in this form, the waverider cannot cast spells, but can expend a spell slot as a bonus action to regain 1d8 hit points per level of the spell slot expended. When the waverider is reduced to 0 hit points, falls unconscious, or dies in this form, it reverts to its humanoid form. It can remain in fishform for up to 3 hours, and can enter fishform twice, regaining expended uses after completing a short or long rest.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Healing Tides</name>
			<text>Whenever the waverider casts a spell of 1st level or higher that affects a nonhostile creature, that creature regains 3 hit points (in addition to any healing the spell may provide).</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Marine Empathy</name>
			<text>The waverider can speak with and understand aquatic plants and animals.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Spellcasting</name>
			<text>The waverider is a 7th-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 14, +6 to hit with spell attacks). It has the following druid spells prepared:</text>
			<text>Cantrips (at will): druidcraft, poison spray, resistance</text>
			<text>1st level (4 slots): cure wounds, create or destroy water, healing word</text>
			<text>2nd level (3 slots): animal messenger, enhance ability, lesser restoration</text>
			<text>3rd level (3 slots): conjure animals (aquatic beasts only), water walk, water breathing</text>
			<text>4th level (1 slots): control water</text>
		</trait>
		<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
		<slots>4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		<spells>Druidcraft, Poison Spray, Resistance, Cure Wounds, Create or Destroy Water, Healing Word, Animal Messenger, Enhance Ability, Lesser Restoration, Conjure Animals, Water Walk, Water Breathing, Control Water</spells>
		<action>
			<name>Harpoon</name>
			<text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +5 to hit, reach 5 ft., range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d6 + 2) piercing damage. Attacks with this weapon while underwater are not made with disadvantage.</text>
			<attack>Harpoon|5|1d6+2</attack>
		</action>
	</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Ashari Skydancer</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<type>humanoid (any race), Tal'dorei Campaign Setting</type>
		<alignment>chaotic neutral</alignment>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<hp>63 (14d8)</hp>
		<speed>30 ft., fly 60 ft. (with skysail)</speed>
		<str>10</str>
		<dex>18</dex>
		<con>10</con>
		<int>12</int>
		<wis>16</wis>
		<cha>11</cha>
		<save>Dex +7</save>
		<skill>Acrobatics +7, Perception +6</skill>
		<resist></resist>
		<immune></immune>
		<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
		<vulnerable></vulnerable>
		<senses></senses>
		<passive>16</passive>
		<languages>Common, Druidic, Primordial (Auran)</languages>
		<cr>5</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Evasion</name>
			<text>If the skydancer is subjected to an effect that allows it to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, the skydancer instead takes no damage if it succeeds on the saving throw, and only half damage if it fails.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Flyby</name>
			<text>The skydancer doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks when it flies out of an enemy’s reach.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Skysail</name>
			<text>The skydancer flies with a special ashari weapon called a skysail (see pg. 45). While the skysail’s wings are extended, the skydancer can cast levitate at will, and can spend an action to cast fly on itself (no concentration required) for up to 1 minute once per day. This use of fly instantly replenishes when in an area of powerful air elemental magic, such as the Rift of Air in Zephrah.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Spellcasting</name>
			<text>The skydancer is a 3rd-level spellcaster. Its spellcasting ability is Wisdom (spell save DC 14, +6 to hit with spell attacks). It has the following druid spells prepared:</text>
			<text>Cantrips (at will): guidance, shillelagh</text>
			<text>1st level (4 slots): fog cloud, entangle, jump</text>
			<text>2nd level (2 slots): gust of wind, skywrite</text>
		</trait>
		<spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
		<slots>4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		<spells>Guidance, Shillelagh, Fog Cloud, Entangle, Jump, Gust of Wind, Skywrite</spells>
		<action>
			<name>Multiattack</name>
			<text>The skydancer makes two skysail staff attacks.</text>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Skysail Staff</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +7 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 7 (1d6 + 4) bludgeoning damage. If the skydancer makes this attack while flying, the target must make a DC 14 Dexterity saving throw, taking 21 (6d6) lightning damage on a failure or half as much damage on a success.</text>
			<attack>Skysail Staff|7|1d6+4</attack>
			<attack>Lightning||6d6</attack>
		</action>
		<reaction>
			<name>Slow Fall</name>
			<text>When the skydancer takes falling damage, it may reduce the damage by half.</text>
		</reaction>
	</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Clasp Cutthroat</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<type>humanoid (any race), Tal'dorei Campaign Setting</type>
		<alignment>any nonlawful alignment</alignment>
		<ac>14 (leather)</ac>
		<hp>44 (8d8 + 8)</hp>
		<speed>30 ft.</speed>
		<str>10</str>
		<dex>16</dex>
		<con>12</con>
		<int>8</int>
		<wis>14</wis>
		<cha>9</cha>
		<save>Dexterity +5</save>
		<skill>Deception +3, Stealth +7</skill>
		<resist></resist>
		<immune></immune>
		<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
		<vulnerable></vulnerable>
		<senses></senses>
		<passive>12</passive>
		<languages>Common, Thieves’ Cant</languages>
		<cr>3</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Cunning Action</name>
			<text>On each of its turns, the cutthroat can use a bonus action to take the Dash, Disengage, or Hide action.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Sneak Attack (1/Turn)</name>
			<text>The cutthroat deals an extra 14 (4d6) damage when it hits a target with a weapon attack and has advantage on the attack roll, or when the target is within 5 feet of an ally of the cutthroat that isn’t incapacitated and the cutthroat doesn’t have disadvantage on the attack roll.</text>
			<roll>4d6</roll>
		</trait>
		<action>
			<name>Multiattack</name>
			<text>The cutthroat makes two shortsword or dagger attacks.</text>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Shortsword</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 6 (1d6 + 3) piercing damage.</text>
			<attack>Shortsword|6|1d6+3</attack>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Dagger</name>
			<text>Melee or Ranged Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., range 20/60 ft., one target. Hit: 5 (1d4 + 3) piercing damage.</text>
			<attack>Dagger|6|1d4+3</attack>
		</action>
		<reaction>
			<name>Uncanny Dodge</name>
			<text>When an attacker that the cutthroat can see hits it with an attack, the cutthroat takes half damage instead.</text>
		</reaction>
	</monster>
	<monster>
		<name>Clasp Enforcer</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<type>humanoid (any race), Tal'dorei Campaign Setting</type>
		<alignment>any nonlawful alignment</alignment>
		<ac>16 (half plate)</ac>
		<hp>102 (12d8 + 48)</hp>
		<speed>30 ft.</speed>
		<str>16</str>
		<dex>12</dex>
		<con>18</con>
		<int>8</int>
		<wis>11</wis>
		<cha>14</cha>
		<save></save>
		<skill>Athletics +6, Intimidation +8</skill>
		<resist></resist>
		<immune></immune>
		<conditionImmune></conditionImmune>
		<vulnerable></vulnerable>
		<senses></senses>
		<passive>10</passive>
		<languages>Common, Thieves’ Cant</languages>
		<cr>5</cr>
		<trait>
			<name>Intimidating Presence</name>
			<text>Whenever the enforcer hits with a melee attack, the target must make a DC 15 Wisdom saving throw. On a failure, the target is frightened of the enforcer until the end of its next turn. The enforcer’s allies have advantage on attack rolls against creatures frightened in this way.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Second Wind (Recharges after a Short or Long Rest)</name>
			<text>As a bonus action, the enforcer can regain 12 hit points.</text>
		</trait>
		<action>
			<name>Multiattack</name>
			<text>The enforcer makes three warhammer attacks.</text>
		</action>
		<action>
			<name>Warhammer</name>
			<text>Melee Weapon Attack: +6 to hit, reach 5 ft., one target. Hit: 8 (1d10 + 3) bludgeoning damage.</text>
			<attack>Warhammer|6|1d10+3</attack>
		</action>
	</monster>
</compendium>
