<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" UA="Artificer">
	<subclass baseclass="Artificer">
		<name>Artificer (Gunsmith)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Artificer Specialist: Gunsmith (UA)</name>
				<text>A master of engineering, you forge a firearm powered by a combination of science and magic.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Gunsmith: Master Smith</name>
				<text>When you choose this specialization at 1st level, you gain proficiency with smith's tools, and you learn the mending cantrip.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Gunsmith: Thunder Cannon</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you forge a deadly firearm using a combination of arcane magic and your knowledge of engineering and metallurgy. This firearm is called a Thunder Cannon. It is a ferocious weapon that fires leaden bullets that can punch through armor with ease.</text>
				<text>You are proficient with the Thunder Cannon. The firearm is a two-handed ranged weapon that deals 2d6 piercing damage. Its normal range is 150 feet, and its maximum range if 500 feet. Once fired, it must be reloaded as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>If you lose your Thunder Cannon, you can create a new one over the course of three days of work (eight hours each day) by expending 100 gp worth of metal and other raw materials.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Gunsmith: Arcane Magazine</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you craft a leather bag used to carry your tools and ammunition for your Thunder Cannon. Your Arcane Magazine includes the powders, lead shot, and other materials needed to keep that weapon functioning.</text>
				<text>You can use the Arcane Magazine to produce ammunition for your gun. At the end of each long rest, you can magically produce 40 rounds of ammunition with this magazine. After each short rest, you can produce 10 rounds.</text>
				<text>If you lose your Arcane Magazine, you can create a new one as part of a long rest, using 25 gp of leather and other raw materials.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Gunsmith: Thundermonger</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you learn to channel thunder energy into your Thunder Cannon. As an action, you can make a special attack with your Thunder Cannon that deals an extra 1d6 thunder damage on a hit.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This extra damage increases by 1d6 when you reach certain levels in this class: 5th level (2d6), 7th level (3d6), 9th level (4d6), 11th level (5d6), 13th level (6d6), 15th level (7d6), 17th level (8d6), and 19th level (9d6).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Gunsmith: Blast Wave</name>
				<text>Starting at 9th level, you can channel force energy into your Thunder Cannon. As an action, you can make a special attack with it. Rather than making an attack roll, you unleash force energy in a 15-foot cone from the gun. Each creature in that area must make a Strength saving throw with a DC of 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier. On a failed saving throw, a target takes 2d6 force damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you.</text>
				<text>This damage increases by 1d6 when you reach certain levels in this class: 13th level (3d6) and 17th level (4d6).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Gunsmith: Piercing Round</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can shoot lightning energy through your Thunder Cannon. As an action, you can make a special attack with it. Rather than making an attack roll, you cause the gun to unleash a bolt of lightning, 5-feet wide and 30-feet long. Each creature in that area must make Dexterity saving throws with a DC of 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier. On a failed saving throw, a target takes 4d6 lightning damage.</text>
				<text>This damage increases to 6d6 when you reach 19th level in this class.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Gunsmith: Explosive Round</name>
				<text>Starting at 17th level, you can channel fiery energy into your Thunder Cannon. As an action, you can make a special attack with it. Rather than making an attack roll, you launch an explosive round from the gun. The round detonates in a 30-foot radius sphere at a point within range. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw with a DC of 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier. On a failed saving throw, a target takes 4d8 fire damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<item>
		<name>Thunder Cannon (Gunsmith Weapon)</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,2H,S</property>
		<range>150/500</range>
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<text>Special: Once fired, it must be reloaded as a bonus action.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Arcane Magazine (Gunsmith Item)</name>
		<type>G</type>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<text>An Arcane Magazine is a leather bag used to carry tools and ammunition for a Gunsmith's Thunder Cannon, which is capable of producing ammunition for the Thunder Cannon.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Thunder Cannon Round (Gunsmith Item)</name>
		<type>A</type>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<text>Ammunition for the Thunder Cannon.</text>
	</item>
	<spellList class="Artificer (Gunsmith)">
		<index name="Mending"/>
	</spellList>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Thunder Monger</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<range>150/500 feet</range>
		<components>M (Thunder Cannon)</components>
		<classes>Artificer (Gunsmith)</classes>
		<text>At 3rd level, you learn to channel thunder energy into your Thunder Cannon. As an action, you can make a special attack with your Thunder Cannon that deals an extra 1d6 thunder damage on a hit. This extra damage increases by 1d6 when you reach certain levels in this class: 5th level (2d6), 7th level (3d6), 9th level (4d6), 11th level (5d6), 13th level (6d6), 15th level (7d6), 17th level (8d6), and 19th level (9d6).</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>3d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
		<roll>5d6</roll>
		<roll>6d6</roll>
		<roll>7d6</roll>
		<roll>8d6</roll>
		<roll>9d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Blast Wave</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<range>15-foot cone</range>
		<components>M (Thunder Cannon)</components>
		<classes>Artificer (Gunsmith)</classes>
		<text>Starting at 9th level, you can channel force energy into your Thunder Cannon. As an action, you can make a special attack with it. Rather than making an attack roll, you unleash force energy in a 15-foot cone from the gun. Each creature in that area must make a Strength saving throw with a DC of 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier. On a failed saving throw, a target takes 2d6 force damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. This damage increases by 1d6 when you reach certain levels in this class: 13th level (3d6) and 17th level (4d6).</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>3d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Piercing Round</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<range>30 by 5 feet line</range>
		<components>M (Thunder Cannon)</components>
		<classes>Artificer (Gunsmith)</classes>
		<text>Starting at 14th level, you can shoot lightning energy through your Thunder Cannon. As an action, you can make a special attack with it. Rather than making an attack roll, you cause the gun to unleash a bolt of lightning, 5-feet wide and 30-feet long. Each creature in that area must make Dexterity saving throws with a DC of 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier. On a failed saving throw, a target takes 4d6 lightning damage. This damage increases to 6d6 when you reach 19th level in this class.</text>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
		<roll>6d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Explosive Round</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<range>150/500 feet</range>
		<components>M (Thunder Cannon)</components>
		<classes>Artificer (Gunsmith)</classes>
		<text>Starting at 17th level, you can channel fiery energy into your Thunder Cannon. As an action, you can make a special attack with it. Rather than making an attack roll, you launch an explosive round from the gun. The round detonates in a 30-foot radius sphere at a point within range. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw with a DC of 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier. On a failed saving throw, a target takes 4d8 fire damage.</text>
		<roll>4d8</roll>
	</spell>
</compendium>
