<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" UA="Artificer">
	<subclass baseclass="Artificer (UA)">
		<name>Artificer (Artillerist)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Artificer Specialist: Artillerist (UA)</name>
				<text>An Artillerist specializes in using magic to create explosions and defensive positions, as well as magic-infused sidearms—especially wands—that can be used on the battlefield. Artillerists were valued by all the armies of the Last War.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Artillerist: Tools of the Trade</name>
				<text>By the time you adopt this specialty at 3rd level, you're deeply familiar with employing its tools.</text>
				<text>	Proficiencies. You gain proficiency with smith's tools and woodcarver's tools, assuming you don't already have them. You also gain those tools for free—the result of tinkering you've done as you've prepared for this specialization.</text>
				<text>	In addition, you gain the ability to use rods, staffs, and wands as spellcasting focuses for your artificer spells. You also gain a nonmagical, wooden wand for free, which you've carved in your spare time.</text>
				<text>	Crafting. If you craft a magic item in the wand category, it takes you a quarter of the normal time, and it costs you half as much of the usual gold.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Artillerist: Artillerist Spells</name>
				<text>Starting at 3rd level, you always have certain spells prepared after you reach particular levels in this class, as shown in the Artillerist Spells table. These spells count as artificer spells for you, but they don't count against the number of artificer spells you prepare.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Artillerist Spells</text>
				<text>Artificer Level    Spell</text>
				<text>3rd                shield, thunderwave</text>
				<text>5th                scorching ray, shatter</text>
				<text>9th                fireball, wind wall</text>
				<text>13th               ice storm, wall of fire</text>
				<text>17th               cone of cold, wall of force</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Artillerist: Arcane Turret</name>
				<text>Arcane Turret</text>
				<text>At 3rd level, you learn how to create a magical  turret. With your smith's tools in hand, you can  take an action to magically summon a Medium  turret in an unoccupied space on a horizontal  surface within 5 feet of you.</text>
				<text>	The turret is a magical object that occupies its  space and that has crablike legs. It has an AC of  18 and a number of hit points equal to five times  your artificer level. It is immune to poison damage, psychic damage, and all conditions. If it  is forced to make an ability check or a saving  throw, treat all its ability scores as 10 (+0). If the  mending spell is cast on it, it regains 2d6 hit  points. It disappears if it is reduced to 0 hit  points or after 10 minutes. You can dismiss it  early as an action.</text>
				<text>	When you summon the turret, you decide  which type it is, choosing from the options on  the Arcane Turrets table. On each of your turns,  you can take a bonus action to cause the turret to  activate if you are within 60 feet of it. As part of  the same action, you can direct the turret to walk  or climb up to 15 feet to an unoccupied space.</text>
				<text>	You can summon a turret once for free and  must finish a long rest before doing so again. You  can also summon the turret by expending a spell  slot of 1st level or higher. If you summon a  second turret, the first turret disappears.</text>
				<text>	As an action, you can command your turret to  detonate if you are within 60 feet of it. Doing so  destroys the turret and forces each creature  within 10 feet of it to make a Dexterity saving  throw against your spell save DC, taking 3d6  force damage on a failed save or half as much  damage on a successful one.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Arcane Turrets</text>
				<text>Turret            Activation</text>
				<text>Flamethrower      The turret exhales fire in an adjacent 15-foot cone that you designate. Each creature in that area must make a Dexterity saving throw against your spell save DC, taking 1d8 fire damage on a failed save or half as much damage on a successful one. The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</text>
				<text>Force Ballista    Make a ranged spell attack, originating from the turret, at one creature or object within 120 feet of it. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 force damage, and if the target is a creature, it is pushed up to 5 feet away from the turret.</text>
				<text>Defender          The turret emits a burst of positive energy that grants itself and each creature of your choice within 10 feet of it a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d8 + your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Artillerist: Wand Prototype</name>
				<text>By 6th level, you now regularly experiment with channeling different types of magic through wands. Whenever you finish a long rest and your woodcarver's tools are with you, you can touch a nonmagical, wooden wand and turn it into a magic item. When you do so, you invest it with one artificer cantrip of your choice—even one you don't know—that has a casting time of 1 action. As an action, you can cause the magicwand to produce the cantrip, using your spellcasting ability modifier (other creatures are unable to use the wand's magic). The wand loses this magic when you finish your next long rest.</text>
				<text>	Any damage roll you make for a cantrip in the wand gains a bonus equal to your Intelligence modifier (minimum of +1).</text>
				<text>	When you reach 14th level in this class, you can invest the wand with two cantrips at the end of a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Artillerist: Fortified Position</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you're a master at conjuring a well-defended emplacement. You and your allies have half cover while within 10 feet of a turret you create with Arcane Turret, as a result of a shimmering field of magical protection that the turret emits.</text>
				<text>	You can also now summon a second turret for free and must finish a long rest before doing so again. If you summon the second turret while the first is still present, the first one doesn't disappear, and each turret can be of a different type (if you summon a third turret, the first turret vanishes). Moreover, you can use one bonus action to activate both turrets.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Artificer (Artillerist)">
		<index name="Shield"/>
		<index name="Thunderwave"/>
		<index name="Scorching Ray"/>
		<index name="Shatter"/>
		<index name="Fireball"/>
		<index name="Wind Wall"/>
		<index name="Ice Storm"/>
		<index name="Wall of Fire"/>
		<index name="Cone of Cold"/>
		<index name="Wall of Force"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
