<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Barbarian" HB="HB">
		<name>Barbarian (Harrier)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Primal Path: Path of the Harrier</name>
				<text>Barbarians channel their rage in many ways. For some, it brings about a near-mindless frenzy, an overpowering urge to slaughter. For others, it provides clarity, focus, and a drive to eliminate any obstacle that stands in their path. The Path of the Harrier leads to a place where barbarians can control their rage and focus it in constructive ways. Unlike many other barbarians, those who follow the Path of the Harrier favor ranged weapons, loosing missile after missile with frightening alacrity and accuracy.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of the Harrier: Deadly Focus</name>
				<text>When you choose this path at 3rd level, you focus your hatred on your enemy whenever you rage. While raging, you gain the following additional benefits:</text>
				<text>	• Targets of your ranged attacks do not bene t from bonuses to AC that originate from any cover less than total cover.</text>
				<text>	• Your speed increases by 10 feet if you aren't wearing heavy armor.</text>
				<text>	• When you make a ranged attack, you gain a bonus to the damage roll that increases as you gain levels as a barbarian, equal to the bonus in the Rage Damage column of the Barbarian table for your level.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of the Harrier: Ferocious Action</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, while you are raging, you can take a bonus action on each of your turns in combat to use either the Dash or Disengage action.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of the Harrier: Inflict Horrible Wound</name>
				<text>Beginning at 10th level, when you score a critical hit, you can forgo rolling one of the additional weapon damage dice from your Brutal Critical class feature to instead in ict a horrible wound upon the target creature. The target creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Dexterity modifier) or become maimed in some way—you take out one of its eyes, or lop o  a few fingers or perhaps an ear. The creature becomes stunned for 1 minute or until it takes damage. A creature stunned in this way can make a Wisdom saving throw at the start of its turn; if it succeeds it is no longer stunned.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Path of the Harrier: Bloody Murder</name>
				<text>When you reach 14th level, whenever you kill a creature within your reach while you are raging, you can use a bonus action to tear off the creature's head or some other body part and raise it in the air. Each creature within 30 feet of you that than can see and hear you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier) or be frightened until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
