<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Wizard" HB="HB">
		<name>Wizard (Reconstruction)</name>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Arcane Tradition: Reconstruction</name>
				<text>You focus your study on manipulating magic in a way that turns the destructive power of arcane evocation into rejuvenating magic. For others, this gift manifests from faith, a pledge to a patron, or a deity’s behest. Many arcane colleges have unlocked these regenerative powers from tireless hours poring over holy texts and alchemical manuals. While most wizards find outlets as talented enchanters, military artillery, or ward-makers, the students of this school could apply their versatility to any employment in nearly every setting, even that of an adventurer.</text>
			</feature>

			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Reconstruction: Creation Savant</name>
				<text>Beginning when you select this school at 2nd level, the gold and time you must spend to copy an evocation spell into your spellbook is halved.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you learn two cantrips and add one 1st- level spell to your spellbook from the cleric spell list. These spells are wizard spells for you, but other wizards can’t copy cleric spells from your spellbook into their own spellbooks.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Reconstruction: Applied Reconstruction</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can reverse the destructive force of your evocation spells, transforming their power into healing energy. When you cast an evocation spell of 1st level or higher that targets only one creature, with an instantaneous duration, and doesn’t require concentration, the target creature takes no damage and instead regains a number of hit points equal to half of the total.</text>
				<text>	If the spell requires you to make an attack roll or requires a creature to make a saving throw, the creature can choose to be hit or fail the saving throw. The spell doesn’t impose any status conditions.</text>
				<text>	Undead and constructs can't regain hit points in this way.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Reconstruction: Prolonged Regeneration</name>
				<text>Beginning at 6th level, when you cast a wizard spell that restores hit points, living creatures affected by the spell continues to regenerate over the next 1d4 rounds. The creature regains hit points equal to your Intelligence modi er at the start of its turn, provided it has at least 1 hit point remaining.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, while a creature is regenerates in this way, it‘s immune to disease and poison. If the creature is currently diseased or poisoned, any effects are suspended for the duration of its regeneration.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Reconstruction: Blossom of Life</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can focus the healing energies around certain pockets within the effects of your evocation spells. When you cast an evocation spells that affects other creatures that you can see, you can choose a number of them equal to 1 + the spell’s level to impose an e ect that uses your wizard’s spell save DC. The chosen creatures automatically succeed on their saving throws and take no damage from the spell. They also regain hit points equal to half the damage the spell would have dealt. Undead and constructs can't regain hit points in this way.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>School of Reconstruction: Overheal</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, you can increase the power of your simpler spells. When you cast a wizard spell of 5th level or lower that restores hit points, you can maximize the healing power of that spell.</text>
				<text>	The first time you do so, you suffer no adverse effect. If you use this feature again before you finish a long rest, you take 1d12 necrotic damage for each level of the spell, immediately after the healing affect occurs. Each time you use this feature again before finishing a long rest, the necrotic damage per spell level increases by 1d12. This damage ignores resistance and immunity.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, you choose four spells from the cleric spell list to add to your spellbook, one from each of the following levels: 2nd, 3rd, 4th, 5th. These spells are wizard spells for you, but other wizards can’t copy cleric spells from your spellbook into their own spellbooks.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

	</subclass>
</compendium>
