<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
<!--Strongholds and Followers-->
<item>
	<name>Grace</name>
	<type>M</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<weight>3</weight>
	<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
	<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
	<dmgType>S</dmgType>
	<property>V</property>
	<rarity>Rare</rarity>
	<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text>The blade of this longsword seems to glow white, like it is a beam of light hammered into the shape of a sword. Its hilt is gold-plated and has three embedded sapphires. This longsword has a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls. Additionally, it gains one charge whenever an attack made with it deals more than 20 damage in a single blow. It can hold up to 3 charges, but all unused charges disappear when you take a long rest.</text>
	<text>	While the sword holds any charges, it radiates bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an extra 20 feet. As an action, you can expend any number of charges to restore hit points to a creature you can touch with the sword’s blade. Expending 1 charge restores 10 hit points, expending 2 charges restores 20 hit points, and expending 3 charges restores 40 hit points.</text>
	<text></text>
	<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
	<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
	<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Armor of St. Gaed the Confessor</name>
	<type>HA</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<weight>65</weight>
	<ac>18</ac>
	<strength>15</strength>
	<stealth>YES</stealth>
	<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
	<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
	<text>Requires Attunement</text>
	<text>This set of magic plate mail covered in silver filigree grants +1 Armor Class to the wearer. Also, once per month, the owner can summon the spirits of the Blue Dragon Phalanx to aid them in battle. The Phalanx serves for 1 hour or two battles, whichever happens first.</text>
	<text>	The spirits of the Blue Dragonflight will fight your enemies, but if ordered to do anything other than fight in a battle against an enemy army, they stand around looking confused, wondering what’s happened to their bodies and the world they once knew.</text>
	<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Potion of Enhance Ability</name>
	<type>P</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<weight></weight>
	<rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
	<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
	<text>Starts as a basic gray potion with no effect. However, if a material component is added, it gains one of the following effects:</text>
	<text>Potion of Bear’s Endurance. You gain 2d6 temporary hit points and have advantage on Constitution checks for 1 hour. Requires a hair from a bear.</text>
	<roll>2d6</roll>
	<text>Potion of Bull’s Strength. You have advantage on Strength checks and your carrying capacity doubles for 1 hour. Requires a tail-hair from a bull.</text>
	<text>Potion of Cat’s Grace. You have advantage on Dexterity checks and do not take damage from falling up to 20 feet while you are not incapacitated for 1 hour. Requires a cat’s claw.</text>
	<text>Potion of Eagle’s Splendor. You have advantage on Charisma checks for 1 hour. Requires an eagle’s feather.</text>
	<text>Potion of Fox’s Cunning. You have advantage on Intelligence checks for 1 hour. Requires a fox’s whisker.</text>
	<text>Potion of Owl’s Wisdom. You have advantage on Wisdom checks for 1 hour. Requires an owl’s feather.</text>
</item>
<item>
	<name>Wound</name>
	<type>M</type>
	<magic>1</magic>
	<weight></weight>
	<rarity>Rare</rarity>
	<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
	<text>Requires Attunement by a barbarian</text>
	<text>The wicked edge of this serrated greataxe is permanently coated in dried blood.</text>
	<text>	This greataxe has a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls. Also, while you are raging, your attacks with this weapon deal an extra 2d6 necrotic damage, and the target’s maximum hit points are decreased in equal amount to the necrotic damage dealt. The target’s hit point maximum does not return to normal until it finishes a long rest or its grievous wounds are soothed by a greater restoration spell.</text>
	<roll>2d6</roll>
	<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
	<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
</item>
</compendium>