<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<!--Strongholds and Followers-->
	<item>
		<name>Grace</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>The blade of this longsword seems to glow white, like it is a beam of light hammered into the shape of a sword. Its hilt is gold-plated and has three embedded sapphires. This longsword has a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls. Additionally, it gains one charge whenever an attack made with it deals more than 20 damage in a single blow. It can hold up to 3 charges, but all unused charges disappear when you take a long rest.</text>
		<text>	While the sword holds any charges, it radiates bright light in a 20-foot radius and dim light for an extra 20 feet. As an action, you can expend any number of charges to restore hit points to a creature you can touch with the sword’s blade. Expending 1 charge restores 10 hit points, expending 2 charges restores 20 hit points, and expending 3 charges restores 40 hit points.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Armor of St. Gaed the Confessor</name>
		<type>HA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>65</weight>
		<ac>18</ac>
		<strength>15</strength>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>This set of magic plate mail covered in silver filigree grants +1 Armor Class to the wearer. Also, once per month, the owner can summon the spirits of the Blue Dragon Phalanx to aid them in battle. The Phalanx serves for 1 hour or two battles, whichever happens first.</text>
		<text>	The spirits of the Blue Dragonflight will fight your enemies, but if ordered to do anything other than fight in a battle against an enemy army, they stand around looking confused, wondering what’s happened to their bodies and the world they once knew.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Potion of Enhance Ability</name>
		<type>P</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Starts as a basic gray potion with no effect. However, if a material component is added, it gains one of the following effects:</text>
		<text>Potion of Bear’s Endurance. You gain 2d6 temporary hit points and have advantage on Constitution checks for 1 hour. Requires a hair from a bear.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<text>Potion of Bull’s Strength. You have advantage on Strength checks and your carrying capacity doubles for 1 hour. Requires a tail-hair from a bull.</text>
		<text>Potion of Cat’s Grace. You have advantage on Dexterity checks and do not take damage from falling up to 20 feet while you are not incapacitated for 1 hour. Requires a cat’s claw.</text>
		<text>Potion of Eagle’s Splendor. You have advantage on Charisma checks for 1 hour. Requires an eagle’s feather.</text>
		<text>Potion of Fox’s Cunning. You have advantage on Intelligence checks for 1 hour. Requires a fox’s whisker.</text>
		<text>Potion of Owl’s Wisdom. You have advantage on Wisdom checks for 1 hour. Requires an owl’s feather.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Wound</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement by a barbarian</text>
		<text>The wicked edge of this serrated greataxe is permanently coated in dried blood.</text>
		<text>	This greataxe has a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls. Also, while you are raging, your attacks with this weapon deal an extra 2d6 necrotic damage, and the target’s maximum hit points are decreased in equal amount to the necrotic damage dealt. The target’s hit point maximum does not return to normal until it finishes a long rest or its grievous wounds are soothed by a greater restoration spell.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Altar of Unyielding Faith</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Installation</text>
		<text>Install this altar in your temple and choose a row on the Servitors chart (page 31). Whenever you roll on this chart, you may choose the chart entry one higher than the result you rolled.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Candles of Accord</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Installation</text>
		<text>This pair of red wax candles burn magically without consuming fuel, symbolizing the alliance between the two holders of the candles. If one candle is lit without the other, it merely provides normal candlelight indefinitely, and extinguishing it does not affect the other candle.</text>
		<text>	If both candles are lit together by the owner of an establishment, the owner can give the other candle to an ally and extend the area of the owner’s Gather Intel ability (page 36) to include their ally’s demesne. When used in this way, extinguishing either candle snuffs out the other one immediately.</text>
		<text>	Gathering Intel using a candle of accord requires meditating for 1 hour with the candle, concentrating on the ally and their territory. At the end of this hour, the owner may make a Gather Intel check, which if successful gives them a vision of the organization they are spying on.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Terragnosis</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Written by Hierophant Prithviraña in the 738th year of the Age of Wonders, this book is a comprehensive treatise on the nature of the Mundane World and the material and philosophical principles that set it apart from Arcadia, Quintessence, and the World Below.</text>
		<text>	This codex illuminates the Law of Nature, the Law of Time, and the Law of Death and contains a description of the world's creation, the origins of divine and arcane magic, as well as the War Between the Gods.</text>
		<text>	The Hierophant built his wisdom and knowledge into the codex terragnosis. The book binds and shapes the world, defines it and defends it. While it resides within this manifold of the timescape, the Mundane World is safe.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The Barrier Between Worlds</text>
		<text>While this book resides in the Mundane World, sending a native of this plane to another plane, unwillingly, requires a saving throw.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Steward of the Earth</text>
		<text>As an action once per day, you can summon an elemental of your choice to do your bidding. After 1 hour, the elemental returns to its home plane.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Stone and Sea, Obey Me</text>
		<text>As an action once per day, you can cast cataclysm.</text>
		<text>	Cataclysm (battle magic): Target: 4 units, Attack: +12, Power: +15. Enemy units damaged by this attack must make a DC 15 Morale save or decrement their casualty die twice.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Defender of All the Earth</text>
		<text>Once, a druid who holds the codex terragnosis may assume the form of the phoenix. This form lasts until sunrise or sunset, whichever comes first, at which point the phoenix dies in a flare of brilliant light. The druid must make a Constitution save against DC 18 to survive the conflagration. The codex terragnosis itself survives the conflagration and, regardless of whether the druid lives, relocates itself somewhere safer, and the Defender of all the Earth ability recharges.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Umbra</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Kalidasa Dhar, writing in the codex umbra in the second century of Wonder, gives us our only glimpse into scholarly thought regarding the essence of shadow magic before the Ganarajyan Empire. It is surprisingly similar to our own modern notions.</text>
		<text>“Primitive cultures view shadow magic as an extension of literal shadow. The shade cast by a bright light. But I find no connection between the two phenomenon and o er an alternate explanation, supported by the success of the incantations found herein.”</text>
		<text>	Dhar hypothesized that the dark power we call shadow is the dead life essence of a previous world. What the nature of this world or the beings that may have inhabited it was, she offers no insight. Few modern sages take Dhar’s theory seriously, but all note that no wizard since has penetrated the heart of shadow so successfully.</text>
		<text>	Whoever holds the codex umbra and understands its secrets gains access to the following abilities.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The Vile Form</text>
		<text>Once per day as an action, you can assume the form of a dark shadow of yourself. While in this form, you gain resistance to acid, cold, fire, lightning, thunder, bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage, including damage from magical weapons. To assume this form, you must sacrifice 1 Hit Die at the end of each round.</text>
		<text>	You are always considered to be hiding, and you gain advantage on attacks in vile form.</text>
		<text>	If you fall unconscious while in vile form, you revert to your normal form. If you die while in vile form, you become a shadow and the codex disappears, relocating itself to elsewhere in the Mundane World.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>No Man Can Escape His Shadow</text>
		<text>Once per day as an action, you can summon 6 shadows, placing each anywhere within 60 feet of you, and each must be adjacent to a character. The shadows act on your turn, doing your bidding. They dissolve after 1 minute.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Shadow Tower</text>
		<text>Once per year as an action, you can summon a round spire made of solid darkness. The tower is 30 feet in diameter and 40 feet high with windows on all sides and a battlement on top. The interior is divided into three floors, with a spiral staircase on the inner wall connecting them. The stairs end at a trapdoor leading to the roof. When summoned, the tower side facing you has a door proportional to your size. The door will only open on your command, which you can speak as a bonus action. Magic of less than 7th level will not open the door.</text>
		<text>	Each creature in the area where the tower appears must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 12d10 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. All creatures in the area are pushed to an unoccupied space outside but next to the tower. Objects in the area are pushed automatically.</text>
		<text>	The sky above the tower is always dark, and the tower itself is made of substantial shadow and melds with the ground, preventing it from being tipped over. The roof, door, and walls each have 90 hit points, immunity to damage from nonmagical weapons except siege weapons, and resistance to all other damage. It cannot be repaired, but can be dismissed as an action. The next time the tower is summoned, it is complete and free of damage.</text>
		<text>	The tower is a 2nd-level tower stronghold and grants units defending it +1 Morale.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Shadow Legion</text>
		<text>Once per week as an action, the holder of the codex umbra can summon a Shadow Legion. The legion dis- solves after 1 hour or two battles, whichever comes first.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Black Star</text>
		<text>Completing this 1-hour ritual replaces the sun with a negative counterpart. The sun winks out and darkness rules the land—a land dominated by a blazing black sun in a sky filled with red stars.</text>
		<text>	This is a supernatural darkness, and all intelligent creatures who live on the surface of the Mundane World can sense it. All diurnal creatures with an Intelligence score greater than 5 gain darkness sensitivity, giving them disadvantage on attack rolls and Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight. As the owner of the codex umbra, you do not suffer this sensitivity. However, while the Black Star blazes, you must sacrifice 1 Hit Die at the end of each hour.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Incabulum</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The only codex known to be written during the Caelian Empire, the codex incabulum is often incorrectly cited as the cause of the Fall of Azshan. This is a popular guess repeated so often that it has attained the status of fact. Rather, the codex stopped the demonic infestation that razed the ruling city of Kham, confining the sea of fiends that erupted from hell and preventing it from spreading across the world. As a result, no contemporaneous accounts of the sack of the city survive, with the popular histories of the event being authored no earlier than 150 years after the event.</text>
		<text>	Authored by Marcus Gaius Orestes in the 101st year of the Age of Conquest, during the height of the Caelian Empire, this book—like all the codices—has been lost and found many times over the centuries since. Often those who attune to it delve deep into dark powers and are lost.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Demon Soul</text>
		<text>As an action, you can sacrifice 3 Hit Dice to assume the form of a Type III demon or a bone devil, replacing your own stats and abilities with the fiend’s. While in this form, you do not benefit from your original race or class abilities, but you can cast your spells normally if you assume a form that can cast spells.</text>
		<text>	You can maintain this form for 1 hour or until you drop unconscious, after which you revert to your original form, and can heal the sacrificed damage and hit points normally.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Damnation</text>
		<text>Demons and devils automatically fail their saving throws against banish cast by you.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Scion of Seven Cities</text>
		<text>After performing a ritual for 10 minutes, you can open a gate to one of the Seven Cities of Hell, allowing you to freely travel there from the Mundane World. Only you can use this gate. It remains open until you return through it, after which it closes.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Flames of Hell</text>
		<text>Once per week as an action, you may sacrifice Hit Dice to summon a Legion of Hell. This unit’s size depends on the number of Hit Dice you sacrificed, as follows.</text>
		<text>Hit Dice  Sacrificed Size of Unit</text>
		<text>2         1d4</text>
		<text>4         1d6</text>
		<text>6         1d8</text>
		<text>8         1d10</text>
		<text>10        1d12</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The Key to the Gate</text>
		<text>While the codex incabulum is on the Mundane World, summoned demons and devils cannot summon more demons or devils. Should the Book of Fiends ever leave the Mundane World, however, this restriction would be lifted, and then even minor demons could gate in powerful allies, who themselves could gate in more allies, until armies of demons flooded the world.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Automata</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Written by the Hànz wizard Huang Fei late in the third dynasty of the Xin Empire, the codex automata—The Book of Machines—synthesized three thousand years of scholarly thought on the subject of magical constructs and was instantly realized as the definitive work on the subject. Other tomes detail the process of creating a golem, but Fei called this “mere smithery.”</text>
		<text>	Fei’s goal was to understand the fundamental magic of animated constructs, and in this he succeeded beyond his wildest dreams. His golem army defended the emperor and secured his dynasty’s rule for a thou- sand years.</text>
		<text>“Now we shall see, Huang Fei! We shall end all debate. Here! Now! Let the scales weigh my power against yours, and the world will know which is greater! Your machine mind...or my supreme sorcery!”</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Machine Mind</text>
		<text>You gain magic resistance</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Walking Tower</text>
		<text>Once per year as an action, you can summon a tall square tower made of metal and gears. The tower is 20 feet on a side and 60 feet high, with windows on all sides and a battlement on top. The tower has six mechanical legs, granting it a movement speed of 24 miles per day. The interior is divided into five floors connected by an automated moving staircase on the inner wall. The stairs end at a trapdoor leading to the roof. When summoned, the tower side facing you has a door proportional to your size. The door will only open on your command, which you can speak as a bonus action. Magic of less than 7th level will not open the door.</text>
		<text>	Each creature in the area where the tower appears must make a DC 13 Dexterity saving throw, taking 13d8 bludgeoning damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. All creatures in the area are pushed to an unoccupied space outside but next to the tower. Objects in the area are pushed automatically.</text>
		<text>	The tower is made of metal. The roof, door, and walls each have 300 hit points, immunity to damage from nonmagical weapons except siege weapons, and resistance to all other damage. It cannot be repaired, but can be dismissed as an action. The next time the tower is summoned, it is complete and free of damage.</text>
		<text>	An automated ballista protrudes from each wall, granting the tower an Attack: 12, Power: 14 attack in battles.</text>
		<text>	The tower counts as a tower stronghold, and it grants units defending it +2 Morale.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Iron Company</text>
		<text>Once per month, as an action you can summon the Iron Company, a unit of iron golems. The Iron Company rusts after 1 hour or two battles, whichever comes first.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Machine Lieutenant</text>
		<text>By spending 1 week in a laboratory worth at least 1,000 gp, you can produce a machine lieutenant. You can only have one lieutenant at a time. It is loyal to you and obeys your commands, but it will not willingly move more than 30 feet away from you. If it is ever more than 30 feet away, the lieutenant shuts down and awaits your return.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Master of Golems</text>
		<text>No construct will attack you. As an action, you can make a Command check against a construct within 30 feet by rolling 1d20 and adding your Wisdom bonus + 2. If the result is greater than the construct’s Hit Dice, then the construct is yours to command, as though you were its creator.</text>
		<text>	This control lasts 1 hour, after which the construct is free of your influence and cannot be commanded again in this way.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Dryadalis</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>A human adopted as an infant by elves, Irllyn Ffwllyg en Orrell ce Yth went on to become the Ganarajyan Empire’s greatest authority on the fae, their magic, and their casual association with cause and effect.</text>
		<text>	Because she was a mortal wizard, she understood the rules that constrained the use of magic. Because she was raised as an elf, she had the mind of a fae. Because she was the greatest wizard of her time, she was able to synthesize these two antithetical philosophies into one coherent masterwork and thereby change the world forever. The elves never allowed this again.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The World for World is Wode</text>
		<text>After spending 1 year in a tower while in a forest, the forest transforms into a wode. This transformation is gradual, and if you leave the forest during this period the forest reverts to its original state. Once the transformation is complete, you can attract elven units as though you were an elf, and the wode begins to disobey cause and effect.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you exit your wode, you can choose to emerge from any other wode. Likewise, you can access your tower’s wode from any wode.</text>
		<text>	Furthermore, when exiting your wode, you can choose to emerge in any age in the past or future. Returning to your own time is tricky and usually requires entering another wode.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>To Serve Us</text>
		<text>After spending 1 year in study in a tower in a wode, you choose a pack of seven mundane beasts of the same species, raising their Intelligence score to 11 and all other attribute scores to 10 or more. They become Medium bipedal creatures and gain the Sylvan language.</text>
		<text>	The wode is their home, but they are under no compulsion to remain in it, though they do prefer it. They are your followers, and like all followers they are independent creatures with their own will.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The Inconsequent</text>
		<text>You cease aging and no longer need to sleep. You cannot be charmed, and magic cannot put you to sleep. You are immune to the effects of slow and time stop. You are immune to the effects of the chronos codex.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Motivate Trees</text>
		<text>Once per month as an action, you can transform a copse of trees into a unit of treants. The treants serve you for 1 hour or two battles, whichever happens first, after which they root back into the ground and become normal trees again.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Miror</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Written by Durthara, the Empress’s Archmage, the Book of Wonder is the first recorded codex and gave the Age of Wonder its name. In those days, the Ganarajyan Empire’s word for “magic” translated as “wonder” or “marvel.” Magic, then, was newly discovered by Men and seemed a limitless resource. Spells were invented, made fashionable, and forgotten before anyone knew they could be written down.</text>
		<text>	History records the codex miror as the greatest, the most powerful of the codices, but no sage has ever owned more than two, so no one in history could claim to be an expert, and most of the records of what the Book of Wonder could do were written hundreds of years after it disappeared.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Sorcerer Supreme</text>
		<text>You learn, prepare, and cast spells as though you were four levels higher. You learn these new spells immedi- ately upon attuning to the codex. Multiclass characters choose from among their highest-level spellcasting classes. You can prepare any spell from the bard, wizard, sorcerer, or warlock spell list.</text>
		<text>	Your spells cannot be resisted.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Master of Magic</text>
		<text>On initiative count 30, you know if any enemies are casting spells on the current turn and which spells they’re casting.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Bound to the Book of Marvels</text>
		<text>Write your True Name into the book. While you are attuned to the book, you have advantage on saving throws against spells. If you lose the book, and some- one speaks your True Name in your presence, you lose this benefit and you have disadvantage on saving throws to resist spells cast by the magic-user who spoke your True Name.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Book of Wonder</text>
		<text>The codex miror remembers a time when magic was much...friskier. Whenever you cast a spell on a creature, there’s a 5% chance one of the following effects occurs (determined randomly).</text>
		<text/>
		<text>D100    RESULT</text>
		<text>01–04   The target loses all hair and clothes.</text>
		<text>05–08   A pit, 10 feet deep and 10 feet wide, opens under the target’s feet.</text>
		<text>09–12   The target has advantage on attack rolls for the next 3 rounds.</text>
		<text>13–17   Fifty bats appear, swarm around your head for 1 round, then flit away.</text>
		<text>18–21   The target grows wings. if it already has wings, its wings transform into tentacles.</text>
		<text>22–25   You are surrounded by a cage, 10 feet on each side, of solid iron bars.</text>
		<text>26–30   Each piece of headgear within 30 feet (including helmets) transforms into a skullcap topped with a bladed device that turns in any breeze.</text>
		<text>31–35   The target’s skin turns paisley permanently.</text>
		<text>36–40   All gold within 10 feet of you transmutes into lead.</text>
		<text>41–45   The target is completely covered in an inch-thick coat of honey. also, 500 bees arrive.</text>
		<text>46–49   Every time the target speaks, the following music plays: (https://flat.io/score/5c1396a35e87c23257ad5965-mcdm-codex-miror-sheet-music?sharingKey=dacf2982723e7f3d0475877fa17b16b3cec6ec44385cca4b366867e54fdde956b82befecbf92bb988859b4184c39c4f00d7bb0158b513ca0e4f01cf1ef3810e6)</text>
		<text>50–54   A small cottage falls on you, dealing 8d10 damage. you are pinned under the house with only your feet sticking out.</text>
		<text>55–59   Rotting fish shower down within 100 feet of the target for 6 seconds.</text>
		<text>60–63   You are polymorphed into a centaur.</text>
		<text>64–67   All weapons within 60 feet turn into bunches of flowers.</text>
		<text>68–71   Summon a hippopotamus (01–10), elephant (11–80), or mouse (81–100).</text>
		<text>72–76   A sperm whale drops from the sky onto the target.</text>
		<text>77–80   You grow by half.</text>
		<text>81–84   You shrink by half.</text>
		<text>85–89   The target becomes permanently invisible.</text>
		<text>90–93   The target is polymorphed into a willow tree.</text>
		<text>94–97   14–85 gems with a base value of 1 gp pour from the target’s nose over the next hour.</text>
		<text>98–99   The target is affected by a flesh to stone spell.</text>
		<text>100     If the target has fewer than 100 hit points, it explodes.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Ignis</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Hu Tai was the last Magister of Fire, and like her contemporaries, the other four elemental magisters, she swore to bind her knowledge into a tome and thereby seal it away, ending the Century of Five Emperors and the wars that ensued as each emperor’s elemental magister used their lore to warp and twist reality for their regent.</text>
		<text>	History records that her efforts were successful. The Five Magisters sealed their power away, and the wars ended. Only rarely in the thousands of years since has one of the five elemental codices emerged and been mastered, and never more than one has been active in the world since.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Magister of Fire</text>
		<text>Your fire spells and cantrips deal their maximum damage. Also, whenever you cast a spell that deals fire damage, there’s a 50% chance you do not use a spell slot. You are immune to fire damage.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Fire Armor</text>
		<text>You are always protected by an invisible fire shield spell. Whenever you take damage from a melee attack, your fire armor erupts in flame, revealing itself and dealing damage to the attacker in equal amount to the damage taken (instead of 2d8).</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Ward of Fire</text>
		<text>Whenever you are surprised in combat, a fire elemental immediately arrives and acts on initiative count 20. It attacks your enemies, putting your safety first, obeying your orders second. It remains in the Mundane World for 1 minute, after which it returns to Quintessence.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Sea of Fire</text>
		<text>Once per day as an action, you can cast sea of fire.</text>
		<text>	Sea of Fire (battle magic): Target: 3 units, Attack: +13, Power: +13. Enemy units damaged by this attack suffer a Power: +11 check on your next round.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Blazing Form</text>
		<text>By staring into a fire and concentrating on a distant location no larger than a castle, you sense all large (as big as a fireplace or larger) fires there. You can see and hear as if you were the fire.</text>
		<text>	Also, once per week you can project an illusory duplicate of yourself into the fire. As an action, you can move this blazing duplicate up to your speed, but it can only move to places illuminated by the fire from which it emerged. You can cast your spells originating from your duplicate.</text>
		<text>	You can make your duplicate gesture, speak, and behave in any way you yourself could. You can see and hear through this duplicate, and you can switch between using its senses and yours as a bonus action. While you’re using its senses, your own body is blind and deaf.</text>
		<text>	The duplicate is insubstantial and has no hit points. It lasts for a number of rounds equal to your Intelligence bonus, after which it evaporates.</text>
		<text>	While deploying this form, you must sacrifice 1 Hit Die at the end of each round.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Chronos</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Like the codex multiversalis, the origins of the chronos codex are not well recorded. Its earliest reference is in the possession of the Ganarajyan wizard Subhadrangi, who may also be the book’s author. The book is also referenced in the Tales of Rupananda, but it’s possible Subhadrangi and Rupananda were the same woman. A handful of references talk of a sage who went by both names during that age, but there’s no direct confirmation from any contemporary source, and no source definitively claims either women wrote it or indeed gives an independent account of the life of either.</text>
		<text>	The Book of Time is the least well known of the codices. It tends to disappear for millennia at a time, and as a result, unlike the other Books of Magic, scholars are happy to leave it drifting in the eddies of the time stream.</text>
		<text>	It was only 300 years ago when the Khoursir scholar Chartam suggested that the book’s author had not yet been born, and that the book’s presence in the past of this time manifold is a result of its future author using its power. This once-fringe hypothesis has grown in popularity in recent years.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Summon Temporal Duplicate</text>
		<text>Once per month as an action, you can summon a version of yourself from the future. It is one possible version of your future character. It has your stats but is four levels higher and may have different items or even spells, at your GM’s discretion.21 You have no control over your temporal duplicate, but it is a version of you and will probably help you out. Because it is from one possible future, it is experiencing one possible past and may not remember the situation it finds itself in, because it never experienced this past.</text>
		<text>	The duplicate remains in this manifold of the timescape for 4 + 1d4 rounds, after which it returns to its own time. If it drops to 0 hit points, it automatically returns—unconscious—to its original manifold.</text>
		<text>	While you are attuned to the book, the GM may ask you to make a percentile roll at random moments. If you roll a 100, you disappear for 4 + 1d4 rounds, as you are relentlessly pulled backward into an alternate past to serve a version of yourself four levels lower.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Nomad of the Timescape</text>
		<text>You cease aging. As an action once per year, you may sacrifice any number of Hit Dice to move forward or backward in time by a hundred years per Hit Die sacrificed. You can observe and interact with, but cannot change, the past or future. Because of the manifold nature of the timescape, the past or future you find yourself in may not be your past or future.</text>
		<text>	While in another temporal manifold, you sacrifice 1 Hit Dice at the end of each week.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Clockwise</text>
		<text>Once per month as an action, choose a mortal enemy you can see within 60 feet. It must make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or instantly advance into extreme old age. Its Strength, Constitution, and Dexterity are permanently halved. Because it gained no new experiences, its mental stats do not change. This effect can be reversed by a greater restoration spell cast within 24 hours of the time shift.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Jaunt</text>
		<text>As a bonus action, choose a target and a number from one to six. If the target is willing, it is removed from the time stream and will reappear on initiative count 20 that number of rounds later. If it is unwilling, it can make a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw to resist.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Blink of an Eye</text>
		<text>As an action, you can sacrifice any number of Hit Dice to take an equal number of turns in a row.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Mortis</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Exiled Empress Wu Jiao wasted no time planning her return to the throne and the restoration of the Wu dynasty. Her first goal was the return of her greatest general, the barbarian Lady Czorgan. As Czorgan was dead, this meant much research was in order. But Empress Jiao was already an accomplished wizard, and her first success took less than a year.</text>
		<text>	Emboldened by her necromantic research and the return of her right hand, Jiao pressed her study further and became the greatest necromancer in history. She succeeded in restoring her family to the throne, but history calls her the Dead Empress and her second period of rule the Dead Empire, granting her no narrative of restoration, only revenge.</text>
		<text>	Attuning to this dread book requires sacrificing 2 Hit Dice.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Unlife</text>
		<text>Reading the Book of Death does not make you undead, but you quickly develop an affinity for the deathless. Your visage and demeanor change, becoming cold and pale. You gain the following attributes:</text>
		<text>	Life Drain. Whenever you deal melee damage, the target must make a DC 13 Constitution saving throw or its hit point maximum is reduced in equal amount to the damage taken.</text>
		<text>	This reduction lasts until the target finishes a long rest. The target dies if this effect reduces its hit point maximum to 0. A humanoid slain by this attack rises 24 hours later as a zombie under your control, unless the humanoid is restored to life or its body is destroyed.</text>
		<text>	Sunlight Sensitivity. While in sunlight, you have disadvantage on attack rolls and on Wisdom (Percep- tion) checks that rely on sight.</text>
		<text>	Undead Fortitude. If damage would reduce you to 0 hit points, you may make a Constitution saving throw with a DC of 5 plus the damage taken, unless the damage is radiant or from a critical hit. On a success, you drop to 1 hit point instead.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Legion of the Dead</text>
		<text>Once per month as an action, you can summon a Legion of the Dead. They remain under your control for 3 days or six battles, whichever comes first.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Lady Czorgan</text>
		<text>As an action, you may sacrifice 2 Hit Dice and summon Lady Czorgan, the Death Knight. Lady Czorgan is a being of hatred and resentment who claws at the power of the Book that binds her, but she must obey you. You must concentrate to maintain Lady Czorgan’s presence in this world, which is limited to 1 hour, after which she returns to the Abyss and will not return for a month.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Master of Death</text>
		<text>You automatically command any undead of less than 9 HD you meet or summon. Mastering undead is automatic for you and does not require an action. These undead obey your commands and serve you faithfully until they are destroyed. Up to 50 HD of undead can be mastered in this way.</text>
		<text>	Once an undead is mastered, it may not be replaced until it is destroyed.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Codex Multiversalis</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Artifact</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Attuning to a Codex</text>
		<text>All the codices require attunement, which requires the reader to spend a month in uninterrupted study of no less than 8 hours per day and 48 hours six days per week.</text>
		<text>	Once attuned, the owner of the codex need not take the book with them. They can leave it in a secure location and still gain its benefits, but must refresh their knowledge through 8 hours of uninterrupted study once per month or else lose its benefits.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Certainly the first Wizard to enter history as an owner of the Book of All Worlds was Padmavati, the Alienist. But there’s no actual record of her writing it, though scholarly consensus is that only she could have done so. Instead, the accepted wisdom is that she did write it, just not in this manifold. She is from a different world, sages presume. The truth may never be known. The deeds she performed are well-documented, including enacting The Forbidding which permanently exiled the Demon Lord of Death to the Seven City of Hells. If the nature of this ritual is detailed in the codex multiversa- lis no Wizard since has deciphered it.</text>
		<text>	Attuning to the Book of All Worlds exposes you to the energies of a million worlds. This turns your eyes solid black. It does not damage your sight, but you are marked for as long as you stay attuned to the book.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Sight Beyond Sight</text>
		<text>You immediately sense the direction, distance, and nature of any being summoned to the Mundane World of 9 HD or greater within thousand-mile radius. As an action, you can teleport to the site of the summoning within one minute of sensing it. You cannot use this ability again for 24 hours.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Traveler</text>
		<text>Once per day as an action, you can name a location you are familiar with in another world,23 and travel there.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Alienist</text>
		<text>As an action you can banish any creature not native to the plane you are on, sending them back to their plane of origin without a saving throw.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>No Barrier Between</text>
		<text>As an action once per day, you can summon any creature from any row of the Servitors chart. They are free agents, not bound to serve you, and they return to their point of origin after 1 hour.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Diplomat's Pouch</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>A letter placed in this pouch, addressed to someone who owns another diplomat’s pouch, disappears, and the recipient listed in the letter finds a copy of it in their pouch. A letter can be listed to multiple recipients with a diplomat’s pouch.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Disruptor</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a chaotic creature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>If you are a neutral character, this dull grey longsword functions as a normal weapon with no bonus or special properties. If you are lawful, touching Disruptor deals 2d8 necrotic damage to you. If you are a chaotic character, you can use Disruptor as a magic weapon with the following properties.</text>
		<text>	You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon. This bonus increases to +3 against lawful creatures. If an attack with Disruptor reduces a creature to 0 hit points, their chest bursts open and their organs spill out.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you score a critical hit with Disruptor, roll a d6 on the Court of All Flesh row of the Servitors chart (page 31). The critical hit lops a limb off the enemy’s body, and the rolled servitor spawns from the severed flesh. This servitor fights for you and obeys your commands. They return to Morphosis after 1 minute or if they drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Foxglove Bow</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value/>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,H,2H</property>
		<range>150/600</range>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a chaotic creature</text>
		<text>If you are a neutral character, this ash longbow functions as a normal weapon with no bonus or magical properties. If you are lawful, touching this weapon deals 2d8 radiant damage to you. If you are chaotic, you can use the foxglove bow as a magic weapon with the following properties.</text>
		<text>	Arrows nocked in this bow begin to drip with poison. All arrows fired from this bow deal poison damage in addition to piercing damage.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you score a critical hit with this bow, roll a d6 on the Court of Arcadia row of the Servitors chart (page 31). Foxglove flowers begin to fall like rain, and the rolled servitor appears behind the target. This servitor fights for you and obeys your commands. They return to Arcadia after 1 minute or if they drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons" later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Glory</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>4</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement by a good creature</text>
		<text>If you are a neutral character, this steel mace functions as a normal weapon with no bonus or special properties. If you are evil, touching this weapon deals 2d8 radiant damage to you. If you are a good character, you can use Glory as a magic weapon with the following properties.</text>
		<text>	You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon, which deals radiant damage in addition to bludgeoning damage. While wielding Glory, you glow with faint light.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you score a critical hit with Glory, roll a d6 on the Celestial Court row of the Servitors chart (page 31). Radiant light floods the battlefield and an angelic chorus begins to play. When the light dissipates, the rolled servitor stands next to you. This servitor fights for you and obeys your commands. They return to their plane after 1 minute or if they drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Sickle</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value/>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d4</dmg1>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>L</property>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement by an evil creature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>If you are a neutral character, this reaping tool functions as a normal weapon with no bonus or special properties. If you are good, touching Harvest deals 2d8 necrotic damage to you. If you are an evil character, you can use this sickle as a magic weapon with the following properties.</text>
		<text>	You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. This bonus increases to +3 against good creatures. If you reduce a living, mortal creature to 0 hit points, you regain 1d8 hit points.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you score a critical hit, roll a d6 on the Undead row of the Servitors chart (page 31). A bell tolls and the rolled servitors burst from the ground. These undead fight for you and obey your commands. The undead turn to dust after 1 minute or if they drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Glaive of Warning</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>6</weight>
		<dmg1>1d10</dmg1>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>H,R,2H</property>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Each time you attack, you choose whether it deals fire, cold, or lightning damage in addition to its normal slashing damage.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you score a critical hit, roll a d6 on the Court of Elements row of the Servitors chart (page 31). A tear opens to the elemental plane of Quintessence and the rolled servitor steps through. This servitor fights for you and obeys your commands. They return to Alloy, the Burning City, after 1 minute or if they drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<text>	The glaive has a large brass blade on the end of a teak shaft with elemental runes carved into it. The runes glow faintly in the presence of an extraplanar being.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Reach: This weapon adds 5 feet to your reach when you attack with it.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Mantle of Regency</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>This billowing red cloak has a mind of its own. It grants the user 30 feet of fly (hover) speed while worn. As an action, the owner can summon the mantle to them, though how long it takes to arrive depends on how far away it is (it flies much faster when not being worn).</text>
		<text>	You are a much more impressive figure while wearing the mantle. You have advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks, and whenever you roll on a follower chart, you can select any result within 10% of your roll.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Obey</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a lawful creature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>If you are a neutral character, this crystal longsword functions as a normal weapon with no bonus or special properties. If you are chaotic, touching Obey deals 2d8 force damage to you. If you are a lawful character, you can use Obey as a magic weapon with the following properties.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. When this weapon strikes a magic-user concentrating on a spell, their concentration is broken and they are knocked prone.</text>
		<text>	When you score a critical hit, roll a d6 on the Inexorables row of the Servitors chart (page 31). A glowing white door opens in front of you, the rolled servitor steps through, and the door vanishes. This servitor fights for you and obeys your commands. They return to Axiom after 1 minute or if they drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<text>	If this weapon strikes a member of the Court of All Flesh, they are immediately returned to Primordius.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Psionic Crystal</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>Chipped off the hide of a gemstone dragon, this crystal grants you psionic abilities depending on its size. It recharges upon completing a long rest. If you ever use the last charge, it turns into an inert precious stone.</text>
		<text>Size     Example    Charges    Recharge    Manifestations</text>
		<text>Small    a coin     8          1d4         Amplify, Flay, Distance</text>
		<text>Medium   an apple   12         1d6         Amplify, Distance, Flay, Forget, Sympathy</text>
		<text>Large    a bowl     16         1d8         Amplify, Distance, Flay, Forget, Mindscape, Reflection, Sympathy</text>
		<text>Huge     a pumpkin  24         1d10        Amplify, Believe, Distance, Elsewhere, Flay, Forget, Mindscape, Reflection, Sympathy</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Sword of the Demon Knight</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by an evil creature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>If you are a neutral character, this jagged longsword functions as a normal weapon with no bonus or special properties. If you are good, touching Sir Malcoda’s blade deals 2d8 necrotic damage to you. If you are an evil character, you can use the sword of the demon knight as a magic weapon with the following properties.</text>
		<text>	You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. Wielding this weapon with two hands causes it to glow with red light, shedding bright light for 20 feet and dim light for an extra 20 feet. Once per day, the wielder can cause the sword to flash a baleful, blinding red light. Lawful good creatures within 30 feet must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or be blinded for 1 round.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you score a critical hit, roll a d6 on the Demons row of the Servitors chart (page 31). Demonic runes appear on the ground and the rolled servitor appears from the shadows. This servitor fights for you and obeys your commands. They return to the Abyss after 1 minute or if they drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<text>	The demonic eye on the sword’s cross-guard focuses intently on any lawful good creature within 30 feet.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Spymaster's Cloak</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Uncommon</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>People who meet you tend to forget you. Gather Intel checks have disadvantage against anyone wearing this fine grey cloak.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Surveyor’s Compass</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>A compass of dwarven origin. Above the north marking of the compass is a small receptacle. Once per season, placing a piece of ore or precious stone into it causes the needle on the compass to point toward the nearest seam containing that material within 12 miles. This seam holds ore and gems worth 4d4 x 100 gp, and mining the seam takes three weeks.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Tapestry of Reweaving</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Installation</text>
		<text>This magnificent tapestry at first appears to display a scene depicting life in the local area. The threads are expensively dyed, and real gold and silver are woven into it, giving it brilliant colors and incredibly fine detail. Expressions can be made out on the tiny faces of any people living nearby.</text>
		<text>	Watching the tapestry closely reveals it is not an idyllic depiction of a time gone by—it is live. It shows what is actually happening around the area in which it is installed. It is impossible to detect motion while looking at it, however—one only notices change when looking away and then looking back.</text>
		<text>	If found uninstalled, the tapestry depicts a scene from wherever it was last installed, and it does not change its scene until it is installed again.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>The Tyrants's Twinblades, Vincere and Punire</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<rarity>Very Rare</rarity>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>F,L</property>
		<text>Rarity: Very Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement by an evil character</text>
		<text>If you are a neutral character, these black iron shortswords function as normal weapons with no bonus or special properties. If you are good, touching either weapon deals 2d8 necrotic damage to you. If you are an evil character, you can use Vincere and Punire as magic weapons with the following properties.</text>
		<text>	You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with these magic weapons. Once per round, if both blades strike a single foe, they deal an extra 1d6 fire damage.</text>
		<text>	When you score a critical hit with either blade, roll a d6 on the Devils row of the Servitors chart (page 31). Flames burst from the ground and the rolled servitor appears. This servitor fights for you and obeys your commands. They return to Hell after 1 minute or if they drop to 0 hit points.</text>
		<text>	If this weapon strikes a demon, it shackles it and pulls it down to Hell, removing it from the battle.</text>
		<text>Finesse: When making an attack with a finesse weapon, you use your choice of your Strength or Dexterity modifier for the attack and damage rolls. You must use the same modifier for both rolls.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Light: A light weapon is small and easy to handle, making it ideal for use when fighting with two weapons.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Velorin's Laboratory</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Installation</text>
		<text>This elaborate laboratory contains everything a magic-user needs to research new spells. The inks, papers, flasks, pipettes, tinctures, and rare ingredients are worth 10,000 gp and can be packed into two large trunks.</text>
		<text>	When installed in a tower, this laboratory allows the owner to adjust their result up or down by one when rolling on a research chart page 24).</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Whispering Stone of Warning</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight/>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Installation</text>
		<text>You may stare intently at the closed eye carved into this stone and repeatedly whisper a creature type or alignment to the stone for 10 minutes. The stone’s eye opens and displays that name in runic text upon its pupil. If any creature of that type or alignment enters your demesne, the stone whispers to you, warning you of its presence. You can hear this whisper across any distance, but only if you are on the plane as the stone. After a season, the rune begins to fade. You can replace the creature type or alignment the stone warns against by performing the ritual again.</text>
	</item>
</compendium>
