<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<!--Tal'dorei-->
	<item>
		<name>Skysail</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight></weight>
		<rarity>Rare</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>These bat-like wings affixed to a pole are constructed out of either bone and leather or wood and cloth. While these wings are opened and the rung of the pole stepped into, you can use an action to cast levitate on yourself at will.</text>
		<text>	Additionally, you can use an action to cast fly on yourself for up to 1 minute (no concentration required). The fly spell ends if you lose physical contact with the skysail. You cannot use this ability again until you complete a long rest, or you (and the Skysail) are immersed in extremely powerful air elemental magic, such as the top of the Summit Peaks near the Rift of Air in Zephrah, or within the Elemental Plane of Air. When not in use, these wings can be easily folded together and worn beneath a cloak, and the pole used as a quarterstaff.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Oloore Root</name>
		<type>G</type>
		<magic></magic>
		<weight></weight>
		<rarity></rarity>
		<text>Oloore Root began as a druidic ceremonial tool for vision quests and communion with nature, but has become sought after by high society for its psychedelic properties. Drinking of the tea brewed from the root leads to heavy hallucinations, and sometimes grants insight to the world around them.</text>
		<text>	The imbiber must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 14) or become poisoned for 1d4 hours. Upon a success, the imbiber gains advantage on any Wisdom ability checks for 1 hour. On a saving throw of 19 or 20, the imbiber gains supernatural distance seeing, as though they had cast a scrying spell. They may Concentrate on this for up to 1 minute. (Valued at around 100 gp per dose.)</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Zeal</name>
		<type>G</type>
		<magic></magic>
		<weight></weight>
		<rarity></rarity>
		<text>Zeal is distilled from the blood of captured or slain quaggoth deep from beneath the surface of Exandria. When brewed properly, a thick, purple-colored liquid that tastes of ash remains.</text>
		<text>	Drinking zeal or applying liberally to exposed skin (requiring an action) forces the user to make a Constitution saving throw (DC 12) or become paralyzed for 1d4 rounds as every muscle seizes up. With a success, the user deals an additional 3 damage to any target it hits with a melee attack for 2d6 rounds. THe user suffers 1 point of exhaustion after the effect ends, regardless of saving throw success. (valued at around 150 gp per dose)</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Suude</name>
		<type>G</type>
		<magic></magic>
		<weight></weight>
		<rarity></rarity>
		<text>Suude is a dangerous, granular substance refined from magic residuum. Initially developed during the Age of Arcanum by archmages as an incense burned to enhance long spell ritual casting, the secret was discovered and spread among the spellcasting riffraff of Exandria. The varying forms of refinement are dangerous, and can produce one of three different types of suude.</text>
		<text>	When burned and the fumes inhaled (requiring an action), the imbiber must make a Constitution saving throw (DC 10) or become unconscious for 2d4 rounds. With a success, the user gains 1 Sorcery Point and access to one Metamagic option (as per the Sorcerer class Font of Magic and Metamagic features) for 1 hour based on the type of suude used. If more than one dose of suude is used within 1 hour of another, the DC of the Constitution saving throw is increased by 3 per additional dose. If three or more doses are used within 1 hour of each other, failing the Constitution saving throw drops the user to 0 hit points. Brown suude grants the Extended Spell option, Blue suude grants the Twinned Spell option, and Red suude grants the Distant Spell option. (valued at around 80 gp per dose)</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Graz’tchar, The Decadent End</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic></magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>6</weight>
		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>H,2H</property>
		<rarity>A</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Artifact</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>This blade appears to be a beautiful cruciform sword of shining silver, inlaid with sparkling rubies.
			<text>You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this magic weapon. It has the following properties.</text>
			<text>Corrosive Submission</text>
			<text>When you hit a humanoid with this weapon, you may force it to take an additional 3d6 acid damage and it must make a DC 14 Charisma saving throw. On a failure, the creature is charmed by you for up to 1 hour. If you attack the creature again while charmed, the acid damage increases to 10d6 and the charm ends. It cannot be charmed again for 24 hours after the charm is ended in this way.</text>
			<text>Hidden Nature</text>
			<text>The acid damage dealt by this greatsword appears to be radiant damage; Any creature who is successfully charmed by it is under the illusion that the damage to it was merely an admonishing jostle. A true seeing spell or similar reveals that this sword is actually a rusted, pitted blade dripping with acid.</text>
			<text>Sentience</text>
			<text>Graz’tchar is a sentient evil weapon with an Intelligence of 14, a Wisdom of 12, and a Charisma of 18. It has hearing and darkvision out to a range of 120 feet.  e weapon can speak, read, and understand Common, and can communicate with its wielder telepathically.  ose who hold it hear the wise voice of a sorrowful king, beckoning the user to seize their destiny.</text>
			<text>Personality</text>
			<text>Graz’tchar slowly attempts to sway the character into sowing chaos in Tal’Dorei, telling lies about great leaders, claiming that the heads of the Tal’Dorei Council are corrupt and must be overthrown. The voice of this blade is actually the Demon Prince of Indulgence, speaking from his Abyssal prison. Should the wielder continue to disobey the urges of the weapon for an extended period of time, it can attempt to charm the wielder. They must make a Charisma saving throw (DC 14). On a success, they are immune to the sword’s charm for 24 hours. Upon a failure, they become charmed by the sword for 24 hours. During this time, the sword can force the character to take an action of its choice once an hour, the wielder accepting this action as their own will. Should the chosen action lead to the harm of a non-hostile creature or ally, the charm immediately breaks.</text>
		</text>
		<roll>3d6</roll>
		<roll>10d6</roll>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Dynamite</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<value>50</value>
		<range>30</range>
		<dmg1>4d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType></dmgType>
		<magic></magic>
		<weight></weight>
		<rarity></rarity>
		<text>4d6 fire damage to all creatures and objects in 20 foot radius (DC 12 Dexterity save for half), detonates at the start of the thrower’s next turn after 6-second fuse</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Glue Bomb</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<range>30</range>
		<value>50</value>
		<magic></magic>
		<weight></weight>
		<rarity></rarity>
		<text>Creatures within 20 foot radius must make a DC 12 Strength or Dexterity saving throw (target’s choice) or be restrained. A creature may make another DC 12 Strength check as an action to escape.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Stink bomb</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<range>30</range>
		<value>25</value>
		<magic></magic>
		<weight></weight>
		<rarity></rarity>
		<text>Creatures within 20 foot radius must make a DC 12 Constitution saving throw or be poisoned for 1d6 rounds, detonates after 6-second fuse</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Wind glider</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<value>200</value>
		<magic></magic>
		<weight></weight>
		<rarity></rarity>
		<text>Requires 1 minute to harness. While harnessed and falling, the bearer falls at 30 feet per round, and the wind glider carries the bearer 40 feet in a line each round until they land. You can change direction each round. While harnessed, your movement is halved, and you have disadvantage on attack rolls. A wind glider has an AC of 10, and 5 hit points.</text>
	</item>
	<!--Vestiges of Divergence-->
	<item>
		<name>Agony</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-good character</text>
		<text>Utilized in countless tortures and slow executions, the hooked chains of this brutal weapon still smell of dried blood and rot. You gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</text>
		<text>	When you hit with an attack using this weapon, and that creature was injured with this weapon on your previous attack, you deal an additional 1d6 piercing damage.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Agony (Awakened)</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-good character</text>
		<text>Utilized in countless tortures and slow executions, the hooked chains of this brutal weapon still smell of dried blood and rot. You gain a +3 bonus to damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</text>
		<text>	When you hit with an attack using this weapon, and that creature was injured with this weapon on your previous attack, you deal an additional 1d8 piercing damage.</text>
		<text>	When a creature is damaged by this weapon, they suffer disadvantage on Strength ability checks until the beginning of your next turn.</text>
		<text>	When you drop a creature to 0 hit points with an attack using Agony, you can immediately make an additional melee attack with this weapon as a bonus action.</text>
		<roll>1d8</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +3</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Agony (Exalted)</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-good character</text>
		<text>Utilized in countless tortures and slow executions, the hooked chains of this brutal weapon still smell of dried blood and rot. You gain a +4 bonus to damage rolls made with this magic weapon.</text>
		<text>	When you hit with an attack using this weapon, and that creature was injured with this weapon on your previous attack, you deal an additional 2d6 piercing damage.</text>
		<text>	When a creature is damaged by this weapon, they suffer disadvantage on Strength ability checks until the beginning of your next turn.</text>
		<text>	When you drop a creature to 0 hit points with an attack using Agony, you can immediately make an additional melee attack with this weapon as a bonus action.</text>
		<text>	When you score a critical hit with this weapon, the target must make a DC 17 Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you for 1 minute. If this saving throw is successful, not only does the target not become frightened, they become immune to this frightening e ect for the next 24 hours.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +4</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +4</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Armor of the Valiant Soul</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>45</weight>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This antique armor forged from jade and black dragon scales was once owned and worn by J’mon Sa Ord of Ank’Harel. You have a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor.</text>
		<text>	You can cast the command spell (save DC 13) while attuned to this armor. You cannot use this ability again until you have completed a long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Armor of the Valiant Soul (Awakened)</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>45</weight>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This antique armor forged from jade and black dragon scales was once owned and worn by J’mon Sa Ord of Ank’Harel. You have a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor.</text>
		<text>	You can cast the command spell (save DC 15) while attuned to this armor. You cannot use this ability again until you have completed a long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain resistance to acid damage while wearing this armor.</text>
		<text>	You gain immunity to the frightened condition while wearing this armor.</text>
		<text>	The spell save DC of the armor’s command spell becomes DC 15, and it can target two additional creatures.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Armor of the Valiant Soul (Exalted)</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>45</weight>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This antique armor forged from jade and black dragon scales was once owned and worn by J’mon Sa Ord of Ank’Harel. You have a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor.</text>
		<text>	You can cast the command spell (save DC 17) while attuned to this armor. You cannot use this ability again until you have completed a long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain immunity to acid damage while you are wear- ing this armor.</text>
		<text>	You gain immunity to the frightened condition while wearing this armor. Your immunity to the frightened condition extends to include all friendly creatures within 15 feet, as long as you are conscious.</text>
		<text>	The spell save DC of the armor’s command spell becomes DC 17, and it can target four additional creatures.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Cabal's Ruin</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This cloak of dark leather and gold trim seems to occasionally shimmer with small sparks of blue energy across the shadowed lining. This cloak has 4 charges, and regains 1d4 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
		<text>	When you are targeted by an enemy’s spell, you can use your reaction to have the cloak swallow part of the spell. The cloak gains a number of charges equal to the spell level of the triggering spell. You are still subject to whatever effects the spell would normally inflict on you. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	When you hit with an attack, you can choose to expend any number of charges from the cloak, dealing an additional 1d6 lightning damage per charge expended, which is inflicted on the target of that attack. If your attack strikes multiple targets, you must choose one target from the group to be subject to this damage.</text>
		<roll>1d4</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Cabal's Ruin (Awakened)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This cloak of dark leather and gold trim seems to occasionally shimmer with small sparks of blue energy across the shadowed lining. This cloak has 6 charges, and regains 1d4+2 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
		<text>	When you are targeted by an enemy’s spell, you can use your reaction to have the cloak swallow part of the spell. The cloak gains a number of charges equal to the spell level of the triggering spell. You are still subject to whatever effects the spell would normally inflict on you. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	When you hit with an attack, you can choose to expend any number of charges from the cloak, dealing an additional 1d6 lightning damage per charge expended, which is inflicted on the target of that attack. If your attack strikes multiple targets, you must choose one target from the group to be subject to this damage.</text>
		<text>	You gain advantage on all saving throws against spells and other magical effects while wearing this cloak.</text>
		<text>	When using the cloak’s ability to swallow a spell, you gain resistance to the damage of that spell.</text>
		<roll>1d4+2</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Cabal's Ruin (Exalted)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This cloak of dark leather and gold trim seems to occasionally shimmer with small sparks of blue energy across the shadowed lining. This cloak has 10 charges, and regains 1d6+4 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
		<text>	When you are targeted by an enemy’s spell, you can use your reaction to have the cloak swallow part of the spell. The cloak gains a number of charges equal to the spell level of the triggering spell. You are still subject to whatever effects the spell would normally inflict on you. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	When you hit with an attack, you can choose to expend any number of charges from the cloak, dealing an additional 1d6 lightning damage per charge expended, which is inflicted on the target of that attack. If your attack strikes multiple targets, you must choose one target from the group to be subject to this damage.</text>
		<text>	You gain advantage on all saving throws against spells and other magical effects while wearing this cloak.</text>
		<text>	When using the cloak’s ability to swallow a spell, you gain resistance to the damage of that spell.</text>
		<roll>1d6+4</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Circlet of Barbed Vision</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-good character</text>
		<text>Upon wearing this circlet of gnarled onyx, black barbs dig into your head, imparting power as it twists your appearance to amuse the Spider Queen. While wearing this circlet, your Charisma score decreases by 2. You also have advantage on initiative rolls.</text>
		<text>	When you make an attack roll, you can use your reaction to gain a +5 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma -2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Circlet of Barbed Vision (Awakened)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-good character</text>
		<text>Upon wearing this circlet of gnarled onyx, black barbs dig into your head, imparting power as it twists your appearance to amuse the Spider Queen. While wearing this circlet, your Charisma score decreases by 2. You also have advantage on initiative rolls.</text>
		<text>	When you make an attack roll, you can use your reaction to gain a +5 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You also gain resistance to poison damage, and gain immunity to the poisoned condition.</text>
		<text>	Your ability to gain a bonus to an attack roll can be used twice between rests.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma -2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Circlet of Barbed Vision (Exalted)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-good character</text>
		<text>Upon wearing this circlet of gnarled onyx, black barbs dig into your head, imparting power as it twists your appearance to amuse the Spider Queen. While wearing this circlet, your Charisma score decreases by 2. You also have advantage on initiative rolls.</text>
		<text>	When you make an attack roll, you can use your reaction to gain a +5 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain immunity to poison damage in addition to the poisoned condition.</text>
		<text>	Your ability to gain a bonus to an attack roll can be used twice between rests.</text>
		<text>	You can also see invisible creatures and objects.</text>
		<text>	Your ability to gain a bonus to an attack roll can be used three times between rests.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma -2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Condemner</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>18</weight>
		<dmg1>1d10</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,H,LD,2H</property>
		<range>100/400</range>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Type: Heavy Crossbow</text>
		<text>This shadow-touched hand crossbow once served as the weapon of choice for the legendary assassin Todora. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls made with this weapon. When you hit with an attack using this weapon, the target takes an additional 1d4 poison damage.</text>
		<text>	If you hit with an attack using this weapon, instead of dealing damage, you can choose one of two effects to trigger: A fog cloud spell centered on the target, or a silence spell centered on the target. You can use each effect once, and cannot use them again until you finish a short rest.</text>
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons" later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Loading: Because of the time required to load this weapon, you can fire only one piece of ammunition from it when you use an action, bonus action, or reaction to fire it, regardless of the number of attacks you can normally make.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<roll>1d4</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Condemner (Awakened)</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>18</weight>
		<dmg1>1d10</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,H,LD,2H</property>
		<range>100/400</range>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Type: Heavy Crossbow</text>
		<text>This shadow-touched hand crossbow once served as the weapon of choice for the legendary assassin Todora. You have a +2 bonus to attack rolls made with this weapon. When you hit with an attack using this weapon, the target takes an additional 1d6 poison damage.</text>
		<text>	If you hit with an attack using this weapon, instead of dealing damage, you can choose one of following effects to trigger: A fog cloud spell centered on the target, a silence spell centered on the target, or the target can be affected by a hold person spell (spell save DC 15). You can use each effect once, and cannot use them again until you finish a short rest.</text>
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons" later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Loading: Because of the time required to load this weapon, you can fire only one piece of ammunition from it when you use an action, bonus action, or reaction to fire it, regardless of the number of attacks you can normally make.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Condemner (Exalted)</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>18</weight>
		<dmg1>1d10</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,H,LD,2H</property>
		<range>100/400</range>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Type: Heavy Crossbow</text>
		<text>This shadow-touched hand crossbow once served as the weapon of choice for the legendary assassin Todora. You have a +3 bonus to attack rolls made with this weapon. When you hit with an attack using this weapon, the target takes an additional 1d8 poison damage.</text>
		<text>	If you hit with an attack using this weapon, instead of dealing damage, you can choose one of following effects to trigger: A fog cloud spell centered on the target, a silence spell centered on the target, the target can be affected by a hold person spell (spell save DC 17), or the blight spell (spell save DC 17). You can use each effect once, and cannot use them again until you finish a short rest.</text>
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons" later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Loading: Because of the time required to load this weapon, you can fire only one piece of ammunition from it when you use an action, bonus action, or reaction to fire it, regardless of the number of attacks you can normally make.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<roll>1d8</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +3</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Deathwalker's Ward</name>
		<type>LA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>13</weight>
		<ac>12</ac>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This beautiful, black leather armor is covered in intricate scrollwork, the mantle bearing the black feathers of the Matron of Ravens. You gain a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor. You have advantage on death saving throws made while wearing this armor.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Deathwalker's Ward (Awakened)</name>
		<type>LA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>13</weight>
		<ac>12</ac>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This beautiful, black leather armor is covered in intricate scrollwork, the mantle bearing the black feathers of the Matron of Ravens. You gain a +2 bonus to AC while wearing this armor. You have advantage on death saving throws made while wearing this armor.</text>
		<text>	While wearing this attuned armor, the wearer chooses and imbues this armor with resistance to a damage type of your choice: fire, cold, acid, lightning, or necrotic. This choice can be changed during a short rest.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Deathwalker's Ward (Exalted)</name>
		<type>LA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>13</weight>
		<ac>12</ac>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This beautiful, black leather armor is covered in intricate scrollwork, the mantle bearing the black feathers of the Matron of Ravens. You gain a +3 bonus to AC while wearing this armor. You have advantage on death saving throws made while wearing this armor.</text>
		<text>	While wearing this attuned armor, the wearer chooses and imbues this armor with resistance to a damage type of your choice: fire, cold, acid, lightning, or necrotic. This choice can be changed during a short rest.</text>
		<text>	As a bonus action, you can grow large, black raven wings. These last for 1 hour, and grant a fly speed of 60 feet. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Fenthras</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,H,2H</property>
		<range>150/600</range>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This gorgeous longbow made of everbark from the Feywild seems to flex and shift like a living entity. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</text>
		<text>When firing an arrow from this weapon, you can declare an oracle shot, allowing you to project your sight through the arrow you fire for up to 10 minutes. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short rest.</text>
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons" later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ranged attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">ranged damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Fenthras (Awakened)</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,H,2H</property>
		<range>150/600</range>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This gorgeous longbow made of everbark from the Feywild seems to flex and shift like a living entity. You gain a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</text>
		<text>When firing an arrow from this weapon, you can declare an oracle shot, allowing you to project your sight through the arrow you fire for up to 10 minutes. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short rest.</text>
		<text>	When a creature is killed by an arrow from this weapon, a single 6-ft tree rapidly grows out of their corpse over the next minute.</text>
		<text>	Additionally when you hit with an attack using this weapon, the target takes an additional 1d4 lightning damage.</text>
		<text>	When you hit with an attack, you can declare a bramble shot. The target takes an additional 3d8 piercing damage, and they must make a DC 15 Strength saving throw or become restrained by the suddenly sprouting steel-hard thorn brambles that immediately grow from the arrow. The restrained target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons" later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<roll>1d4</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">ranged attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">ranged damage +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Fenthras (Exalted)</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmgType>P</dmgType>
		<property>A,H,2H</property>
		<range>150/600</range>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>This gorgeous longbow made of everbark from the Feywild seems to flex and shift like a living entity. You gain a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</text>
		<text>When firing an arrow from this weapon, you can declare an oracle shot, allowing you to project your sight through the arrow you  re for up to 10 minutes. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short rest.</text>
		<text>	When a creature is killed by an arrow from this weapon, a single 6-ft tree rapidly grows out of their corpse over the next minute.</text>
		<text>	Additionally when you hit with an attack using this weapon, the target takes an additional 1d6 lightning damage.</text>
		<text>	When you hit with an attack, you can declare a bramble shot. The target takes an additional 3d8 piercing damage, and they must make a DC 17 Strength saving throw or become restrained by the suddenly sprouting steel-hard thorn brambles that immediately grow from the arrow. The restrained target can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on a success. You can use this ability twice between rests.</text>
		<text>Ammunition: You can use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a ranged attack only if you have ammunition to fire from the weapon. Each time you attack with the weapon, you expend one piece of ammunition. Drawing the ammunition from a quiver, case, or other container is part of the attack. At the end of the battle, you can recover half your expended ammunition by taking a minute to search the battlefield.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>If you use a weapon that has the ammunition property to make a melee attack, you treat the weapon as an improvised weapon (see "Improvised Weapons" later in the section). A sling must be loaded to deal any damage when used in this way.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Range: A weapon that can be used to make a ranged attack has a range shown in parentheses after the ammunition or thrown property. The range lists two numbers. The first is the weapon's normal range in feet, and the second indicates the weapon's maximum range. When attacking a target beyond normal range, you have disadvantage on the attack roll. You can't attack a target beyond the weapon's long range.</text>
		<text></text>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">ranged attacks +3</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">ranged damage +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Honor's Last Stand</name>
		<type>S</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>6</weight>
		<ac>2</ac>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-evil character</text>
		<text>This massive, silvered shield bearing the crest of the Platinum Dragon never tarnishes. The metal is warm to the touch. While holding the shield, you have a +1 bonus to AC.  is bonus is in addition to the shield’s normal bonus to AC. You are also immune to the prone condition while bearing this shield.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Honor's Last Stand (Awakened)</name>
		<type>S</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>6</weight>
		<ac>2</ac>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-evil character</text>
		<text>This massive, silvered shield bearing the crest of the Platinum Dragon never tarnishes. The metal is warm to the touch. While holding the shield, you have a +2 bonus to AC.  is bonus is in addition to the shield’s normal bonus to AC. You are also immune to the prone condition while bearing this shield.</text>
		<text>	Whenever a creature’s attack against you misses, you can use your reaction to immediately attempt to make a shove attack against that creature.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Honor's Last Stand (Exalted)</name>
		<type>S</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>6</weight>
		<ac>2</ac>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a non-evil character</text>
		<text>This massive, silvered shield bearing the crest of the Platinum Dragon never tarnishes. The metal is warm to the touch. While holding the shield, you have a +3 bonus to AC.  is bonus is in addition to the shield’s normal bonus to AC. You are also immune to the prone condition while bearing this shield.</text>
		<text>	Whenever a creature’s attack against you misses, you can use your reaction to immediately attempt to make a shove attack against that creature.</text>
		<text>	Using a bonus action, you can protect an adjacent ally, imparting +3 to their AC until the beginning of your next turn, or they are no longer adjacent to you (whichever comes first).</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Kiss of the Changebringer</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>A beautiful, glittering emerald is set within the center of this silver chain, humming with power and possibility.</text>
		<text>	While wearing this amulet, you gain a +1 bonus to all saving throws, and are immune to the grappled condition.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">saving throws +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Kiss of the Changebringer (Awakened)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>A beautiful, glittering emerald is set within the center of this silver chain, humming with power and possibility.</text>
		<text>	While wearing this amulet, you gain a +2 bonus to all saving throws, and are immune to the restrained and grappled conditions.</text>
		<text>	You may use an action to cast the spell blink on yourself without needing any components. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">saving throws +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Kiss of the Changebringer (Exalted)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>A beautiful, glittering emerald is set within the center of this silver chain, humming with power and possibility.</text>
		<text>	While wearing this amulet, you gain a +3 bonus to all saving throws, and are immune to the paralyzed, petrified, restrained and grappled conditions.</text>
		<text>	You may use an action to cast the spell blink on yourself without needing any components. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a long rest.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you make an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can choose to roll an additional d20. You can choose to do this after you roll the die, but before the outcome is determined. You choose which of the d20s is used for the attack roll, ability check, or saving throws. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">saving throws +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Mythcarver</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a bard</text>
		<text>This incredible silvered blade once belonged to the White Duke himself, and many more master bards before him. It resonates with nearby musical tones. You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you use your Bardic Inspiration feature, you gain advantage on attacks with this weapon until the end of your turn.</text>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Mythcarver (Awakened)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a bard</text>
		<text>This incredible silvered blade once belonged to the White Duke himself, and many more master bards before him. It resonates with nearby musical tones. You have a +2 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</text>
		<text>	In addition, targets damaged with this weapon take an additional 1d6 points of force damage.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you use your Bardic Inspiration feature, you gain advantage on attacks with this weapon until the end of your turn.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you use your Cutting Words feature while wielding this blade, the target has disadvantage on their next saving throw.</text>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Mythcarver (Exalted)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d8</dmg1>
		<dmg2>1d10</dmg2>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement by a bard</text>
		<text>This incredible silvered blade once belonged to the White Duke himself, and many more master bards before him. It resonates with nearby musical tones. You have a +3 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon.</text>
		<text>	In addition, targets damaged with this weapon take an additional 1d6 points of force damage.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you use your Bardic Inspiration feature, you gain advantage on attacks with this weapon until the end of your turn.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you use your Cutting Words feature while wielding this blade, the target has disadvantage on their next saving throw.</text>
		<text>	You can spend an action to let the spirit of the sword overtake you momentarily. You make four melee attacks with this sword, then suffer one point of exhaustion. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a long rest.</text>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +3</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Plate of the Dawnmartyr</name>
		<type>HA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>65</weight>
		<ac>18</ac>
		<strength>15</strength>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Beautiful silver scrolling and priceless, cut rubies adorn this set of brass-and-gold armor. Worn by the High Priest Duana of the Dawnfather as she fell in the Battle of Ghor Dranas. You gain a +1 bonus to AC while wearing this armor. When you are struck by a melee attack, you may use your reaction to cause the attacker to suffer 1d6 points of fire damage.</text>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Plate of the Dawnmartyr (Awakened)</name>
		<type>HA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>65</weight>
		<ac>18</ac>
		<strength>15</strength>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Beautiful silver scrolling and priceless, cut rubies adorn this set of brass-and-gold armor. Worn by the High Priest Duana of the Dawnfather as she fell in the Battle of Ghor Dranas. You gain a +2 bonus to AC while wearing this armor. When you are struck by a melee attack, you may use your reaction to cause the attacker to suffer 2d6 points of fire damage.</text>
		<text>You gain immunity to the frightened condition.</text>
		<text>You gain resistance to fire damage.</text>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Plate of the Dawnmartyr (Exalted)</name>
		<type>HA</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<value></value>
		<weight>65</weight>
		<ac>18</ac>
		<strength>15</strength>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Beautiful silver scrolling and priceless, cut rubies adorn this set of brass-and-gold armor. Worn by the High Priest Duana of the Dawnfather as she fell in the Battle of Ghor Dranas. You gain a +3 bonus to AC while wearing this armor. When you are struck by a melee attack, you may use your reaction to cause the attacker to suffer 2d6 points of fire damage.</text>
		<text>You gain immunity to the frightened condition.</text>
		<text>You gain resistance to fire damage.</text>
		<text>If you are knocked unconscious by an attack or spell, a blast of healing flame surrounds you. You immediately regain 1 hit point and are lifted to your feet. All enemy creatures within 10 feet of you suffer 2d6 fire damage. You cannot use this ability again until you finish a long rest.</text>
		<text>Versatile: This weapon can be used with one or two hands. A damage value in parentheses appears with the property — the damage when the weapon is used with two hands to make a melee attack.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">ac +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Pyremaul</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>10</weight>
		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<property>H,2H</property>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Forged from deep red iron, this massive hammer houses an ever-burning gemstone of orange flame. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls made with this weapon. When you hit with an attack using this weapon, the target takes an additional 1d6 fire damage.</text>
		<text>	You can choose to have this weapon shed bright light in a 30 foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. If you kill a creature with an attack using this weapon, the corpse is immolated, turning to ash.</text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +1</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Pyremaul (Awakened)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>10</weight>
		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<property>H,2H</property>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Forged from deep red iron, this massive hammer houses an ever-burning gemstone of orange flame. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls made with this weapon. When you hit with an attack using this weapon, the target takes an additional 1d6 fire damage.</text>
		<text>	You can choose to have this weapon shed bright light in a 30 foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. If you kill a creature with an attack using this weapon, the corpse is immolated, turning to ash.</text>
		<text>	As an action, you can slam the Pyremaul into the ground to cast the burning hands spell at 2nd level (spell save DC 15). You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	When you score a critical hit with this weapon, the target must succeed on a DC 15 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +2</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +2</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Pyremaul (Exalted)</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>10</weight>
		<dmg1>2d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType>B</dmgType>
		<property>H,2H</property>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>Forged from deep red iron, this massive hammer houses an ever-burning gemstone of orange flame. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls made with this weapon. When you hit with an attack using this weapon, the target takes an additional 1d6 fire damage.</text>
		<text>	You can choose to have this weapon shed bright light in a 30 foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. If you kill a creature with an attack using this weapon, the corpse is immolated, turning to ash.</text>
		<text>	As an action, you can slam the Pyremaul into the ground to cast the burning hands spell at 3rd level (spell save DC 17). You cannot use this ability again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	When you score a critical hit with this weapon, the target must succeed on a DC 17 Strength saving throw or be knocked prone. You can also roll an additional 3d6 fire damage when determining the extra damage for the critical hit.</text>
		<text>Heavy: Small creatures have disadvantage on attack rolls with heavy weapons. A heavy weapon's size and bulk make it too large for a Small creature to use effectively.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Two-Handed: This weapon requires two hands to use.</text>
		<roll>3d6</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee attacks +3</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">melee damage +3</modifier>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Spire of Conflux</name>
		<type>ST</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>4</weight>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>A powerful relic passed down from generation to generation of Ashari leaders. The staff has 8 charges and regains 1d4 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding the staff, you can expend some of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC and spellcasting ability: burning hands (1 charge), fireball (3 charges).</text>
		<roll>1d4+2</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Spire of Conflux (Awakened)</name>
		<type>ST</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>4</weight>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>A powerful relic passed down from generation to generation of Ashari leaders. The staff has 12 charges and regains 1d6 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding the staff, you can expend some of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC and spellcasting ability: burning hands (1 charge), fireball (3 charges), ice storm (4 charges), conjure elemental (5 charges).</text>
		<text>	Whenever you cast a spell that deals fire, ice, or lightning damage and you roll a 1 on a damage die, you can reroll the die and must use the new result.</text>
		<roll>1d6+2</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Spire of Conflux</name>
		<type>ST</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>4</weight>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>A powerful relic passed down from generation to generation of Ashari leaders. The staff has 8 charges and regains 1d4 + 2 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding the staff, you can expend some of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC and spellcasting ability: burning hands (1 charge), fireball (3 charges).</text>
		<roll>1d4+2</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Spire of Conflux (Exalted)</name>
		<type>ST</type>
		<magic>1</magic>
		<weight>4</weight>
		<rarity>Legendary</rarity>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires attunement</text>
		<text>A powerful relic passed down from generation to generation of Ashari leaders. The staff has 20 charges and regains 1d6 + 4 expended charges daily at dawn. While holding the staff, you can expend some of its charges to cast one of the following spells from it, using your spell save DC and spellcasting ability: burning hands (1 charge), fireball (3 charges), ice storm (4 charges), conjure elemental (5 charges), chain lightning (6 charges), fire storm (7 charges).</text>
		<text>	Whenever you cast a spell that deals fire, ice, or lightning damage and you roll a 1 on a damage die, you can reroll the die and must use the new result.</text>
		<text>	While holding this staff, you gain a +1 bonus to spell attack rolls, and your spell save DC increases by 1</text>
		<roll>1d6+4</roll>
		<modifier category="bonus">spell attack +1</modifier>
		<modifier category="bonus">spell dc +1</modifier>
	</item>
</compendium>
