<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<item>
		<name>Arranavel</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d10</dmg1>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<value/>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>This mithral longsword is of elven design, bearing runes along the blade that read "Arelind", an ancient elven word that means “Champion of the People”. These blades were often gifts given by elven wizards to non-elven allies of great esteem.</text>
		<text>	You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon. It sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius when unsheathed. You can speak, read, and write the elven language so long as the sword is on your person.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Breastplate of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight>20</weight>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Chain Shirt of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight>20</weight>
		<ac>13</ac>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Half Plate of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight>40</weight>
		<ac>15</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Hide Armor of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight>12</weight>
		<ac>12</ac>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Scale Mail of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight/>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Spiked Armor of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight/>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Belt of Hidden Knives</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight/>
		<value/>
		<text>Rarity: very rare</text>
		<text>This appears to be a simple, unassuming black leather belt when wrapped around the user’s waist. When removed, a small diamond can be seen stitched into the belt’s underside. Each time this belt is buckled, it sounds like a sword being drawn from a sheath. As part of an attack, you can draw a hidden +2 dagger from the belt. If the dagger leaves your hands it ceases to exist at the end of your turn. The belt doesn’t run out of daggers. You must be wearing the belt to use this property.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Belt of the Monkey</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<value/>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>This metal belt is made of silver monkeys locked arm in arm with tiny pieces of jade for each primate’s eyes. While wearing it, you feel the tickling urge to treat the world as a playground by swinging on objects, climbing trees, and scaling buildings. While wearing this belt you add double your proficiency to Strength (Athletics) checks to climb.</text>
		<text>	As an action any tail you have becomes prehensile for an hour. If you don’t have a tail, you grow a 3-foot prehensile tail out of your posterior for an hour. You can hang from your tail, provided it has something to hold onto. Your tail also acts as a third arm and hand, allowing you to manipulate and wield objects that weigh 5 lbs. or less. In this state you could hold three weapons at once, but you can still only  ght with two at a time. You can’t use this ability again until you have completed a long rest.</text>
	</item>
</compendium>
