<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<item>
		<name>Arranavel</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d10</dmg1>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>V</property>
		<value/>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>This mithral longsword is of elven design, bearing runes along the blade that read "Arelind", an ancient elven word that means “Champion of the People”. These blades were often gifts given by elven wizards to non-elven allies of great esteem.</text>
		<text>	You have a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls made with this weapon. It sheds dim light in a 5-foot radius when unsheathed. You can speak, read, and write the elven language so long as the sword is on your person.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Breastplate of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight>20</weight>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Chain Shirt of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight>20</weight>
		<ac>13</ac>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Half Plate of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight>40</weight>
		<ac>15</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Hide Armor of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight>12</weight>
		<ac>12</ac>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Scale Mail of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight/>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Spiked Armor of Ease</name>
		<type>MA</type>
		<magic/>
		<value/>
		<weight/>
		<ac>14</ac>
		<stealth>YES</stealth>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While the magic of this armor doesn't provide any additional protection, armor of ease can be slept in with no detrimental effects.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Belt of Hidden Knives</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight/>
		<value/>
		<text>Rarity: very rare</text>
		<text>This appears to be a simple, unassuming black leather belt when wrapped around the user’s waist. When removed, a small diamond can be seen stitched into the belt’s underside. Each time this belt is buckled, it sounds like a sword being drawn from a sheath. As part of an attack, you can draw a hidden +2 dagger from the belt. If the dagger leaves your hands it ceases to exist at the end of your turn. The belt doesn’t run out of daggers. You must be wearing the belt to use this property.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Belt of the Monkey</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<value/>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>This metal belt is made of silver monkeys locked arm in arm with tiny pieces of jade for each primate’s eyes. While wearing it, you feel the tickling urge to treat the world as a playground by swinging on objects, climbing trees, and scaling buildings. While wearing this belt you add double your proficiency to Strength (Athletics) checks to climb.</text>
		<text>	As an action any tail you have becomes prehensile for an hour. If you don’t have a tail, you grow a 3-foot prehensile tail out of your posterior for an hour. You can hang from your tail, provided it has something to hold onto. Your tail also acts as a third arm and hand, allowing you to manipulate and wield objects that weigh 5 lbs. or less. In this state you could hold three weapons at once, but you can still only  ght with two at a time. You can’t use this ability again until you have completed a long rest.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Bow of Grounding</name>
		<type>R</type>
		<value/>
		<text>Rarity: rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>A stiff but bendable chain makes up the curvature of this longbow. Each link of chain has a small pink pearl in the center. You gain a +1 bonus to attack and damage roll made with this longbow. When you shoot a creature with a flying speed with this bow, it must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or have its flying speed reduced by 10 feet. The target must complete a short rest before it can regain any speed lost in this way.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Box of Shrinking</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<value/>
		<text>These plain boxes are carved with Dwarvish runes, surprisingly light, and roughly the size of a loaf of bread. Inside, the box is much more extravagant, lined with crushed velvet and studded with gems. An old dwarf nursery rhyme plays when the box is open. "The Legend of Calibra Daliq" is about a dwarf wizard thief who shrunk herself to sneak past guards and locked doors in order to get her riches.</text>
		<text>The DM either rolls to determine the box’s type or chooses one from the options available.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Box of Shrinking Type</text>
		<text>d100    Metal         Original object space    Rarity</text>
		<text>01-50   Iron          5-ft cube or smaller     Uncommon</text>
		<text>51-80   Steel         10-ft cube or smaller    Rare</text>
		<text>81-95   Mithral       15-ft cube or smaller    Very Rare</text>
		<text>96-100  Adamantine    20-ft cube or smaller    Legendary</text>
		<text>	You can use the box of shrinking’s Grow and Shrink abilities once per day each. You must be holding the box to use either ability.</text>
		<text>	Grow. As an action, any item previously shrunken by a box of shrinking of equal or lesser rarity and power may be grown. The item must be placed in the box of shrinking and its original size must be within the parameters on the table above. Once the command word is spoken the object appears in an unoccupied space adjacent to the box of shrinking. You must be holding the box of shrinking to use this ability.</text>
		<text>	Shrink. As an action you may speak a command word and one non-living object within 50 feet of the box of shrinking has its size reduced to a 1-inch cube, weighs half a pound, and is teleported into the box. The item stays this size until it is grown by a box of shrinking. The shrunken item may be no larger than specified on the table above.</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Bramblebriar</name>
		<type>M</type>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<dmg1>1d6</dmg1>
		<dmgType>S</dmgType>
		<property>F,L</property>
		<value/>
		<text>Rarity: Legendary</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text>While holding this scimitar, you can use a bonus action to activate its brambles. When you do, several barbed vines coil around its crossguard, over your wrist, and dig into your flesh. At the start of each of your turns, it drains 2 hit points from you to empower its poison. While attached to you in this way, you can’t be disarmed by normal means, and you are resistant to poison damage and immune to the poisoned condition. Each time the weapon drains your hit points, it gains one charge, to a maximum of 5 charges. The weapon continues to drain your hit points while fully charged.</text>
		<text>	On a hit, its vicious barbs lash out from the scimitar and rake your target with venomous brambles, expending all charges within its vines. The creature must make a Constitution saving throw with a DC equal to 10 + your proficiency bonus. On a failure, the creature takes 1d4 poison damage for each charge spent.</text>
		<text>	If you stow the weapon without expending all of its charges, the poison courses through your veins as you release the hilt and you must make a successful Constitution saving throw or take the damage from its thorns for each remaining charge.</text>
	</item>
</compendium>
