<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Warlock" HB="HB">
		<name>Warlock (Oracle)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: Oracle</name>
				<text>The gifts bestowed upon you by your patron are those of foreknowledge. The Oracle is a being of prophecy and mystery, and manifests to you in ways that leave you questioning the nature of your patron. The Oracle communicates to you through whispered words that only you hear, visions that only you see, writings that only you can read, and hazy manifestations in the incense braziers and crystal balls that you use as a medium to call upon your patron. The Oracle might be a god, a fiend, or even a mortal of vast power, though you would never know it; you know only the prophecies that your patron bestows, and the arcane knowledge you are granted to conjure such visions for yourself.</text>
				<text />
				<text>Expanded Spell List:</text>
				<text>	Oracle lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text />
				<text>1st - guiding bolt, identify</text>
				<text>2nd - augury, detect thoughts</text>
				<text>3rd - clairvoyance, speak with dead</text>
				<text>4th - arcane eye, divination</text>
				<text>5th - commune, legend lore</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oracle: Foretelling</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, you can listen to the whispered words of your otherworldly patron and interpret the fates that they foretell. You can spend 10 minutes imparting the knowledge you gained from this foretelling to your companions. When you do so, choose up to six friendly creatures (which can include yourself) within 30 feet of you who can see or hear you and who can understand you. Each creature gains a single fore- telling, which they can expend at any time for one of the following benefits:</text>
				<text>	• Gain advantage on a single attack roll, ability check, or saving throw before making the roll.</text>
				<text>	• Gain a +5 bonus to AC against a single attack before the attack roll is made.</text>
				<text>	• Gain 5 temporary hit points, which last until the creature takes a long rest or uses another foretelling.</text>
				<text>	A single creature can have no more than one foretelling at a time (from you, or any other source), and if a creature with a foretelling finishes a long rest, that foretelling is lost. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oracle: Foretell Disaster</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, the visions you can impart upon your allies can reveal ambushes and potentially devastating attacks, allowing your companions to avoid them. Any creature that has a foretelling granted by you can choose to expend it to gain one of the following benefits:</text>
				<text>	• When the creature would be surprised, it is instead not surprised.</text>
				<text>	• When the creature succeeds on a saving throw to take only half damage from an effect, the creature instead takes no damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oracle: Foretell Battle</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, any creature that has a foretelling granted by you can choose to expend it to gain advantage on a roll for initiative.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Oracle: Prophecy</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, when you grant creatures a foretelling, you give them two foretellings instead of one, and each creature can have up to two foretellings at a time, provided they both come from you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

	</subclass>

	<spellList class="Warlock (Oracle)">
		<index name="Guiding Bolt" />
		<index name="Identify" />
		<index name="Augury" />
		<index name="Detect Thoughts" />
		<index name="Clairvoyance" />
		<index name="Speak with Dead" />
		<index name="Arcane Eye" />
		<index name="Divination" />
		<index name="Commune" />
		<index name="Legend Lore" />
	</spellList>
</compendium>
