<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Warlock" HB="HB">
		<name>Warlock (The Chaos)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Chaos</name>
				<text>You have made a pact with a creature that revels in the madness and infinite possibility of the chaotic planes. Your patron could be a powerful slaad lord of Limbo, an ever-changing and roiling soup of impermanent matter and energy. Your patron could be a god of madness, such as Cyric, or a demon lord-in-exile in the depths of Pandemonium, a dark plane of tunnels carved by howling winds. Your patron could be a fearsome giant or celestial valkyrie of Ysgard, a heroic plane of soaring mountains, endless battles, and boundless creativity.</text>
				<text>	Unlike devils with their carefully crafted words and contracts, your patron is beholden to nothing but its twisted whims. Many chaos warlocks find their powers to be a cruel curse, but those who embrace the chaos learn that unpredictability is their greatest source of strength.</text>
				<text />
				<text>Expanded Spell List:</text>
				<text>	The Chaos lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text />
				<text>1st - chaos bolt, color spray</text>
				<text>2nd - alter self, blindness/deafness</text>
				<text>3rd - bestow curse, blink</text>
				<text>4th - confusion, phantasmal killer</text>
				<text>5th - destructive wave, mislead</text>
			</feature>

			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Chaos: Strings Attached</name>
				<text>When you take this pact at 1st level, you learn the strings your patron attached are greater than they seem. Each night, denizens from the chaotic planes visit you in your sleep to play cruel tricks but reward you with the sweetest of treats. When you finish a long rest, roll 1d6 to determine the "gifts" bestowed on you. When you roll for a new gift, it replaces the old one.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>1d6    Trick    Treat</text>
				<text>1    You wake to eyes fogged over. You are blind beyond 5 feet.    You can see invisible creatures and objects out to a range of 120 feet.</text>
				<text>2    You speak only in screams audible out to 300 feet. You have disadvantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks whether your mouth is open or closed.    Once per short or long rest, you can channel your booming voice to cast thunderwave at the level of your warlock spell slots.</text>
				<text>3    You can't tell a lie. You have disadvantage on Charisma (Deception) checks.    People find you trustworthy. You gain advantage on Charisma (Persuasion) checks.</text>
				<text>4    You are filled with a bloodlust and act with abandon. Attacks against you are rolled with advantage.    Your seemingly random and aggressive lash-outs mark your instability. You have advantage on attack rolls.</text>
				<text>5    You've shrunk! You are Tiny, and your base walking speed is 20 feet.    You have advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks and can take the Hide action as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>6    You have a masochistic urge to inflict ridicule and pain on yourself. When you make an attack roll, you always miss your target on a 1 or a 2, and hit yourself instead.    Your attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Chaos: Tumble Through The Chaos</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can conjure a portal to travel through the planes of chaos. You can cast dimension door with this feature without expending a spell slot or material components. However, denizens of that plane try to hamper your progress. When you use your action to use this feature in this way, you declare your intended destination and then roll 1d4 to determine how the denizens intervene.</text>
				<text>	Whenever you would bring a willing creature with you, that creature always arrives at the intended destination unharmed.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest. At 14th level, at the end of the turn you use this feature, you can roll 1d6 and, on a 6, you regain the use of this feature immediately.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Chaotic Intervention</text>
				<text>1    Ysgard's war horns call you to battle, and you are compelled to answer. When you reappear on your original plane, at the end of your next turn, you have aged 7 days and bear a fresh scar as a souvenir of your conquests.</text>
				<text>2    Tiny, disorienting slaad tadpoles whirl around you as you float through gravity-less limbo. You reappear by yourself 1d6 x 5 feet short of your intended destination.</text>
				<text>3    Howling headwinds rake your senses as you dash through the twisted tunnels of Pandemonium. You take 2d4 psychic damage and arrive at your destination deafened for a number of rounds equal to the damage you received.</text>
				<text>4    You arrive at your destination unscathed.</text>
				<text>5    Denizens in cahoots with your patron aid your travel your through the planes. You gain temporary hit points equal to 1d6 + your warlock level.</text>
				<text>6    Your patron blesses your travel through its plane, and you are under the effects of the bless spell for the next hour.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Chaos: The Chaos Walker</name>
				<text>our dreams are so nonsensical they would drive most creatures insane, but your senses have been dulled to the madness. Starting at 10th level, you gain advantage on saving throws against being frightened and madness checks, and your physical form begins to re ect the chaos in your mind. Bits of energy, planar residue from your travels through the chaotic planes, cling to your body in constantly shifting forms and color. Whenever you finish a short or long rest, roll 1d6 to determine your current chaotic features.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>The Chaos Walker's Features</text>
				<text>1    Horns made of magenta planar energy grow from your head. If you already have horns, magenta energy wraps around them and writhe like tendrils behind you.</text>
				<text>2    Massive, muscled, and clawed arms made of jet black planar energy overlap your own arms and stutter behind your movements.</text>
				<text>3    Your eyes bulge to twice their size, and your pupils narrow like those of a slaad.</text>
				<text>4    Shimmering wings made of indigo planar energy sprout from your back but don't give you a fly speed.</text>
				<text>5    You are seemingly unchanged. However, whenever your shadow is cast, it reflects a different demon shape from a tiny quasit to a hulking barlgura, watching your every move</text>
				<text>6    Whenever someone looks at you, your nose seems to drift slowly to the side of your face but returns to its normal position when they blink.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Chaos: Planar Vertigo</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you can draw the chaotic essence of their patron's plane to launch yourself and all creatures within 30 feet of you into the air. Each affected creature must make an Intelligence saving throw. On a failure, it is launched into the air 10 feet in a random direction and suspended in midair for 1 minute. While suspended, the creature is incapacitated by supernatural vertigo. You can grant advantage on this saving throw to a number of creatures of your choice, up to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1), including yourself.</text>
				<text>	On a success, a creature gains a fly speed equal to its walking speed for the duration.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>1d6    Feature</text>
				<text>1      North</text>
				<text>2      South</text>
				<text>3      West</text>
				<text>4      East</text>
				<text>5      Skyward</text>
				<text>6      Earthward</text>
				<text/>
				<text>At the end of each of its turns, a creature incapacitated in this way repeats this saving throw. On a failure, the creature is launched another 10 feet in a random direction and remains incapacitated. On a success, it gains a fly speed equal to its walking speed for the duration and is no longer incapacitated.</text>
				<text>	An incapacitated creature that impacts a solid surface takes 2d6 bludgeoning damage, and the effect immediately ends, causing it to fall to the ground.</text>
				<text>	The effect ends for all creatures after 1 minute, when each creature loses the fly speed gained from this feature and fall to the ground, unless they already have a fly speed.</text>
				<text>	Once you have used this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

	</subclass>

	<spellList class="Warlock (The Chaos)">
		<index name="Chaos Bolt" />
		<index name="Color Spray" />
		<index name="Alter Self" />
		<index name="Blindness/Deafness" />
		<index name="Bestow Curse" />
		<index name="Blink" />
		<index name="Confusion" />
		<index name="Phantasmal Killer" />
		<index name="Destructive Wave" />
		<index name="Mislead" />
	</spellList>
</compendium>
