<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Warlock" HB="HB">
		<name>Warlock (Genie)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Noble Genie</name>
				<text>Your pact is one that has been made by legendary advisors, philosophers, and tale-spinners of the desert lands, known throughout the land of Zakhara as sha'irs. Your patron is a noble genie, a creature whose spirit is infused with the primordial essence of the Elemental Planes. These creatures are the rarest and most powerful of their kind. They aim to achieve ultimate greatness, splendor, and the reverence of all beings.</text>
				<text>Though noble genies aren't gods, they feel deserving of such veneration from their servants. They're accustomed to wealth and opulence and treat their insatiable indulgence as an entitlement to their own power and grandeur.</text>
				<text />
				<text>Expanded Spell List:</text>
				<text>	The Noble Genie lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text />
				<text>1st - chromatic orb, shield</text>
				<text>2nd - flaming sphere, Maximillian's earthen grasp</text>
				<text>3rd - lightning bolt, sleet storm</text>
				<text>4th - conjure minor elementals, elemental bane</text>
				<text>5th - far step, planar binding</text>
			</feature>

			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Noble Genie: Noble Patronage</name>
				<text>At 1st level, your patron grants you the ability to speak Primordial. You also gain advantage on Intelligence (Arcana) checks made to identify portals to elemental planes and magical inscriptions or items created by other sha'irs, their patrons, or other genie-kind.</text>
				<text>Additionally, you choose the one of the four types of noble genie to be your patron as shown on the Noble Genie Patrons table below. Your choice determines several of your class features as you gain level.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Genie Type        Damage Type</text>
				<text>Dao (Earth)       Poison</text>
				<text>Djinni (Air)      Lightning</text>
				<text>Efreeti (Fire)    Fire</text>
				<text>Marid (Water)     Cold</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Noble Genie: Gen Vizier</name>
				<text>At 1st level, your patron assigns a lesser genie, a gen, to accompany you during your travels. The type of gen is dependent upon your patron's genie type as defined on the Noble Genie Patron table. Your gen vizier isn't required to obey your commands, although it usually tries to the best of its ability, and doesn't participate in combat.</text>
				<text>	You gain the following benefit from your gen vizier.</text>
				<text>	Spell Fetching. You can send your gen to find and retrieve the knowledge of an additional spell you don't know. The spell must be of a level you can cast and can be from any class spell list. As a bonus action, you can request a spell for your gen to retrieve and it returns in a number of rounds equal to 1d12 minus your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1).</text>
				<text>	When the gen returns, it immediately imparts the spell knowledge to you at the beginning of your turn, which you can then cast normally by expending a spell slot. If you don't cast the spell within two rounds of receiving it, the spell knowledge disappears, and you can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	You can use this feature twice between long rests at 6th level and three times between long rests at 14th level.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Gen Familiar</text>
				<text>A warlock who attains the Pact of the Chain at 3rd level can choose their gen as their familiar. See appendix A for the stat blocks of each gen type.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Noble Genie: Bargain of Power</name>
				<text>At 6th level, your gen vizier's familiarity with other beings, the magic they possess, and their desires speed its retrieval of the magic you desire. The dice for your Spell Fetching feature turns into a d10. At 14th level, it turns into a d8.</text>
				<text>Additionally, you can expend one of these die, to gain advantage on a Charisma (Intimidation or Persuasion) check.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Noble Genie: Elemental Attunement</name>
				<text>At 10th level, you become more attuned to the primordial realm of your patron. You have resistance to the damage type de ned by the Noble Genie Patron table. Also, whenever you cast a spell that deals damage of the type defined by the Noble Genie Patron table, add your Charisma modifier to that damage (minimum of 1).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Noble Genie: Genie Form</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you can merge with yourself with your gen vizier to assume the form of an aspect of your genie patron.</text>
				<text>	Using your action, you undergo a transformation. For 1 minute, you gain the following benefits.</text>
				<text>• You gain flying speed equal to your walking speed.</text>
				<text>• You gain resistance to slashing, bludgeoning, and piercing damage from nonmagical attacks.</text>
				<text>• You gain advantage to saving throws versus magical spells and effects.</text>
				<text>• While this feature is active, the damage dealt by your eldritch blast changes to the damage type defined by your Noble Genie Patron table. In addition, the damage dealt by this spell can't be reduced by a target's resistances or immunities.</text>
				<text>After you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

	</subclass>

	<spellList class="Warlock (Genie)">
		<index name="Chromatic Orb" />
		<index name="Shield" />
		<index name="Flaming Sphere" />
		<index name="Maximilian's Earthen Grasp" />
		<index name="Lightning Bolt" />
		<index name="Sleet Storm" />
		<index name="Conjure Minor Elementals" />
		<index name="Elemental Bane" />
		<index name="Far Step" />
		<index name="Planar Binding" />
	</spellList>
</compendium>
