<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Lingering Soul" HB="HB">
		<name>Lingering Soul (Spirit Guardian)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Phantom Calling: Calling of the Spirit Guardian</name>
				<text>Some souls that persist in the mortal realm seek a greater purpose, Whether they remain to see to some divine duty, or wish to entice and corrupt the souls of others in the name of a dark patron, Its these spirits who invite deific guidance into their fate that begin to resemble the celestial beings or twisted fiends they worship. Relying on physical vessels to channel their fury, these guardians use their gifts to protect, harm, or influence all they encounter.</text>
				<text>	Upon becoming a spirit guardian, choose either your Wisdom Or Charisma to become your Aspect. Your Aspect modifier is equal to that of the chosen Ability Score. You gain proficiency in Charisma saving throws.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Calling of the Spirit Guardian: Invoke Smite</name>
				<text>When you choose this calling at 1st level, can instill power into the weapons of nearby creatures to strike with divine flame. As an action, target a weapon or object within 30 feet of you. Until the end of your next turn, the next time that weapon or object hits a creature, it deals an additional 1d8 radiant damage (if you are good or neutral), or 1d8 necrotic damage (if you are evil). You can use this feature while possessing a host.</text>
				<text>	This damage increases by 1d8 at 6th level, and again at 11th level and 15th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Calling of the Spirit Guardian: Sympathetic Mending</name>
				<text>Beginning with this calling at 1st level, you discover how to restore vitality through divine spiritual energy. As an action, target a creature within 30 feet of you to regain a number of hit points equal to 1d8 + your Aspect modifier. You can use this feature while possessing a host, and if your host is not your target, your host also regains hit points equal to your Aspect modifier.</text>
				<text>	You can use this feature twice. Upon reaching 6th level, the healing increases by 1d8 and you can use this feature three times. At 11th level, the healing increases by 1d8 and you can use this feature four times. When you reach 15th level, the healing increases by 1d8 and you can use this feature five times.</text>
				<text>	You regain all uses of this feature after a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Calling of the Spirit Guardian: Divine Barrier</name>
				<text>At 6th level, you learn to protect your host by using your ghostly body to create a temporary shield. While you are possessing a host, if an attacker that you can see hits your host with an attack, you can use your reaction to grant your host a bonus to their AC or saving throw against the triggering attack equal to your Aspect modifier. Once the attack is resolved, the possession immediately ends, and you cannot use your Possession feature until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Calling of the Spirit Guardian: Consecrated Emanation</name>
				<text>Upon reaching 11th level, you can exude an aura that punishes those you deem unworthy. You can use an action to emit an aura around you up to a distance of 15 feet for up to 1 minute. You then designate any number of creatures you can see to be unaffected by it. An affected creature's speed is halved in the area, and when the creature enters the area for the first time on a turn or starts its turn there, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d6 radiant damage (if you are good or neutral), or 3d6 necrotic damage (if you are evil). On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage. You can use this feature while possessing a host.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Calling of the Spirit Guardian: Savior Spirit</name>
				<text>When you reach 15th level, you radiate protective energy that staves off the shadow of death. All friendly creatures within 30 feet of you gain 1 hit point on a death saving throw roll of 18 to 20 on the d20.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Calling of the Spirit Guardian: Guardian Transformation</name>
				<text>At 15th level, you can use your action to temporarily imbue your host with some of your ghostly properties. For 10 minutes, your host gains the following features:</text>
				<text>• They have damage resistance against bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.</text>
				<text>• They are immune to poison damage and the poisoned condition.</text>
				<text>• They are immune to the prone, grappled, restrained, and petrified conditions.</text>
				<text>• They can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You both take 1d10 force damage if they end their turn inside an object.</text>
				<text>• They have a fly speed equal to their speed.</text>
				<text>	The duration ends prematurely if the possession ends.</text>
				<text>Once you use this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can use it again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>
