<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
<subclass baseclass="Lingering Soul" HB="HB">
	<name>Lingering Soul (Wraith)</name>
	<autolevel level="1">
	<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Phantom Calling: Calling of the Wraith</name>
			<text>The Wraith is a dangerous path for any soul to take, and few have a choice should their life been entwined with dubious arcane pursuits or necromantic corruption. Those who take the path of the wraith embrace the desire for warmth and the hunger for the life they once had. Their energy becomes dark, enshrouded in shadow and malice... but the will remains, and there are tales of those lost souls who could master the craving and focus their hate on those who deserve it.</text>
			<text>	Upon becoming a wraith, choose either your Dexterity, Intelligence, or Charisma to become your Aspect. Your Aspect modifier is equal to that of the chosen Ability Score. You gain proficiency in Intelligence saving throws.</text>
		</feature>

		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Calling of the Wraith: Scything Claw</name>
			<text>Upon following this calling at 1st level, you gain the ability to tear through creatures with ghastly claws, stealing some of their essence. As an action, you can make a melee Aspect attack against a creature within 5 feet of you. On a hit, the target takes necrotic damage equal to 1d8 + your Aspect modifier. If the target isn't undead or a construct, you regain hit points equal to half of the damage dealt.</text>
			<text>	The damage of your Scything Claw increases to 2d8 at 6th level, 3d8 at 11th level, and 4d8 at 15th level.</text>
		</feature>
			</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
				<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Calling of the Wraith: Shadow of the Grave</name>
			<text>At 6th level, your spectral body becomes further attuned to the cold, dark world of the undead. Your ghostly form no longer emits a cold, dim light out in a 5 foot radius. You gain darkvision out to 60 feet, as well as resistance to cold and necrotic damage, but also have disadvantage on attack rolls and Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight while in direct sunlight.</text>
			<text>	While possessing a host. you can choose to impart them with the benefits of this feature, but in doing so also impart the penalties while in direct sunlight.</text>
			</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
	<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Calling of the Wraith: Aura of Midnight</name>
			<text>Beginning at 11th level, your presence devours nearby light, obscuring your form while syphoning life lost tinder darkness. Your icy presence extinguishes any natural open flame within 30 feet of you. While in dim light or darkness, you can take the Hide action as a bonus action. Whenever a living creature in dim light or darkness dies within 30 feet of you, you gain temporary hit points equal to 1d8 + your Aspect modifier. This aura remains while possessing a host.</text>
			<text>	At 15th level, the amount of temporary hit points gained increases to 2d8 + your Aspect modifier.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
	<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Calling of the Wraith: Create Specter</name>
			<text>Upon reaching 15th level, you've learned how to spread the curse of undeath to your fallen foes. As an action, you can target a humanoid corpse within 10 feet that has been dead for no longer than 1 minute, and died violently. The target's spirit rises as a specter in the space of the corpse or in the nearest unoccupied space. The specter is under your control, allowing you to issue commands to the creature while you are conscious (no action required), which it does its best to obey. You can specify a simple and general course of the action, such as "Attack that creature", "Run over there," or "Fetch that object." If the creature completed the order and doesn't receive further direction from you, it defends and preserves itself and you to the best of its ability. You can have no more than a number of specters equal to your Aspect modifier under your control at one time.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</subclass>
</compendium>
