<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<baseclass name="Lingering Soul" HB="HB">
		<name>Lingering Soul</name>
		<hd>6</hd>
		<proficiency>Constitution, History, Investigation, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, Religion, Sleight of Hand, Stealth</proficiency>
		<numSkills>3</numSkills>
		<armor>None</armor>
		<weapons>None</weapons>
		<tools>None</tools>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>Armor: None</text>
				<text>Weapons: None</text>
				<text>Tools: None</text>
				<text>Skills: Choose three from History, Investigation, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, Religion, Sleight of Hand, or Stealth</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following equipment your body would have on it, in addition to the equipment granted by your background, though carrying this equipment may prove difficult without aid.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• a simple weapon</text>
				<text>• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
				<text>• a trinket (rolled on the Trinkets table, PHB pg. 160)</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Taking over a dead character</text>
				<text>If a deceased player character returns as a Lingering Soul, they lose all previous class levels and abilities, instead returning with a number of levels in Lingering Soul equal to one less than their previous character level. They retain any languages they knew in life, as well as racial benefits and abilities, but lose all previous skill proficiencies, saving throw proficiencies, feats, and Ability Score improvements gained via class levels.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Spirit Binding</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, you must select an object or creature of your choice (it could be an heirloom, weapon, or ally) to bind to indefinitely. You must remain within 150 feet of your bound target at all time, and if the object or creature leaves your 150 foot radius, you are dragged along with it. You are always aware of where your bound object or creature is in relation to you.</text>
				<text>	Should the object be destroyed, or the creature slain, you immediately drop to 0 hit points. If you regain Consciousness without a spirit bond, you must immediately select a new object or creature within 150 feet to bind to. If nothing is present to bind to, you are paralyzed until an object or creature comes within 150 feet for you to bind to.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Phantom Calling</name>
				<text>Beginning at 1st level, you select a Phantom Calling that defines the path of your spiritual journey. Choose Poltergeist, Wraith, or Spirit Guardian, all detailed at the end of the class description. The calling you choose grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 11th, and 15th level.</text>
				<text>	The Phantom Calling you select will define one of your Ability Scores to carry over from life as the characteristic that now defines you in undeath, called your Aspect. The ability modifier form this ability score also acts as your Aspect modifier in regards to Lingering Soul features.</text>
				<text>	Some of your Lingering Soul features require you to make an Aspect attack, or your target to make a saving throw to resist a feature's effects. The modifier and saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</text>
				<text>	Lingering Soul save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Aspect modifier</text>
				<text>	Aspect Attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Aspect modifier</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Phantom Callings</name>
				<text>When a soul lingers long enough to buck the draw to the afterlife, they begin to walk a path of transformation. The choices they made in life, and in this current state of undeath, instill their spirit with varying degrees of positive and negative energy, slowly forging the soul into a hungry specter seeking to feast on the life force of the living, a mischievous reflection of nature's trickery who can bend the corporeal world to their will, or a divine spirit of protection using their ethereal gifts to aid their still-living allies.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Ghostly Form</name>
				<text>At 1st level, your physical body is no more, your new, spectral form existing in the space between realms. You gain the following benefits:</text>
				<text>• Your creature type is Undead, and you are considered undead in respect to all spells, abilities, and effects.</text>
				<text>• You give off a cold glow equal to dim light for a 5 foot radius.</text>
				<text>• You cannot physically carry any objects or wear equipment. You also no longer need to eat or drink, nor gain the benefits of any objects or substances that require ingestion.</text>
				<text>• While you are not possessing a creature. you have damage resistance against bludgeoning. piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.</text>
				<text>• You are immune to poison damage and the poisoned condition.</text>
				<text>• You are immune to the prone, grappled, restrained, and petrified conditions.</text>
				<text>• You can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You take 1d10 force damage if you end your turn inside an object.</text>
				<text>• You fall at a rate of 60 feet per round, and do not suffer falling damage.</text>
				<text>• You still take short or long rests per usual to use hit dice and regain the use of abilities, but do not require sleep.</text>
				<text>• Should you fall to 0 hit points, you begin fading. You are considered unconscious, and make death saving throws as normal. Should you fail three death saving throws, your spirit withers away into the ether. Your soul is cast into the vaults of the underworld and cannot be recovered or resurrected outside of the use of a Wish spell.</text>
				<text>• Should you ever be brought back to life via a spell or resurrection effect, you immediately lose all levels in Lingering Soul and return to life as your previous, living self. You gain back class levels in your original classes as they were upon death, plus one additional character level per level of Lingering Soul gained while playing as a spirit.</text>
			</feature>
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Possession</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you discover the ability to enter the bodies of other creatures and influence their actions. As a bonus action. you can attempt to possess one creature within 5 feet of you. The creature must succeed on a Charisma saving throw or become possessed. A creature can fail this saving throw voluntarily.</text>
				<text>	Wile possessing a creature, your body occupies the same space as the host and is not visible. You cannot be targeted or affected by any attacks or spells, but you suffer damage equal to half of any damage dealt to the host while possessed. If the host moves, you move with them. You can only experience what the host sees and hears, and can communicate with them telepathically. You can only use features that specify their use while possessing a host.</text>
				<text>	A possessed creature acts as normal on its turn. However. you can use your action to force the possessed creature to make an immediate weapon attack against a target of your choice within range, adding your Aspect modifier to the damage dealt. You can instead use your action to force the possessed creature to Dash in a direction of your choice, or to the Dodge action.</text>
				<text>	This possession lasts until the host drops to 0 hit points, you drop to 0 hit points, or you are forced out by an effect like the dispel evil and good spell or turn undead ability. You then reappear in an unoccupied space within 5 feet of the creature. You can choose to end your possession for free at the start of your turn. The host creature is immune to your possession for 24 hours after succeeding on the possession saving throw or after the possession ends (unless the creature wishes otherwise).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature>
				<name>Consume Enchantment</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you have learned how to absorb powerful arcane enchantments from potent items. You can spend an hour syphoning the mystic properties of a magical item. When the hour ritual is complete. the enchantment (and any attunement) becomes indefinitely bound to your ghostly form, leaving the item inert. You still have a limit of three enchantments you can have attuned at once, and no more than five enchantments total can be bound to you in this way. To consume a new enchantment beyond five, you must permanently discard an existing enchantment you harbor.</text>
				<text>	A weapon enchantment you have consumed can be applied to any physical or weapon attack you make. If you are possessing a host, you can apply one of your consumed weapon enchantments to any attacks you force them to make with a non-magical weapon.</text>
				<text>	Some items and artifacts cannot be consumed in this way (DM's discretion).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<feature>
				<name>Pervade the Fallen</name>
				<text>At 5th level, you've become adept enough at possession to utilize the shell of a slain creature as a vessel. Your Possession ability can now target the dead body of a creature within 5 feet of you, and the corpse automatically fails their saving throw. This possession ends after 1 minute. The host corpse is considered to have 1 hit point and starts prone. You can use your movement to move the host corpse at your speed. If a host corpse is reduced in 0 hit points, or the possession ends, it is destroyed and cannot be possessed again.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Unseen Passenger</name>
				<text>At 5th level, you've become more adept at controlling and manipulating the bodies of your host. If a creature is unaware of your presence, you can attempt to possess them without them knowing. Make a Dexterity (Stealth) contested by the target's Wisdom (Perception) check. If you win, and they fail their saving throw, you successfully possess them without their knowledge. Whenever you force the host to do anything, they can make a Wisdom (Insight) check against your Lingering Soul DC. On a success, they become aware of the possession.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature>
				<name>Obfuscate</name>
				<text>Beginning at 7th level, you can temporarily become incorporeal to avoid the brunt of an attack against you. When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack's damage against you.</text>
				<text>	When you would receive half of the damage a possessed creature suffers from an attack, you can use your reaction to reduce it to a quarter of the damage suffered.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<feature>
				<name>Xenoglossia</name>
				<text>Starling at 9th level, you can use an action while possessing a host to manipulate their speech and force them to say or yell a short phrase of twenty-five words or less. Any Charisma ability checks initiated this way use your Charisma score and skills in place of the host's.</text>
				<text>	If the host begins casting a spell that uses verbal components, you can use your reaction to try to force them to fumble the incantation. The host must make a Constitution saving throw against your Lingering Soul DC. On a failure, the spell fails, the spell slot is expended, and the possession immediately ends.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature>
				<name>Supernal Body</name>
				<text>Upon reaching 10th level, you've further expanded the capabilities of your ghostly body. You gain the following benefits:</text>
				<text>• You gain a fly speed equal to your speed.</text>
				<text>• You can cast invisibility on yourself, without requiring material components, twice per day.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<feature>
				<name>Piercing Chill</name>
				<text>At 13th level, you have learned to expand your ghostly chill to temporarily freeze your host's vitals. When a possessed host makes an attack, you can use your reaction to give the triggering attack disadvantage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature>
				<name>Ghastly Visage</name>
				<text>Beginning at 14th level, you can twist your appearance into a terrifying vision of undeath. As an action, choose any number of creatures within 30 feet of you. If they can see you, they must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn. On subsequent turns, you can use your action to extend the duration of this effect on the frightened creatures until the end of your next turn. This effect ends if a creature ends its turn out of line of sight of you.</text>
				<text>	If a creature succeeds on its saving throw, you can't use this feature on that creature again for 24 hours.</text>
				<text>	You must finish a short or long rest before you can use this feature again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature>
				<name>Eternal Spirit</name>
				<text>Upon reaching 17th level, your spirit body has evolved to become tethered to this plane, never truly destroyed by unhallowed weapons. You are no longer bound to an object or creature, as per your Spirit Binding feature, and may wander as you please.</text>
				<text>	Whenever you would be destroyed by failing a third death saving throw, you instead vanish for 24 hours, slumbering on the Ethereal Plane. You then return at the spot where you fell, rested as if you completed a long rest. You suffer a -4 penalty to all attack rolls, saving throws, and ability checks. Every time you finish a subsequent long rest, the penalty is reduced by 1 until it disappears.</text>
				<text>	If the area where your spirit was struck down is under the effect of a Hallow spell when you return, your spirit is instead scattered and lost forever in the Ethereal Plane.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Possession Mastery</name>
				<text>At 18th level, you have gained the ability to completely control a host. While possessing a living host, you can use your action to take total and precise control of the target. Until the end of your next turn, the creature takes only the actions you choose, and doesn't do anything that you don't allow it to do. During this time. you can also cause the creature to use a reaction, but this requires you to use your own reaction as well.</text>
				<text>	Each time the host takes damage during a turn where you are controlling it this way, it makes a new Charisma saving throw against your possession. If the saving throw succeeds, the possession ends.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Ravage Soul</name>
				<text>When you reach 20th level, you can try to sunder the spirit of a host from its body. While possessing a host that is neither undead nor a construct, you can use your action to end the possession and force the creature to make a Constitution saving throw. It takes 12d10 necrotic damage on a failure, and half as much damage on a success. If the creature is brought to under 50 hit points by this damage, it dies.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</baseclass>
</compendium>
