<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Cleric">
		<name>Cleric (Corruption)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Divine Domain Corruption</name>
				<text>The Corruption domain embodies the darkness that lurks in all creatures and the act of giving in to evil impulses. Only evil deities are ever associated with corruption, for they work through their servants to lead others down the path to evil. Clerics of corruption are as cancers in the world, tempting others toward wickedness to gain favor from their gods. Most conceal their true agenda and nature, wearing pleasing masks to conceal the horror they would visit on others.</text>
				<text />
				<text>Corruption Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.</text>
				<text />
				<text>1st - charm person, disguise self</text>
				<text />
				<text>3rd - crown of madness, suggestion</text>
				<text />
				<text>5th - fear, major image</text>
				<text />
				<text>7th - confusion, polymorph</text>
				<text />
				<text>9th - modify memory, seeming</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Corruption Domain: Tools of Corruption</name>
				<text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency in Deception and gain the friends and minor illusion cantrips if you don’t have them already.</text>
				<proficiency>Deception</proficiency>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Corruption Domain Channel Divinity: Inveigling Words</name>
				<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use Channel Divinity to influence another creature and make them amenable to your vile suggestions.</text>
				<text>	As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. If that creature can hear you and understand what you say, it must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature succeeds, you can’t use this feature on it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
				<text>	If the creature fails its save, it becomes charmed for 1 minute or until you or your companions do anything harmful to it. The charmed creature regards you as a trusted friend and confidant and you have advantage on Charisma checks you make against it. When the effect ends, the creature knows it was charmed by you.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Corruption Domain: Corrupting Words</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, when you have a creature charmed from your use of Inveigling Words, you can use an action to end the e ect and cast the suggestion spell against the target without expending a casting.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Corruption Domain: Divine Strike</name>
				<text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Corruption Domain: Corrupting Charm</name>
				<text>Starting at 17th level, creatures that become charmed from spells you cast or from your class features change their alignment to evil, if they are not evil already. If they are already evil, they have advantage on attack rolls and saving throws until they stop being charmed. When a creature stops being charmed, it must succeed on Wisdom saving throw or the change to its alignment becomes permanent.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>

	<spellList class="Cleric (Corruption)">
		<index name="Friends" />
		<index name="Minor Illusion" />
		<index name="Charm Person" />
		<index name="Disguise Self" />
		<index name="Crown of Madness" />
		<index name="Suggestion" />
		<index name="Fear" />
		<index name="Major Image" />
		<index name="Confusion" />
		<index name="Polymorph" />
		<index name="Modify Memory" />
		<index name="Seeming" />
	</spellList>
</compendium>