<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5" HB="HB">
	<feat name="Master of a Minor Domain">
		<name>Master of a Minor Domain</name>
		<text>You worship a deity that has dominion over more than one divine domain, and have access to spells that fall within your god’s extended portfolio. Choose a Divine Domain other than the one you already possess. The domain spells for that domain are added to your domain spell list.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat name="Sail Master">
		<name>Sail Master</name>
		<text>You’re an old hand when it comes to the sailing of ships and you know just what to do when danger strikes. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Strength or Dexterity by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You are proficient in navigator’s tools and vehicles (water) if you aren’t already. As well, you double your proficiency bonus for any checks that involve these proficiencies.</text>
		<text>• You ignore the effects of moving across difficult terrain caused by moving across the deck of a ship.</text>
		<text>• Swimming doesn’t halve your speed.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat name="Triad Feat: The Arm">
		<name>Triad Feat: The Arm</name>
		<text>The Arm acts for the Unity, learning to stand in the path of danger, slay foes, and take blows intended for her sisters, just as Canelle did on the Journey to the East. You can only select this feat at the same time as other characters take the feats for The Breath and The Eye, and you can never take either of those feats. You and those characters form your Unity. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Strength or Constitution by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You have proficiency in all saving throws in which other members of your Unity have proficiency.</text>
		<text>• You can communicate with the members of your Unity telepathically, even if you are not on the same plane.</text>
		<text>• While you are within 60 feet of both of the other members of your Unity, the other members of your Unity have resistance to all damage, and when they take damage, you take the same amount of damage.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat name="Triad Feat: The Breath">
		<name>Triad Feat: The Breath</name>
		<prerequisite>The ability to cast at least one spell</prerequisite>

		<text>The Breath speaks for the Unity, learning to understand and influence people as a leader and lawmaker, and to comprehend the world for her sisters, just as Naryne did on the Journey to the East. You can only select this feat at the same time as other characters take the feats for The Arm and The Eye, and you can never take either of those feats. You and those characters form your Unity. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Wisdom or Charisma by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You can communicate with the members of your Unity telepathically, even if you are not on the same plane.</text>
		<text>• When you cast a spell with a range of touch, another member of your Unity can deliver the spell as if they had cast the spell. That member of the Unity must be within 100 feet of you, and they must use their reaction to deliver the spell when you cast it. If the spell requires an attack roll, you use your attack modifier for the roll.</text>
		<text>• When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher on another member of your Unity that targets only one creature and doesn’t have a range of self, you can also target the other member of your Unity, provided he or she is within the range of the spell. To be eligible, the spell must be incapable of targeting more than one creature at the spell’s current level.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat name="Triad Feat: The Eye">
		<name>Triad Feat: The Eye</name>

		<text>The Eye observes for the Unity, learning to see details others miss, to hear the sounds others ignore, and to protect her family with her observations, just as Thellyne did on the Journey to the East. You can only select this feat at the same time as other characters take the feats for The Arm and The Breath, and you can never take either of those feats. You and those characters form your Unity. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Dexterity or Intelligence by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You can communicate with the members of your Unity telepathically, even if you are not on the same plane.</text>
		<text>• While you are within 60 feet of both other members of your Unity and none of you are Incapacitated, none of you can be surprised, and you (but not other members of the Unity) have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks.</text>
		<text>• As an action, other members of your Unity can see through your eyes and hear what you hear until the start of their next turn, gaining the benefits of any special senses that you have. During this time, they are deaf and blind with regard to their own surroundings. This benefit can be used at any distance, even across planes, provided you are conscious and not incapacitated.</text>
	</feat>
</compendium>
