<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<!-- Artificer Class and Subclass (Specialist) and spells de-duplicated into /Classes,
	but this project doesn't have a good solution to PC Monster and Magic Item compendiums yet -->
	<item>
		<name>Bag of Holding</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>15</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This bag has an interior space considerably larger than its outside dimensions, roughly 2 feet in diameter at the mouth and 4 feet deep. The bag can hold up to 500 pounds, not exceeding a volume of 64 cubic feet. The bag weighs 15 pounds, regardless of its contents. Retrieving an item from the bag requires an action.</text>
		<text>If the bag is overloaded, pierced, or torn, it ruptures and is destroyed, and its contents are scattered in the Astral Plane. If the bag is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, but the bag must be put right before it can be used again. Breathing creatures inside the bag can survive up to a number of minutes equal to 10 divided by the number of creatures (minimum 1 minute), after which time they begin to suffocate.</text>
		<text>Placing a bag of holding inside an extradimensional space created by a Heward's handy haversack, portable hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10 feet of the gate is sucked through it to a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 153</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Cap of Water Breathing</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While wearing this cap underwater, you can speak its command word as an action to create a bubble of air around your head. It allows you to breathe normally underwater. This bubble stays with you until you speak the command word again, the cap is removed, or you are no longer underwater.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 157</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Driftglobe</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This small sphere of thick glass weighs 1 pound. If you are within 60 feet of it, you can speak its command word and cause it to emanate the light or daylight spell. Once used, the daylight effect can't be used again until the next dawn.</text>
		<text>You can speak another command word as an action to make the illuminated globe rise into the air and float no more than 5 feet off the ground. The globe hovers in this way until you or another creature grasps it. If you move more than 60 feet from the hovering globe, it follows you until it is within 60 feet of you. It takes the shortest route to do so. If prevented from moving, the globe sinks gently to the ground and becomes inactive, and its light winks out.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 166</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Goggles of Night</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While wearing these dark lenses, you have darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision. wearing the goggles increases its range by 60 feet.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 172</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Sending Stones</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Sending stones come in pairs, with each smooth stone carved to match the other so the pairing is easily recognized. While you touch one stone, you can use an action to cast the sending spell from it. The target is the bearer of the other stone. If no creature bears the other stone, you know that fact as soon as you use the stone and don't cast the spell.</text>
		<text>Once sending is cast through the stones, they can't be used again until the next dawn. If one of the stones in a pair is destroyed, the other one becomes nonmagical.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 199</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Alchemy Jug</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>12</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This ceramic jug appears to be able to hold a gallon of liquid and weighs 12 pounds whether full or empty. Sloshing sounds can be heard from within the jug when it is shaken, even if the jug is empty.</text>
		<text>You can use an action and name one liquid from the table below to cause the jug to produce the chosen liquid. Afterward, you can uncork the jug as an action and pour that liquid out, up to 2 gallons per minute. The maximum amount of liquid the jug can produce depends on the liquid you named.</text>
		<text>Once the jug starts producing a liquid, it can't produce a different one, or more of one that has reached its maximum, until the next dawn.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Liquid — Max Amount:</text>
		<text>Acid — 8 ounces</text>
		<text>Basic poison — 1/2 ounce</text>
		<text>Beer — 4 gallons</text>
		<text>Honey — 1 gallon</text>
		<text>Mayonnaise — 2 gallons</text>
		<text>Oil — 1 quart</text>
		<text>Vinegar — 2 gallons</text>
		<text>Water, fresh — 8 gallons</text>
		<text>Water, salt — 12 gallons</text>
		<text>Wine — 1 gallon</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 150</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Helm of Comprehending Languages</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While wearing this helm, you can use an action to cast the comprehend languages spell from it at will.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 173</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Lantern of Revealing</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>While lit, this hooded lantern burns for 6 hours on 1 pint of oil, shedding bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Invisible creatures and objects are visible as long as they are in the lantern's bright light. You can use an action to lower the hood, reducing the light to dim light in a 5-foot radius.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 179</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Ring of Swimming</name>
		<type>RG</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>You have a swimming speed of 40 feet while wearing this ring.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 193</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Robe of Useful Items</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This robe has cloth patches of various shapes and colors covering it. While wearing the robe. you can use an action to detach one of the patches, causing it to become the object or creature it represents. Once the last patch is removed, the robe becomes an ordinary garment.</text>
		<text>The robe has two of each of the following patches:</text>
		<text>• Dagger</text>
		<text>• Bullseye lantern (filled and lit)</text>
		<text>• Steel mirror</text>
		<text>• 10-foot pole</text>
		<text>• Hempen rope (50 feet, coiled)</text>
		<text>• Sack</text>
		<text>In addition, the robe has 4d4 other patches. The DM chooses the patches or determines them randomly.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>d100 — Patch:</text>
		<text>01-08 — Bag of 100 gp</text>
		<text>09-15 — Silver coffer (1 foot long, 6 inches wide and deep) worth 500 gp</text>
		<text>16-22 — Iron door (up to 10 feet wide and 10 feet high, barred on one side of your choice), which you can place in an opening you can reach; it conforms to fit the opening, attaching and hinging itself</text>
		<text>23-30 — 10 gems worth 100 gp each</text>
		<text>31-44 — Wooden ladder (24 feet long)</text>
		<text>45-51 — A riding horse with saddle bags (see the Monster Manual for statistics)</text>
		<text>52-59 — Pit (a cube 10 feet on a side), which you can place on the ground within 10 feet of you</text>
		<text>60-68 — 4 potions of healing</text>
		<text>69-75 — Rowboat (12 feet long)</text>
		<text>76-83 — Spell scroll containing one spell of 1st to 3rd level</text>
		<text>84-90 — 2 mastiffs (see the Monster Manual for statistics)</text>
		<text>91-96 — Window (2 feet by 4 feet, up to 2 feet deep), which you can place on a vertical surface you can reach</text>
		<text>97-00 — Portable ram</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 195</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Rope of Climbing</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This 60-foot length of silk rope weighs 3 pounds and can hold up to 3,000 pounds. If you hold one end of the rope and use an action to speak the command word, the rope animates. As a bonus action, you can command the other end to move toward a destination you choose. That end moves 10 feet on your turn when you first command it and 10 feet on each of your turns until reaching its destination, up to its maximum length away, or until you tell it to stop. You can also tell the rope to fasten itself securely to an object or to unfasten itself, to knot or unknot itself, or to coil itself for carrying.</text>
		<text>If you tell the rope to knot, large knots appear at 1-foot intervals along the rope. While knotted, the rope shortens to a 50-foot length and grants advantage on checks made to climb it.</text>
		<text>The rope has AC 20 and 20 hit points. It regains 1 hit point every 5 minutes as long as it has at least 1 hit point. If the rope drops to 0 hit points, it is destroyed.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 197</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Wand of Magic Detection</name>
		<type>WD</type>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This wand has 3 charges. While holding it, you can expend 1 charge as an action to cast the detect magic spell from it. The wand regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 211</text>
		<roll>1d3</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Wand of Secrets</name>
		<type>WD</type>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>The wand has 3 charges. While holding it. you can use an action to expend 1 of its charges, and if a secret door or trap is within 30 feet of you, the wand pulses and points at the one nearest to you. The wand regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 211</text>
		<roll>1d3</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Bag of Beans</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>0.5</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Inside this heavy cloth bag are 3d4 dry beans. The bag weighs 1/2 pound plus 1/4 pound for each bean it contains.</text>
		<text>If you dump the bag's contents out on the ground, they explode in a 10-foot radius, extending from the beans. Each creature in the area, including you, must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 5d4 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. The fire ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</text>
		<text>If you remove a bean from the bag, plant it in dirt or sand, and then water it, the bean produces an effect 1 minute later from the ground where it was planted. The DM can choose an effect from the following table, determine it randomly, or create an effect.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>d100 — Effect:</text>
		<text>01 — 5d4 toadstools sprout. If a creature eats a toadstool, roll any die. On an odd roll, the eater must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or take Sd6 poison damage and become poisoned for 1 hour. On an even roll, the eater gains 5d6 temporary hit points for 1 hour.</text>
		<text>2-10 — A geyser erupts and spouts water, beer, berry juice, tea, vinegar, wine, or oil (DM's choice) 30 feet into the air for 1d12 rounds.</text>
		<text>11-20 — A treant sprouts (see the Monster Manual for statistics). There's a 50 percent chance that the treant is chaotic evil and attacks.</text>
		<text>21-30 — An animate, immobile stone statue in your likeness rises. It makes verbal threats against you. If you leave it and others come near, it describes you as the most heinous of villains and directs the newcomers to find and attack you. If you are on the same plane of existence as the statue, it knows where you are. The statue becomes inanimate after 24 hours.</text>
		<text>31-40 — A campfire with blue flames springs forth and burns for 24 hours (or until it is extinguished).</text>
		<text>41-50 — 1d6 + 6 shriekers sprout (see the Monster Manual for statistics).</text>
		<text>51-60 — 1d4 + 8 bright pink toads crawl forth. Whenever a toad is touched, it transforms into a Large or smaller monster of the DM's choice. The monster remains for 1 minute, then disappears in a puff of bright pink smoke.</text>
		<text>61-70 — A hungry bulette (see the Monster Manual for statistics) burrows up and attacks.</text>
		<text>71-80 A fruit tree grows. It has 1d10+20 fruit, 1d8 of which act as randomly determined magic potions, while one acts as an ingested poison of the DM's choice. The tree vanishes after 1 hour. Picked fruit remains, retaining any magic for 30 days.</text>
		<text>81-90 — A nest of 1d4 + 3 eggs springs up. Any creature that eats an egg must make a DC 20 Constitution saving throw. On a successful save, a creature permanently increases its lowest ability score by 1, randomly choosing among equally low scores. On a failed save, the creature takes 10d6 force damage from an internal magical explosion.</text>
		<text>91-99 — A pyramid with a 60-foot-square base bursts upward. Inside is a sarcophagus containing a mummy lord (see the Monster Manual for statistics). The pyramid is treated as the mummy lord's lair, and its sarcophagus contains treasure of the DM's choice.</text>
		<text>00 — A giant beanstalk sprouts, growing to a height of the DM's choice. The top leads where the DM chooses, such as to a great view, a cloud giant's castle, or a different plane of existence.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 152</text>
		<roll>5d4</roll>
		<roll>1d100</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Chime of Opening</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>This hollow metal tube measures about 1 foot long and weighs 1 pound. You can strike it as an action, pointing it at an object within 120 feet of you that can be opened, such as a door, lid, or lock. The chime issues a clear tone, and one lock or latch on the object opens unless the sound can't reach the object. If no locks or latches remain, the object itself opens.</text>
		<text>The chime can be used ten times. After the tenth time it cracks and becomes useless.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 158</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Decanter of Endless Water</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>2</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This stoppered flask sloshes when shaken, as if it contains water. The decanter weighs 2 pounds.</text>
		<text>You can use an action to remove the stopper and speak one of three command words, whereupon an amount of fresh water or salt water (your choice) pours out of the flask. The water stops pouring out at the start of your next turn. Choose from the following options:</text>
		<text>• "Stream" produces 1 gallon of water.</text>
		<text>• "Fountain" produces 5 gallons of water.</text>
		<text>• "Geyser" produces 30 gallons of water that gushes forth in a geyser 30 feet long and 1 foot wide. As a bonus action while holding the decanter, you can aim the geyser at a creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The target must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or take 1d4 bludgeoning damage and fall prone. Instead of a creature, you can target an object that isn't being worn or carried and that weighs no more than 200 pounds. The object is either knocked over or pushed up to 15 feet away from you.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 161</text>
		<roll>1d4</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Eyes of Minute Seeing</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>These crystal lenses fit over the eyes. While wearing them, you can see much better than normal out to a range of 1 foot. You have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) checks that rely on sight while searching an area or studying an object within that range.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 168</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Folding Boat</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>4</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>This object appears as a wooden box that measures 12 inches long, 6 inches wide, and 6 inches deep. It weighs 4 pounds and floats. It can be opened to store items inside. This item also has three command words, each requiring you to use an action to speak it.</text>
		<text>One command word causes the box to unfold into a boat 10 feet long, 4 feet wide, and 2 feet deep. The boat has one pair of oars, an anchor, a mast, and a lateen sail. The boat can hold up to four Medium creatures comfortably.</text>
		<text>The second command word causes the box to unfold into a ship 24 feet long, 8 feet wide; and 6 feet deep. The ship has a deck, rowing seats, five sets of oars, a steering oar, an anchor, a deck cabin, and a mast with a square sail. The ship can hold fifteen Medium creatures comfortably.</text>
		<text>When the box becomes a vessel, its weight becomes that of a normal vessel its size, and anything that was stored in the box remains in the boat.</text>
		<text>The third command word causes the folding boat to fold back into a box, provided that no creatures are aboard. Any objects in the vessel that can't fit inside the box remain outside the box as it folds. Any objects in the vessel that can fit inside the box do so.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 170</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Heward's Handy Haversack</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>5</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>This backpack has a central pouch and two side pouches, each of which is an extradimensional space. Each side pouch can hold up to 20 pounds of material, not exceeding a volume of 2 cubic feet. The large central pouch can hold up to 8 cubic feet or 80 pounds of material. The backpack always weighs 5 pounds, regardless of its contents.</text>
		<text>Placing an object in the haversack follows the normal rules for interacting with objects. Retrieving an item from the haversack requires you to use an action. When you reach into the haversack for a specific item, the item is always magically on top.</text>
		<text>The haversack has a few limitations. If it is overloaded, or if a sharp object pierces it or tears it, the haversack ruptures and is destroyed. If the haversack is destroyed, its contents are lost forever, although an artifact always turns up again somewhere. If the haversack is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, and the haversack must be put right before it can be used again. If a breathing creature is placed within the haversack, the creature can survive for up to 10 minutes, after which time it begins to suffocate.</text>
		<text>Placing the haversack inside an extradimensional space created by a bag of holding, portable hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10-feet of the gate is sucked through it and deposited in a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 174</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Boots of Striding and Springing</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While you wear these boots, your walking speed becomes 30 feet, unless your walking speed is higher, and your speed isn't reduced if you are encumbered or wearing heavy armor. In addition, you can jump three times the normal distance, though you can't jump farther than your remaining movement would allow.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 156</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Bracers of Archery</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While wearing these bracers, you have proficiency with the longbow and shortbow, and you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls on ranged attacks made with such weapons.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 156</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Brooch of Shielding</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While wearing this brooch, you have resistance to force damage, and you have immunity to damage from the magic missile spell.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 156</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Broom of Flying</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>3</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This wooden broom, which weighs 3 pounds, functions like a mundane broom until you stand astride it and speak its command word. It then hovers beneath you and can be ridden in the air. It has a flying speed of 50 feet. It can carry up to 400 pounds, but its flying speed becomes 30 feet while carrying over 200 pounds. The broom stops hovering when you land.</text>
		<text>You can send the broom to travel alone to a destination within 1 mile of you if you speak the command word, name the location, and are familiar with that place. The broom comes back to you when you speak another command word, provided that the broom is still within 1 mile of you.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 156</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Hat of Disguise</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While wearing this hat, you can use an action to cast the disguise self spell from it at will. The spell ends if the hat is removed.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 173</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Slippers of Spider Climbing</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While you wear these light shoes, you can move up, down, and across vertical surfaces and upside down along ceilings, while leaving your hands free. You have a climbing speed equal to your walking speed. However, the slippers don't allow you to move this way on a slippery surface, such as one covered by ice or oil.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 200</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Eyes of the Eagle</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>These crystal lenses fit over the eyes. While wearing them, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight. In conditions of clear visibility, you can make out details of even extremely distant creatures and objects as small as 2 feet across.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 168</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Gem of Brightness</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<weight>1</weight>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>This prism has 50 charges. While you are holding it, you can use an action to speak one of three command words to cause one of the following effects:</text>
		<text>• The first command word causes the gem to shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. This effect doesn't expend a charge. It lasts until you use a bonus action to repeat the command word or until you use another function of the gem.</text>
		<text>• The second command word expends 1 charge and causes the gem to fire a brilliant beam of light at one creature you can see within 60 feet of you. The creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or become blinded for 1 minute. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
		<text>• The third command word expends 5 charges and causes the gem to flare with blinding light in a 30-foot cone originating from it. Each creature in the cone must make a saving throw as if struck by the beam created with the second command word.</text>
		<text>When all of the gem's charges are expended, the gem becomes a nonmagical jewel worth 50 gp.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 171</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Gloves of Missile Snaring</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>These gloves seem to almost meld into your hands when you don them. When a ranged weapon attack hits you while you're wearing them, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d10 + your Dexterity modifier, provided that you have a free hand. If you reduce the damage to 0, you can catch the missile if it is small enough for you to hold in that hand.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 172</text>
		<roll>1d10+DEX</roll>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Gloves of Swimming and Climbing</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While wearing these gloves, climbing and swimming don't cost you extra movement, and you gain a +5 bonus to Strength (Athletics) checks made to climb or swim.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 172</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Ring of Jumping</name>
		<type>RG</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While wearing this ring, you can cast the jump spell from it as a bonus action at will, but can target only yourself when you do so.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 191</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Ring of Mind Shielding</name>
		<type>RG</type>
		<text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While wearing this ring, you are immune to magic that allows other creatures to read your thoughts, determine whether you are lying, know your alignment, or know your creature type. Creatures can telepathically communicate with you only if you allow it.</text>
		<text>You can use an action to cause the ring to become invisible until you use another action to make it visible, until you remove the ring, or until you die.</text>
		<text>If you die while wearing the ring, your soul enters it, unless it already houses a soul. You can remain in the ring or depart for the afterlife. As long as your soul is in the ring, you can telepathically communicate with any creature wearing it. A wearer can't prevent this telepathic communication.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 191</text>
	</item>
	<item>
		<name>Wings of Flying</name>
		<type>W</type>
		<text>Rarity: Rare</text>
		<text>Requires Attunement</text>
		<text/>
		<text>While wearing this cloak, you can use an action to speak its command word. This turns the cloak into a pair of bat wings or bird wings on your back for 1 hour or until you repeat the command word as an action. The wings give you a flying speed of 60 feet. When they disappear, you can't use them again for 1d12 hours.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 214</text>
		<roll>1d12</roll>
	</item>
</compendium>
