<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
<class>

	<name>Shield Master</name>

	<hd>12</hd>
	<feature>
	<name>Multiclassing Prerequisites</name>
	<text>To qualify for multiclassing into the Shield Master class, you must meet these prerequisites:a 13 Strength and 13 Constitution</text>
	</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Shield Master</name>
			<text>A master of the shield who specializes in defending themselves and those they travel with. Whether made to combat the harsh magics of spellcasters, or trained to become the steel-covered defender of the group, a Shield Master excels in defense and surviving what most others couldn’t.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Shield Up, Soldier</name>
			<text>You are a Shield Master. Whether you are a soldier in training, or a mercenary that happens to be more proficient with their shield than most, you are a pro when it comes to defense. Others you travel with might be able to hit harder and deal more damage in comparison, but that doesn’t faze you. Because at the end of the day you’re able to go toe-to-toe with some of the worst creatures the world has to offer and laugh as their attacks bounce harmlessly off your shield. </text>
<text />
<text>As a Shield Master, you put more focus into training your defensive capabilities than your offensive ones. Most of your fellow Shield Masters come from some form of military training; being utilized in armies or the local guard regiment as the tank of the group meant to draw attacks away from the squishier members of your party. That or you could be a member of a mercenary group that’s sent in when skirmishes get a little too hot for the rest of the group to handle. Either way, your job mostly comes about from having to deal with combat on a regular basis and not wanting to be poked full of holes like other party members. </text>
<text />
<text>Whether you’re a grizzled old veteran who has survived some of the most brutal moments in more than a few skirmishes, or the heavy duty guardsmen sent in when things truly get well out of hand; seeing your well armored and defensible form spells disaster for your enemies and a miracle for your allies. Who needs the calvary when you can have a ball of pure defense? </text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Creating a Shield Master</name>
			<text>When creating a Shield Master it is important to keep in mind that you aren’t the one dealing massive amounts of damage; you’re the one rushing in and taking all the hits that would normally fell your teammates but hardly put a dent in your own armor. It’s typically a job seen for those with a military background of some sort, or those whose job is to protect others and want to do it efficiently. </text>
			<text   />
<text>So that brings up the question: Why did you become a Shield Master? What are you trying to protect? Yourself? Others? Are you in some sort of group and serve as the tank? Were you assigned this job? Did you intentionally pick up the class to be able to wade into battle relatively unharmed? Or did you shoulder the responsibility as a tank so that others wouldn’t get hurt? Is this for some reason in your backstory? Or do you simply like laughing at enemies as they try to hit you? </text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
		<name>Path of the Frontline Shield Master</name>
		<text> On the battlefield, you are the protector of the team. You laugh in the face of danger as attacks clink uselessly off your armor, the few that get through barely hurting at all. You are a walking behemoth in terms of defense.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
		<name>Path of the Mage Bane Shield Master</name>
		<text>You are a figure all magic users should fear. Stepping into the battlefield, you specialize in absorbing the damage caused by spells and preventing the casters from casting their spells in the first place. </text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Quick Build</name>
			<text>You can make a Shield Master quickly by following these suggestions. First, Strength should be your highest ability score, followed by Constitution. Second, choose the Soldier background.</text>
			</feature>
	<Proficiency>Strength, Constitution</Proficiency>
		<feature>
			<name>Proficiencies</name>
			<text>Armor: All </text>
			<text /><!--this is a line break in the text block-->
			<text>Weapons: Simple and Martial Weapons, Shields</text>
			<text />
			<text>Tools: None </text>
			<text />
			<text>Saving Throws:Strength, Constitution </text>
			<text />
			<text>Skills: Pick 3 from Athletics, Perception, Intimidation, or Survival</text>
		</feature>
		<feature>
			<name>Starting Equipment</name>
			<text>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background.</text>
			<text />
			<text>• (a) A morningstar or (b) a longsword  </text>
			<text />
			<text>• (a) A hand-crossbow with 20 bolts or (b) a longbow with 20 arrows or (c) 5 javelins </text>
			<text />
			<text>• (a) An Explorer’s Pack or (b) a Dungeoner’s Pack  </text>
          <text />
			<text>• (a) A shield and chainmail or (b) A tower shield and chainshirt </text>
             <text />
			<text>• If you are using starting wealth, you have 3d6 x 10 in funds. </text>
		</feature>
		<autolevel level="1">
		<feature>
			<name>Master of Shields</name>

			<text>Where most warriors spend their time learning how to fight with weapons, you have practiced how to best utilize a shield for not just defense but offense as well. At 1st level, whenever you are wielding a shield and are not incapacitated you may add your shield’s AC bonus to any Dexterity saving throw you make against a spell or other harmful AOE effect. If this effect is a saving throw to determine whether or not you take half damage, you may use your reaction to impose your shield between you and the effect to take no damage so long as you make the save. </text>
<text  />
<text>With the Shield Master Feat you instead take one quarter damage on a failed save, and no damage on a successful one. You also may add double your shield's AC value to your Dexterity saving throw, provided you are able to. 
You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>

		</feature>
    
		<feature>
			<name>Untiring Arm</name>
			<text>A shield does not burden you but aids you instead. When using a shield, you do not feel its weight- meaning that its weight does not count towards encumbrance. In addition, whenever you use a tower shield you do not have disadvantage on Attack rolls. You still, however, have disadvantage on Stealth rolls. </text>
		</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="2">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Shield Bash</name>
	<text>A shield may mainly be for defense, but you know how to utilize it just as deftly as a weapon. At 2nd level, on your turn you may take an Attack action to bash your opponent with your shield. You add your proficiency bonus to the Attack roll. If the attack hits, you deal 1d6 + your Strength Modifier. The target must then make a Strength Saving throw of 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength Modifier or be pushed back 10 feet. If this pushes the target outside the attack range of your allies, they may make opportunity attacks against the creature. You, however, cannot. </text>
<text  />
<text>You may perform a Shield Bash as your second attack once you reach 5th level. </text>
<text  />
<text>However, you cannot perform two Shield Bash attacks if you choose to dual-wield shields (should your DM allow you to initially). Your offhand shield will only do 1d4 + your Strength modifier of damage should you hit. </text>
<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="3">
	
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Frontline: Armored Hide</name>
	<text>It takes a lot to get through your defense, as enemies will soon learn. At 3rd level, you are resistant to to all forms of bludgeoning, slashing, and piercing damage. This can stack with your additional resistance, reducing the damage to one quarter. </text>
<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>
		
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Mage Bane Shield Master: Magical Tolerance</name>
	<text>Your particular type of training has prepared you to resist the power magic users wield. At 3rd level you may pick one type from Fire, Cold, Lightning, Psychic, Poison, Thunder, Acid, Necrotic, Radiant, or Force to be resistant to. In addition, your damage resistance gained from extreme protection extends to magical, silvered, and adamantine weapons as well. </text>
<text  />
<text>At 7th, 11th, 15th, and 19th you may pick an additional type to gain resistance to. 
<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability.</text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="4">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
	<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
	</feature>
	
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="5">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Extra Attack</name>
	<text>Beginning at 5th lvl, when you take the attack option, you may attack twice.</text>
	</feature>

	<feature>
	<name>Extreme Protection</name>
	<text>You know just where to put your shield to get the best protection from it. At 5th level, you now resistant all forms of bludgeoning, slashing and piercing damage. This can stack with additional resistances granted by other means. In addition, you gain an additional +1 to your AC when wielding a shield on top of the current bonus it gives. </text>
	<text  />
	<text>This benefit increases to +2 when you reach 10th level, +3 when you reach 15th level, and +4 when you reach 20th level.</text>
	<text  />
	<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability.</text>
	</feature>
	
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="6">
	
		
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Frontline: Shield Wall</name>
	<text>You were made to protect your allies and be their shield. As such, at 6th level any attacks made against your allies when they are 5 feet from you are done with disadvantage. In addition, any allies near you when your “Sunken In” ability is active benefit from the bonus AC your shield provides, including your Extreme Protection bonus. Furthermore, you may use your Reaction to provide one ally within 5ft of you ¾ cover against an attack targeting them when you are Sunken In. This does not work against AoE spells or attacks. </text>
	<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>
	
	
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Mage Bane Shield Master: Reflective Shield</name>
	<text>Time to give those spellcasters a taste of their own medicine. At 6th level, you can use your Reaction to reflect back a spell that specifically targets you. Roll an Attack (d20) and add your proficiency modifier plus your Strength modifier. If the result is higher than the target’s spell attack roll or the target’s spellcasting DC, then you reflect the spell back to them. </text>
<text  />
<text>This does not work against area-effect spells or spells that do not target you specifically. </text>
<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Sunken In</name>
	<text>When you decide to settle into a defensive stance, there aren’t many who can break past it. At 7th level, if you do not use your movement on your turn you go into a defensive stance. Meaning that all attacks made against you are done with disadvantage. In addition, if a creature tries to leave your attack range and you manage to hit them with an opportunity attack, you reduce their movement to 0. If you take the Sentinel feat, you not only reduce their speed to 0, but also make them fall prone. Furthermore, any attack or effect that knocks you prone that you make a save for, you make the save with advantage. </text>
	<text  />
	<text>In order to use this ability, you must not move (even 5 feet) on your turn. </text>
	<text  />
	<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="8">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
	<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="9">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Shielded Mind</name>
	<text>You have not only become the master of shields, but also the master of a shielded mind. At 9th level, you gain proficiency with wisdom saving throws. You also have advantage on saving throws against being charmed, frightened, or being controlled. If you have the fey ancestry trait any attempt to charm, frighten, or control you is additionally made with disadvantage. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	
	
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Frontline: Offensive Defense</name>
	<text>Defense can make the best offense; or at least as far as you’re concerned. At 10th level you are able to modify your shield (spending 25 gold) so that it is equipped with spikes. Now when you do a Shield Bash and it successfully hits, you add an additional 2d4 piercing damage to your damage roll. </text>
	<text  />
<text>You cannot modify your offhand shield, should you be dual-wielding shields, to gain this additional damage at this level. 
You must be wielding a shield to use this ability.</text>
	</feature>
	
	
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Mage Bane Shield Master: Magical Enfusement</name>
	<text>Taking the brute of spells with your shield has begun to warp the metal in very mysterious ways. At 10th level, you may choose to imbue your shield with one of the magical damage types you have chosen resistance for. This gives you additional resistance against that one type (you now take a quarter of that damage from that type), and your Shield Bash now does 1d8 of that damage against foes. In addition, whenever you make a Shield Bash attack against a spellcaster using a concentration spell, they must make the save with disadvantage. </text>
	<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="11">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Armor Piercer</name>
	<text>Defense is what you’re all about. So you know just where to hit to find the weakest point. At 11th level, whenever you make an Attack against another creature, you may use up your Bonus Action to ignore 2 points of their AC when making your roll. If the attack hits, then the very next attack done against the creature has advantage. </text>
<text  />
<text>The amount of AC you ignore increases to 3 at 16th level, and 4 at 20th level. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="12">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
	<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="13">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Brutal Force</name>
	<text>Further training has taught you how to put your full weight against your shield bash. At 13th level, whenever you make a Shield Bash against a creature and they fail, you may choose to either knock them prone or disarm them. In addition, should you manage to trap an enemy between you and a wall while performing a shield bash, if the target fails the save they will take an additional 2d8 + your Strength modifier of bludgeoning damage rather than moving 10 feet back. </text>
<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="14">
	
	
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Frontline: Indomitable Force</name>
	<text>Your defense capabilities are practically second to none. At 14th level, you have advantage on any saves that determine whether or not you are knocked prone or moved from your space. When your “Sunken In” ability is active, you are immune to being knocked prone or moved from your spot.</text<
	<text  />
<text>You are also now capable to dual-wield shields and gain proficiency in your Attack rolls with your offhand shield. The offhand shield now does the same 1d6 damage your main shield does, and it can also be modified by your Offensive Defense ability to deal the additional 2d4 piercing damage. However, the additional shield still does not give you the AC bonus granted by your Extreme protection ability and cannot do a Shield Bash attack (meaning the target does not have to make a Strength save, but will still take the damage associated with the shield). </text>
	</feature>
	
	
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Mage Bane Shield Master:Spell Disturbance</name>
	<text>You can tell the signs of a spell about to fire, so you know exactly when to strike. At 14th level, whenever a spell is cast that only targets you, they have disadvantages on the roll. In addition, whenever a spell caster within 5ft of you casts a spell, you may take a Reaction to disrupt the spell. Make an Attack roll with your shield (1d20 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier). If it hits, the spell instantly fails. </text>
	<text  />
	<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Hostile Barrier</name>
	<text>You might not be the heaviest hitter, but ignoring you isn’t a wise decision. At 15th level whenever an enemy steps into your Attack range, you may take an opportunity attack against them with your shield. If it manages to hit while you are Sunken In, then their movement speed is reduced to 0 and they cannot move past you. If you additionally have the Sentinel feat, they are then knocked prone. </text>
	<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="16">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
	<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="17">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Mobile Defender</name>
	<text>Though you do best when you’ve set yourself up in your position, you’ve learned how to maintain that sort of stability even after moving. At 17th level your movement speed increases by 20 feet. In addition, you may now move 15 feet and still be able to maintain your Sunken In status. </text>
	<text  />
<text>Furthermore, any time you leave an enemy’s attack range, any opportunity attacks made against you are done so with disadvantage as you raise your shield while fleeing. </text>
<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Power Bash</name>
	<text>Your experience in using your shield not only for its defensive properties, but also for its offensive capabilities has made you all the more effective in using it. At 18th level, whenever you make a Shield Bash you may take up your Bonus Action to make the attack a Power Bash. If the attack hits, the target will be pushed back 10 feet regardless. However, now if they fail to make a Strength saving throw against 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier, they are thrown back in a straight line for 30 feet from you. If they do not hit anything before then, they fall prone at the end of the distance and take 1d8 + your Strength Modifier of damage. However, if they hit a wall or another being during this 30 feet, they take 4d8 + your Strength Modifier of damage and stop there. If what they hit is another creature, that creature also takes the damage and must make the same Strength Saving throw against 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength Modifier or also be knocked prone.</text> 
<text  />
<text>Lastly, if you have taken the Frontline Shield Master Path and are dual-wielding shields, your offhand shield may also make a Shield Bash attack. Though only one may do a Power Bash since it uses your Bonus Action. </text>
<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="19">
	
	<feature>
	<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
	<text>You can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="20">
	
	
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Frontline: The Walking Bastion</name>
	<text>You are essentially a walking fortress at this point; your defensive capabilities are legendary in nature. At 20th level, your “Sunken In” ability is always active regardless of whether or not you have moved. </text>
	<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability. </text>
	</feature>
	
	
	<feature optional="YES">
	<name>Path of the Mage Bane Shield Master: Anti-Magic Master</name>
	<text>All your time dealing first-hand with the brunt of magic has taught you just how to deal with it to minimize its effects. At 20th level, you gain resistance to all types of magically caused damage and have advantage on all spell-caused saving throws. This resistance stacks with your Magical Tolerance types (reducing them to quarter damage), and makes you immune to the damage type you choose for Magical Enfusement. </text>
<text  />
<text>You must be wielding a shield to use this ability.</text>
	</feature>

	</autolevel>

</class>
</compendium>
