<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Bard" HB="HB">
		<name>Bard (Keys)</name>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Bard College: College of Keys</name>
				<text>Bards of the College of Keys believe that performance can manipulate anything, be it person, magic, or machine. Their preternatural charm allows these daring performers to delve into dungeons seething with traps, assured that they can use their words and song to protect themselves and allies. These bards often become spies and infiltrators, since no lock can stand up to their charms.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Keys: Bonus Proficiency</name>
				<text>When you join the College of Keys at 3rd level, you gain proficiency with thieves' tools, if you don't already have it.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Keys: Key Change</name>
				<text>Also at 3rd level, you learn to bend locks and traps with dashing style. If you have Expertise in one of your Charisma skills, you can use that skill instead of making a Dexterity check with your thieves' tools.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Keys: Timbre Illuminous</name>
				<text>At 3rd level, you can coax a variety of information from a mechanism regarding its composition using merely verse and rhyme. When you spend at least 1 minute in speaking or singing to a construct or inanimate mechanism, you can expend one Bardic Inspiration to learn certain information about its capabilities compared to your own. The DM tells you two of the following characteristics of the mechanism, of your choice:</text>
				<text>• Purpose (lock, trap, surveillance, etc.)</text>
				<text>• Intricacy (singular, compound, or complex)</text>
				<text>• Nature (magical, mundane, or otherwise),</text>
				<text>• Approximate diffiiculty class (easy, hard, nearly impossible, etc.)</text>
				<text>• Elemental energies present (if any)</text>
				<text>• Additional imbed magical qualities (if any)</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Keys: Cypheric Ostinato</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you learn to control vocal range and resonance of your voice to offset the magic or material mechanisms within security and surveillance spells.</text>
				<text>	When you use your action to disarm, dispel, and when you make a saving throw to dodge a glyph, lock, trap, or ward, or as part of a divination spell to locate or scry with you as the target, you can choose to expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration, rolling a Bardic Inspiration die and adding the number rolled to the skill check or saving throw. You can choose to use this feature after seeing the roll but before the DM determines whether the ability check or saving throw succeeds or fails, or before the trap deals its damage.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>College of Keys: Master Keynote</name>
				<text>At 14th level, you learn how to focus the pitch and rhythm of your voice cause even the strongest measures designed to keep you out to fail. As an action, you can expend one use of your Bardic Inspiration to strike a frequency that suspends the magical and mechanical enhancements locks, traps, and wards within a 30-foot radius of you. Once you use this feature, roll a Bardic Inspiration die. The number rounds these impediments are suspended is equal to the result.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
</compendium>