<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
	<class name="Cleric"><name>Cleric</name>
        <hd>8</hd>
        <proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma</proficiency>
        <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
        <autolevel level="1"> <slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="2"> <slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="3"> <slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="4"> <slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="5"> <slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="6"> <slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="7"> <slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="8"> <slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="9"> <slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="10"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="11"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="12"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="13"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="14"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="15"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="16"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="17"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="18"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="19"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="20"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="1">
            <feature>
                <name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
                <text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
                <text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
                <text>Weapons: simple weapons</text>
                <text>Tools: none</text>
                <text>Skills: Choose two from History, Insight, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Starting Equipment</name>
                <text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• (a) a mace or (b) a warhammer (if proficient)</text>
                <text>• (a) scale mail, (b) leather armor, or (c) chain mail (if proficient)</text>
                <text>• (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>
                <text>• (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
                <text>• A shield and a holy symbol</text>
                <text />
                <text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="1">
            <feature>
                <name>Spellcasting</name>
                <text>As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for a selection of cleric spells.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Cantrips</text>
                <text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn additional cleric cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Cleric table.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
                <text>The Cleric table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
                <text>    You prepare the list of cleric spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
                <text>    For example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>
                <text>    You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
                <text>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells. The power of your spells comes from your devotion to your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
                <text>    Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
                <text>    Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
                <text />
                <text>Ritual Casting</text>
                <text>You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
                <text>You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Divine Domain</name>
                <text>Choose one domain related to your deity: Arcana, Knowledge, Life, Light, Nature, Tempest, Trickery, or War. Each domain is detailed in their own feature, and each one provides examples of gods associated with it. Your choice grants you domain spells and other features when you choose it at 1st level. It also grants you additional ways to use Channel Divinity when you gain that feature at 2nd level, and additional benefits at 6th, 8th, and 17th levels.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Domain Spells</text>
                <text>Each domain has a list of spells-its domain spells-that you gain at the cleric levels noted in the domain description. Once you gain a domain spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
                <text>    If you have a domain spell that doesn't appear on the cleric spell list, the spell is nonetheless a cleric spell for you.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="2">
            <feature>
                <name>Channel Divinity</name>
                <text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as noted in the domain description.</text>
                <text>    When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.</text>
                <text>    Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell save DC.</text>
                <text>    Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests, and beginning at 18th level, you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead</name>
                <text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.</text>
                <text>    A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="4">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="5">
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 1/2)</name>
                <text>Starting at 5th level, when an undead of CR 1/2 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="6">
            <feature>
                <name>Channel Divinity (2/rest)</name>
                <text>Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="8">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 1)</name>
                <text>Starting at 8th level, when an undead of CR 1 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="10">
            <feature>
                <name>Divine Intervention</name>
                <text>Beginning at 10th level, you can call on your deity to intervene on your behalf when your need is great.</text>
                <text>    Imploring your deity's aid requires you to use your action. Describe the assistance you seek, and roll percentile dice. If you roll a number equal to or lower than your cleric level, your deity intervenes. The DM chooses the nature of the intervention; the effect of any cleric spell or cleric domain spell would be appropriate. If your deity intervenes, you can't use this feature again for 7 days. Otherwise, you can use it again after you finish a long rest.</text>
                <text>    At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="11">
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 2)</name>
                <text>Starting at 11th level, when an undead of CR 2 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="12">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="14">
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 3)</name>
                <text>Starting at 14th level, when an undead of CR 3 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="16">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="17">
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 4)</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, when an undead of CR 4 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="18">
            <feature>
                <name>Channel Divinity (3/rest)</name>
                <text>Beginning at 18th level, you can use your Channel Divinity three times between rests.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="19">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="20">
            <feature>
                <name>Divine Intervention Improvement</name>
                <text>At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Nature</name>
                <text>Gods of nature are as varied as the natural world itself, from inscrutable gods of the deep forests (such as Silvanus, Obad-Hai, Chislev, Balinor, and Pan) to friendly deities associated with particular springs and groves (such as Eldath). Druids revere nature as a whole and might serve one of these deities, practicing mysterious rites and reciting all-but-forgotten prayers in their own secret tongue. But many of these gods have clerics as well, champions who take a more active role in advancing the interests of a particular nature god. These clerics might hunt the evil monstrosities that despoil the woodlands, bless the harvest of the faithful, or wither the crops of those who anger their gods.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Nature Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - animal friendship, speak with animals</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - barkskin, spike growth</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - plant growth, wind wall</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - dominate beast, grasping vine</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - insect plague, tree stride</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Acolyte of Nature</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you learn one druid cantrip of your choice. You also gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, or Survival.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>Also at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain Channel Divinity: Charm Animals and Plants</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to charm animals and plants.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you present your holy symbol and invoke the name of your deity. Each beast or plant creature that can see you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is charmed by you for 1 minute or until it takes damage. While it is charmed by you, it is friendly to you and other creatures you designate.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Dampen Elements</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, when you or a creature within 30 feet of you takes acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can use your reaction to grant resistance to the creature against that instance of the damage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Master of Nature</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to command animals and plant creatures. While creatures are charmed by your Charm Animals and Plants feature, you can take a bonus action on your turn to verbally command what each of those creatures will do on its next turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Grave (UA)</name>
                <text>Gods of the grave watch over the line between life and death. To these deities, death and the afterlife are a foundational part of the multiverse's workings. To resist death, or to desecrate the dead's rest, is an abomination. Deities of the grave include Kelemvor, Wee Jas, the ancestral spirits of the Undying Court, Hades, Anubis, and Osiris. These deities teach their followers to respect the dead and pay them due homage. Followers of these deities seek to put restless spirits to rest, destroy the undead wherever they find them, and ease the suffering of dying creatures. Their magic also allows them to stave off a creature's death, though they refuse to use such magic to extend a creature's lifespan beyond its mortal limits.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Grave Domain Spells</text>
                <text>1st - bane, false life</text>
                <text>3rd - gentle repose, ray of enfeeblement</text>
                <text>5th - revivify, vampiric touch</text>
                <text>7th - blight, death ward</text>
                <text>9th - antilife shell, raise dead</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Divine Domain is from Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Circle of Mortality</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to manipulate the line between life and death. When you cast a spell that restores hit points to a living creature currently at 0, treat any dice rolled to determine the spell's healing as having rolled their maximum result. In addition, if you have the spare the dying cantrip, you can cast it as a bonus action.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Eyes of the Grave</name>
                <text>Starting at 1st level, you gain an innate sense of creatures whose existence is an insult to the natural cycle of life. If you spend 1 minute in uninterrupted contemplation, you can determine the presence and nature of undead creatures in the area. This detection extends up to 1 mile in all directions. You learn the number of undead and their distance and direction from you. In addition, you learn the creature type of the undead in that area that has the highest challenge rating. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain Channel Divinity: Path to the Grave</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to mark another creature's life force for termination. </text>
                <text>	As an action, you touch a creature. The next time that creature takes damage from a spell or an attack from you or an ally, it is vulnerable to that spell or attack's damage. If the source of damage has multiple damage types, the creature is vulnerable to all of them. The vulnerability applies only to the first time that source inflicts damage, and then ends. </text>
                <text>	If the creature has resistance or is immune to the damage, it instead loses its resistance or immunity against that spell or attack when it first applies damage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Sentinel at Death's Door</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, you gain the ability to impede death's progress. As a reaction when you or an ally that you can see within 30 feet of you suffers a critical hit, you can turn that attack into a normal hit. Any effects triggered by a critical hit are canceled. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Keeper of Souls</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to manipulate the boundary between life and death. When an enemy you can see dies within 30 feet of you, you or one ally of your choice that is within 30 feet of you regains hit points equal to the enemy's number of Hit Dice. You can use this feature as long as you aren't incapacitated, but no more than once per round.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: War</name>
                <text>War has many manifestations. It can make heroes of ordinary people. It can be desperate and horrific, with acts of cruelty and cowardice eclipsing instances of excellence and courage. In either case, the gods of war watch over warriors and reward them for their great deeds. The clerics of such gods excel in battle, inspiring others to fight the good fight or offering acts of violence as prayers. Gods of war include champions of honor and chivalry (such as Torm, Heironeous, and Kiri-Jolith) as well as gods of destruction and pillage (such as Erythnul, the Fury, Gruumsh, and Ares) and gods of conquest and domination (such as Bane, Hextor, and Maglubiyet). Other war gods (such as Tempus, Nike, and Nuada) take a more neutral stance, promoting war in all its manifestations and supporting warriors in any circumstance.</text>
                <text />
                <text>War Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - divine favor, shield of faith</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - magic weapon, spiritual weapon</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - crusader's mantle, spirit guardians</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - freedom of movement, stoneskin</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - flame strike, hold monster</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain: War Priest</name>
                <text>From 1st level, your god delivers bolts of inspiration to you while you are engaged in battle. When you use the Attack action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain Channel Divinity: Guided Strike</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to strike with supernatural accuracy. When you make an attack roll, you can use your Channel Divinity to gain a +10 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain Channel Divinity: War God's Blessing</name>
                <text>At 6th level, when a creature within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to grant that creature a +10 bonus to the roll, using your Channel Divinity. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain: Avatar of Battle</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Life</name>
                <text>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy - one of the fundamental forces of the universe -  that sustains all life. The gods of life promote vitality and health through healing the sick and wounded, caring for those in need, and driving away the forces of death and undeath. Almost any non-evil deity can claim influence over this domain, particularly agricultural deities (such as Chauntea, Arawai, and Demeter), sun gods (such as Lathander, Pelor, and Re-Horakhty), gods of healing or endurance (such as Ilmater, Mishakal, Apollo, and Diancecht), and gods of home and community (such as Hestia, Hathor, and Boldrei).</text>
                <text />
                <text>Life Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - bless, cure wounds</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - lesser restoration, spiritual weapon</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - beacon of hope, revivify</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - death ward, guardian of faith</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - mass cure wounds, raise dead</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Disciple of Life</name>
                <text>Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2 + the spell's level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain Channel Divinity: Preserve Life</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to heal the badly injured.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you present your holy symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore a number of hit points equal to five times your cleric level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. You can't use this feature on an undead or a construct.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Blessed Healer</name>
                <text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others heal you as well. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hit points to a creature other than you, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the spell's level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Supreme Healing</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, when you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hit points to a creature, you restore 12.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Knowledge</name>
                <text>The gods of knowledge - including Oghma, Boccob, Gilean, Aureon, and Thoth - value learning and understanding above all. Some teach that knowledge is to be gathered and shared in libraries and universities, or promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention. Some deities hoard knowledge and keep its secrets to themselves. And some promise their followers that they will gain tremendous power if they unlock the secrets of the multiverse. Followers of these gods study esoteric lore, collect old tomes, delve into the secret places of the earth, and learn all they can. Some gods of knowledge promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention, including smith deities like Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Knowledge Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - command, identify</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - augury, suggestion</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - nondetection, speak with dead</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - arcane eye, confusion</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - legend lore, scrying</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain: Blessings of Knowledge</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you learn two languages of your choice. You also become proficient in your choice of two of the following skills: Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion.</text>
                <text>    Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those skills.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain Channel Divinity: Knowledge of the Ages</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to tap into a divine well of knowledge. As an action, you choose one skill or tool. For 10 minutes, you have proficiency with the chosen skill or tool.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain Channel Divinity: Read Thoughts</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to read a creature's thoughts. You can then use your access to the creature's mind to command it.</text>
                <text>As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature succeeds on the saving throw, you can't use this feature on it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
                <text>If the creature fails its save, you can read its surface thoughts (those foremost in its mind, reflecting its current emotions and what it is actively thinking about) when it is within 60 feet of you. This effect lasts for 1 minute.</text>
                <text>During that time, you can use your action to end this effect and cast the suggestion spell on the creature without expending a spell slot. The target automatically fails its saving throw against the spell.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain: Potent Spellcasting</name>
                <text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain: Visions of the Past</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, you can call up visions of the past that relate to an object you hold or your immediate surroundings. You spend at least 1 minute in meditation and prayer, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of recent events. You can meditate in this way for a number of minutes equal to your Wisdom score and must maintain concentration during that time, as if you were casting a spell.</text>
                <text>    Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
                <text>    Object Reading. Holding an object as you meditate, you can see visions of the object's previous owner. After meditating for 1 minute, you learn how the owner acquired and lost the object, as well as the most recent significant event involving the object and that owner. If the object was owned by another creature in the recent past (within a number of days equal to your Wisdom score), you can spend 1 additional minute for each owner to learn the same information about that creature.</text>
                <text>    Area Reading. As you meditate, you see visions of recent events in your immediate vicinity (a room, street, tunnel, clearing, or the like, up to a 50-foot cube), going back a number of days equal to your Wisdom score. For each minute you meditate, you learn about one significant event, beginning with the most recent. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as battles and betrayals, marriages and murders, births and funerals. However, they might also include more mundane events that are nevertheless important in your current situation.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Death</name>
                <text>The Death domain is concerned with the forces that cause death, as well as the negative energy that gives rise to undead creatures. Deities such as Chemosh, Myrkul, and WeeJas are patrons of necromancers, death knights, liches, mummy lords, and vampires. Gods of the Death domain also embody murder (Anubis, Bhaal, and Pyremius), pain (Iuz or Loviatar), disease or poison (Incabulos, Talona, or Morgion), and the underworld (Hades and He!).</text>
                <text />
                <text>Death Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - false life, ray of sickness</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - animate dead, vampiric touch</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - blight, death ward</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - antilife shell, cloudkill</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When the cleric chooses this domain at 1st level, he or she gains proficiency with martial weapons.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Reaper</name>
                <text>At 1st level, the cleric learns one necromancy cantrip of his or her choice from any spell list. When the cleric casts a necromancy cantrip that normally targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain Channel Divinity: Touch of Death</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to destroy another creature's life force by touch.</text>
                <text>    When the cleric hits a creature with a melee attack, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to deal extra necrotic damage to the target. The damage equals 5 + twice his or her cleric level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Inescapable Destruction</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, the cleric's ability to channel negative energy becomes more potent. Necrotic damage dealt by the character's cleric spells and Channel Divinity options ignores resistance to necrotic damage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric's turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Improved Reaper</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, when the cleric casts a Necromancy spell of 1st through 5th level that targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other. If the spell consumes its material components, the cleric must provide them for each target.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Trickery</name>
                <text>Gods of trickery - such as Tymora, Beshaba, Olidammara, the Traveler, Garl Glittergold, and Loki - are mischief-makers and instigators who stand as a constant challenge to the accepted order among both gods and mortals. They're patrons of thieves, scoundrels, gamblers, rebels, and liberators. Their clerics are a disruptive force in the world, puncturing pride, mocking tyrants, stealing from the rich, freeing captives, and flouting hollow traditions. They prefer subterfuge, pranks, deception, and theft rather than direct confrontation.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Trickery Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - charm person, disguise self</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - mirror image, pass without trace</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - blink, dispel magic</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - dimension door, polymorph</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - dominate person, modify memory</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain: Blessing of the Trickster</name>
                <text>Starting when you choose this domain at 1st level, you can use your action to touch a willing creature other than yourself to give it advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. This blessing lasts for 1 hour or until you use this feature again.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain Channel Divinity: Invoke Duplicity</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create an illusory duplicate of yourself.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you create a perfect illusion of yourself that lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell). The illusion appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the illusion up to 30 feet to a space you can see, but it must remain within 120 feet of you.</text>
                <text>    For the duration, you can cast spells as though you were in the illusion's space, but you must use your own senses. Additionally, when both you and your illusion are within 5 feet of a creature that can see the illusion, you have advantage on attack rolls against that creature, given how distracting the illusion is to the target.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain Channel Divinity: Cloak of Shadows</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to vanish.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you become invisible until the end of your next turn. You become visible if you attack or cast a spell.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain: Improved Duplicity</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you can create up to four duplicates of yourself, instead of one, when you use Invoke Duplicity. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move any number of them up to 30 feet, to a maximum range of 120 feet.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Forge (UA)</name>
                <text>The gods of the forge are patrons of artisans who work with metal, from a humble blacksmith who keeps a village in horseshoes and plow blades to the mighty elf artisan whose diamond-tipped arrows of mithral have felled demon lords. The gods of the forge teach that, with patience and hard work, even the most intractable metal can transform from a lump of ore to a beautifully wrought object. Clerics of these deities quest to search for objects lost to the forces of darkness, liberate mines overrun by orcs, and uncover rare and wondrous materials necessary to create potent magic items. Followers of these gods take great pride in their work, and they are willing to craft and use heavy armor and powerful weapons to protect them. Deities of this domain include Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Forge Domain Spells </text>
                <text>1st - searing smite, shield </text>
                <text>3rd - heat metal, magic weapon </text>
                <text>5th - elemental weapon, protection from energy </text>
                <text>7th - fabricate, wall of fire </text>
                <text>9th - animate objects, creation</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Divine Domain is from Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Blessing of the Forge</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to imbue magic into a weapon or armor. At the end of a long rest, touch one nonmagical object that is a suit of armor or a simple or martial weapon. Until the end of your next long rest, the object becomes a magic item, granting a +1 bonus to AC if it's armor or a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls if it's a weapon. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain Channel Divinity: Artisan's Blessing</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create simple items. </text>
                <text>	Starting at the beginning of a short rest, you conduct a ritual to your deity that grants you the ability to craft a finished item that is at least part metal. The item is completed at the end of the rest. </text>
                <text>	The object can be worth no more than 100 gp, and as part of this ritual you must expend metals, such as coins or other finished items, with a value equal to the item you want to make. The item can be an exact duplicate of a nonmagical item, such as a copy of a key, if you possess the original during your short rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Soul of the Forge</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, your mastery of the forge grants you a number of special abilities: </text>
                <text>• You gain a +1 bonus to AC while you are wearing medium or heavy armor. </text>
                <text>• You gain resistance to fire damage. </text>
                <text>• When you hit a construct with an attack, you deal additional force damage to it equal to your cleric level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with the fiery power of the forge. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 fire damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Saint of Forge and Fire</name>
                <text>At 17th level, your affinity for fire and metal becomes more powerful due to your deity's blessing. You gain immunity to fire damage, and while you're wearing heavy armor, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Protection (UA)</name>
                <text>The protection domain is the purview of deities who charge their followers to shield the weak from the strong. The gods' faithful dwell in villages and towns on the borderlands, where they help bolster defenses and seek out evils to defeat. These gods believe that a strong shield and a suit of armor is the best defense against evil, second only to a stout mace on hand to respond to any attacks in kind. Deities who grant this domain include Helm, Ilmater, Torm, Tyr, Heironeous, St. Cuthbert, Paladine, Dol Dorn, the Silver Flame, Bahamut, Yondalla, Athena, and Odin. </text>
                <text>Protection Domain Spells </text>
                <text>1st - compelled duel, protection from evil and good </text>
                <text>3rd - aid, protection from poison </text>
                <text>5th - protection from energy, slow </text>
                <text>7th - guardian of faith, Otiluke's resilient sphere </text>
                <text>9th - antilife shell, wall of force</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Divine Domain is from Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Shield of the Faithful</name>
                <text>Starting at 1st level, you gain the ability to hinder attacks intended for others. When a creature attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. To do so, you must be able to see both the attacker and the target. You interpose an arm, a shield, or some other part of yourself to try to throw the attack off target.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain Channel Divinity: Radiant Defense</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to cloak your allies in radiant armor. </text>
                <text>	As an action, you channel blessed energy into an ally that you can see within 30 feet of you. The first time that ally is hit by an attack within the next minute, the attacker takes radiant damage equal to 2d10 + your cleric level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Blessed Healer</name>
                <text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others can heal you as well. When you cast a spell with a spell slot and it restores hit points to any creature other than you this turn, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the spell's level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Indomitable Defense</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to two damage types of your choice, choosing from bludgeoning, necrotic, piercing, radiant, and slashing. Whenever you finish a short or long rest, you can change the damage types you chose. </text>
                <text>	As an action, you can temporarily give up this resistance and transfer it to one creature you touch. The creature keeps the resistance until the end of your next short or long rest or until you transfer it back to yourself as a bonus action.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain Arcana</name>
                <text>Magic is an energy that suffuses the multiverse and that fuels both destruction and creation. Gods of the Arcana domain know the secrets and potential of magic intimately. For some of these gods, magical knowledge is a great responsibility that comes with a special understanding of the nature of reality. Other gods of Arcana see magic as pure power, to be used as its wielder sees fit.</text>
                <text />
                <text>The gods of this domain are often associated with knowledge, as learning and arcane power tend to go hand-in-hand. In the Realms, deities of this domain include Azuth and Mystra, as well as Corellon Larethian of the elven pantheon. In other worlds, this domain includes Hecate, Math Mathonwy, and Isis; the triple moon gods of Solinari, Lunitari, and Nuitari of Krynn; and Boccob, Vecna, and WeeJas of Greyhawk.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Arcana Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - detect magic, magic missile</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - magic weapon, Nystul's magic aura</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - dispel magic, magic circle</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - arcane eye, Leomund's secret chest</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - planar binding, teleportation circle</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain: Arcane Initiate</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency in the Arcana skill, and you gain two cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. For you, these cantrips count as cleric cantrips.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain Channel Divinity: Arcane Abjuration</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to abjure otherworldly creatures</text>
                <text />
                <text>As an action, you present your holy symbol, and one celestial, elemental, fey, or fiend of your choice that is within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw, provided that the creature can see or hear you. IF the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.</text>
                <text />
                <text>A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly end its move in a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use use the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it form moving. If there's nowhere to move, then the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>
                <text />
                <text>After you reach 5th level, when a creature fails its saving throw against you Arcane Abjuration feature, the creature is banished for 1 minute (as in the banishment spell, no concentration required) if it isn't oin its plane of origin, and its challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold, as shown below.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Cleric level - Banishes Creatures of CR...</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - 1/2 or lower</text>
                <text />
                <text>8th - 1 or lower</text>
                <text />
                <text>11th - 2 or lower</text>
                <text />
                <text>14th - 3 or lower</text>
                <text />
                <text>17th - 4 or lower</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain: Spell Breaker</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, when you restore hit points to an ally with a spell of 1st level or higher, you can also end one spell of your choice on that creature. The level of the spell you end must be equal to or lower than the level of the spell slot you use to cast the healing spell</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain: Potent Spellcasting</name>
                <text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain: Arcane Mastery</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you choose four spells from the Wizard spell list, one from each of the following levels: 6th, 7th, 8th, and 9th. You add them to your list of domain spells. Like your other domain spells, they are always prepared and count as cleric spells for you.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Tempest</name>
                <text>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain - including Talos, Umberlee, Kord, Zeboim, the Devourer, Zeus, and Thor - govern storms, sea, and sky. They include gods of lightning and thunder, gods of earthquakes, some fire gods, and certain gods of violence, physical strength, and courage. In some pantheons, a god of this domain rules over other deities and is known for swift justice delivered by thunderbolts. In the pantheons of seafaring people, gods of this domain are ocean deities and the patrons of sailors. Tempest gods send their clerics to inspire fear in the common folk, either to keep those folk on the path of righteousness or to encourage them to offer sacrifices of propitiation to ward off divine wrath.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Tempest Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - fog cloud, thunderwave</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - gust of wind, shatter</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - call lightning, sleet storm</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - control water, ice storm</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - destructive wave, insect plague</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Wrath of the Storm</name>
                <text>Also at 1st level, you can thunderously rebuke attackers. When a creature within 5 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 lightning or thunder damage (your choice) on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
                <text>    You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain Channel Divinity: Destructive Wrath</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to wield the power of the storm with unchecked ferocity.</text>
                <text>    When you roll lightning or thunder damage, you can use your Channel Divinity to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Thunderbolt Strike</name>
                <text>At 6th level, when you deal lightning damage to a Large or smaller creature, you can also push it up to 10 feet away from you.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Stormborn</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed whenever you are not underground or indoors.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Light</name>
                <text>Gods of light - including Helm, Lathander, Pholtus, Branchala, the Silver Flame, Belenus, Apollo, and Re-Horakhty - promote the ideals of rebirth and renewal, truth, vigilance, and beauty, often using the symbol of the sun. Some of these gods are portrayed as the sun itself or as a charioteer who guides the sun across the sky. Others are tireless sentinels whose eyes pierce every shadow and see through every deception. Some are deities of beauty and artistry, who teach that art is a vehicle for the soul's improvement. Clerics of a god of light are enlightened souls infused with radiance and the power of their gods' discerning vision, charged with chasing away lies and burning away darkness.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Light Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - burning hands, faerie fire</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - flaming sphere, scorching ray</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - daylight, fireball</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - guardian of faith, wall of fire</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - flame strike, scrying</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Bonus Cantrip</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain the light cantrip if you don't already know it.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Warding Flare</name>
                <text>Also at 1st level, you can interpose divine light between yourself and an attacking enemy. When you are attacked by a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll, causing light to flare before the attacker before it hits or misses. An attacker that can't be blinded is immune to this feature.</text>
                <text>    You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain Channel Divinity: Radiance of the Dawn</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to harness sunlight, banishing darkness and dealing radiant damage to your foes.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you present your holy symbol, and any magical darkness within 30 feet of you is dispelled. Additionally, each hostile creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes radiant damage equal to 2d10 + your cleric level on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that has total cover from you is not affected.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Improved Flare</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, you can also use your Warding Flare feature when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you attacks a creature other than you.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Potent Spellcasting</name>
                <text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Corona of Light</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, you can use your action to activate an aura of sunlight that lasts for 1 minute or until you dismiss it using another action. You emit bright light in a 60-foot radius and dim light 30 feet beyond that. Your enemies in the bright light have disadvantage on saving throws against any spell that deals fire or radiant damage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric !Base">
		<name>Cleric !Base</name>
<hd>8</hd>
        <proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma</proficiency>
        <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
        <autolevel level="1"> <slots>3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="2"> <slots>3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="3"> <slots>3,4,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="4"> <slots>4,4,3,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="5"> <slots>4,4,3,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="6"> <slots>4,4,3,3,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="7"> <slots>4,4,3,3,1,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="8"> <slots>4,4,3,3,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="9"> <slots>4,4,3,3,3,1,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="10"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,0,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="11"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="12"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,0,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="13"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="14"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,0,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="15"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="16"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,0</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="17"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,2,1,1,1,1</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="18"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,1,1,1,1</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="19"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,1,1,1</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="20"><slots>5,4,3,3,3,3,2,2,1,1</slots></autolevel>
        <autolevel level="1">
            <feature>
                <name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
                <text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
                <text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, shields</text>
                <text>Weapons: simple weapons</text>
                <text>Tools: none</text>
                <text>Skills: Choose two from History, Insight, Medicine, Persuasion, and Religion</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Starting Equipment</name>
                <text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• (a) a mace or (b) a warhammer (if proficient)</text>
                <text>• (a) scale mail, (b) leather armor, or (c) chain mail (if proficient)</text>
                <text>• (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>
                <text>• (a) a priest's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
                <text>• A shield and a holy symbol</text>
                <text />
                <text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="1">
            <feature>
                <name>Spellcasting</name>
                <text>As a conduit for divine power, you can cast cleric spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for a selection of cleric spells.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Cantrips</text>
                <text>At 1st level, you know three cantrips of your choice from the cleric spell list. You learn additional cleric cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Cleric table.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Preparing and Casting Spells</text>
                <text>The Cleric table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
                <text>    You prepare the list of cleric spells that are available for you to cast, choosing from the cleric spell list. When you do so, choose a number of cleric spells equal to your Wisdom modifier + your cleric level (minimum of one spell). The spells must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
                <text>    For example, if you are a 3rd-level cleric, you have four 1st-level and two 2nd-level spell slots. With a Wisdom of 16, your list of prepared spells can include six spells of 1st or 2nd level, in any combination. If you prepare the 1st-level spell cure wounds, you can cast it using a 1st-level or 2nd-level slot. Casting the spell doesn't remove it from your list of prepared spells.</text>
                <text>    You can change your list of prepared spells when you finish a long rest. Preparing a new list of cleric spells requires time spent in prayer and meditation: at least 1 minute per spell level for each spell on your list.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
                <text>Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for your cleric spells. The power of your spells comes from your devotion to your deity. You use your Wisdom whenever a cleric spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Wisdom modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a cleric spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
                <text>    Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
                <text>    Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
                <text />
                <text>Ritual Casting</text>
                <text>You can cast a cleric spell as a ritual if that spell has the ritual tag and you have the spell prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
                <text>You can use a holy symbol (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your cleric spells.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Divine Domain</name>
                <text>Choose one domain related to your deity: Arcana, Knowledge, Life, Light, Nature, Tempest, Trickery, or War. Each domain is detailed in their own feature, and each one provides examples of gods associated with it. Your choice grants you domain spells and other features when you choose it at 1st level. It also grants you additional ways to use Channel Divinity when you gain that feature at 2nd level, and additional benefits at 6th, 8th, and 17th levels.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Domain Spells</text>
                <text>Each domain has a list of spells-its domain spells-that you gain at the cleric levels noted in the domain description. Once you gain a domain spell, you always have it prepared, and it doesn't count against the number of spells you can prepare each day.</text>
                <text>    If you have a domain spell that doesn't appear on the cleric spell list, the spell is nonetheless a cleric spell for you.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="2">
            <feature>
                <name>Channel Divinity</name>
                <text>At 2nd level, you gain the ability to channel divine energy directly from your deity, using that energy to fuel magical effects. You start with two such effects: Turn Undead and an effect determined by your domain. Some domains grant you additional effects as you advance in levels, as noted in the domain description.</text>
                <text>    When you use your Channel Divinity, you choose which effect to create. You must then finish a short or long rest to use your Channel Divinity again.</text>
                <text>    Some Channel Divinity effects require saving throws. When you use such an effect from this class, the DC equals your cleric spell save DC.</text>
                <text>    Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests, and beginning at 18th level, you can use it three times between rests. When you finish a short or long rest, you regain your expended uses.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Channel Divinity: Turn Undead</name>
                <text>As an action, you present your holy symbol and speak a prayer censuring the undead. Each undead that can see or hear you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.</text>
                <text>    A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly move to a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use only the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it from moving. If there's nowhere to move, the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="4">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="5">
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 1/2)</name>
                <text>Starting at 5th level, when an undead of CR 1/2 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="6">
            <feature>
                <name>Channel Divinity (2/rest)</name>
                <text>Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity twice between rests.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="8">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 1)</name>
                <text>Starting at 8th level, when an undead of CR 1 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="10">
            <feature>
                <name>Divine Intervention</name>
                <text>Beginning at 10th level, you can call on your deity to intervene on your behalf when your need is great.</text>
                <text>    Imploring your deity's aid requires you to use your action. Describe the assistance you seek, and roll percentile dice. If you roll a number equal to or lower than your cleric level, your deity intervenes. The DM chooses the nature of the intervention; the effect of any cleric spell or cleric domain spell would be appropriate. If your deity intervenes, you can't use this feature again for 7 days. Otherwise, you can use it again after you finish a long rest.</text>
                <text>    At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="11">
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 2)</name>
                <text>Starting at 11th level, when an undead of CR 2 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="12">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="14">
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 3)</name>
                <text>Starting at 14th level, when an undead of CR 3 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="16">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="17">
            <feature>
                <name>Destroy Undead (CR 4)</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, when an undead of CR 4 or lower fails its saving throw against your Turn Undead feature, the creature is instantly destroyed.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="18">
            <feature>
                <name>Channel Divinity (3/rest)</name>
                <text>Beginning at 18th level, you can use your Channel Divinity three times between rests.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="19">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="20">
            <feature>
                <name>Divine Intervention Improvement</name>
                <text>At 20th level, your call for intervention succeeds automatically, no roll required.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
    </class><class name="Cleric (Arcana)">
	<name>Cleric (Arcana)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain Arcana</name>
                <text>Magic is an energy that suffuses the multiverse and that fuels both destruction and creation. Gods of the Arcana domain know the secrets and potential of magic intimately. For some of these gods, magical knowledge is a great responsibility that comes with a special understanding of the nature of reality. Other gods of Arcana see magic as pure power, to be used as its wielder sees fit.</text>
                <text />
                <text>The gods of this domain are often associated with knowledge, as learning and arcane power tend to go hand-in-hand. In the Realms, deities of this domain include Azuth and Mystra, as well as Corellon Larethian of the elven pantheon. In other worlds, this domain includes Hecate, Math Mathonwy, and Isis; the triple moon gods of Solinari, Lunitari, and Nuitari of Krynn; and Boccob, Vecna, and WeeJas of Greyhawk.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Arcana Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - detect magic, magic missile</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - magic weapon, Nystul's magic aura</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - dispel magic, magic circle</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - arcane eye, Leomund's secret chest</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - planar binding, teleportation circle</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain: Arcane Initiate</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency in the Arcana skill, and you gain two cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. For you, these cantrips count as cleric cantrips.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain Channel Divinity: Arcane Abjuration</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to abjure otherworldly creatures</text>
                <text />
                <text>As an action, you present your holy symbol, and one celestial, elemental, fey, or fiend of your choice that is within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw, provided that the creature can see or hear you. IF the creature fails its saving throw, it is turned for 1 minute or until it takes any damage.</text>
                <text />
                <text>A turned creature must spend its turns trying to move as far away from you as it can, and it can't willingly end its move in a space within 30 feet of you. It also can't take reactions. For its action, it can use use the Dash action or try to escape from an effect that prevents it form moving. If there's nowhere to move, then the creature can use the Dodge action.</text>
                <text />
                <text>After you reach 5th level, when a creature fails its saving throw against you Arcane Abjuration feature, the creature is banished for 1 minute (as in the banishment spell, no concentration required) if it isn't oin its plane of origin, and its challenge rating is at or below a certain threshold, as shown below.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Cleric level - Banishes Creatures of CR...</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - 1/2 or lower</text>
                <text />
                <text>8th - 1 or lower</text>
                <text />
                <text>11th - 2 or lower</text>
                <text />
                <text>14th - 3 or lower</text>
                <text />
                <text>17th - 4 or lower</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain: Spell Breaker</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, when you restore hit points to an ally with a spell of 1st level or higher, you can also end one spell of your choice on that creature. The level of the spell you end must be equal to or lower than the level of the spell slot you use to cast the healing spell</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain: Potent Spellcasting</name>
                <text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Arcana Domain: Arcane Mastery</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you choose four spells from the Wizard spell list, one from each of the following levels: 6th, 7th, 8th, and 9th. You add them to your list of domain spells. Like your other domain spells, they are always prepared and count as cleric spells for you.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Death)">
	<name>Cleric (Death)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Death</name>
                <text>The Death domain is concerned with the forces that cause death, as well as the negative energy that gives rise to undead creatures. Deities such as Chemosh, Myrkul, and WeeJas are patrons of necromancers, death knights, liches, mummy lords, and vampires. Gods of the Death domain also embody murder (Anubis, Bhaal, and Pyremius), pain (Iuz or Loviatar), disease or poison (Incabulos, Talona, or Morgion), and the underworld (Hades and He!).</text>
                <text />
                <text>Death Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared. They do not count towards your limit.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - false life, ray of sickness</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - animate dead, vampiric touch</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - blight, death ward</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - antilife shell, cloudkill</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When the cleric chooses this domain at 1st level, he or she gains proficiency with martial weapons.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Reaper</name>
                <text>At 1st level, the cleric learns one necromancy cantrip of his or her choice from any spell list. When the cleric casts a necromancy cantrip that normally targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain Channel Divinity: Touch of Death</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to destroy another creature's life force by touch.</text>
                <text>    When the cleric hits a creature with a melee attack, the cleric can use Channel Divinity to deal extra necrotic damage to the target. The damage equals 5 + twice his or her cleric level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Inescapable Destruction</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, the cleric's ability to channel negative energy becomes more potent. Necrotic damage dealt by the character's cleric spells and Channel Divinity options ignores resistance to necrotic damage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, the cleric gains the ability to infuse his or her weapon strikes with necrotic energy. Once on each of the cleric's turns when he or she hits a creature with a weapon attack, the cleric can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage to the target. When the cleric reaches 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Death Domain: Improved Reaper</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, when the cleric casts a Necromancy spell of 1st through 5th level that targets only one creature, the spell can instead target two creatures within range and within 5 feet of each other. If the spell consumes its material components, the cleric must provide them for each target.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Forge)">
	<name>Cleric (Forge)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Forge (UA)</name>
                <text>The gods of the forge are patrons of artisans who work with metal, from a humble blacksmith who keeps a village in horseshoes and plow blades to the mighty elf artisan whose diamond-tipped arrows of mithral have felled demon lords. The gods of the forge teach that, with patience and hard work, even the most intractable metal can transform from a lump of ore to a beautifully wrought object. Clerics of these deities quest to search for objects lost to the forces of darkness, liberate mines overrun by orcs, and uncover rare and wondrous materials necessary to create potent magic items. Followers of these gods take great pride in their work, and they are willing to craft and use heavy armor and powerful weapons to protect them. Deities of this domain include Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Forge Domain Spells </text>
                <text>1st - searing smite, shield </text>
                <text>3rd - heat metal, magic weapon </text>
                <text>5th - elemental weapon, protection from energy </text>
                <text>7th - fabricate, wall of fire </text>
                <text>9th - animate objects, creation</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Divine Domain is from Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Blessing of the Forge</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to imbue magic into a weapon or armor. At the end of a long rest, touch one nonmagical object that is a suit of armor or a simple or martial weapon. Until the end of your next long rest, the object becomes a magic item, granting a +1 bonus to AC if it's armor or a +1 bonus to attack and damage rolls if it's a weapon. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain Channel Divinity: Artisan's Blessing</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create simple items. </text>
                <text>	Starting at the beginning of a short rest, you conduct a ritual to your deity that grants you the ability to craft a finished item that is at least part metal. The item is completed at the end of the rest. </text>
                <text>	The object can be worth no more than 100 gp, and as part of this ritual you must expend metals, such as coins or other finished items, with a value equal to the item you want to make. The item can be an exact duplicate of a nonmagical item, such as a copy of a key, if you possess the original during your short rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Soul of the Forge</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, your mastery of the forge grants you a number of special abilities: </text>
                <text>• You gain a +1 bonus to AC while you are wearing medium or heavy armor. </text>
                <text>• You gain resistance to fire damage. </text>
                <text>• When you hit a construct with an attack, you deal additional force damage to it equal to your cleric level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with the fiery power of the forge. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 fire damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Forge Domain: Saint of Forge and Fire</name>
                <text>At 17th level, your affinity for fire and metal becomes more powerful due to your deity's blessing. You gain immunity to fire damage, and while you're wearing heavy armor, you have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical attacks.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Grave)">
	<name>Cleric (Grave)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Grave (UA)</name>
                <text>Gods of the grave watch over the line between life and death. To these deities, death and the afterlife are a foundational part of the multiverse's workings. To resist death, or to desecrate the dead's rest, is an abomination. Deities of the grave include Kelemvor, Wee Jas, the ancestral spirits of the Undying Court, Hades, Anubis, and Osiris. These deities teach their followers to respect the dead and pay them due homage. Followers of these deities seek to put restless spirits to rest, destroy the undead wherever they find them, and ease the suffering of dying creatures. Their magic also allows them to stave off a creature's death, though they refuse to use such magic to extend a creature's lifespan beyond its mortal limits.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Grave Domain Spells</text>
                <text>1st - bane, false life</text>
                <text>3rd - gentle repose, ray of enfeeblement</text>
                <text>5th - revivify, vampiric touch</text>
                <text>7th - blight, death ward</text>
                <text>9th - antilife shell, raise dead</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Divine Domain is from Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Circle of Mortality</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain the ability to manipulate the line between life and death. When you cast a spell that restores hit points to a living creature currently at 0, treat any dice rolled to determine the spell's healing as having rolled their maximum result. In addition, if you have the spare the dying cantrip, you can cast it as a bonus action.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Eyes of the Grave</name>
                <text>Starting at 1st level, you gain an innate sense of creatures whose existence is an insult to the natural cycle of life. If you spend 1 minute in uninterrupted contemplation, you can determine the presence and nature of undead creatures in the area. This detection extends up to 1 mile in all directions. You learn the number of undead and their distance and direction from you. In addition, you learn the creature type of the undead in that area that has the highest challenge rating. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain Channel Divinity: Path to the Grave</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to mark another creature's life force for termination. </text>
                <text>	As an action, you touch a creature. The next time that creature takes damage from a spell or an attack from you or an ally, it is vulnerable to that spell or attack's damage. If the source of damage has multiple damage types, the creature is vulnerable to all of them. The vulnerability applies only to the first time that source inflicts damage, and then ends. </text>
                <text>	If the creature has resistance or is immune to the damage, it instead loses its resistance or immunity against that spell or attack when it first applies damage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Sentinel at Death's Door</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, you gain the ability to impede death's progress. As a reaction when you or an ally that you can see within 30 feet of you suffers a critical hit, you can turn that attack into a normal hit. Any effects triggered by a critical hit are canceled. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 necrotic damage. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Grave Domain: Keeper of Souls</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to manipulate the boundary between life and death. When an enemy you can see dies within 30 feet of you, you or one ally of your choice that is within 30 feet of you regains hit points equal to the enemy's number of Hit Dice. You can use this feature as long as you aren't incapacitated, but no more than once per round.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Knowledge)">
	<name>Cleric (Knowledge)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Knowledge</name>
                <text>The gods of knowledge - including Oghma, Boccob, Gilean, Aureon, and Thoth - value learning and understanding above all. Some teach that knowledge is to be gathered and shared in libraries and universities, or promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention. Some deities hoard knowledge and keep its secrets to themselves. And some promise their followers that they will gain tremendous power if they unlock the secrets of the multiverse. Followers of these gods study esoteric lore, collect old tomes, delve into the secret places of the earth, and learn all they can. Some gods of knowledge promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention, including smith deities like Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Knowledge Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - command, identify</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - augury, suggestion</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - nondetection, speak with dead</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - arcane eye, confusion</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - legend lore, scrying</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain: Blessings of Knowledge</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you learn two languages of your choice. You also become proficient in your choice of two of the following skills: Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion.</text>
                <text>    Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses either of those skills.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain Channel Divinity: Knowledge of the Ages</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to tap into a divine well of knowledge. As an action, you choose one skill or tool. For 10 minutes, you have proficiency with the chosen skill or tool.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain Channel Divinity: Read Thoughts</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to read a creature's thoughts. You can then use your access to the creature's mind to command it.</text>
                <text>As an action, choose one creature that you can see within 60 feet of you. That creature must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature succeeds on the saving throw, you can't use this feature on it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
                <text>If the creature fails its save, you can read its surface thoughts (those foremost in its mind, reflecting its current emotions and what it is actively thinking about) when it is within 60 feet of you. This effect lasts for 1 minute.</text>
                <text>During that time, you can use your action to end this effect and cast the suggestion spell on the creature without expending a spell slot. The target automatically fails its saving throw against the spell.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain: Potent Spellcasting</name>
                <text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Knowledge Domain: Visions of the Past</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, you can call up visions of the past that relate to an object you hold or your immediate surroundings. You spend at least 1 minute in meditation and prayer, then receive dreamlike, shadowy glimpses of recent events. You can meditate in this way for a number of minutes equal to your Wisdom score and must maintain concentration during that time, as if you were casting a spell.</text>
                <text>    Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
                <text>    Object Reading. Holding an object as you meditate, you can see visions of the object's previous owner. After meditating for 1 minute, you learn how the owner acquired and lost the object, as well as the most recent significant event involving the object and that owner. If the object was owned by another creature in the recent past (within a number of days equal to your Wisdom score), you can spend 1 additional minute for each owner to learn the same information about that creature.</text>
                <text>    Area Reading. As you meditate, you see visions of recent events in your immediate vicinity (a room, street, tunnel, clearing, or the like, up to a 50-foot cube), going back a number of days equal to your Wisdom score. For each minute you meditate, you learn about one significant event, beginning with the most recent. Significant events typically involve powerful emotions, such as battles and betrayals, marriages and murders, births and funerals. However, they might also include more mundane events that are nevertheless important in your current situation.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Life)">
	<name>Cleric (Life)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Life</name>
                <text>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy - one of the fundamental forces of the universe -  that sustains all life. The gods of life promote vitality and health through healing the sick and wounded, caring for those in need, and driving away the forces of death and undeath. Almost any non-evil deity can claim influence over this domain, particularly agricultural deities (such as Chauntea, Arawai, and Demeter), sun gods (such as Lathander, Pelor, and Re-Horakhty), gods of healing or endurance (such as Ilmater, Mishakal, Apollo, and Diancecht), and gods of home and community (such as Hestia, Hathor, and Boldrei).</text>
                <text />
                <text>Life Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - bless, cure wounds</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - lesser restoration, spiritual weapon</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - beacon of hope, revivify</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - death ward, guardian of faith</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - mass cure wounds, raise dead</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Disciple of Life</name>
                <text>Also starting at 1st level, your healing spells are more effective. Whenever you use a spell of 1st level or higher to restore hit points to a creature, the creature regains additional hit points equal to 2 + the spell's level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain Channel Divinity: Preserve Life</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to heal the badly injured.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you present your holy symbol and evoke healing energy that can restore a number of hit points equal to five times your cleric level. Choose any creatures within 30 feet of you, and divide those hit points among them. This feature can restore a creature to no more than half of its hit point maximum. You can't use this feature on an undead or a construct.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Blessed Healer</name>
                <text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others heal you as well. When you cast a spell of 1st level or higher that restores hit points to a creature other than you, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the spell's level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Life Domain: Supreme Healing</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, when you would normally roll one or more dice to restore hit points with a spell, you instead use the highest number possible for each die. For example, instead of restoring 2d6 hit points to a creature, you restore 12.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Light)">
	<name>Cleric (Light)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Light</name>
                <text>Gods of light - including Helm, Lathander, Pholtus, Branchala, the Silver Flame, Belenus, Apollo, and Re-Horakhty - promote the ideals of rebirth and renewal, truth, vigilance, and beauty, often using the symbol of the sun. Some of these gods are portrayed as the sun itself or as a charioteer who guides the sun across the sky. Others are tireless sentinels whose eyes pierce every shadow and see through every deception. Some are deities of beauty and artistry, who teach that art is a vehicle for the soul's improvement. Clerics of a god of light are enlightened souls infused with radiance and the power of their gods' discerning vision, charged with chasing away lies and burning away darkness.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Light Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - burning hands, faerie fire</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - flaming sphere, scorching ray</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - daylight, fireball</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - guardian of faith, wall of fire</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - flame strike, scrying</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Bonus Cantrip</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain the light cantrip if you don't already know it.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Warding Flare</name>
                <text>Also at 1st level, you can interpose divine light between yourself and an attacking enemy. When you are attacked by a creature within 30 feet of you that you can see, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll, causing light to flare before the attacker before it hits or misses. An attacker that can't be blinded is immune to this feature.</text>
                <text>    You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain Channel Divinity: Radiance of the Dawn</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to harness sunlight, banishing darkness and dealing radiant damage to your foes.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you present your holy symbol, and any magical darkness within 30 feet of you is dispelled. Additionally, each hostile creature within 30 feet of you must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes radiant damage equal to 2d10 + your cleric level on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one. A creature that has total cover from you is not affected.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Improved Flare</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, you can also use your Warding Flare feature when a creature that you can see within 30 feet of you attacks a creature other than you.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Potent Spellcasting</name>
                <text>Starting at 8th level, you add your Wisdom modifier to the damage you deal with any cleric cantrip.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Light Domain: Corona of Light</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, you can use your action to activate an aura of sunlight that lasts for 1 minute or until you dismiss it using another action. You emit bright light in a 60-foot radius and dim light 30 feet beyond that. Your enemies in the bright light have disadvantage on saving throws against any spell that deals fire or radiant damage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Nature)">
	<name>Cleric (Nature)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Nature</name>
                <text>Gods of nature are as varied as the natural world itself, from inscrutable gods of the deep forests (such as Silvanus, Obad-Hai, Chislev, Balinor, and Pan) to friendly deities associated with particular springs and groves (such as Eldath). Druids revere nature as a whole and might serve one of these deities, practicing mysterious rites and reciting all-but-forgotten prayers in their own secret tongue. But many of these gods have clerics as well, champions who take a more active role in advancing the interests of a particular nature god. These clerics might hunt the evil monstrosities that despoil the woodlands, bless the harvest of the faithful, or wither the crops of those who anger their gods.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Nature Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - animal friendship, speak with animals</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - barkskin, spike growth</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - plant growth, wind wall</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - dominate beast, grasping vine</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - insect plague, tree stride</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Acolyte of Nature</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you learn one druid cantrip of your choice. You also gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, or Survival.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>Also at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain Channel Divinity: Charm Animals and Plants</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to charm animals and plants.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you present your holy symbol and invoke the name of your deity. Each beast or plant creature that can see you within 30 feet of you must make a Wisdom saving throw. If the creature fails its saving throw, it is charmed by you for 1 minute or until it takes damage. While it is charmed by you, it is friendly to you and other creatures you designate.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Dampen Elements</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, when you or a creature within 30 feet of you takes acid, cold, fire, lightning, or thunder damage, you can use your reaction to grant resistance to the creature against that instance of the damage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Nature Domain: Master of Nature</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to command animals and plant creatures. While creatures are charmed by your Charm Animals and Plants feature, you can take a bonus action on your turn to verbally command what each of those creatures will do on its next turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Protection)">
	<name>Cleric (Protection)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Protection (UA)</name>
                <text>The protection domain is the purview of deities who charge their followers to shield the weak from the strong. The gods' faithful dwell in villages and towns on the borderlands, where they help bolster defenses and seek out evils to defeat. These gods believe that a strong shield and a suit of armor is the best defense against evil, second only to a stout mace on hand to respond to any attacks in kind. Deities who grant this domain include Helm, Ilmater, Torm, Tyr, Heironeous, St. Cuthbert, Paladine, Dol Dorn, the Silver Flame, Bahamut, Yondalla, Athena, and Odin. </text>
                <text>Protection Domain Spells </text>
                <text>1st - compelled duel, protection from evil and good </text>
                <text>3rd - aid, protection from poison </text>
                <text>5th - protection from energy, slow </text>
                <text>7th - guardian of faith, Otiluke's resilient sphere </text>
                <text>9th - antilife shell, wall of force</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Divine Domain is from Unearthed Arcana: Cleric Divine Domains, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Bonus Proficiency</name>
                <text>When you choose this domain at 1st level, you gain proficiency with heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Shield of the Faithful</name>
                <text>Starting at 1st level, you gain the ability to hinder attacks intended for others. When a creature attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. To do so, you must be able to see both the attacker and the target. You interpose an arm, a shield, or some other part of yourself to try to throw the attack off target.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain Channel Divinity: Radiant Defense</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to cloak your allies in radiant armor. </text>
                <text>	As an action, you channel blessed energy into an ally that you can see within 30 feet of you. The first time that ally is hit by an attack within the next minute, the attacker takes radiant damage equal to 2d10 + your cleric level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Blessed Healer</name>
                <text>Beginning at 6th level, the healing spells you cast on others can heal you as well. When you cast a spell with a spell slot and it restores hit points to any creature other than you this turn, you regain hit points equal to 2 + the spell's level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Protection Domain: Indomitable Defense</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to two damage types of your choice, choosing from bludgeoning, necrotic, piercing, radiant, and slashing. Whenever you finish a short or long rest, you can change the damage types you chose. </text>
                <text>	As an action, you can temporarily give up this resistance and transfer it to one creature you touch. The creature keeps the resistance until the end of your next short or long rest or until you transfer it back to yourself as a bonus action.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Tempest)">
	<name>Cleric (Tempest)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Tempest</name>
                <text>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain - including Talos, Umberlee, Kord, Zeboim, the Devourer, Zeus, and Thor - govern storms, sea, and sky. They include gods of lightning and thunder, gods of earthquakes, some fire gods, and certain gods of violence, physical strength, and courage. In some pantheons, a god of this domain rules over other deities and is known for swift justice delivered by thunderbolts. In the pantheons of seafaring people, gods of this domain are ocean deities and the patrons of sailors. Tempest gods send their clerics to inspire fear in the common folk, either to keep those folk on the path of righteousness or to encourage them to offer sacrifices of propitiation to ward off divine wrath.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Tempest Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - fog cloud, thunderwave</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - gust of wind, shatter</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - call lightning, sleet storm</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - control water, ice storm</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - destructive wave, insect plague</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Wrath of the Storm</name>
                <text>Also at 1st level, you can thunderously rebuke attackers. When a creature within 5 feet of you that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to cause the creature to make a Dexterity saving throw. The creature takes 2d8 lightning or thunder damage (your choice) on a failed saving throw, and half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
                <text>    You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain Channel Divinity: Destructive Wrath</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to wield the power of the storm with unchecked ferocity.</text>
                <text>    When you roll lightning or thunder damage, you can use your Channel Divinity to deal maximum damage, instead of rolling.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Thunderbolt Strike</name>
                <text>At 6th level, when you deal lightning damage to a Large or smaller creature, you can also push it up to 10 feet away from you.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Tempest Domain: Stormborn</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you have a flying speed equal to your current walking speed whenever you are not underground or indoors.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (Trickery)">
	<name>Cleric (Trickery)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: Trickery</name>
                <text>Gods of trickery - such as Tymora, Beshaba, Olidammara, the Traveler, Garl Glittergold, and Loki - are mischief-makers and instigators who stand as a constant challenge to the accepted order among both gods and mortals. They're patrons of thieves, scoundrels, gamblers, rebels, and liberators. Their clerics are a disruptive force in the world, puncturing pride, mocking tyrants, stealing from the rich, freeing captives, and flouting hollow traditions. They prefer subterfuge, pranks, deception, and theft rather than direct confrontation.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Trickery Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, you add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - charm person, disguise self</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - mirror image, pass without trace</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - blink, dispel magic</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - dimension door, polymorph</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - dominate person, modify memory</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain: Blessing of the Trickster</name>
                <text>Starting when you choose this domain at 1st level, you can use your action to touch a willing creature other than yourself to give it advantage on Dexterity (Stealth) checks. This blessing lasts for 1 hour or until you use this feature again.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain Channel Divinity: Invoke Duplicity</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to create an illusory duplicate of yourself.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you create a perfect illusion of yourself that lasts for 1 minute, or until you lose your concentration (as if you were concentrating on a spell). The illusion appears in an unoccupied space that you can see within 30 feet of you. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move the illusion up to 30 feet to a space you can see, but it must remain within 120 feet of you.</text>
                <text>    For the duration, you can cast spells as though you were in the illusion's space, but you must use your own senses. Additionally, when both you and your illusion are within 5 feet of a creature that can see the illusion, you have advantage on attack rolls against that creature, given how distracting the illusion is to the target.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain Channel Divinity: Cloak of Shadows</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, you can use your Channel Divinity to vanish.</text>
                <text>    As an action, you become invisible until the end of your next turn. You become visible if you attack or cast a spell.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Trickery Domain: Improved Duplicity</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you can create up to four duplicates of yourself, instead of one, when you use Invoke Duplicity. As a bonus action on your turn, you can move any number of them up to 30 feet, to a maximum range of 120 feet.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Cleric (War)">
	<name>Cleric (War)</name>

		<autolevel level="1">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Divine Domain: War</name>
                <text>War has many manifestations. It can make heroes of ordinary people. It can be desperate and horrific, with acts of cruelty and cowardice eclipsing instances of excellence and courage. In either case, the gods of war watch over warriors and reward them for their great deeds. The clerics of such gods excel in battle, inspiring others to fight the good fight or offering acts of violence as prayers. Gods of war include champions of honor and chivalry (such as Torm, Heironeous, and Kiri-Jolith) as well as gods of destruction and pillage (such as Erythnul, the Fury, Gruumsh, and Ares) and gods of conquest and domination (such as Bane, Hextor, and Maglubiyet). Other war gods (such as Tempus, Nike, and Nuada) take a more neutral stance, promoting war in all its manifestations and supporting warriors in any circumstance.</text>
                <text />
                <text>War Domain Spells: At each indicated cleric level, add the listed spells to your spells prepared.</text>
                <text />
                <text>1st - divine favor, shield of faith</text>
                <text />
                <text>3rd - magic weapon, spiritual weapon</text>
                <text />
                <text>5th - crusader's mantle, spirit guardians</text>
                <text />
                <text>7th - freedom of movement, stoneskin</text>
                <text />
                <text>9th - flame strike, hold monster</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
                <text>At 1st level, you gain proficiency with martial weapons and heavy armor.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain: War Priest</name>
                <text>From 1st level, your god delivers bolts of inspiration to you while you are engaged in battle. When you use the Attack action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action. You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Wisdom modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="2">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain Channel Divinity: Guided Strike</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, you can use your Channel Divinity to strike with supernatural accuracy. When you make an attack roll, you can use your Channel Divinity to gain a +10 bonus to the roll. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain Channel Divinity: War God's Blessing</name>
                <text>At 6th level, when a creature within 30 feet of you makes an attack roll, you can use your reaction to grant that creature a +10 bonus to the roll, using your Channel Divinity. You make this choice after you see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="8">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain: Divine Strike</name>
                <text>At 8th level, you gain the ability to infuse your weapon strikes with divine energy. Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can cause the attack to deal an extra 1d8 radiant damage to the target. When you reach 14th level, the extra damage increases to 2d8.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>War Domain: Avatar of Battle</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><spellList class="Cleric (Forge)">
		<index name="Searing Smite" />
		<index name="Shield" />
		<index name="Heat Metal" />
		<index name="Magic Weapon" />
		<index name="Elemental Weapon" />
		<index name="Protection from Energy" />
		<index name="Fabricate" />
		<index name="Wall of Fire" />
		<index name="Animate Objects" />
		<index name="Creation" />
	</spellList>
<spellList class="Cleric (Grave)">
		<index name="Bane" />
		<index name="False Life" />
		<index name="Gentle Repose" />
		<index name="Ray of Enfeeblement" />
		<index name="Revivify" />
		<index name="Vampiric Touch" />
		<index name="Blight" />
		<index name="Death Ward" />
		<index name="Antilife Shell" />
		<index name="Raise Dead" />
	</spellList>
<spellList class="Cleric (Protection)">
		<index name="Compelled Duel" />
		<index name="Protection from Evil and Good" />
		<index name="Aid" />
		<index name="Protection from Poison" />
		<index name="Protection from Energy" />
		<index name="Slow" />
		<index name="Guardian of Faith" />
		<index name="Otiluke's Resilient Sphere" />
		<index name="Antilife Shell" />
		<index name="Wall of Force" />
	</spellList>
</compendium>