<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
  <class name="Fighter"><name>Fighter</name>
	<hd>10</hd>
	<proficiency>Strength, Constitution</proficiency>
	<autolevel level="1">
	  <feature>
		<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
		<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
		</text>
		<text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields</text>
		<text>Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
		<text>Tools: none</text>
		<text>Skills: Choose two skills from Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, and Survival
		</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature>
		<name>Starting Equipment</name>
		<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• (a) chain mail or (b) leather, longbow, and 20 arrows</text>
		<text>• (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</text>
		<text>• (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) two handaxes</text>
		<text>• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
		<text />
		<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="1">
	  <feature>
		<name>Fighting Style</name>
		<text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose a fighting style from the list of optional features. You can't take the same Fighting Style option more than once, even if you get to choose again.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Archery</name>
		<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
		<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
		<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name>
		<text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.
		</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Protection</name>
		<text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name>
		<text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature>
		<name>Second Wind</name>
		<text>You have a limited well of stamina that you can draw on to protect yourself from harm. On your turn, you can use a bonus action to regain hit points equal to 1d10 + your fighter level.</text>
		<text>    Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="2">
	  <feature>
		<name>Action Surge</name>
		<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can push yourself beyond your normal limits for a moment. On your turn, you can take one additional action on top of your regular action and a possible bonus action.</text>
		<text>    Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again. Starting at 17th level, you can use it twice before a rest, but only once on the same turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature>
		<name>Martial Archetype</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate in your combat styles and techniques. Choose Champion, Battle Master, or Eldritch Knight, all detailed at the end of the class description. The archetype you choose grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="4">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="5">
	  <feature>
		<name>Extra Attack</name>
		<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
		<text>    The number of attacks increases to three when you reach 11th level in this class and to four when you reach 20th level in this class.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="6">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 6th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="8">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="9">
	  <feature>
		<name>Indomitable</name>
		<text>Beginning at 9th level, you can reroll a saving throw that you fail. If you do so, you must use the new roll, and you can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
		<text>    You can use this feature twice between long rests starting at 13th level and three times between long rests starting at 17th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="11">
	  <feature>
		<name>Extra Attack (2)</name>
		<text>At 11th level, you can attack three times whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="12">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="13">
	  <feature>
		<name>Indomitable (two uses)</name>
		<text>At 13th level, you can use Indomitable twice between long rests.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="14">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 14th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="16">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
		</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="17">
	  <feature>
		<name>Action Surge (two uses)</name>
		<text>At 17th level, you can use Action Surge twice before a rest, but only once on the same turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature>
		<name>Indomitable (three uses)</name>
		<text>At 17th level, you can use Indomitable three times between long rests.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="19">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="20">
	  <feature>
		<name>Extra Attack (3)</name>
		<text>At 20th level, you can attack four times whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	
	
	<autolevel UA="UA" level="1">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooter (UA)</name>
		<text>When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This fighting style is from Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.
		</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Mariner (UA)</name>
		<text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This fighting style is from Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.
		</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Tunnel Fighter (UA)</name>
		<text>As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This fighting style is from Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  <autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Arcane Archer (UA)</name>
		<text>An Arcane Archer studies a unique elven method of archery that weaves magic into attacks to produce supernatural effects. Among elves, Arcane Archers are some of their most elite warriors. These archers stand watch over the fringes of elven domains, keeping a keen eye out for trespassers and using magic-infused arrows to defeat monsters and invaders before they can reach elven settlements. Over the centuries, the methods of these elf archers have been learned by members of other races who can also balance arcane aptitude with archery.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Subclasses, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
		<text>	This had an earlier version included in Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Magic Arrow</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the ability to infuse arrows with magic. Whenever you fire a nonmagical arrow from a shortbow or longbow, you can make it a magic arrow, with a +1 bonus to the attack and damage rolls. The magic fades from the arrow immediately after it hits or misses its target.</text>
	  </feature>
	<feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you learn to unleash special magical effects with some of your shots. When you gain this feature, you learn two Arcane Shot options of your choice (see the “Arcane Shot Options” section below).</text>
		<text>	Once per turn when you fire a magic arrow from a shortbow or longbow as part of the Attack action, you can apply one of your Arcane Shot options to that arrow. You decide to use the option when the arrow hits, unless the option doesn’t involve an attack roll. You have two uses of this ability, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice when you reach certain levels in this class: 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level. Each option also improves when you become an 18th-level fighter.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Archer's Lore</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you learn magical theory or some of the secrets of nature—typical for practitioners of this elven martial tradition. You gain proficiency in either the Arcana or the Nature skill.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Options</name>
			<text>The Arcane Shot feature lets you choose options for it at certain levels. The options are presented here in alphabetical order. They are all magical effects, and each one is associated with one of the schools of magic.</text>
			<text>	If an option requires a saving throw, your Arcane Shot save DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Banishing Arrow:</text>
			<text>You use abjuration magic to try to temporarily banish your target to a harmless location in the Feywild. If the arrow hits a creature, the target must also succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be banished. While banished in this way, its speed is 0, and it is incapacitated. At the end of its next turn, the target reappears in the space it vacated or in the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied.</text>
			<text>	After you reach 18th level in this class, a target also takes 2d6 force damage when the arrow hits it.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Brute Bane Arrow:</text>
			<text>You weave necromantic magic into your arrow. If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 necrotic damage, and it must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the damage of the target’s attacks is halved until the start of your next turn.</text>
			<text>	The necrotic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Bursting Arrow:</text>
			<text>You imbue your arrow with a blast of force energy drawn from the school of evocation. If the arrow hits a creature, the target and each creature within 10 feet of it also take 2d6 force damage each.</text>
			<text>	The force damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Grasping Arrow:</text>
			<text>When this arrow strikes its target, conjuration magic creates grasping, poisonous brambles, which wrap around the target. If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 poison damage, its speed is reduced by 10 feet, and it takes 2d6 slashing damage the first time on each turn it moves 1 foot or more without teleporting. The target or any creature that can reach it can use its action to remove the brambles with a successful Strength (Athletics) check against your Arcane Shot save DC. Otherwise, the brambles last for 1 minute or until you use this option again.</text>
			<text>	The poison and slashing damage both increase to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Mind-Scrambling Arrow:</text>
			<text>Your enchantment magic causes this arrow to temporarily beguile its target. Choose one of your allies within 30 feet of the target. If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 psychic damage, and it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or it can’t attack the chosen ally or include that ally in a harmful area of effect until the start of your next turn. This effect ends early if the chosen ally deals any damage to the target.</text>
			<text>	The psychic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Piercing Arrow:</text>
			<text>You use transmutation magic to give your arrow an ethereal quality. When you use this option, you don’t make an attack roll for the attack. Instead, the arrow fires forward in a line that is 1 foot wide and 30 feet long, before disappearing. The arrow passes harmlessly through objects, ignoring cover. Each creature in that line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a target takes damage as if it were hit by the arrow, plus an extra 1d6 piercing damage. On a successful save, a target takes half as much damage.</text>
			<text>	The piercing damage increases to 2d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Seeking Arrow:</text>
			<text>Using divination magic, you grant your arrow the ability to seek out your target, allowing the arrow to curve and twist its path in search of its prey. When you use this option, you don’t make an attack roll for the attack. Instead, choose one creature you have seen in the past minute. The arrow flies toward that creature, moving around corners if necessary and ignoring three-quarters cover and half cover. If the target is within the weapon’s range and there is a path large enough for the arrow to travel to the target, the target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, it takes damage as if it were hit by the arrow, plus an extra 1d6 force damage, and you learn the target’s current location. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage, and you don’t learn its location.</text>
			<text>	The force damage increases to 2d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Shadow Arrow:</text>
			<text>You weave illusion magic into your arrow, causing it to occlude your foe's vision with shadows. If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 psychic damage, and it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be unable to see anything farther than 5 feet away until the start of your next turn.</text>
			<text>	The psychic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Curving Shot</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you learn how to direct an errant arrow toward a new target. When you make an attack roll with a magic arrow and miss, you can use a bonus action to reroll the attack roll against a different target within 60 feet of the original target.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (3rd)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (4th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Ever-Ready Shot</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, your magical archery is ever available to you when you need it most. If you roll initiative and have no uses of Arcane Shot remaining, you regain one use of it</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (5th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Deadly Arrow</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your Arcane Arrow's bonus damage increases to 4d6 force damage.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (6th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  <autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Purple Dragon Knight (Banneret)</name>
		<text>Purple Dragon Knights are warriors who hail from the kingdom of Cormyr. Pledged to protect the crown, they take the fight against evil beyond the kingdom's borders. They are tasked with wandering the land as knights errant, relying on their judgment, bravery, and fidelity to guide them in defeating evildoers.</text>
		<text>A Purple Dragon Knight inspires greatness in others by committing brave deeds in battle. The mere presence of a knight in a hamlet is enough to cause some orcs and bandits to seek easier prey. A lone knight is a skilled warrior, but a knight leading a band of allies can transform even the most poorly equipped militia into a ferocious war band.</text>
		<text>A knight prefers to lead through deeds, not words. As a knight spearheads an attack, the knight's actions can awaken reserves of courage and conviction in allies that they never suspected they had.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Restriction: Knighthood</name>
		<text>Purple Dragon Knights are tied to a specific order of Cormyrean knighthood.</text>
		<text>Banneret serves as the generic name for this archetype if you use it in other campaign settings or to model warlords other than the Purple Dragon Knights.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Rallying Cry</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn how to inspire your allies to fight on past their injuries.</text>
		<text>	When you use your Second Wind feature, you can choose up to three creatures within 60 feet of you that are allied with you. Each one regains hit points equal to your fighter level, provided that the creature can see or hear you.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Royal Envoy</name>
		<text>A Purple Dragon Knight serves as an envoy of the Cormyrean crown. Knights of high standing are expected to conduct themselves with grace.</text>
		<text>	At 7th level, you gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient in it, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Insight, Intimidation, or Performance.</text>
		<text>	Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses Persuasion. You receive this benefit regardless of the skill proficiency you gain from this feature.</text>
		<proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
		<modifier category="skills">Persuasion+%0</modifier>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Inspiring Surge</name>
		<text>Starting at 10th level, when you use your Action Surge feature, you can choose one creature within 60 feet of you that is allied with you. That creature can make one melee or ranged weapon attack with its reaction, provided that it can see or hear you.</text>
		<text>	Starting at 17th level, you can choose two allies within 60 feet of you, rather than one.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Bulwark</name>
		<text>Beginning at 15th level, you can extend the benefit of your Indomitable feature to an ally. When you decide to use Indomitable to reroll an Intelligence, a Wisdom, or a Charisma saving throw and you aren't incapacitated, you can choose one ally within 60 feet of you that also failed its saving throw against the same effect. If that creature can see or hear you, it can reroll its saving throw and must use the new roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	</autolevel>

  <autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Sharpshooter (UA)</name>
		<text>The Sharpshooter is a master of ranged combat. An excellent sniper and eagle-eyed scout, this fighter is a perilous foe who can defeat an entire war band so long as they are kept at range.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Steady Aim</name>
		<text>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your aim becomes deadly. As a bonus action on your turn, you can take careful aim at a creature you can see that is within range of a ranged weapon you're wielding. Until the end of this turn, your ranged attacks with that weapon gain two benefits against the target:</text>
		<text />
		<text>• The attacks ignore half and three-quarters cover.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• On each hit, the weapon deals additional damage to the target equal to 2 + half your fighter level.</text>
		<text>	You can use this feature three times. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Careful Eyes</name>
		<text>Starting at 7th level, you excel at picking out hidden enemies and other threats. You can take the Search action as a bonus action.</text>
		<text>	You also gain proficiency in the Perception, Investigation, or Survival skill (choose one).</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Close-Quarters Shooting</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you learn to handle yourself in close combat. Making a ranged attack roll while within 5 feet of an enemy doesn't impose disadvantage on your roll.</text>
		<text>	In addition, if you hit a creature within 5 feet of you with a ranged attack on your turn, that creature can't take reactions until the end of this turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Rapid Strike</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Snap Shot</name>
		<text>Starting at 18th level, you are ever ready to spring into action. If you take the Attack action on your first turn of a combat, you can make one additional ranged weapon attack as part of that action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  <autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Knight (UA)</name>
		<text>The Knight is a colossus on the battlefield who can shrug off attacks and protect allies from harm. Knights fight from the saddle when they can, and in combat they are expected to seek out and lock down the mightiest of the enemy's forces. On adventures, they are the armored bulwark that strives to keep the rest of the party safe.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Born to the Saddle</name>
		<text>Starting at 3rd level, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed. In addition, you have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount. If you fall off it, you can automatically land on your feet if you aren't incapacitated and you fall less than 10 feet.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Implacable Mark</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you excel at foiling attacks and protecting your allies by menacing your foes. When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, the target is marked by you until the end of your next turn. A creature ignores this effect if the creature can't be frightened.</text>
		<text>	The marked target has disadvantage on any attack roll against a creature other than you or someone else who marked it.</text>
		<text>	If a target marked by you is within 5 feet of you on its turn and it moves at least 1 foot or makes an attack that suffers disadvantage from this feature, you can make one melee weapon attack against it using your reaction. This attack roll has advantage, and if it hits, the attack's weapon deals extra damage to the target equal to your fighter level.</text>
		<text>	You can make this special attack even if you have already expended your reaction this round, but not if you have already used your reaction this turn. You can make this attack three times, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Noble Cavalry</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, History, Insight, Persuasion, or Religion. Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Hold the Line</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you master the ability to harass and slow your enemies. As a reaction when a creature moves at least 1 foot within 5 feet of you, you can make one melee weapon attack against that creature. If you hit, the attack's weapon deals extra damage to the target equal to half your fighter level, and the target's speed is reduced to 0 until the end of this turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Rapid Strike</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Defender's Blade</name>
		<text>At 18th level, you respond to danger with extraordinary vigilance. You can use your reaction for an opportunity attack even if you have already expended your reaction this round, but not if you have already used your reaction this turn.</text>
		<text>	In addition, you gain a +1 bonus to AC while wearing heavy armor.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  <spellAbility>Strength</spellAbility>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Cavalier (UA)</name>
		<text>The archetypal Cavalier excels at mounted combat. Usually born among the nobility and raised at court, a Cavalier is equally at home leading a cavalry charge or exchanging repartee at a state dinner. Cavaliers also learn how to guard those in their charge from harm, often serving as the protectors of their superiors and of the weak. Drawn to right wrongs or earn prestige, many of these fighters leave their lives of comfort to embark on glorious adventure.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
		<text>	This had an earlier version included in Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old</text>
	  </feature>

	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Bonus Proficiency</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, History, Insight, Performance, or Persuasion. Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Born to the Saddle</name>
		<text>Starting at 3rd level, your mastery as a rider becomes apparent. You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount. If you fall off your mount and descend no more than 10 feet, you can land on your feet if you’re not incapacitated.</text>
		<text>Finally, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed.</text>
	  </feature>

		<slots optional="YES">0,4</slots>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>	You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Maneuvers:</text>
		<text>	You spend your superiority dice on your maneuvers. You can use more than one maneuver per turn, but no more than one maneuver per attack.</text>
		<text>	You know the following maneuvers:</text>
		<text />
		<text>Control Mount. When you make a Wisdom (Animal Handling) check to influence a creature that you or an ally is riding, you can expend one superiority die, roll it, and add the number rolled to the check. You can do this before or after rolling the d20, but before applying the results of the check.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Precision Attack. When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die, roll it, and add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after rolling the d20, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Trip Attack. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to knock the target down. Roll the die, and add it to the attack’s damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must also succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier) or be knocked prone.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Warding Maneuver. If you or a creature within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack, you can expend one superiority die as a reaction if you’re wielding a weapon or a shield. Roll the die, and add the number rolled to the target’s AC against that attack. If the attack still hits, the target has resistance against the attack’s damage.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <slots optional="YES">0,5</slots>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Ferocious Charger</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you gain additional benefits when you use your Trip Attack maneuver. You can expend up to two superiority dice on it, adding both dice to the damage roll. When you spend two dice in this way, the target has disadvantage on its Strength saving throw to avoid being knocked prone.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <slots optional="YES">0,6</slots>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Relentless</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain one superiority die.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your superiority dice turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  <autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Monster Hunter (UA)</name>
		<text>As an archetypal Monster Hunter, you are an expert at defeating supernatural threats. Typically mentored by an older, experienced Monster Hunter, you learn to overcome a variety of unnatural defenses and attacks, including those of undead, lycanthropes, and other creatures of horror.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Gothic heroes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Nature, or Perception. You can gain proficiency with a tool of your choice in place of one skill choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Using Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>You can expend superiority dice to gain a number of different benefits:</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after making the attack roll, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you damage a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the damage roll. You can use this ability after rolling damage. If the attack causes the target to make a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration, it has disadvantage on that save.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make an Intelligence, a Wisdom, or a Charisma saving throw, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this feature only before you learn if the save succeeded or failed.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make a Wisdom (Perception) check to detect a hidden creature or object, or a Wisdom (Insight) check to determine if someone is lying to you, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this feature after seeing the total but before learning if you succeeded or failed.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Hunter's Mysticism</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, your study of the supernatural gives you a limited ability to use magic. You can cast detect magic as a ritual. You can cast protection from evil and good, but you cannot cast it again with this feature until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
		<text>	In addition, you gain the ability to speak one of the following languages of your choice: Abyssal, Celestial, or Infernal.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Monster Slayer</name>
		<text>At 7th level, whenever you expend superiority dice to add to a damage roll, you can expend up to two dice instead of just one, adding both to the roll. Both dice are expended as normal. If the target of your attack is an aberration, a fey, a fiend, or an undead, you deal maximum damage with both dice, instead of rolling them.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Relentless</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	</autolevel>

  <autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Scout (UA)</name>
		<text>The archetypal Scout excels at finding safe passage through dangerous regions. Scouts usually favor light armor and ranged weapons, but they are comfortable using heavier gear when faced with intense fighting.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in three of the following skills of your choice: Acrobatics, Athletics, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival. You can choose to gain proficiency with thieves' tools in place of one skill choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a long or short rest. You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Using Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>You can expend superiority dice to gain a number of different benefits.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make a check that allows you to apply your proficiency in Athletics, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival, you can expend one superiority die to bolster the check. Add half the number rolled on the superiority die (rounding up) to your check. You apply this bonus after making the check but before learning if it was successful.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after making the attack roll, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• If you are hit by an attack while wearing light or medium armor, you can expend one superiority die as a reaction, adding the number rolled to your AC. If the attack still hits, you take half damage from it.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Natural Explorer</name>
		<text>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions. Choose one type of favored terrain: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or the Underdark. When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you're proficient in.</text>
		<text>	While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• Your group can't become lost except by magical means.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</text>
		<text />
		<text>You choose additional favored terrain types at 7th and 15th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Relentless</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your superiority dice turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  <spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<autolevel level="3">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,2,0,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="13">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="17">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,1</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,1</slots>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Eldritch Knight</name>
		<text>The archetypal Eldritch Knight combines the martial mastery common to all fighters with a careful study of magic. Eldritch Knights use magical techniques similar to those practiced by wizards. They focus their study on two of the eight schools of magic - abjuration and evocation. Abjuration spells grant an Eldritch Knight additional protection in battle, and evocation spells deal damage to many foes at once, extending the fighter's reach in combat. These knights learn a comparatively small number of spells, committing them to memory instead of keeping them in a spellbook.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Spellcasting</name>
		<text>When you reach 3rd level, you augment your martial prowess with the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Cantrips</text>
		<text>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Spell Slots</text>
		<text>The Eldritch Knight Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
		<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell shield and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast shield using either slot.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Spells Known of 1st-Level and Higher</text>
		<text>You know three 1st-level wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the abjuration and evocation spells on the wizard spell list.</text>
		<text>	The Spells Known column of the Eldritch Knight Spellcasting table shows when you learn more wizard spells of 1st level or higher. Each of these spells must be an abjuration or evocation spell of your choice, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
		<text>	The spells you learn at 8th, 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the wizard spells you know with another spell of your choice from the wizard spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, and it must be an abjuration or evocation spell, unless you're replacing the spell you gained at 8th, 14th, or 20th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
		<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
		<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</text>
		<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Weapon Bond</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you learn a ritual that creates a magical bond between yourself and one weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. The weapon must be within your reach throughout the ritual, at the conclusion of which you touch the weapon and forge the bond.</text>
		<text>	Once you have bonded a weapon to yourself, you can't be disarmed of that weapon unless you are incapacitated. If it is on the same plane of existence, you can summon that weapon as a bonus action on your turn, causing it to teleport instantly to your hand.</text>
		<text>	You can have up to two bonded weapons, but can summon only one at a time with your bonus action. If you attempt to bond with a third weapon, you must break the bond with one of the other two.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: War Magic</name>
		<text>Beginning at 7th level, when you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Additional Cantrip</name>
		<text>You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Eldritch Strike</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you learn how to make your weapon strikes undercut a creature's resistance to your spells. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, that creature has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes against a spell you cast before the end of your next turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Arcane Charge</name>
		<text>At 15th level, you gain the ability to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see when you use your Action Surge. You can teleport before or after the additional action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Improved War Magic</name>
		<text>Starting at 18th level, when you use your action to cast a spell, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  <autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Champion</name>
		<text>The archetypal Champion focuses on the development of raw physical power honed to deadly perfection. Those who model themselves on this archetype combine rigorous training with physical excellence to deal devastating blows.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Improved Critical</name>
		<text>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. </text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Remarkable Athlete</name>
		<text>Starting at 7th level, you can add half your proficiency bonus (round up) to any Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution check you make that doesn't already use your proficiency bonus.</text>
		<text>	In addition, when you make a running long jump, the distance you can cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Strength modifier.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Additional Fighting Style</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you can choose a second option from the Fighting Style class feature.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Superior Critical</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 18-20.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Survivor</name>
		<text>At 18th level, you attain the pinnacle of resilience in battle. At the start of each of your turns, you regain hit points equal to 5 + your Constitution modifier if you have no more than half of your hit points left. You don't gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>
  <autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Samurai (UA)</name>
		<text>The Samurai is a fighter who draws on an implacable fighting spirit to overcome enemies. A Samurai's willpower is nearly unbreakable, and the enemies in a Samurai's path have two choices: yield or die fighting.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Fighting Spirit</name>
		<text>Starting at 3rd level, the might of your willpower can shield you and help you strike true. As a bonus action on your turn, you can give yourself two benefits: advantage on all attack rolls and resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. These benefits last until the end of your next turn.</text>
		<text>	You can use this feature three times. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Elegant Courtier</name>
		<text>Starting at 7th level, your discipline and attention to detail allow you to excel in social situations that require strict adherence to etiquette. You can add your Wisdom modifier to any Charisma check you make to persuade or please a noble or anyone else of high social station.</text>
		<text>	You also gain proficiency in the History, Insight, or Persuasion skill (choose one). Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Unbreakable Will</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superior willpower allows you to shrug off mind-assaulting effects. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency in Intelligence or Charisma saving throws (choose one).</text>
		<text>	Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 3</text>
		<proficiency>wisdom</proficiency>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Rapid Strike</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Strength Before Death</name>
		<text>Starting at 18th level, your fighting spirit can delay the grasp of death. If you take damage that would reduce you to 0 hit points, you can delay that damage and immediately take a bonus turn, interrupting the current turn. You don't take the damage until the bonus turn ends. It is possible to do things, such as gaining resistance, that change how much of that damage you take.</text>
		<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  <spellAbility>Dexterity</spellAbility>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Battle Master</name>
		<text>Those who emulate the archetypal Battle Master employ martial techniques passed down through generations. To a Battle Master, combat is an academic field, sometimes including subjects beyond battle such as weaponsmithing and calligraphy. Not every fighter absorbs the lessons of history, theory, and artistry that are reflected in the Battle Master archetype, but those who do are well-rounded fighters of great skill and knowledge.</text>
	  </feature>

	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn maneuvers that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Maneuvers</text>
		<text>You learn three maneuvers of your choice, which are listed in the Fighter (Battle Master) spell list, as well as optional features. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack.</text>
		<text>	You learn two additional maneuvers of your choice at 7th, 10th, and 15th level. Each time you learn new maneuvers, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Superiority Dice</text>
		<text>You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Saving Throws</text>
		<text>Some of your maneuvers require your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver's effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows: Maneuver save DC = 8 + proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice)</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Student of War</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you gain proficiency with one type of artisan's tools of your choice.</text>
	  </feature>

	  
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Commander's Strike</name>
		<text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks and use a bonus action to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you and expend one superiority die. That creature can immediately use its reaction to make one weapon attack, adding the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Disarming Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to disarm the target, forcing it to drop one item of your choice that it's holding. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, it drops the object you choose. The object lands at its feet.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Distracting Strike</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to distract the creature, giving your allies an opening. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll. The next attack roll against the target by an attacker other than you has advantage if the attack is made before the start of your next turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Evasive Footwork</name>
		<text>When you move, you can expend one superiority die, rolling the die and adding the number rolled to your AC until you stop moving.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Feinting Attack</name>
		<text>You can expend one superiority die and use a bonus action on your turn to feint, choosing one creature within 5 feet of you as your target. You have advantage on your next attack roll this turn against that creature. If that attack hits, add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Goading Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to goad the target into attacking you. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on all attack rolls against targets other than you until the end of your next turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Lunging Attack</name>
		<text>When you make a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can expend one superiority die to increase your reach for that attack by 5 feet. If you hit, you add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Maneuvering Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to maneuver one of your comrades into a more advantageous position. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and you choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you. That creature can use its reaction to move up to half its speed without provoking opportunity attacks from the target of your attack.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Menacing Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to frighten the target. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Parry</name>
		<text>When another creature damages you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction and expend one superiority die to reduce the damage by the number you roll on your superiority die + your Dexterity modifier</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Precision Attack</name>
		<text>When you make a weapon attack roll against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this maneuver before or after making the attack roll, but before any effects of the attack are applied.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Pushing Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to drive the target back. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and if the target is Large or smaller, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you push the target up to 15 feet away from you.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Rally</name>
		<text>On your turn, you can use a bonus action and expend one superiority die to bolster the resolve of one of your companions. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you. That creature gains temporary hit points equal to the superiority die roll + your Charisma modifier.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Riposte</name>
		<text>When a creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction and expend one superiority die to make a melee weapon attack against the creature. If you hit, you add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Sweeping Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to damage another creature with the same attack. Choose another creature within 5 feet of the original target and within your reach. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes damage equal to the number you roll on your superiority die. The damage is of the same type dealt by the original attack.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Trip Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to knock the target down. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and if the target is Large or smaller, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you knock the target prone.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Maneuvers</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you learn two additional maneuvers of your choice, which are listed in the Fighter (Battle Master) spell list, as well as optional features at level 3.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Superiority Die</name>
		<text>You gain another superiority die at 7th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Know Your Enemy</name>
		<text>If you spend at least 1 minute observing or interacting with another creature outside combat, you can learn certain information about its capabilities compared to your own. The DM tells you if the creature is your equal, superior, or inferior in regard to two of the following characteristics of your choice:</text>
		<text>• Strength score</text>
		<text>• Dexterity score</text>
		<text>• Constitution score</text>
		<text>• Armor Class</text>
		<text>• Current hit points</text>
		<text>• Total class levels (if any)</text>
		<text>• Fighter class levels (if any)</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Maneuvers</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you learn two additional maneuvers of your choice, which are listed in the Fighter (Battle Master) spell list, as well as optional features at level 3.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Improved Combat Superiority (d10)</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Maneuvers</name>
		<text>At 15th level, you learn two additional maneuvers of your choice, which are listed in the Fighter (Battle Master) spell list, as well as optional features at level 3.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Superiority Die</name>
		<text>You gain another superiority die at 15th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Relentless</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Improved Combat Superiority (d12)</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your superiority dice turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter !Base">
		<name>Fighter !Base</name>
<hd>10</hd>
	<proficiency>Strength, Constitution</proficiency>
	<autolevel level="1">
	  <feature>
		<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
		<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.
		</text>
		<text>Armor: light armor, medium armor, heavy armor, shields</text>
		<text>Weapons: simple weapons, martial weapons</text>
		<text>Tools: none</text>
		<text>Skills: Choose two skills from Acrobatics, Animal Handling, Athletics, History, Insight, Intimidation, Perception, and Survival
		</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature>
		<name>Starting Equipment</name>
		<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• (a) chain mail or (b) leather, longbow, and 20 arrows</text>
		<text>• (a) a martial weapon and a shield or (b) two martial weapons</text>
		<text>• (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) two handaxes</text>
		<text>• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
		<text />
		<text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="1">
	  <feature>
		<name>Fighting Style</name>
		<text>You adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose a fighting style from the list of optional features. You can't take the same Fighting Style option more than once, even if you get to choose again.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Archery</name>
		<text>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Defense</name>
		<text>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Dueling</name>
		<text>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Great Weapon Fighting</name>
		<text>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.
		</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Protection</name>
		<text>When a creature you can see attacks a target other than you that is within 5 feet of you, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll. You must be wielding a shield.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Two-Weapon Fighting</name>
		<text>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature>
		<name>Second Wind</name>
		<text>You have a limited well of stamina that you can draw on to protect yourself from harm. On your turn, you can use a bonus action to regain hit points equal to 1d10 + your fighter level.</text>
		<text>    Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="2">
	  <feature>
		<name>Action Surge</name>
		<text>Starting at 2nd level, you can push yourself beyond your normal limits for a moment. On your turn, you can take one additional action on top of your regular action and a possible bonus action.</text>
		<text>    Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again. Starting at 17th level, you can use it twice before a rest, but only once on the same turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature>
		<name>Martial Archetype</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate in your combat styles and techniques. Choose Champion, Battle Master, or Eldritch Knight, all detailed at the end of the class description. The archetype you choose grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="4">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="5">
	  <feature>
		<name>Extra Attack</name>
		<text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
		<text>    The number of attacks increases to three when you reach 11th level in this class and to four when you reach 20th level in this class.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="6">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 6th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="8">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="9">
	  <feature>
		<name>Indomitable</name>
		<text>Beginning at 9th level, you can reroll a saving throw that you fail. If you do so, you must use the new roll, and you can't use this feature again until you finish a long rest.</text>
		<text>    You can use this feature twice between long rests starting at 13th level and three times between long rests starting at 17th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="11">
	  <feature>
		<name>Extra Attack (2)</name>
		<text>At 11th level, you can attack three times whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="12">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="13">
	  <feature>
		<name>Indomitable (two uses)</name>
		<text>At 13th level, you can use Indomitable twice between long rests.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="14">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 14th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature. </text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="16">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.
		</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="17">
	  <feature>
		<name>Action Surge (two uses)</name>
		<text>At 17th level, you can use Action Surge twice before a rest, but only once on the same turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature>
		<name>Indomitable (three uses)</name>
		<text>At 17th level, you can use Indomitable three times between long rests.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="19">
	  <feature>
		<name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
		<text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
		<text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="20">
	  <feature>
		<name>Extra Attack (3)</name>
		<text>At 20th level, you can attack four times whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	
	
	<autolevel UA="UA" level="1">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Close Quarters Shooter (UA)</name>
		<text>When making a ranged attack while you are within 5 feet of a hostile creature, you do not have disadvantage on the attack roll. Your ranged attacks ignore half cover and three-quarters cover against targets within 30 feet of you. You have a +1 bonus to attack rolls on ranged attacks.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This fighting style is from Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.
		</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Mariner (UA)</name>
		<text>As long as you are not wearing heavy armor or using a shield, you have a swimming speed and a climbing speed equal to your normal speed, and you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This fighting style is from Unearthed Arcana: Waterborne Adventures, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.
		</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Fighting Style: Tunnel Fighter (UA)</name>
		<text>As a bonus action, you can enter a defensive stance that lasts until the start of your next turn. While in your defensive stance, you can make opportunity attacks without using your reaction, and you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against a creature that moves more than 5 feet while within your reach.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This fighting style is from Unearthed Arcana: Light, Dark, Underdark!, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Arcane Archer)">
	<name>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Arcane Archer (UA)</name>
		<text>An Arcane Archer studies a unique elven method of archery that weaves magic into attacks to produce supernatural effects. Among elves, Arcane Archers are some of their most elite warriors. These archers stand watch over the fringes of elven domains, keeping a keen eye out for trespassers and using magic-infused arrows to defeat monsters and invaders before they can reach elven settlements. Over the centuries, the methods of these elf archers have been learned by members of other races who can also balance arcane aptitude with archery.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Subclasses, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
		<text>	This had an earlier version included in Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Magic Arrow</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain the ability to infuse arrows with magic. Whenever you fire a nonmagical arrow from a shortbow or longbow, you can make it a magic arrow, with a +1 bonus to the attack and damage rolls. The magic fades from the arrow immediately after it hits or misses its target.</text>
	  </feature>
	<feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you learn to unleash special magical effects with some of your shots. When you gain this feature, you learn two Arcane Shot options of your choice (see the “Arcane Shot Options” section below).</text>
		<text>	Once per turn when you fire a magic arrow from a shortbow or longbow as part of the Attack action, you can apply one of your Arcane Shot options to that arrow. You decide to use the option when the arrow hits, unless the option doesn’t involve an attack roll. You have two uses of this ability, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain an additional Arcane Shot option of your choice when you reach certain levels in this class: 7th, 10th, 15th, and 18th level. Each option also improves when you become an 18th-level fighter.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Archer's Lore</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you learn magical theory or some of the secrets of nature—typical for practitioners of this elven martial tradition. You gain proficiency in either the Arcana or the Nature skill.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Options</name>
			<text>The Arcane Shot feature lets you choose options for it at certain levels. The options are presented here in alphabetical order. They are all magical effects, and each one is associated with one of the schools of magic.</text>
			<text>	If an option requires a saving throw, your Arcane Shot save DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Banishing Arrow:</text>
			<text>You use abjuration magic to try to temporarily banish your target to a harmless location in the Feywild. If the arrow hits a creature, the target must also succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be banished. While banished in this way, its speed is 0, and it is incapacitated. At the end of its next turn, the target reappears in the space it vacated or in the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied.</text>
			<text>	After you reach 18th level in this class, a target also takes 2d6 force damage when the arrow hits it.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Brute Bane Arrow:</text>
			<text>You weave necromantic magic into your arrow. If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 necrotic damage, and it must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the damage of the target’s attacks is halved until the start of your next turn.</text>
			<text>	The necrotic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Bursting Arrow:</text>
			<text>You imbue your arrow with a blast of force energy drawn from the school of evocation. If the arrow hits a creature, the target and each creature within 10 feet of it also take 2d6 force damage each.</text>
			<text>	The force damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Grasping Arrow:</text>
			<text>When this arrow strikes its target, conjuration magic creates grasping, poisonous brambles, which wrap around the target. If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 poison damage, its speed is reduced by 10 feet, and it takes 2d6 slashing damage the first time on each turn it moves 1 foot or more without teleporting. The target or any creature that can reach it can use its action to remove the brambles with a successful Strength (Athletics) check against your Arcane Shot save DC. Otherwise, the brambles last for 1 minute or until you use this option again.</text>
			<text>	The poison and slashing damage both increase to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Mind-Scrambling Arrow:</text>
			<text>Your enchantment magic causes this arrow to temporarily beguile its target. Choose one of your allies within 30 feet of the target. If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 psychic damage, and it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or it can’t attack the chosen ally or include that ally in a harmful area of effect until the start of your next turn. This effect ends early if the chosen ally deals any damage to the target.</text>
			<text>	The psychic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Piercing Arrow:</text>
			<text>You use transmutation magic to give your arrow an ethereal quality. When you use this option, you don’t make an attack roll for the attack. Instead, the arrow fires forward in a line that is 1 foot wide and 30 feet long, before disappearing. The arrow passes harmlessly through objects, ignoring cover. Each creature in that line must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a target takes damage as if it were hit by the arrow, plus an extra 1d6 piercing damage. On a successful save, a target takes half as much damage.</text>
			<text>	The piercing damage increases to 2d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Seeking Arrow:</text>
			<text>Using divination magic, you grant your arrow the ability to seek out your target, allowing the arrow to curve and twist its path in search of its prey. When you use this option, you don’t make an attack roll for the attack. Instead, choose one creature you have seen in the past minute. The arrow flies toward that creature, moving around corners if necessary and ignoring three-quarters cover and half cover. If the target is within the weapon’s range and there is a path large enough for the arrow to travel to the target, the target must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, it takes damage as if it were hit by the arrow, plus an extra 1d6 force damage, and you learn the target’s current location. On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage, and you don’t learn its location.</text>
			<text>	The force damage increases to 2d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
			<text />
			<text>	Shadow Arrow:</text>
			<text>You weave illusion magic into your arrow, causing it to occlude your foe's vision with shadows. If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 psychic damage, and it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be unable to see anything farther than 5 feet away until the start of your next turn.</text>
			<text>	The psychic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Curving Shot</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you learn how to direct an errant arrow toward a new target. When you make an attack roll with a magic arrow and miss, you can use a bonus action to reroll the attack roll against a different target within 60 feet of the original target.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (3rd)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (4th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Ever-Ready Shot</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, your magical archery is ever available to you when you need it most. If you roll initiative and have no uses of Arcane Shot remaining, you regain one use of it</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (5th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Deadly Arrow</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your Arcane Arrow's bonus damage increases to 4d6 force damage.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Arcane Archer: Arcane Shot Option (6th)</name>
		<text>You gain an additional Arcane Shot option.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Battle Master)">
	<name>Fighter (Battle Master)</name>
	<spellAbility>Dexterity</spellAbility>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Battle Master</name>
		<text>Those who emulate the archetypal Battle Master employ martial techniques passed down through generations. To a Battle Master, combat is an academic field, sometimes including subjects beyond battle such as weaponsmithing and calligraphy. Not every fighter absorbs the lessons of history, theory, and artistry that are reflected in the Battle Master archetype, but those who do are well-rounded fighters of great skill and knowledge.</text>
	  </feature>

	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn maneuvers that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Maneuvers</text>
		<text>You learn three maneuvers of your choice, which are listed in the Fighter (Battle Master) spell list, as well as optional features. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack.</text>
		<text>	You learn two additional maneuvers of your choice at 7th, 10th, and 15th level. Each time you learn new maneuvers, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Superiority Dice</text>
		<text>You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Saving Throws</text>
		<text>Some of your maneuvers require your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver's effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows: Maneuver save DC = 8 + proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice)</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Student of War</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you gain proficiency with one type of artisan's tools of your choice.</text>
	  </feature>

	  
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Commander's Strike</name>
		<text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks and use a bonus action to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you and expend one superiority die. That creature can immediately use its reaction to make one weapon attack, adding the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Disarming Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to disarm the target, forcing it to drop one item of your choice that it's holding. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, it drops the object you choose. The object lands at its feet.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Distracting Strike</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to distract the creature, giving your allies an opening. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll. The next attack roll against the target by an attacker other than you has advantage if the attack is made before the start of your next turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Evasive Footwork</name>
		<text>When you move, you can expend one superiority die, rolling the die and adding the number rolled to your AC until you stop moving.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Feinting Attack</name>
		<text>You can expend one superiority die and use a bonus action on your turn to feint, choosing one creature within 5 feet of you as your target. You have advantage on your next attack roll this turn against that creature. If that attack hits, add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Goading Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to goad the target into attacking you. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on all attack rolls against targets other than you until the end of your next turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Lunging Attack</name>
		<text>When you make a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can expend one superiority die to increase your reach for that attack by 5 feet. If you hit, you add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Maneuvering Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to maneuver one of your comrades into a more advantageous position. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and you choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you. That creature can use its reaction to move up to half its speed without provoking opportunity attacks from the target of your attack.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Menacing Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to frighten the target. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Parry</name>
		<text>When another creature damages you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction and expend one superiority die to reduce the damage by the number you roll on your superiority die + your Dexterity modifier</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Precision Attack</name>
		<text>When you make a weapon attack roll against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this maneuver before or after making the attack roll, but before any effects of the attack are applied.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Pushing Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to drive the target back. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and if the target is Large or smaller, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you push the target up to 15 feet away from you.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Rally</name>
		<text>On your turn, you can use a bonus action and expend one superiority die to bolster the resolve of one of your companions. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you. That creature gains temporary hit points equal to the superiority die roll + your Charisma modifier.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Riposte</name>
		<text>When a creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction and expend one superiority die to make a melee weapon attack against the creature. If you hit, you add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Sweeping Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to damage another creature with the same attack. Choose another creature within 5 feet of the original target and within your reach. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes damage equal to the number you roll on your superiority die. The damage is of the same type dealt by the original attack.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Maneuver: Trip Attack</name>
		<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to knock the target down. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and if the target is Large or smaller, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you knock the target prone.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Maneuvers</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you learn two additional maneuvers of your choice, which are listed in the Fighter (Battle Master) spell list, as well as optional features at level 3.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Superiority Die</name>
		<text>You gain another superiority die at 7th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Know Your Enemy</name>
		<text>If you spend at least 1 minute observing or interacting with another creature outside combat, you can learn certain information about its capabilities compared to your own. The DM tells you if the creature is your equal, superior, or inferior in regard to two of the following characteristics of your choice:</text>
		<text>• Strength score</text>
		<text>• Dexterity score</text>
		<text>• Constitution score</text>
		<text>• Armor Class</text>
		<text>• Current hit points</text>
		<text>• Total class levels (if any)</text>
		<text>• Fighter class levels (if any)</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Maneuvers</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you learn two additional maneuvers of your choice, which are listed in the Fighter (Battle Master) spell list, as well as optional features at level 3.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Improved Combat Superiority (d10)</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Maneuvers</name>
		<text>At 15th level, you learn two additional maneuvers of your choice, which are listed in the Fighter (Battle Master) spell list, as well as optional features at level 3.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Additional Superiority Die</name>
		<text>You gain another superiority die at 15th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Relentless</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Battle Master: Improved Combat Superiority (d12)</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your superiority dice turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Cavalier)">
	<name>Fighter (Cavalier)</name>
	<spellAbility>Strength</spellAbility>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Cavalier (UA)</name>
		<text>The archetypal Cavalier excels at mounted combat. Usually born among the nobility and raised at court, a Cavalier is equally at home leading a cavalry charge or exchanging repartee at a state dinner. Cavaliers also learn how to guard those in their charge from harm, often serving as the protectors of their superiors and of the weak. Drawn to right wrongs or earn prestige, many of these fighters leave their lives of comfort to embark on glorious adventure.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
		<text>	This had an earlier version included in Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old</text>
	  </feature>

	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Bonus Proficiency</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, History, Insight, Performance, or Persuasion. Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Born to the Saddle</name>
		<text>Starting at 3rd level, your mastery as a rider becomes apparent. You have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount. If you fall off your mount and descend no more than 10 feet, you can land on your feet if you’re not incapacitated.</text>
		<text>Finally, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed.</text>
	  </feature>

		<slots optional="YES">0,4</slots>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>	You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Maneuvers:</text>
		<text>	You spend your superiority dice on your maneuvers. You can use more than one maneuver per turn, but no more than one maneuver per attack.</text>
		<text>	You know the following maneuvers:</text>
		<text />
		<text>Control Mount. When you make a Wisdom (Animal Handling) check to influence a creature that you or an ally is riding, you can expend one superiority die, roll it, and add the number rolled to the check. You can do this before or after rolling the d20, but before applying the results of the check.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Precision Attack. When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die, roll it, and add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after rolling the d20, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Trip Attack. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to knock the target down. Roll the die, and add it to the attack’s damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must also succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier) or be knocked prone.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Warding Maneuver. If you or a creature within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack, you can expend one superiority die as a reaction if you’re wielding a weapon or a shield. Roll the die, and add the number rolled to the target’s AC against that attack. If the attack still hits, the target has resistance against the attack’s damage.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <slots optional="YES">0,5</slots>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Ferocious Charger</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you gain additional benefits when you use your Trip Attack maneuver. You can expend up to two superiority dice on it, adding both dice to the damage roll. When you spend two dice in this way, the target has disadvantage on its Strength saving throw to avoid being knocked prone.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <slots optional="YES">0,6</slots>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Relentless</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain one superiority die.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Cavalier: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your superiority dice turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Champion)">
	<name>Fighter (Champion)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Champion</name>
		<text>The archetypal Champion focuses on the development of raw physical power honed to deadly perfection. Those who model themselves on this archetype combine rigorous training with physical excellence to deal devastating blows.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Improved Critical</name>
		<text>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20. </text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Remarkable Athlete</name>
		<text>Starting at 7th level, you can add half your proficiency bonus (round up) to any Strength, Dexterity, or Constitution check you make that doesn't already use your proficiency bonus.</text>
		<text>	In addition, when you make a running long jump, the distance you can cover increases by a number of feet equal to your Strength modifier.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Additional Fighting Style</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you can choose a second option from the Fighting Style class feature.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Superior Critical</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 18-20.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Champion: Survivor</name>
		<text>At 18th level, you attain the pinnacle of resilience in battle. At the start of each of your turns, you regain hit points equal to 5 + your Constitution modifier if you have no more than half of your hit points left. You don't gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>
  </class><class name="Fighter (Eldritch Knight)">
	<name>Fighter (Eldritch Knight)</name>
	<spellAbility>Intelligence</spellAbility>
	<autolevel level="3">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,2,0,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="4">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="5">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="6">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,3,0,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="8">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="9">
	  <slots optional="YES">2,4,2,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="10">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="12">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,0,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="13">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="14">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,2,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="16">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="17">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,0</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="19">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,1</slots>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="20">
	  <slots optional="YES">3,4,3,3,1</slots>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Eldritch Knight</name>
		<text>The archetypal Eldritch Knight combines the martial mastery common to all fighters with a careful study of magic. Eldritch Knights use magical techniques similar to those practiced by wizards. They focus their study on two of the eight schools of magic - abjuration and evocation. Abjuration spells grant an Eldritch Knight additional protection in battle, and evocation spells deal damage to many foes at once, extending the fighter's reach in combat. These knights learn a comparatively small number of spells, committing them to memory instead of keeping them in a spellbook.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Spellcasting</name>
		<text>When you reach 3rd level, you augment your martial prowess with the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the wizard spell list.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Cantrips</text>
		<text>You learn two cantrips of your choice from the wizard spell list. You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Spell Slots</text>
		<text>The Eldritch Knight Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have to cast your spells of 1st level and higher. To cast one of these spells, you must expend a slot of the spell's level or higher. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a long rest.</text>
		<text>	For example, if you know the 1st-level spell shield and have a 1st-level and a 2nd-level spell slot available, you can cast shield using either slot.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Spells Known of 1st-Level and Higher</text>
		<text>You know three 1st-level wizard spells of your choice, two of which you must choose from the abjuration and evocation spells on the wizard spell list.</text>
		<text>	The Spells Known column of the Eldritch Knight Spellcasting table shows when you learn more wizard spells of 1st level or higher. Each of these spells must be an abjuration or evocation spell of your choice, and must be of a level for which you have spell slots. For instance, when you reach 7th level in this class, you can learn one new spell of 1st or 2nd level.</text>
		<text>	The spells you learn at 8th, 14th, and 20th level can come from any school of magic.</text>
		<text>	Whenever you gain a level in this class, you can replace one of the wizard spells you know with another spell of your choice from the wizard spell list. The new spell must be of a level for which you have spell slots, and it must be an abjuration or evocation spell, unless you're replacing the spell you gained at 8th, 14th, or 20th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
		<text>Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your wizard spells, since you learn your spells through study and memorization. You use your Intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a wizard spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
		<text>	Spell save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</text>
		<text>	Spell attack modifier = your proficiency bonus + your Intelligence modifier</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Weapon Bond</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you learn a ritual that creates a magical bond between yourself and one weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. The weapon must be within your reach throughout the ritual, at the conclusion of which you touch the weapon and forge the bond.</text>
		<text>	Once you have bonded a weapon to yourself, you can't be disarmed of that weapon unless you are incapacitated. If it is on the same plane of existence, you can summon that weapon as a bonus action on your turn, causing it to teleport instantly to your hand.</text>
		<text>	You can have up to two bonded weapons, but can summon only one at a time with your bonus action. If you attempt to bond with a third weapon, you must break the bond with one of the other two.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: War Magic</name>
		<text>Beginning at 7th level, when you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Additional Cantrip</name>
		<text>You learn an additional wizard cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Eldritch Strike</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you learn how to make your weapon strikes undercut a creature's resistance to your spells. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, that creature has disadvantage on the next saving throw it makes against a spell you cast before the end of your next turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Arcane Charge</name>
		<text>At 15th level, you gain the ability to teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see when you use your Action Surge. You can teleport before or after the additional action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Eldritch Knight: Improved War Magic</name>
		<text>Starting at 18th level, when you use your action to cast a spell, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Knight)">
	<name>Fighter (Knight)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Knight (UA)</name>
		<text>The Knight is a colossus on the battlefield who can shrug off attacks and protect allies from harm. Knights fight from the saddle when they can, and in combat they are expected to seek out and lock down the mightiest of the enemy's forces. On adventures, they are the armored bulwark that strives to keep the rest of the party safe.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Born to the Saddle</name>
		<text>Starting at 3rd level, mounting or dismounting a creature costs you only 5 feet of movement, rather than half your speed. In addition, you have advantage on saving throws made to avoid falling off your mount. If you fall off it, you can automatically land on your feet if you aren't incapacitated and you fall less than 10 feet.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Implacable Mark</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you excel at foiling attacks and protecting your allies by menacing your foes. When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, the target is marked by you until the end of your next turn. A creature ignores this effect if the creature can't be frightened.</text>
		<text>	The marked target has disadvantage on any attack roll against a creature other than you or someone else who marked it.</text>
		<text>	If a target marked by you is within 5 feet of you on its turn and it moves at least 1 foot or makes an attack that suffers disadvantage from this feature, you can make one melee weapon attack against it using your reaction. This attack roll has advantage, and if it hits, the attack's weapon deals extra damage to the target equal to your fighter level.</text>
		<text>	You can make this special attack even if you have already expended your reaction this round, but not if you have already used your reaction this turn. You can make this attack three times, and you regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Noble Cavalry</name>
		<text>At 7th level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, History, Insight, Persuasion, or Religion. Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Hold the Line</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you master the ability to harass and slow your enemies. As a reaction when a creature moves at least 1 foot within 5 feet of you, you can make one melee weapon attack against that creature. If you hit, the attack's weapon deals extra damage to the target equal to half your fighter level, and the target's speed is reduced to 0 until the end of this turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Rapid Strike</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Knight: Defender's Blade</name>
		<text>At 18th level, you respond to danger with extraordinary vigilance. You can use your reaction for an opportunity attack even if you have already expended your reaction this round, but not if you have already used your reaction this turn.</text>
		<text>	In addition, you gain a +1 bonus to AC while wearing heavy armor.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Monster Hunter)">
	<name>Fighter (Monster Hunter)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Monster Hunter (UA)</name>
		<text>As an archetypal Monster Hunter, you are an expert at defeating supernatural threats. Typically mentored by an older, experienced Monster Hunter, you learn to overcome a variety of unnatural defenses and attacks, including those of undead, lycanthropes, and other creatures of horror.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Gothic heroes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in two of the following skills of your choice: Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, Nature, or Perception. You can gain proficiency with a tool of your choice in place of one skill choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>	You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Using Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>You can expend superiority dice to gain a number of different benefits:</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after making the attack roll, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you damage a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the damage roll. You can use this ability after rolling damage. If the attack causes the target to make a Constitution saving throw to maintain concentration, it has disadvantage on that save.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make an Intelligence, a Wisdom, or a Charisma saving throw, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this feature only before you learn if the save succeeded or failed.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make a Wisdom (Perception) check to detect a hidden creature or object, or a Wisdom (Insight) check to determine if someone is lying to you, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this feature after seeing the total but before learning if you succeeded or failed.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Hunter's Mysticism</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, your study of the supernatural gives you a limited ability to use magic. You can cast detect magic as a ritual. You can cast protection from evil and good, but you cannot cast it again with this feature until you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
		<text>	In addition, you gain the ability to speak one of the following languages of your choice: Abyssal, Celestial, or Infernal.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Monster Slayer</name>
		<text>At 7th level, whenever you expend superiority dice to add to a damage roll, you can expend up to two dice instead of just one, adding both to the roll. Both dice are expended as normal. If the target of your attack is an aberration, a fey, a fiend, or an undead, you deal maximum damage with both dice, instead of rolling them.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Monster Hunter: Relentless</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Purple Dragon Knight)">
	<name>Fighter (Purple Dragon Knight)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Purple Dragon Knight (Banneret)</name>
		<text>Purple Dragon Knights are warriors who hail from the kingdom of Cormyr. Pledged to protect the crown, they take the fight against evil beyond the kingdom's borders. They are tasked with wandering the land as knights errant, relying on their judgment, bravery, and fidelity to guide them in defeating evildoers.</text>
		<text>A Purple Dragon Knight inspires greatness in others by committing brave deeds in battle. The mere presence of a knight in a hamlet is enough to cause some orcs and bandits to seek easier prey. A lone knight is a skilled warrior, but a knight leading a band of allies can transform even the most poorly equipped militia into a ferocious war band.</text>
		<text>A knight prefers to lead through deeds, not words. As a knight spearheads an attack, the knight's actions can awaken reserves of courage and conviction in allies that they never suspected they had.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Restriction: Knighthood</name>
		<text>Purple Dragon Knights are tied to a specific order of Cormyrean knighthood.</text>
		<text>Banneret serves as the generic name for this archetype if you use it in other campaign settings or to model warlords other than the Purple Dragon Knights.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Rallying Cry</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you learn how to inspire your allies to fight on past their injuries.</text>
		<text>	When you use your Second Wind feature, you can choose up to three creatures within 60 feet of you that are allied with you. Each one regains hit points equal to your fighter level, provided that the creature can see or hear you.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Royal Envoy</name>
		<text>A Purple Dragon Knight serves as an envoy of the Cormyrean crown. Knights of high standing are expected to conduct themselves with grace.</text>
		<text>	At 7th level, you gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient in it, you gain proficiency in one of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Insight, Intimidation, or Performance.</text>
		<text>	Your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make that uses Persuasion. You receive this benefit regardless of the skill proficiency you gain from this feature.</text>
		<proficiency>Persuasion</proficiency>
		<modifier category="skills">Persuasion+%0</modifier>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Inspiring Surge</name>
		<text>Starting at 10th level, when you use your Action Surge feature, you can choose one creature within 60 feet of you that is allied with you. That creature can make one melee or ranged weapon attack with its reaction, provided that it can see or hear you.</text>
		<text>	Starting at 17th level, you can choose two allies within 60 feet of you, rather than one.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Purple Dragon Knight: Bulwark</name>
		<text>Beginning at 15th level, you can extend the benefit of your Indomitable feature to an ally. When you decide to use Indomitable to reroll an Intelligence, a Wisdom, or a Charisma saving throw and you aren't incapacitated, you can choose one ally within 60 feet of you that also failed its saving throw against the same effect. If that creature can see or hear you, it can reroll its saving throw and must use the new roll.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Samurai)">
	<name>Fighter (Samurai)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Samurai (UA)</name>
		<text>The Samurai is a fighter who draws on an implacable fighting spirit to overcome enemies. A Samurai's willpower is nearly unbreakable, and the enemies in a Samurai's path have two choices: yield or die fighting.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Fighting Spirit</name>
		<text>Starting at 3rd level, the might of your willpower can shield you and help you strike true. As a bonus action on your turn, you can give yourself two benefits: advantage on all attack rolls and resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage. These benefits last until the end of your next turn.</text>
		<text>	You can use this feature three times. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Elegant Courtier</name>
		<text>Starting at 7th level, your discipline and attention to detail allow you to excel in social situations that require strict adherence to etiquette. You can add your Wisdom modifier to any Charisma check you make to persuade or please a noble or anyone else of high social station.</text>
		<text>	You also gain proficiency in the History, Insight, or Persuasion skill (choose one). Alternatively, you learn one language of your choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Unbreakable Will</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superior willpower allows you to shrug off mind-assaulting effects. You gain proficiency in Wisdom saving throws. If you already have this proficiency, you gain proficiency in Intelligence or Charisma saving throws (choose one).</text>
		<text>	Source: Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, p. 3</text>
		<proficiency>wisdom</proficiency>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Rapid Strike</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Samurai: Strength Before Death</name>
		<text>Starting at 18th level, your fighting spirit can delay the grasp of death. If you take damage that would reduce you to 0 hit points, you can delay that damage and immediately take a bonus turn, interrupting the current turn. You don't take the damage until the bonus turn ends. It is possible to do things, such as gaining resistance, that change how much of that damage you take.</text>
		<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Scout)">
	<name>Fighter (Scout)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Scout (UA)</name>
		<text>The archetypal Scout excels at finding safe passage through dangerous regions. Scouts usually favor light armor and ranged weapons, but they are comfortable using heavier gear when faced with intense fighting.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Kits of Old, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Bonus Proficiencies</name>
		<text>When you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in three of the following skills of your choice: Acrobatics, Athletics, Investigation, Medicine, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival. You can choose to gain proficiency with thieves' tools in place of one skill choice.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 3rd level, you gain a set of abilities that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a long or short rest. You gain another superiority die at 7th level and one more at 15th level.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Using Superiority Dice:</text>
		<text>You can expend superiority dice to gain a number of different benefits.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make a check that allows you to apply your proficiency in Athletics, Nature, Perception, Stealth, or Survival, you can expend one superiority die to bolster the check. Add half the number rolled on the superiority die (rounding up) to your check. You apply this bonus after making the check but before learning if it was successful.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after making the attack roll, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• If you are hit by an attack while wearing light or medium armor, you can expend one superiority die as a reaction, adding the number rolled to your AC. If the attack still hits, you take half damage from it.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Natural Explorer</name>
		<text>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions. Choose one type of favored terrain: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or the Underdark. When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you're proficient in.</text>
		<text>	While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• Difficult terrain doesn't slow your group's travel.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• Your group can't become lost except by magical means.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</text>
		<text />
		<text>You choose additional favored terrain types at 7th and 15th level.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 10th level, your superiority dice turn into d10s. At 18th level, they turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Relentless</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Scout: Improved Combat Superiority</name>
		<text>At 18th level, your superiority dice turn into d12s.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><class name="Fighter (Sharpshooter)">
	<name>Fighter (Sharpshooter)</name>

	<autolevel level="3">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Martial Archetype: Sharpshooter (UA)</name>
		<text>The Sharpshooter is a master of ranged combat. An excellent sniper and eagle-eyed scout, this fighter is a perilous foe who can defeat an entire war band so long as they are kept at range.</text>
		<text />
		<text>This Martial Archetype is from Unearthed Arcana: Fighter Martial Archetypes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
	  </feature>
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Steady Aim</name>
		<text>Beginning when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, your aim becomes deadly. As a bonus action on your turn, you can take careful aim at a creature you can see that is within range of a ranged weapon you're wielding. Until the end of this turn, your ranged attacks with that weapon gain two benefits against the target:</text>
		<text />
		<text>• The attacks ignore half and three-quarters cover.</text>
		<text />
		<text>• On each hit, the weapon deals additional damage to the target equal to 2 + half your fighter level.</text>
		<text>	You can use this feature three times. You regain all expended uses of it when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="7">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Careful Eyes</name>
		<text>Starting at 7th level, you excel at picking out hidden enemies and other threats. You can take the Search action as a bonus action.</text>
		<text>	You also gain proficiency in the Perception, Investigation, or Survival skill (choose one).</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="10">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Close-Quarters Shooting</name>
		<text>At 10th level, you learn to handle yourself in close combat. Making a ranged attack roll while within 5 feet of an enemy doesn't impose disadvantage on your roll.</text>
		<text>	In addition, if you hit a creature within 5 feet of you with a ranged attack on your turn, that creature can't take reactions until the end of this turn.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="15">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Rapid Strike</name>
		<text>Starting at 15th level, you learn to trade accuracy for swift strikes. If you have advantage on a weapon attack against a target on your turn, you can forgo that advantage to immediately make an additional weapon attack against the same target as a bonus action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

	<autolevel level="18">
	  <feature optional="YES">
		<name>Sharpshooter: Snap Shot</name>
		<text>Starting at 18th level, you are ever ready to spring into action. If you take the Attack action on your first turn of a combat, you can make one additional ranged weapon attack as part of that action.</text>
	  </feature>
	</autolevel>

  </class><spell PS="PS">
		<name>Banishing Arrow</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>A</school>
		<time />
		<duration />
		<range />
		<components />
		<classes>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</classes>
		<text>You use abjuration magic to try to temporarily banish your target to a harmless location in the Feywild.</text>
		<text>If the arrow hits a creature, the target must also succeed on a Charisma saving throw or be banished.</text>
		<text>While banished in this way, its speed is 0, and it is incapacitated.</text>
		<text>At the end of its next turn, the target reappears in the space it vacated or in the nearest unoccupied space if that space is occupied.</text>
		<text>	After you reach 18th level in this class, a target also takes 2d6 force damage when the arrow hits it.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Brute Bane Arrow</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>N</school>
		<time />
		<duration />
		<range />
		<components />
		<classes>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</classes>
		<text>You weave necromantic magic into your arrow.  </text>
		<text>If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 necrotic damage, and it must make a Constitution saving throw.</text>
		<text>On a failed save, the damage of the target’s attacks is halved until the start of your next turn.</text>
		<text>	The necrotic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Bursting Arrow</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time />
		<duration />
		<range />
		<components />
		<classes>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</classes>
		<text>You imbue your arrow with a blast of force energy drawn from the school of evocation.</text>
		<text>If the arrow hits a creature, the target and each creature within 10 feet of it also take 2d6 force damage each.</text>
		<text>	The force damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
	<name>Commander's Strike</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can forgo one of your attacks and use a bonus action to direct one of your companions to strike. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you and expend one superiority die. That creature can immediately use its reaction to make one weapon attack, adding the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell PS="PS" UA="Revised Class Options">
	<name>Control Mount</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school />
	<time>superiority die</time>
	<range />
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Cavalier)</classes>
	<text>When you make a Wisdom (Animal Handling) check to influence a creature that you or an ally is riding, you can expend one superiority die, roll it, and add the number rolled to the check. You can do this before or after rolling the d20, but before applying the results of the check.</text>
	<text />
  	<text>Add roll to Skill Check</text>
	<roll>1d8</roll>
	<roll>1d10</roll>
	<roll>1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Disarming Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to disarm the target, forcing it to drop one item of your choice that it's holding. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, it drops the object you choose. The object lands at its feet.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Distracting Strike</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to distract the creature, giving your allies an opening. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll. The next attack roll against the target by an attacker other than you has advantage if the attack is made before the start of your next turn.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Evasive Footwork</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you move, you can expend one superiority die, rolling the die and adding the number rolled to your AC until you stop moving.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Feinting Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>You can expend one superiority die and use a bonus action on your turn to feint, choosing one creature within 5 feet of you as your target. You have advantage on your next attack roll against that creature. If that attack hits, add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Goading Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to goad the target into attacking you. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the target has disadvantage on all attack rolls against targets other than you until the end of your next turn.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell PS="PS">
		<name>Grasping Arrow</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>C</school>
		<time />
		<duration />
		<range />
		<components />
		<classes>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</classes>
		<text>When this arrow strikes its target, conjuration magic creates grasping, poisonous brambles, which wrap around the target.</text>
		<text>If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 poison damage, its speed is reduced by 10 feet, and it takes 2d6 slashing damage the first time on each turn it moves 1 foot or more without teleporting. The target or any creature that can reach it can use its action to remove the brambles with a successful Strength (Athletics) check against your Arcane Shot save DC.</text>
		<text>Otherwise, the brambles last for 1 minute or until you use this option again.</text>
		<text>	The poison and slashing damage both increase to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
	<name>Lunging Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you make a melee weapon attack on your turn, you can expend one superiority die to increase your reach for that attack by 5 feet. If you hit, you add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Maneuvering Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to maneuver one of your comrades into a more advantageous position. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and you choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you. That creature can use its reaction to move up to half its speed without provoking opportunity attacks from the target of your attack.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Menacing Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to frighten the target. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and the target must make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, it is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell PS="PS">
		<name>Mind-Scrambling Arrow</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EN</school>
		<time />
		<duration />
		<range />
		<components />
		<classes>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</classes>
		<text>Your enchantment magic causes this arrow to temporarily beguile its target.</text>
		<text>Choose one of your allies within 30 feet of the target.</text>
		<text>If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 psychic damage, and it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or it can’t attack the chosen ally or include that ally in a harmful area of effect until the start of your next turn.</text>
		<text>This effect ends early if the chosen ally deals any damage to the target.</text>
		<text>	The psychic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
	<name>Parry</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When another creature damages you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction and expend one superiority die to reduce the damage by the number you roll on your superiority die + your Dexterity modifier</text>
  </spell>
  <spell PS="PS">
		<name>Piercing Arrow</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>T</school>
		<time />
		<duration />
		<range />
		<components />
		<classes>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</classes>
		<text>You use transmutation magic to give your arrow an ethereal quality.</text>
		<text>When you use this option, you don’t make an attack roll for the attack. Instead, the arrow fires forward in a line that is 1 foot wide and 30 feet long, before disappearing. The arrow passes harmlessly through objects, ignoring cover.</text>
		<text>Each creature in that line must make a Dexterity saving throw.</text>
		<text>On a failed save, a target takes damage as if it were hit by the arrow, plus an extra 1d6 piercing damage. On a successful save, a target takes half as much damage.</text>
		<text>	The piercing damage increases to 2d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
	<name>Precision Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you make a weapon attack roll against a creature, you can expend one superiority die to add it to the roll. You can use this maneuver before or after making the attack roll, but before any effects of the attack are applied.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell PS="PS" UA="Revised Class Options">
	<name>Precision Attack (Cavalier)</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school />
	<time>superiority die</time>
	<range />
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Cavalier)</classes>
	<text>When you make a weapon attack against a creature, you can expend one superiority die, roll it, and add it to the attack roll. You can use this ability before or after rolling the d20, but before any of the effects of the attack are applied.</text>
	<text />
	<text>Add roll to Weapon Attack Roll</text>
	<roll>1d8</roll>
	<roll>1d10</roll>
	<roll>1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Pushing Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to drive the target back. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and if the target is Large or smaller, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you push the target up to 15 feet away from you.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Rally</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>On your turn, you can use a bonus action and expend one superiority die to bolster the resolve of one of your companions. When you do so, choose a friendly creature who can see or hear you. That creature gains temporary hit points equal to the superiority die roll + your Charisma modifier.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Riposte</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When a creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction and expend one superiority die to make a melee weapon attack against the creature. If you hit, you add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell PS="PS">
		<name>Seeking Arrow</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>D</school>
		<time />
		<duration />
		<range />
		<components />
		<classes>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</classes>
		<text>Using divination magic, you grant your arrow the ability to seek out your target, allowing the arrow to curve and twist its path in search of its prey.</text>
		<text>When you use this option, you don’t make an attack roll for the attack. Instead, choose one creature you have seen in the past minute.</text>
		<text>The arrow flies toward that creature, moving around corners if necessary and ignoring three-quarters cover and half cover.</text>
		<text>If the target is within the weapon’s range and there is a path large enough for the arrow to travel to the target, the target must make a Dexterity saving throw.</text>
		<text>On a failed save, it takes damage as if it were hit by the arrow, plus an extra 1d6 force damage, and you learn the target’s current location.</text>
		<text>On a successful save, the target takes half as much damage, and you don’t learn its location.</text>
		<text>	The force damage increases to 2d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Shadow Arrow</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>I</school>
		<time />
		<duration />
		<range />
		<components />
		<classes>Fighter (Arcane Archer)</classes>
		<text>You weave illusion magic into your arrow, causing it to occlude your foe's vision with shadows.</text>
		<text>If the arrow hits a creature, the target takes an extra 2d6 psychic damage, and it must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be unable to see anything farther than 5 feet away until the start of your next turn.</text>
		<text>	The psychic damage increases to 4d6 when you reach 18th level in this class.</text>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>

<spell>
	<name>Sweeping Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a melee weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to damage another creature with the same attack. Choose another creature within 5 feet of the original target and within your reach. If the original attack roll would hit the second creature, it takes damage equal to the number you roll on your superiority die. The damage is of the same type dealt by the original attack.</text>
  </spell>
  <spell>
	<name>Trip Attack</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school>EV</school>
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Battle Master)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to knock the target down. You add the superiority die to the attack's damage roll, and if the target is Large or smaller, it must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, you knock the target prone.</text>
  </spell>

<spell PS="PS" UA="Revised Class Options">
	<name>Trip Attack (Cavalier)</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school />
	<time>superiority die</time>
	<range />
	<components />
	<classes>Fighter (Cavalier)</classes>
	<text>When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, you can expend one superiority die to attempt to knock the target down. Roll the die, and add it to the attack’s damage roll. If the target is Large or smaller, it must also succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier) or be knocked prone.</text>
	<text />
	<text>	At 7th level, you gain additional benefits when you use your Trip Attack maneuver. You can expend up to two superiority dice on it, adding both dice to the damage roll. When you spend two dice in this way, the target has disadvantage on its Strength saving throw to avoid being knocked prone.</text>
	<text />
	<text>Add roll to damage, knock prone (Large) vs Strength Saving Throw</text>
	<text>At 7th (class) level, use twice for disadvantage.</text>
	<roll>1d8</roll>
	<roll>1d10</roll>
	<roll>1d12</roll>
  </spell>
  <spell PS="PS" UA="Revised Class Options">
	<name>Warding Maneuver</name>
	<level>1</level>
	<school />
	<time>1 reaction</time>
	<range>creature within 5 feet</range>
	<components />
	<duration />
	<classes>Fighter (Cavalier)</classes>
	<text>If you or a creature within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack, you can expend one superiority die as a reaction if you’re wielding a weapon or a shield. Roll the die, and add the number rolled to the target’s AC against that attack. If the attack still hits, the target has resistance against the attack’s damage.</text>
	<text />
	<text>Add roll to AC, resistance if still hit.</text>
	<roll>1d8</roll>
	<roll>1d10</roll>
	<roll>1d12</roll>
  </spell>

	<spellList UA="Revised Class Options" class="Fighter (Cavalier)">
		
		
		
	</spellList>

</compendium>