<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
	<class name="Monk"><name>Monk</name>
        <hd>8</hd>
        <proficiency>Strength, Dexterity</proficiency>
        <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
        <autolevel level="1">
            <feature>
                <name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
                <text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
                <text>Armor: none</text>
                <text>Weapons: simple weapons, shortswords</text>
                <text>Tools: any one type of artisan's tools or any one musical instrument of your choice</text>
                <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Insight, Religion, and Stealth</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Starting Equipment</name>
                <text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• (a) a shortsword or (b) any simple weapon</text>
                <text>• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
                <text>• 10 darts</text>
                <text />
                <text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level="1">
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmored Defense</name>
                <text>Beginning at 1st level, while you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Wisdom modifier.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Martial Arts</name>
                <text>Your practice of martial arts gives you mastery of combat styles that use unarmed strikes and monk weapons, which are shortswords and any simple melee weapons that don't have the two-handed or heavy property.</text>
                <text>    You gain the following benefits while you are unarmed or wielding only monk weapons and you aren't wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes and monk weapons.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike or a monk weapon on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action. For example, if you take the Attack action and attack with a quarterstaff, you can also make an unarmed strike as a bonus action, assuming you haven't already taken a bonus action this turn.</text>
                <text />
                <text>    Certain monasteries use specialized forms of the monk weapons. For example, you might use a club that is two lengths of wood connected by a short chain (called a nunchaku) or a sickle with a shorter, straighter blade (called a kama).</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="2">
            <feature>
                <name>Ki</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, your training allows you to harness the mystic energy of ki. Your access to this energy is represented by a number of ki points. Your monk level determines the number of points you have, as shown in the Ki Points column of the Monk table.</text>
                <text>    You can spend these points to fuel various ki features. You start knowing three such features: Flurry of Blows, Patient Defense, and Step of the Wind. You learn more ki features as you gain levels in this class.</text>
                <text>    When you spend a ki point, it is unavailable until you finish a short or long rest, at the end of which you draw all of your expended ki back into yourself. You must spend at least 30 minutes of the rest meditating to regain your ki points.</text>
                <text>    Some of your ki features require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature's effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows: Ki save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Flurry of Blows</name>
                <text>Immediately after you take the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed strikes as a bonus action.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Patient Defense</name>
                <text>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Dodge action as a bonus action on your turn.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Step of the Wind</name>
                <text>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action on your turn, and your jump distance is doubled for the turn.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmored Movement</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels, as shown in the Monk table.</text>
                <text>    At 9th level, you gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids on your turn without falling during the move.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +10</modifier>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="3">
            <feature>
                <name>Monastic Tradition</name>
                <text>When you reach 3rd level, you commit yourself to a monastic tradition: the Way of the Open Hand, the Way of Shadow, or the Way of the Four Elements. Your tradition grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Deflect Missiles</name>
                <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your reaction to deflect or catch the missile when you are hit by a ranged weapon attack. When you do so, the damage you take from the attack is reduced by 1d 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your monk level.</text>
                <text>    If you reduce the damage to 0, you can catch the missile if it is small enough for you to hold in one hand and you have at least one hand free. If you catch a missile in this way, you can spend 1 ki point to make a ranged attack (range 20 feet/60 feet) with the weapon or piece of ammunition you just caught, as part of the same reaction. You make this attack with proficiency, regardless of your weapon proficiencies, and the missile counts as a monk weapon for the attack.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="4">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Slow Fall</name>
                <text>Beginning at 4th level, you can use your reaction when you fall to reduce any falling damage you take by an amount equal to five times your monk level.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="5">
            <feature>
                <name>Extra Attack</name>
                <text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Stunning Strike</name>
                <text>Starting at 5th level, you can interfere with the flow of ki in an opponent's body. When you hit another creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 1 ki point to attempt a stunning strike. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of your next turn.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Martial Arts (1d6)</name>
                <text>You can  now roll a d6 in the place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="6">
            <feature>
                <name>Ki-Empowered Strikes</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmed Movement (+ 15 ft.)</name>
                <text>The bonus to your speed increases to 15 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="7">
            <feature>
                <name>Stillness of Mind</name>
                <text>Starting at 7th level, you can use your action to end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Evasion</name>
                <text>At 7th level, your instinctive agility lets you dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a blue dragon's lightning breath or a fireball spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="8">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="9">
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmored Movement (Vertical Surfaces)</name>
                <text>You gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids on your turn without falling during the move.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="10">
            <feature>
                <name>Purity of Body</name>
                <text>At 10th level, your mastery of the ki flowing through you makes you immune to disease and poison.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmed Movement (+ 20 ft.)</name>
                <text>The bonus to your speed increases to 20 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="11">
            <feature>
                <name>Martial Arts (1d8)</name>
                <text>You can  now roll a d8 in the place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="12">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="13">
            <feature>
                <name>Tongue of the Sun and Moon</name>
                <text>Starting at 13th level, you learn to touch the ki of other minds so that you understand all spoken languages. Moreover, any creature that can understand a language can understand what you say.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="14">
            <feature>
                <name>Diamond Soul</name>
                <text>Beginning at 14th level, your mastery of ki grants you proficiency in all saving throws.</text>
                <text>    Additionally, whenever you make a saving throw and fail, you can spend 1 ki point to reroll it and take the second result.</text>
                <proficiency>constitution, intelligence, wisdom, charisma</proficiency>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmed Movement (+ 25 ft.)</name>
                <text>The bonus to your speed increases to 25 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="15">
            <feature>
                <name>Timeless Body</name>
                <text>At 15th level, your ki sustains you so that you suffer none of the frailty of old age, and you can't be aged magically. You can still die of old age, however. In addition, you no longer need food or water.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="16">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="17">
            <feature>
                <name>Martial Arts (1d10)</name>
                <text>You can  now roll a d10 in the place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="18">
            <feature>
                <name>Empty Body</name>
                <text>Beginning at 18th level, you can use your action to spend 4 ki points to become invisible for 1 minute. During that time, you also have resistance to all damage but force damage.</text>
                <text>    Additionally, you can spend 8 ki points to cast the astral projection spell, without needing material components. When you do so, you can't take any other creatures with you.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmed Movement (+ 30 ft.)</name>
                <text>The bonus to your speed increases to 30 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="19">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="20">
            <feature>
                <name>Perfect Soul</name>
                <text>At 20th level, when you roll for initiative and have no ki points remaining, you regain 4 ki points.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
    <autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Sun Soul</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of the Sun Soul learn to channel their own life energy into searing bolts of light. They teach that meditation can unlock the ability to unleash the indomitable light shed by the soul of every living creature.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Sun Soul: Radiant Sun Bolt</name>
                <text>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can hurl searing bolts of magical radiance.</text>
                <text>    You gain a ranged spell attack that you can use with the Attack action. The attack has a range of 30 feet. You are proficient with it, and you add your Dexterity modifier to its attack and damage rolls. Its damage is radiant, and its damage die is a d4. This die changes as you gain monk levels — to a d6 at 5th level, a d8 at 11th level, and a d10 at 17th level.</text>
                <text>    When you use the Attack action on your turn to use this special attack, you can spend 1 ki point to make two additional attacks with it as a bonus action.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Sun Soul: Searing Arc Strike</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to channel your ki into searing waves of energy. Immediately after you take the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 2 ki points to cast the 1st-level spell burning hands as a bonus action.</text>
                <text>    You can spend additional ki points to cast burning hands as a higher level spell. Each additional ki point you spend increases the spell's level by 1. The maximum number of ki points (2 plus any additional points) that you can spend on the spell equals half your monk level (round down).</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Sun Soul: Searing Sunburst</name>
                <text>At 11th level, you gain the ability to create an orb of light that erupts into a devastating explosion. As an action, you create an orb and hurl it at a point you choose within 150 feet, where it erupts into a sphere of radiant light for a brief but deadly instant.</text>
                <text>    Each creature in that 20-foot radius sphere must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 2d6 radiant damage. A creature doesn't need to make the save if the creature is behind total cover that is opaque.</text>
                <text>    You can increase the sphere's damage by spending ki points. Each point you spend, up to a maximum of 3, increases the damage by 2d6.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Sun Soul: Sun Shield</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you become wreathed in a luminous aura. You shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. You can extinguish or restore the light as a bonus action.</text>
                <text>    If a creature hits you with a melee attack while this light shines, you can use your reaction to deal radiant damage to the creature. The radiant damage equals 5 + your Wisdom modifier.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Kensei (UA)</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of Kensei train relentlessly with their weapons, to the point that the weapon becomes like an extension of the body. A kensei sees a weapon in much the same way a painter regards a brush or a writer sees parchment, ink, and quill. A sword or bow is a tool used to express the beauty and elegance of the martial arts. That such mastery makes a kensei a peerless warrior is but a side effect of intense devotion, practice, and study.</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Monastic Tradition is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Subclasses, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This had an earlier version included in Unearthed Arcana: Monk Monastic Traditions</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Kensei: Path of the Kensei</name>
                <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, your special martial arts training leads you to master the use of certain weapons.</text>
                <text>	You gain the following benefits: </text>
                <text />
                <text>• Choose two types of weapons to be your kensei weapons: one melee weapon and one ranged weapon.</text>
				<text>Each of these weapons can be any simple or martial weapon that lacks the heavy and special properties. The longbow is also a valid choice.</text>
				<text>You gain proficiency with these weapons if you don’t already have it. Weapons of the chosen types are monk weapons for you. </text>
				<text>Many of this tradition’s features work only with your kensei weapons.</text>
				<text>When you reach 6th, 11th, and 17th level in this class, you can choose another type of weapon—melee or ranged—to be a kensei weapon for you, following the criteria above.</text>
                <text />
				<text>• If you make an unarmed strike as part of the Attack action on your turn and are holding a kensei weapon, you can use it to defend yourself if it is a melee weapon.</text>
				<text>You gain a +2 bonus to AC until the start of your next turn, while the weapon is in your hand and you aren't incapacitated.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• You can use a bonus action on your turn to make your ranged attacks with a kensei weapon more deadly.</text>
				<text>When you do so, any target you hit with a ranged attack using a kensei weapon takes an extra 1d4 damage of the weapon’s type.</text>
				<text>You retain this benefit until the end of the current turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Kensei: One with the Blade</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you extend your ki into your kensei weapons, granting you the following benefits.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Magic Kensei Weapons: </text>
                <text>	Your attacks with your kensei weapons count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Precise Strike: </text>
                <text>	When you hit a target with a kensei weapon, you can spend 1 ki point to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target equal to your Martial Arts die. You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Kensei: Sharpen the Blade</name>
                <text>At 11th level, you gain the ability to augment your weapons further with your ki. As a bonus action, you can expend up to 3 ki points to grant one kensei weapon you touch a bonus to attack and damage rolls when you attack with it. The bonus equals the number of ki points you spent. This bonus lasts for 1 minute or until you use this feature again.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Kensei: Unerring Accuracy</name>
                <text>At 17th level, your mastery of weapons grants you extraordinary accuracy. If you make an attack roll with a monk weapon and miss, you can reroll it. You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of Tranquility (UA)</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of Tranquility see violence as a last resort. They use diplomacy, mercy, and understanding to resolve conflicts. If pushed, though, they are capable warriors who can bring an end to the unjust or cruel folk who refuse to listen to reason. When adventuring, these monks make excellent diplomats. They are also skilled in the healing arts, and can preserve their allies in the face of daunting foes.</text>
                <text>	</text>
                <text>This Monastic Tradition is from Unearthed Arcana: Monk Monastic Traditions, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Path of Tranquility</name>
                <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can become an island of calm in even the most chaotic of situations. With this feature, you can cast the sanctuary spell on yourself, no material component required, and it lasts up to 8 hours. Its saving throw DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier. A creature that succeeds on the save is immune to this effect for 1 hour. </text>
                <text>	Once you cast the spell in this way, you can't do so again for 1 minute.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Healing Hands</name>
                <text>Your mystical touch can heal wounds. Starting at 3rd level, you have a pool of magical healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your monk level x 10. </text>
                <text>	As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in the pool. </text>
                <text>	Instead of healing the creature, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multiple poisons with a single use of Healing Hands, expending hit points separately for each one. </text>
                <text>	When you use your Flurry of Blows, you can replace one of the unarmed strikes with a use of this feature. </text>
                <text>	This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Emissary of Peace</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to diffuse violent situations. Whenever you make a Charisma check to calm violent emotions or to counsel peace, you have advantage on the roll. You must make this entreaty in good faith; it doesn't apply if proficiency in the Deception or Intimidation skill applies to your check. </text>
                <text>	You also gain proficiency in the Performance or Persuasion skill (choose one).</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Douse the Flames of War</name>
                <text>At 11th level, you gain the ability to temporarily extinguish a creature's violent impulses. As an action, you can touch a creature, and it must make a Wisdom saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier. The target automatically succeeds if it's missing any of its hit points. If the target fails the save, it can't attack for 1 minute. During that time, it also can't cast spells that deal damage or that force someone to make a saving throw. </text>
                <text>	This effect ends if the target is attacked, takes damage, or is forced to make a saving throw or if the target witnesses any of those things happening to its allies.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Anger of a Gentle Soul</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to visit vengeance on someone who fells others. If you see a creature reduce another creature to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to grant yourself a bonus to all damage rolls against the aggressor until the end of your next turn. The bonus equals your monk level. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Four Elements</name>
                <text>You follow a monastic tradition that teaches you to harness the elements. When you focus your ki, you can align yourself with the forces of creation and bend the four elements to your will, using them as an extension of your body. Some members of this tradition dedicate themselves to a single element, but others weave the elements together.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Many monks of this tradition tattoo their bodies with representations of their ki powers, commonly imagined as coiling dragons, but also as phoenixes, fish, plants, mountains, and cresting waves.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Disciple of the Elements</name>
                <text>You learn magical disciplines that harness the power of the four elements. A discipline requires you to spend ki points each time you use it.</text>
                <text />
                <text>You know the Elemental Attunement discipline and one other elemental discipline of your choice. You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Casting Elemental Spells. Some elemental disciplines allow you to cast spells. To cast one of these spells, you use its casting time and other rules, but you don't need to provide material components for it.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Once you reach 5th level in this class, you can spend additional ki points to increase the level of an elemental discipline spell that you cast, provided that the spell has an enhanced effect at a higher level, as burning hands does. The spell's level increases by 1 for each additional ki point you spend. For example, if you are a 5th-level monk and use Sweeping Cinder Strike to cast burning hands, you can spend 3 ki points to cast it as a 2nd-level spell (the discipline's base cost of 2 ki points plus 1).</text>
                <text />
                <text>The maximum number of ki points you can spend to cast a spell in this way (including its base ki point cost and any additional ki points you spend to increase its level) is determined by your monk level. At 5th level, you may spend up to 3 ki points; this increases to 4 ki points at 9th level, 5 at 13th level, and 6 at 17th level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 2 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 3 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 4 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Drunken Master (UA)</name>
				<text>The Way of the Drunken Master teaches its students to move with the jerky, unpredictable movements of a drunkard. A drunken master sways, tottering on unsteady feet, to present what seems like an incompetent combatant but proves frustrating to engage. The drunken master’s erratic stumbles conceal a carefully executed dance of blocks, parries, advances, attacks, and retreats. Cunning warriors can see through the drunken master’s apparent incompetence to recognize the masterful technique employed.</text>
				<text />
				<text>This Monastic Tradition is from Unearthed Arcana: A Trio of Subclasses, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of the Drunken Master: Drunken Technique</name>
				<text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Performance skill if you don’t already have it; your martial arts technique mixes martial training with the precision of a dancer and the antics of a jester.</text>
				<text>	You also learn how to twist and turn quickly as part of your Flurry of Blows. Whenever you use Flurry of Blows, you gain the benefit of the Disengage action, and your walking speed increases by 10 feet until the end of the current turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of the Drunken Master: Tipsy Sway</name>
				<text>At 6th level, your swaying in combat becomes maddeningly unpredictable. As a reaction when an enemy misses you with a melee attack roll, you can cause that attack to hit one creature of your choice, other than the attacker, that you can see within 5 feet of you. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of the Drunken Master: Drunkard’s Luck</name>
				<text>Starting at 11th level, you always seem to get a lucky bounce at just the right moment to save you from doom. When you make a saving throw, you can spend 1 ki point to give yourself advantage on that roll. You must decide to use this feature before rolling.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of the Drunken Master: Intoxicated Frenzy</name>
				<text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to make an overwhelming number of attacks against a group of enemies. When you use your Flurry of Blows, you can make up to three additional attacks with it (up to a total of five attacks), provided that each Flurry of Blows attack targets a different creature this turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of Shadow</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of Shadow follow a tradition that values stealth and subterfuge. These monks might be called ninjas or shadowdancers, and they serve as spies and assassins. Sometimes the members of a ninja monastery are family members, forming a clan sworn to secrecy about their arts and missions. Other monasteries are more like thieves' guilds, hiring out their services to nobles, rich merchants, or anyone else who can pay their fees. Regardless of their methods, the heads of these monasteries expect the unquestioning obedience of their students.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Shadow: Shadow Arts</name>
                <text>You can use your ki to duplicate the effects of certain spells. As an action, you can spend 2 ki points to cast darkness, darkvision, pass without trace, or silence, without providing material components. Additionally, you gain the minor illusion cantrip if you don't already know it.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Shadow: Shadow Step</name>
                <text>You gain the ability to step from one shadow into another. When you are in dim light or darkness, as a bonus action you can teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness. You then have advantage on the first melee attack you make before the end of the turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Shadow: Cloak of Shadows</name>
                <text>You have learned to become one with the shadows. When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible. You remain invisible until you make an attack, cast a spell, or are in an area of bright light.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Shadow: Opportunist</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you can exploit a creature's momentary distraction when it is hit by an attack. Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack made by a creature other than you, you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against that creature.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Open Hand</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of the Open Hand are the ultimate masters of martial arts combat, whether armed or unarmed. They learn techniques to push and trip their opponents, manipulate ki to heal damage to their bodies, and practice advanced meditation that can protect them from harm.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Open Hand: Open Hand Technique</name>
                <text>You can manipulate your enemy's ki when you harness your own. Whenever you hit a creature with one of the attacks granted by your Flurry of Blows, you can impose one of the following effects on that target.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• It must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• It must make a Strength saving throw. If it fails, you can push it up to 15 feet away from you.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• It can't take reactions until the end of your next turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Open Hand: Wholeness of Body</name>
                <text>You gain the ability to heal yourself. As an action, you can regain hit points equal to three times your monk level. You must finish a long rest before you can use this feature again.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Open Palm: Tranquility</name>
                <text>Beginning at 11th level, you can enter a special meditation that surrounds you with an aura of peace. At the end of a long rest, you gain the effect of a sanctuary spell that lasts until the start of your next long rest (the spell can end early as normal). The saving throw DC for the spell equals 8 + your Wisdom modifier + your Proficiency bonus.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Sanctuary gives this effect: You ward a creature within range against attack. Until the spell ends, any creature who targets the warded creature with an attack or a harmful spell must first make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or lose the attack or spell. This spell doesn't protect the warded creature from area effects, such as the explosion of a fireball.</text>
                <text />
                <text>If the warded creature makes an attack or casts a spell that affects an enemy creature, this spell ends.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Open Palm: Quivering Palm</name>
                <text>You gain the ability to set up lethal vibrations in someone's body. When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can spend 3 ki points to start these imperceptible vibrations, which last for a number of days equal to your monk level. The vibrations are harmless unless you use your action to end them. To do so, you and the target must be on the same plane of existence. When you use this action, the creature must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, it is reduced to 0 hit points. If it succeeds, it takes 10d10 necrotic damage.</text>
                <text />
                <text>You can have only one creature under the effect of this feature at a time. You can choose to end the vibrations harmlessly without using an action.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Long Death</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of the Long Death are obsessed with the meaning and mechanics of dying. They capture creatures and prepare elaborate experiments to capture, record, and understand the moments of their demise. They use this knowledge to guide their understanding of martial arts, yielding a deadly fighting style.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Long Death: Touch of Death</name>
                <text>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, your study of death allows you to extract vitality from another creature as it nears its demise. When you reduce a creature within 5 feet of you to 0 hit points, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier + your monk level (minimum of 1 temporary hit point).</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Long Death: Hour of Reaping</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to unsettle or terrify those around you as an action, for your soul has been touched by the shadow of death. When you take this action, each creature within 30 feet of you that can see you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Long Death: Mastery of Death</name>
                <text>Beginning at 11th level, you use your familiarity with death to escape its grasp. When you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can expend 1 ki point (no action required) to have 1 hit point instead.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Long Death: Touch of the Long Death</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, your touch can channel the energy of death into a creature. As an action, you touch one creature within 5 feet of you, and you expend 1 to 10 ki points. The target must make a Constitution saving throw, and it takes 2d10 necrotic damage per ki point spent on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Monk !Base">
		<name>Monk !Base</name>
<hd>8</hd>
        <proficiency>Strength, Dexterity</proficiency>
        <spellAbility>Wisdom</spellAbility>
        <autolevel level="1">
            <feature>
                <name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
                <text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
                <text>Armor: none</text>
                <text>Weapons: simple weapons, shortswords</text>
                <text>Tools: any one type of artisan's tools or any one musical instrument of your choice</text>
                <text>Skills: Choose two from Acrobatics, Athletics, History, Insight, Religion, and Stealth</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Starting Equipment</name>
                <text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• (a) a shortsword or (b) any simple weapon</text>
                <text>• (a) a dungeoneer's pack or (b) an explorer's pack</text>
                <text>• 10 darts</text>
                <text />
                <text>Alternatively, you may start with 5d4 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
        <autolevel level="1">
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmored Defense</name>
                <text>Beginning at 1st level, while you are wearing no armor and not wielding a shield, your AC equals 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your Wisdom modifier.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Martial Arts</name>
                <text>Your practice of martial arts gives you mastery of combat styles that use unarmed strikes and monk weapons, which are shortswords and any simple melee weapons that don't have the two-handed or heavy property.</text>
                <text>    You gain the following benefits while you are unarmed or wielding only monk weapons and you aren't wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes and monk weapons.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• You can roll a d4 in place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike or a monk weapon on your turn, you can make one unarmed strike as a bonus action. For example, if you take the Attack action and attack with a quarterstaff, you can also make an unarmed strike as a bonus action, assuming you haven't already taken a bonus action this turn.</text>
                <text />
                <text>    Certain monasteries use specialized forms of the monk weapons. For example, you might use a club that is two lengths of wood connected by a short chain (called a nunchaku) or a sickle with a shorter, straighter blade (called a kama).</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="2">
            <feature>
                <name>Ki</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, your training allows you to harness the mystic energy of ki. Your access to this energy is represented by a number of ki points. Your monk level determines the number of points you have, as shown in the Ki Points column of the Monk table.</text>
                <text>    You can spend these points to fuel various ki features. You start knowing three such features: Flurry of Blows, Patient Defense, and Step of the Wind. You learn more ki features as you gain levels in this class.</text>
                <text>    When you spend a ki point, it is unavailable until you finish a short or long rest, at the end of which you draw all of your expended ki back into yourself. You must spend at least 30 minutes of the rest meditating to regain your ki points.</text>
                <text>    Some of your ki features require your target to make a saving throw to resist the feature's effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows: Ki save DC = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Flurry of Blows</name>
                <text>Immediately after you take the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to make two unarmed strikes as a bonus action.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Patient Defense</name>
                <text>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Dodge action as a bonus action on your turn.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Step of the Wind</name>
                <text>You can spend 1 ki point to take the Disengage or Dash action as a bonus action on your turn, and your jump distance is doubled for the turn.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmored Movement</name>
                <text>Starting at 2nd level, your speed increases by 10 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield. This bonus increases when you reach certain monk levels, as shown in the Monk table.</text>
                <text>    At 9th level, you gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids on your turn without falling during the move.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +10</modifier>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="3">
            <feature>
                <name>Monastic Tradition</name>
                <text>When you reach 3rd level, you commit yourself to a monastic tradition: the Way of the Open Hand, the Way of Shadow, or the Way of the Four Elements. Your tradition grants you features at 3rd level and again at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Deflect Missiles</name>
                <text>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your reaction to deflect or catch the missile when you are hit by a ranged weapon attack. When you do so, the damage you take from the attack is reduced by 1d 10 + your Dexterity modifier + your monk level.</text>
                <text>    If you reduce the damage to 0, you can catch the missile if it is small enough for you to hold in one hand and you have at least one hand free. If you catch a missile in this way, you can spend 1 ki point to make a ranged attack (range 20 feet/60 feet) with the weapon or piece of ammunition you just caught, as part of the same reaction. You make this attack with proficiency, regardless of your weapon proficiencies, and the missile counts as a monk weapon for the attack.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="4">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 4th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Slow Fall</name>
                <text>Beginning at 4th level, you can use your reaction when you fall to reduce any falling damage you take by an amount equal to five times your monk level.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="5">
            <feature>
                <name>Extra Attack</name>
                <text>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Stunning Strike</name>
                <text>Starting at 5th level, you can interfere with the flow of ki in an opponent's body. When you hit another creature with a melee weapon attack, you can spend 1 ki point to attempt a stunning strike. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or be stunned until the end of your next turn.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Martial Arts (1d6)</name>
                <text>You can  now roll a d6 in the place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="6">
            <feature>
                <name>Ki-Empowered Strikes</name>
                <text>Starting at 6th level, your unarmed strikes count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmed Movement (+ 15 ft.)</name>
                <text>The bonus to your speed increases to 15 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="7">
            <feature>
                <name>Stillness of Mind</name>
                <text>Starting at 7th level, you can use your action to end one effect on yourself that is causing you to be charmed or frightened.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Evasion</name>
                <text>At 7th level, your instinctive agility lets you dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a blue dragon's lightning breath or a fireball spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="8">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 8th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="9">
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmored Movement (Vertical Surfaces)</name>
                <text>You gain the ability to move along vertical surfaces and across liquids on your turn without falling during the move.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="10">
            <feature>
                <name>Purity of Body</name>
                <text>At 10th level, your mastery of the ki flowing through you makes you immune to disease and poison.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmed Movement (+ 20 ft.)</name>
                <text>The bonus to your speed increases to 20 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="11">
            <feature>
                <name>Martial Arts (1d8)</name>
                <text>You can  now roll a d8 in the place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="12">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 12th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="13">
            <feature>
                <name>Tongue of the Sun and Moon</name>
                <text>Starting at 13th level, you learn to touch the ki of other minds so that you understand all spoken languages. Moreover, any creature that can understand a language can understand what you say.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="14">
            <feature>
                <name>Diamond Soul</name>
                <text>Beginning at 14th level, your mastery of ki grants you proficiency in all saving throws.</text>
                <text>    Additionally, whenever you make a saving throw and fail, you can spend 1 ki point to reroll it and take the second result.</text>
                <proficiency>constitution, intelligence, wisdom, charisma</proficiency>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmed Movement (+ 25 ft.)</name>
                <text>The bonus to your speed increases to 25 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="15">
            <feature>
                <name>Timeless Body</name>
                <text>At 15th level, your ki sustains you so that you suffer none of the frailty of old age, and you can't be aged magically. You can still die of old age, however. In addition, you no longer need food or water.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="16">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 16th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="17">
            <feature>
                <name>Martial Arts (1d10)</name>
                <text>You can  now roll a d10 in the place of the normal damage of your unarmed strike or monk weapon.</text>
            </feature>
			
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="18">
            <feature>
                <name>Empty Body</name>
                <text>Beginning at 18th level, you can use your action to spend 4 ki points to become invisible for 1 minute. During that time, you also have resistance to all damage but force damage.</text>
                <text>    Additionally, you can spend 8 ki points to cast the astral projection spell, without needing material components. When you do so, you can't take any other creatures with you.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature>
                <name>Unarmed Movement (+ 30 ft.)</name>
                <text>The bonus to your speed increases to 30 feet while you are not wearing armor or wielding a shield.</text>
                <modifier category="bonus">speed +5</modifier>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="19">
            <feature>
                <name>Ability Score Improvement</name>
                <text>When you reach 19th level you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can't increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</text>
                <text>    If your DM allows the use of feats, you may instead take a feat.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>

        <autolevel level="20">
            <feature>
                <name>Perfect Soul</name>
                <text>At 20th level, when you roll for initiative and have no ki points remaining, you regain 4 ki points.</text>
            </feature>
        </autolevel>
    </class><class name="Monk (Drunken Master)">
	<name>Monk (Drunken Master)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Drunken Master (UA)</name>
				<text>The Way of the Drunken Master teaches its students to move with the jerky, unpredictable movements of a drunkard. A drunken master sways, tottering on unsteady feet, to present what seems like an incompetent combatant but proves frustrating to engage. The drunken master’s erratic stumbles conceal a carefully executed dance of blocks, parries, advances, attacks, and retreats. Cunning warriors can see through the drunken master’s apparent incompetence to recognize the masterful technique employed.</text>
				<text />
				<text>This Monastic Tradition is from Unearthed Arcana: A Trio of Subclasses, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of the Drunken Master: Drunken Technique</name>
				<text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you gain proficiency in the Performance skill if you don’t already have it; your martial arts technique mixes martial training with the precision of a dancer and the antics of a jester.</text>
				<text>	You also learn how to twist and turn quickly as part of your Flurry of Blows. Whenever you use Flurry of Blows, you gain the benefit of the Disengage action, and your walking speed increases by 10 feet until the end of the current turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of the Drunken Master: Tipsy Sway</name>
				<text>At 6th level, your swaying in combat becomes maddeningly unpredictable. As a reaction when an enemy misses you with a melee attack roll, you can cause that attack to hit one creature of your choice, other than the attacker, that you can see within 5 feet of you. Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of the Drunken Master: Drunkard’s Luck</name>
				<text>Starting at 11th level, you always seem to get a lucky bounce at just the right moment to save you from doom. When you make a saving throw, you can spend 1 ki point to give yourself advantage on that roll. You must decide to use this feature before rolling.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Way of the Drunken Master: Intoxicated Frenzy</name>
				<text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to make an overwhelming number of attacks against a group of enemies. When you use your Flurry of Blows, you can make up to three additional attacks with it (up to a total of five attacks), provided that each Flurry of Blows attack targets a different creature this turn.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Monk (Four Elements)">
	<name>Monk (Four Elements)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Four Elements</name>
                <text>You follow a monastic tradition that teaches you to harness the elements. When you focus your ki, you can align yourself with the forces of creation and bend the four elements to your will, using them as an extension of your body. Some members of this tradition dedicate themselves to a single element, but others weave the elements together.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Many monks of this tradition tattoo their bodies with representations of their ki powers, commonly imagined as coiling dragons, but also as phoenixes, fish, plants, mountains, and cresting waves.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Disciple of the Elements</name>
                <text>You learn magical disciplines that harness the power of the four elements. A discipline requires you to spend ki points each time you use it.</text>
                <text />
                <text>You know the Elemental Attunement discipline and one other elemental discipline of your choice. You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice at 6th, 11th, and 17th level.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Casting Elemental Spells. Some elemental disciplines allow you to cast spells. To cast one of these spells, you use its casting time and other rules, but you don't need to provide material components for it.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Once you reach 5th level in this class, you can spend additional ki points to increase the level of an elemental discipline spell that you cast, provided that the spell has an enhanced effect at a higher level, as burning hands does. The spell's level increases by 1 for each additional ki point you spend. For example, if you are a 5th-level monk and use Sweeping Cinder Strike to cast burning hands, you can spend 3 ki points to cast it as a 2nd-level spell (the discipline's base cost of 2 ki points plus 1).</text>
                <text />
                <text>The maximum number of ki points you can spend to cast a spell in this way (including its base ki point cost and any additional ki points you spend to increase its level) is determined by your monk level. At 5th level, you may spend up to 3 ki points; this increases to 4 ki points at 9th level, 5 at 13th level, and 6 at 17th level.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 2 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 3 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Four Elements: Extra Elemental Discipline</name>
                <text>You learn one additional elemental discipline of your choice. You should know 4 elemental disciplines, as well as Elemental Attunement.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Whenever you learn a new elemental discipline, you can also replace one elemental discipline that you already know with a different discipline.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Monk (Kensei)">
	<name>Monk (Kensei)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Kensei (UA)</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of Kensei train relentlessly with their weapons, to the point that the weapon becomes like an extension of the body. A kensei sees a weapon in much the same way a painter regards a brush or a writer sees parchment, ink, and quill. A sword or bow is a tool used to express the beauty and elegance of the martial arts. That such mastery makes a kensei a peerless warrior is but a side effect of intense devotion, practice, and study.</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Monastic Tradition is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Subclasses, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This had an earlier version included in Unearthed Arcana: Monk Monastic Traditions</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Kensei: Path of the Kensei</name>
                <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, your special martial arts training leads you to master the use of certain weapons.</text>
                <text>	You gain the following benefits: </text>
                <text />
                <text>• Choose two types of weapons to be your kensei weapons: one melee weapon and one ranged weapon.</text>
				<text>Each of these weapons can be any simple or martial weapon that lacks the heavy and special properties. The longbow is also a valid choice.</text>
				<text>You gain proficiency with these weapons if you don’t already have it. Weapons of the chosen types are monk weapons for you. </text>
				<text>Many of this tradition’s features work only with your kensei weapons.</text>
				<text>When you reach 6th, 11th, and 17th level in this class, you can choose another type of weapon—melee or ranged—to be a kensei weapon for you, following the criteria above.</text>
                <text />
				<text>• If you make an unarmed strike as part of the Attack action on your turn and are holding a kensei weapon, you can use it to defend yourself if it is a melee weapon.</text>
				<text>You gain a +2 bonus to AC until the start of your next turn, while the weapon is in your hand and you aren't incapacitated.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• You can use a bonus action on your turn to make your ranged attacks with a kensei weapon more deadly.</text>
				<text>When you do so, any target you hit with a ranged attack using a kensei weapon takes an extra 1d4 damage of the weapon’s type.</text>
				<text>You retain this benefit until the end of the current turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Kensei: One with the Blade</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you extend your ki into your kensei weapons, granting you the following benefits.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Magic Kensei Weapons: </text>
                <text>	Your attacks with your kensei weapons count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Precise Strike: </text>
                <text>	When you hit a target with a kensei weapon, you can spend 1 ki point to cause the weapon to deal extra damage to the target equal to your Martial Arts die. You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Kensei: Sharpen the Blade</name>
                <text>At 11th level, you gain the ability to augment your weapons further with your ki. As a bonus action, you can expend up to 3 ki points to grant one kensei weapon you touch a bonus to attack and damage rolls when you attack with it. The bonus equals the number of ki points you spent. This bonus lasts for 1 minute or until you use this feature again.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Kensei: Unerring Accuracy</name>
                <text>At 17th level, your mastery of weapons grants you extraordinary accuracy. If you make an attack roll with a monk weapon and miss, you can reroll it. You can use this feature only once on each of your turns.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Monk (Long Death)">
	<name>Monk (Long Death)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Long Death</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of the Long Death are obsessed with the meaning and mechanics of dying. They capture creatures and prepare elaborate experiments to capture, record, and understand the moments of their demise. They use this knowledge to guide their understanding of martial arts, yielding a deadly fighting style.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Long Death: Touch of Death</name>
                <text>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, your study of death allows you to extract vitality from another creature as it nears its demise. When you reduce a creature within 5 feet of you to 0 hit points, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Wisdom modifier + your monk level (minimum of 1 temporary hit point).</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Long Death: Hour of Reaping</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to unsettle or terrify those around you as an action, for your soul has been touched by the shadow of death. When you take this action, each creature within 30 feet of you that can see you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Long Death: Mastery of Death</name>
                <text>Beginning at 11th level, you use your familiarity with death to escape its grasp. When you are reduced to 0 hit points, you can expend 1 ki point (no action required) to have 1 hit point instead.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Long Death: Touch of the Long Death</name>
                <text>Starting at 17th level, your touch can channel the energy of death into a creature. As an action, you touch one creature within 5 feet of you, and you expend 1 to 10 ki points. The target must make a Constitution saving throw, and it takes 2d10 necrotic damage per ki point spent on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Monk (Open Hand)">
	<name>Monk (Open Hand)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Open Hand</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of the Open Hand are the ultimate masters of martial arts combat, whether armed or unarmed. They learn techniques to push and trip their opponents, manipulate ki to heal damage to their bodies, and practice advanced meditation that can protect them from harm.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Open Hand: Open Hand Technique</name>
                <text>You can manipulate your enemy's ki when you harness your own. Whenever you hit a creature with one of the attacks granted by your Flurry of Blows, you can impose one of the following effects on that target.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• It must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or be knocked prone.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• It must make a Strength saving throw. If it fails, you can push it up to 15 feet away from you.</text>
                <text />
                <text>• It can't take reactions until the end of your next turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Open Hand: Wholeness of Body</name>
                <text>You gain the ability to heal yourself. As an action, you can regain hit points equal to three times your monk level. You must finish a long rest before you can use this feature again.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Open Palm: Tranquility</name>
                <text>Beginning at 11th level, you can enter a special meditation that surrounds you with an aura of peace. At the end of a long rest, you gain the effect of a sanctuary spell that lasts until the start of your next long rest (the spell can end early as normal). The saving throw DC for the spell equals 8 + your Wisdom modifier + your Proficiency bonus.</text>
                <text />
                <text>Sanctuary gives this effect: You ward a creature within range against attack. Until the spell ends, any creature who targets the warded creature with an attack or a harmful spell must first make a Wisdom saving throw. On a failed save, the creature must choose a new target or lose the attack or spell. This spell doesn't protect the warded creature from area effects, such as the explosion of a fireball.</text>
                <text />
                <text>If the warded creature makes an attack or casts a spell that affects an enemy creature, this spell ends.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Open Palm: Quivering Palm</name>
                <text>You gain the ability to set up lethal vibrations in someone's body. When you hit a creature with an unarmed strike, you can spend 3 ki points to start these imperceptible vibrations, which last for a number of days equal to your monk level. The vibrations are harmless unless you use your action to end them. To do so, you and the target must be on the same plane of existence. When you use this action, the creature must make a Constitution saving throw. If it fails, it is reduced to 0 hit points. If it succeeds, it takes 10d10 necrotic damage.</text>
                <text />
                <text>You can have only one creature under the effect of this feature at a time. You can choose to end the vibrations harmlessly without using an action.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Monk (Shadow)">
	<name>Monk (Shadow)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of Shadow</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of Shadow follow a tradition that values stealth and subterfuge. These monks might be called ninjas or shadowdancers, and they serve as spies and assassins. Sometimes the members of a ninja monastery are family members, forming a clan sworn to secrecy about their arts and missions. Other monasteries are more like thieves' guilds, hiring out their services to nobles, rich merchants, or anyone else who can pay their fees. Regardless of their methods, the heads of these monasteries expect the unquestioning obedience of their students.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Shadow: Shadow Arts</name>
                <text>You can use your ki to duplicate the effects of certain spells. As an action, you can spend 2 ki points to cast darkness, darkvision, pass without trace, or silence, without providing material components. Additionally, you gain the minor illusion cantrip if you don't already know it.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Shadow: Shadow Step</name>
                <text>You gain the ability to step from one shadow into another. When you are in dim light or darkness, as a bonus action you can teleport up to 60 feet to an unoccupied space you can see that is also in dim light or darkness. You then have advantage on the first melee attack you make before the end of the turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Shadow: Cloak of Shadows</name>
                <text>You have learned to become one with the shadows. When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible. You remain invisible until you make an attack, cast a spell, or are in an area of bright light.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Shadow: Opportunist</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you can exploit a creature's momentary distraction when it is hit by an attack. Whenever a creature within 5 feet of you is hit by an attack made by a creature other than you, you can use your reaction to make a melee attack against that creature.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Monk (Sun Soul)">
	<name>Monk (Sun Soul)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of the Sun Soul</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of the Sun Soul learn to channel their own life energy into searing bolts of light. They teach that meditation can unlock the ability to unleash the indomitable light shed by the soul of every living creature.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Sun Soul: Radiant Sun Bolt</name>
                <text>Starting when you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can hurl searing bolts of magical radiance.</text>
                <text>    You gain a ranged spell attack that you can use with the Attack action. The attack has a range of 30 feet. You are proficient with it, and you add your Dexterity modifier to its attack and damage rolls. Its damage is radiant, and its damage die is a d4. This die changes as you gain monk levels — to a d6 at 5th level, a d8 at 11th level, and a d10 at 17th level.</text>
                <text>    When you use the Attack action on your turn to use this special attack, you can spend 1 ki point to make two additional attacks with it as a bonus action.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Sun Soul: Searing Arc Strike</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to channel your ki into searing waves of energy. Immediately after you take the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 2 ki points to cast the 1st-level spell burning hands as a bonus action.</text>
                <text>    You can spend additional ki points to cast burning hands as a higher level spell. Each additional ki point you spend increases the spell's level by 1. The maximum number of ki points (2 plus any additional points) that you can spend on the spell equals half your monk level (round down).</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Sun Soul: Searing Sunburst</name>
                <text>At 11th level, you gain the ability to create an orb of light that erupts into a devastating explosion. As an action, you create an orb and hurl it at a point you choose within 150 feet, where it erupts into a sphere of radiant light for a brief but deadly instant.</text>
                <text>    Each creature in that 20-foot radius sphere must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 2d6 radiant damage. A creature doesn't need to make the save if the creature is behind total cover that is opaque.</text>
                <text>    You can increase the sphere's damage by spending ki points. Each point you spend, up to a maximum of 3, increases the damage by 2d6.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of the Sun Soul: Sun Shield</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you become wreathed in a luminous aura. You shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. You can extinguish or restore the light as a bonus action.</text>
                <text>    If a creature hits you with a melee attack while this light shines, you can use your reaction to deal radiant damage to the creature. The radiant damage equals 5 + your Wisdom modifier.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><class name="Monk (Tranquility)">
	<name>Monk (Tranquility)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Monastic Tradition: Way of Tranquility (UA)</name>
                <text>Monks of the Way of Tranquility see violence as a last resort. They use diplomacy, mercy, and understanding to resolve conflicts. If pushed, though, they are capable warriors who can bring an end to the unjust or cruel folk who refuse to listen to reason. When adventuring, these monks make excellent diplomats. They are also skilled in the healing arts, and can preserve their allies in the face of daunting foes.</text>
                <text>	</text>
                <text>This Monastic Tradition is from Unearthed Arcana: Monk Monastic Traditions, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Path of Tranquility</name>
                <text>When you choose this tradition at 3rd level, you can become an island of calm in even the most chaotic of situations. With this feature, you can cast the sanctuary spell on yourself, no material component required, and it lasts up to 8 hours. Its saving throw DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier. A creature that succeeds on the save is immune to this effect for 1 hour. </text>
                <text>	Once you cast the spell in this way, you can't do so again for 1 minute.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Healing Hands</name>
                <text>Your mystical touch can heal wounds. Starting at 3rd level, you have a pool of magical healing power that replenishes when you take a long rest. With that pool, you can restore a total number of hit points equal to your monk level x 10. </text>
                <text>	As an action, you can touch a creature and draw power from the pool to restore a number of hit points to that creature, up to the maximum amount remaining in the pool. </text>
                <text>	Instead of healing the creature, you can expend 5 hit points from your pool of healing to cure the target of one disease or neutralize one poison affecting it. You can cure multiple diseases and neutralize multiple poisons with a single use of Healing Hands, expending hit points separately for each one. </text>
                <text>	When you use your Flurry of Blows, you can replace one of the unarmed strikes with a use of this feature. </text>
                <text>	This feature has no effect on undead and constructs.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Emissary of Peace</name>
                <text>At 6th level, you gain the ability to diffuse violent situations. Whenever you make a Charisma check to calm violent emotions or to counsel peace, you have advantage on the roll. You must make this entreaty in good faith; it doesn't apply if proficiency in the Deception or Intimidation skill applies to your check. </text>
                <text>	You also gain proficiency in the Performance or Persuasion skill (choose one).</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="11">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Douse the Flames of War</name>
                <text>At 11th level, you gain the ability to temporarily extinguish a creature's violent impulses. As an action, you can touch a creature, and it must make a Wisdom saving throw with a DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier. The target automatically succeeds if it's missing any of its hit points. If the target fails the save, it can't attack for 1 minute. During that time, it also can't cast spells that deal damage or that force someone to make a saving throw. </text>
                <text>	This effect ends if the target is attacked, takes damage, or is forced to make a saving throw or if the target witnesses any of those things happening to its allies.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="17">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Way of Tranquility: Anger of a Gentle Soul</name>
                <text>At 17th level, you gain the ability to visit vengeance on someone who fells others. If you see a creature reduce another creature to 0 hit points, you can use your reaction to grant yourself a bonus to all damage rolls against the aggressor until the end of your next turn. The bonus equals your monk level. </text>
                <text>	Once you use this ability, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>
	</class><spell>
        <name>Breath of Winter (17th level required)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>Self (60-foot cone)</range>
        <components>6 Ki Points - Cast Cone of Cold</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>A blast of cold air erupts from your hands. Each creature in a 60-foot cone must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 8d8 cold damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <text />
        <text>A creature killed by this spell becomes a frozen statue until it thaws.</text>
        <text />
        <text>At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of a higher level, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Clench of the North Wind (6th level required)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>3 Ki Points - Cast Hold Person</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>Choose a humanoid that you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or be paralyzed for the duration. At the end of each of its turns, the target can make another Wisdom saving throw. On a success, the spell ends on the target.</text>
        <text />
        <text>At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a higher spell slot, you can target an additional humanoid for each slot of a higher level. The humanoids must be within 30 feet of each other when you target them.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Darkness (Monk)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of Shadow)</classes>
        <text>Magical darkness spreads from a point you choose within range to fill a 15-foot radius sphere for the duration. The darkness spreads around corners. A creature with darkvision can't see through this darkness, and nonmagical light can't illuminate it.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If the point you choose is on an object you are holding or one that isn't being worn or carried, the darkness emanates from the object and moves with it. Completely covering the source of the darkness with an opaque object, such as a bowl or a helm, blocks the darkness.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If any of this spell's area overlaps with an area of light created by a spell of or lower, the spell that created the light is dispelled.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Darkvision (Monk)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Touch</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points</components>
        <duration>8 hours</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of Shadow)</classes>
        <text>You touch a willing creature to grant it the ability to see in the dark. For the duration, that creature has darkvision out to a range of 60 feet.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Elemental Attunement</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>Self (60-foot cone)</range>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>You can use your action to briefly control elemental forces nearby, causing one of the following effects of your choice.</text>
        <text />
        <text>• Create a harmless, instantaneous sensory effect related to air, earth, fire, or water, such as a shower of sparks, a puff of wind, a spray of mist, or a gentle rumbling of stone.</text>
        <text />
        <text>• Instantaneously light or snuff out a candle, a torch, or a small campfire.</text>
        <text />
        <text>• Chill or warm up to 1 pound of nonliving material for up to 1 hour.</text>
        <text />
        <text>• Cause earth, fire, water, or mist that can fit within a 1-foot cube to shape itself into a crude form you designate for 1 minute.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Eternal Mountain Defense (11th level required)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>Only on Self</range>
        <components>5 Ki Points - Cast stoneskin</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>This spell turns the flesh of a willing creature you touch as hard as stone. Until the spell ends, the target has resistance to nonmagical bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Fangs of the Fire Snake</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Attack Action</time>
        <range>Only on Self</range>
        <components>1 Ki Point + 1 ki on hit (optional)</components>
        <duration>Rest of turn</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>When you use the Attack action on your turn, you can spend 1 ki point to cause tendrils of flame to stretch out from your fists and feet. Your reach with your unarmed strikes increases by 10 feet for that action, as well as the rest of the turn. A hit with such an attack deals fire damage instead of bludgeoning damage, and if you spend 1 ki point when the attack hits, it also deals an extra 1d1O fire damage.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Fist of Four Thunders</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot cube)</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>A wave of thunderous force sweeps out from you. Each creature in a 15-foot cube originating from you must make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 2d8 thunder damage and is pushed 10 feet away from you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage and isn't pushed.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Fist of Unbroken Air</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>30-feet</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points + 1 ki per boost</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>You can create a blast of compressed air that strikes like a mighty fist. As an action, you can spend 2 ki points and choose a creature within 30 feet of you. That creature must make a Strength saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d10 bludgeoning damage, plus an extra 1d1O bludgeoning damage for each additional ki point you spend, and you can push the creature up to 20 feet away from you and knock it prone. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage, and you don't push it or knock it prone.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Flames of the Phoenix (11th level required)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>150 feet</range>
        <components>4 Ki Points - cast fireball</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>A bright streak flashes from your pointing finger to a point you choose within range then blossoms with a low roar into an explosion of flame. Each creature in a 20-foot radius must make a Dexterity saving throw. A target takes 8d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Gong of the Summit (6th level required)</name>
        <level>2</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>60 feet</range>
        <components>3 Ki Points - cast shatter</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>A sudden loud ringing noise, painfully intense, erupts from a point of your choice within range. Each creature in a 10-foot-radius sphere centered on that point must make a Constitution saving throw. A creature takes 3d8 thunder damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. A creature made of inorganic material such as stone, crystal, or metal has disadvantage on this saving throw.</text>
        <text />
        <text>A nonmagical object that isn't being worn or carried also takes the damage if it's in the spell's area. At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of or higher, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot level.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Minor Illusion (Monk)</name>
        <level>0</level>
        <school>I</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>S, M</components>
        <duration>1 Minute</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of Shadow)</classes>
        <text>You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration. The illusion also ends if you dismiss it as an action or cast this spell again.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If you create a sound, its volume can range from a whisper to a scream. It can be your voice, someone else's voice, a lion's roar, a beating of drums, or any other sound you choose. The sound continues unabated throughout the duration, or you can make discrete sounds at different times before the spell ends.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If you create an image of an object, such as a chair, muddy footprints, or a small chest. It must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. The image can't create sound, light, smell, or any other sensory effect. Physical interaction with the image reveals it to be an illusion, because things can pass through it.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If a creature uses its action to examine the sound or image, the creature can determine that it is an illusion with a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC. If a creature discerns the illusion for what it is, the illusion becomes faint to the creature.</text>
    </spell>
<spell>
        <name>Mist Stance (11th level required)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>self only</range>
        <components>4 Ki Points - cast gaseous form (on self)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>You transform a willing creature you touch, along with everything it's wearing and carrying, into a misty cloud for the duration. The spell ends if the creature drops to 0 hit points. An incorporeal creature isn't affected.</text>
        <text />
        <text>While in this form, the target's only method of movement is a flying speed of 10 feet. The target can enter and occupy the space of another creature. The target has resistance to nonmagical damage, and it has advantage on Strength, Dexterity, and Constitution saving throws. The target can pass through small holes, narrow openings, and even mere cracks, though it treats liquids as though they were solid surfaces. The target can't fall and remains hovering in the air even when stunned or otherwise incapacitated.</text>
        <text />
        <text>While in the form of a misty cloud, the target can't talk or manipulate objects, and any objects it was carrying or holding can't be dropped, used, or otherwise interacted with. The target can't attack or cast spells.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Pass without Trace (Monk)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>A</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>Self</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of Shadow)</classes>
        <text>A veil of shadows and silence radiates from you, masking you and your companions from detection. For the duration, each creature you choose within 30 feet of you (including you) has a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks and can't be tracked except by magical means. A creature that receives this bonus leaves behind no tracks or other traces of its passage.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Ride the Wind (11th level required)</name>
        <level>3</level>
        <school>T</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>self only</range>
        <components>4 Ki Points - cast fly (on self)</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>You gain a flying speed of 60 feet for the duration. When the spell ends, the target falls if it is still aloft, unless it can stop the fall.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>River of Hungry Flame (17th level required)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <components>5 Ki Points - cast wall of fire</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>You create a wall of fire on a solid surface within range. You can make the wall up to 60 feet long, 20 feet high, and 1 foot think, or a ringed wall up to 20 feet in diameter, 20 feet high, and 1 foot think. The wall is opaque and lasts for the duration.</text>
        <text />
        <text>When the wall appears, each creature within its area must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, a creature takes 5d8 fire damage, or half as much damage on a successful save.</text>
        <text />
        <text>One side of the wall, selected by you when you cast this spell, deals 5d8 fire damage to each creature that ends its turn within 10 feet of that side or inside the wall. A creature takes the same damage when it enters the wall for the first time on a turn or ends its turn there. The other side of the wall deals no damage.</text>
        <text />
        <text>At Higher Levels, when you cast this spell, the damage increases by 1d8 for each slot increased.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Rush of the Gale Spirits</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>Self (60-foot line)</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points - cast gust of wind</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>A line of strong wind 60 feet long and 10 feet wide blasts from you in a direction you choose for the spell's duration. Each creature that starts its turn in the line must succeed on a Strength saving throw or be pushed 15 feet away from you in a direction following the line.</text>
        <text />
        <text>Any creature in the line must spend 2 feet of movement for every 1 foot it moves when moving closer to you.</text>
        <text />
        <text>The gust disperses gas or vapor, and it extinguishes candles, torches, and similar unprotected flames in the area. It causes protected flames, such as those of lanterns, to dance wildly and has a 50 percent chance to extinguish them.</text>
        <text />
        <text>As a bonus action on each of your turns before the spell ends, you can change the direction in which the line blasts from you.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Shape the Flowing River</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>30 foot side within 120 feet of you</range>
        <components>1 Ki Point</components>
        <duration>special</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>As an action, you can spend 1 ki point to choose an area of ice or water no larger than 30 feet on a side within 120 feet of you. You can change water to ice within the area and vice versa, and you can reshape ice in the area in any manner you choose. You can raise or lower the ice's elevation, create or fill in a trench, erect or flatten a wall, or form a pillar. The extent of any such changes can't exceed half the area's largest dimension. For example, if you affect a 30-foot square, you can create a pillar up to 15 feet high, raise or lower the square's elevation by up to 15 feet, dig a trench up to 15 feet deep, and so on. You can't shape the ice to trap or injure a creature in the area.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Silence (Monk)</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>I</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of Shadow)</classes>
        <text>For the duration, no sound can be created within or pass through a 20-foot-radius sphere centered on a point you choose within range. Any creature or object entirely inside the sphere is immune to thunder damage, and creatures are deafened while entirely inside it. Casting a spell that includes a verbal component is impossible there.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Sweeping Cinder Strike</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Action</time>
        <range>Self (15-foot cone)</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points - cast burning hands</components>
        <duration>Instantaneous</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>As you hold your hands with thumbs touching and fingers spread, a thin sheet of flames shoots forth from your outstretched fingertips. Each creature in a 15-foot cone must make a Dexterity saving throw. A creature takes 3d6 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one.</text>
        <text />
        <text>The fire ignites any flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</text>
        <text />
        <text>When you cast this spell using a higher spell slot, the damage increases by 1d6 for each additional spell slot.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Water Whip</name>
        <level>1</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 Bonus Action</time>
        <range>30 feet</range>
        <components>2 Ki Points + 1 per extra damage (optional)</components>
        <duration>1 turn</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>You can spend 2 ki points as an action to create a whip of water that shoves and pulls a creature to unbalance it. A creature that you can see that is within 30 feet of you must make a Dexterity saving throw. On a failed save, the creature takes 3d10 bludgeoning damage, plus an extra 1d1O bludgeoning damage for each additional ki point you spend, and you can either knock it prone or pull it up to 25 feet closer to you. On a successful save, the creature takes half as much damage, and you don't pull it or knock it prone.</text>
    </spell>
    <spell>
        <name>Wave of Rolling Earth (17th level required)</name>
        <level>4</level>
        <school>EV</school>
        <time>1 action</time>
        <range>120 feet</range>
        <components>6 Ki Points - cast wall of stone</components>
        <duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
        <classes>Monk (Way of the Four Elements)</classes>
        <text>A nonmagical wall of solid stone springs into existence at a point you choose within range. The wall is 6 inches thick and is composed of ten 10-foot-by-10-foot panels. Each panel must be contiguous with at least one other panel. Alternatively, you can create 10-foot-by-20-foot panels that are only 3 inches thick.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If the wall cuts through a creature's space when it appears, the creature is pushed to one side of the wall (your choice). If a creature would be surrounded on all sides by the wall (or the wall and another solid surface), that creature can make a Dexterity saving throw. On a success, it can use its reaction to move up to its speed so that it is no longer enclosed by the wall.</text>
        <text />
        <text>The wall can have any shape you desire, though it can't occupy the same space as a creature or object. the wall doesn't need to be vertical or resting on any firm foundation. It must, however, merge with and be solidly supported by existing stone. Thus you can use this spell to bridge a chasm or create a ramp.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If you create a span greater than 20 feet in length, you must halve the size of each panel to create supports. You can crudely shape the wall to create crenellations, battlements, and so on.</text>
        <text />
        <text>The wall is an object made of stone that can be damaged and thus breached. Each panel has AC 15 and 30 hit points per inch of thickness. Reducing a panel to 0 hit points destroys it and might cause connected panels to collapse at the DM's discretion.</text>
        <text />
        <text>If you maintain your concentration on this spell for its whole duration, the wall becomes permanent and can't be dispelled. Otherwise, the wall disappears when the spell ends.</text>
    </spell>
</compendium>