<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
	
  <feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Acrobat">
		<name>Acrobat (UA)</name>
		<text>You become more nimble, gaining the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Acrobatics skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• As a bonus action, you can make a DC 15 Dexterity (Acrobatics) check. If you succeed, difficult terrain doesn’t cost you extra movement until the end of the current turn.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats" name="Alchemist">
		<name>Alchemist (UA)</name>
		<text>You have studied the secrets of alchemy and are an expert in its practice, gaining the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency with alchemist's supplies. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them.</text>
		<text>• As an action, you can identify one potion within 5 feet of you, as if you had tasted it. You must see the liquid for this benefit to work.</text>
		<text>• Over the course of any short rest, you can temporarily improve the potency of one potion of healing of any rarity. To use this benefit, you must have alchemist's supplies with you, and the potion must be within reach. If the potion is drunk no more than 1 hour after the short rest ends, the creature drinking the potion can forgo the potion's die roll and regains the maximum number of hit points that the potion can restore.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Animal Handler">
		<name>Animal Handler (UA)</name>
		<text>You master the techniques needed to train and handle animals. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Animal Handling skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You can use a bonus action on your turn to command one friendly beast within 60 feet of you that can hear you and that isn’t currently following the command of someone else. You decide now what action the beast will take and where it will move during its next turn, or you issue a general command that lasts for 1 minute, such as to guard a particular area.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Arcanist">
		<name>Arcanist (UA)</name>
		<text>study the arcane arts, gaining the following benefits: </text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Arcana skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You learn the prestidigitation and detect magic spells. You can cast detect magic once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Barbed Hide">
		<name>Barbed Hide (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Tiefling</prerequisite>
		<text>One of your ancestors was a barbed devil or other spiky fiend. Barbs protrude from your head. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Constitution or Charisma score by 1, up to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• As a bonus action, you can cause small barbs to protrude all over your body or cause them to retract. At the start of each of your turns while the barbs are out, you deal 1d6 piercing damage to any creature grappling you or any creature grappled by you.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill. If you’re already proficient in it, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with it.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats" name="Blade Mastery">
		<name>Blade Mastery (UA)</name>
		<text>You master the shortsword, longsword, scimitar, rapier, and greatsword. You gain the following benefits when using any of them</text>
		<text>• You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with the weapon.</text>
		<text>• On your turn, you can use your reaction to assume a parrying stance, provided you have the weapon in hand. Doing so grants you a +1 bonus to your AC until the start of your next turn or until you're not holding the weapon.</text>
		<text>• When you make an opportunity attack with the weapon, you have advantage on the attack roll.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Bountiful Luck">
		<name>Bountiful Luck (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Halfling</prerequisite>
		<text>Whenever an ally you can see within 30 feet of you rolls a 1 on the d20 for an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can use your reaction to let the ally reroll the die. The ally must use the new roll.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Brawny">
		<name>Brawny (UA)</name>
		<text>You become stronger, gaining the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Strength score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Athletics skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You count as if you were one size larger for the purpose of determining your carrying capacity.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">strength +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats" name="Burglar">
		<name>Burglar (UA)</name>
		<text>You pride yourself on your quickness and your close study of certain clandestine activities. You gain the following benefits</text>
		<text>• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency with thieves' tools. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Critter Friend">
		<name>Critter Friend (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Gnome (Forest)</prerequisite>
		<text>Your friendship with animals mystically deepens. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Animal Handling skill. If you’re already proficient in it, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You learn the speak with animals spell and can cast it at will, without expending a spell slot. You also learn the animal friendship spell, and you can cast it once with this feat, without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to cast it in this way when you finish a long rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Diplomat">
		<name>Diplomat (UA)</name>
		<text>You master the arts of diplomacy, gaining the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Persuasion skill. If you are already proficient in this skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• If you spend 1 minute talking to someone who can understand what you say, you can make a Charisma (Persuasion) check contested by the creature’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If you or your companions are fighting the creature, your check automatically fails. If your check succeeds, the target is charmed by you as long as it remains within 60 feet of you and for 1 minute thereafter.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Dragon Fear">
		<name>Dragon Fear (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Dragonborn</prerequisite>
		<text>When angered, you radiate menace. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Strength or Charisma score by 1, up to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• Instead of exhaling destructive energy, you can roar and expend a use of your breath weapon to force each creature of your choice within 30 feet of you to make a Wisdom saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Charisma modifier). A target automatically succeeds if it can’t hear or see you. On a failed save, a target becomes frightened for 1 minute. If the frightened target takes any 	damage, it can repeat the saving throw, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Dragon Hide">
		<name>Dragon Hide  (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Dragonborn</prerequisite>
		<text>You inherited the might and majesty of your dragon ancestors. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Strength or Charisma score by 1, up to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You grow retractable claws from the tips of your fingers. Extending or retracting the claws requires no action. The claws are natural weapons, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with them, you deal slashing damage equal to 1d4 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</text>
		<text>• Your scales harden; you gain a +1 bonus to AC while you aren’t wearing armor.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Drow High Magic">
		<name>Drow High Magic (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Elf (Drow)</prerequisite>
		<text>You learn more of the spells typical for your people. You learn detect magic and can cast it at will, without expending a spell slot. You also learn levitate and dispel magic, each of which you can cast once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to cast the spell in this way when you finish a long rest. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Dwarf Resilience">
		<name>Dwarf Resilience (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Dwarf</prerequisite>
		<text>You have the blood of dwarf heroes flowing through your veins. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• Whenever you take the Dodge action in combat, you can spend one Hit Die to heal yourself. Roll the die, add your Constitution modifier, and regain a number of hit points equal to the total (minimum of 1).</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Elven Accuracy">
		<name>Elven Accuracy (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Elf or Half-elf</prerequisite>
		<text>You have uncanny aim. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• Whenever you have advantage on an attack roll, you can reroll one of the dice once.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Empathic">
		<name>Empathic (UA)</name>
		<text>You possess keen insight into how other people think and feel. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Insight skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You can use your action to try to get uncanny insight about one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you. Make a Wisdom (Insight) check contested by the target’s Charisma (Deception) check. If your check succeeds, you have advantage on attack rolls and ability checks against the target until the end of your next turn.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Everybody's Friend">
		<name>Everybody’s Friend (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Half-elf</prerequisite>
		<text>You develop your magnetic personality to ease your way through the world. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Charisma score by 1, up to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills. If you’re already proficient in either skill, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with that skill.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Fade Away">
		<name>Fade Away (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Gnome</prerequisite>
		<text>You can draw on your magical heritage to escape danger. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, up to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• When you take damage, you can use a reaction to magically become invisible until the end of your next turn or until you attack, deal damage, or force someone to make a saving throw. Once you use this ability, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats" name="Fell Handed">
		<name>Fell Handed (UA)</name>
		<text>You master the handaxe, battleaxe, greataxe, warhammer, and maul. You gain the following benefits when using any of them</text>
		<text>• You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with the weapon.</text>
		<text>• Whenever you have advantage on a melee attack roll you make with the weapon and hit, you can knock the target prone if the lower of the two d20s would also hit the target.</text>
		<text>• Whenever you have disadvantage on a melee attack roll you make with the weapon, the target takes bludgeoning damage equal to your Strength modifier (minimum of 0) if the attack misses but the higher of the two d20 rolls would have hit.</text>
		<text>• If you use the Help action to aid an ally's melee attack while you're wielding the weapon, you knock the target's shield aside momentarily. In addition to the ally gaining advantage on the attack roll, the ally gains a +2 bonus to the roll if the target is using a shield.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Fey Teleportation">
		<name>Fey Teleportation (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Elf (high)</prerequisite>
		<text>Drawing on your fey ancestry, you have learned how to teleport. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You learn the misty step spell and can cast it once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to cast it in this way when you finish a short or long rest. Intelligence is your spellcasting ability for this spell.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats" name="Flail Mastery">
		<name>Flail Mastery (UA)</name>
		<text>The flail is a tricky weapon to use, but you have spent countless hours mastering it. You gain the following benefits.</text>
		<text>• You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with a flail.</text>
		<text>• As a bonus action on your turn, you can prepare yourself to extend your flail to sweep over targets' shields. Until the end of this turn, your attack rolls with a flail gain a +2 bonus against any target using a shield.</text>
		<text>• When you hit with an opportunity attack using a flail, the target must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength modifier) or be knocked prone.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Flames of Phlegethos">
		<name>Flames of Phlegethos (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Tiefling</prerequisite>
		<text>You learn to call on hellfire to serve your commands. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• When you roll fire damage for a spell you cast, you can reroll any roll of 1 on the fire damage dice, but you must use the new roll, even if it is another 1.</text>
		<text>• Whenever you cast a spell that deals fire damage, you can cause flames to wreathe you until the end of your next turn. The flames don’t harm you or your possessions, and they shed bright light out to 30 feet and dim light for an additional 30 feet. While the flames are present, any creature within 5 feet of you that hits you with a melee attack takes 1d4 fire damage.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats" name="Gourmand">
		<name>Gourmand(UA)</name>
		<text>You have mastered a variety of special recipes, allowing you to prepare exotic dishes with useful effects. You gain the following benefits</text>
		<text>• Increase your Constitution score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency with cook's utensils. If you are already proficient with them, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with them.</text>
		<text>• As an action, you can inspect a drink or a plate of food within 5 feet of you and determine whether it is poisoned, provided that you can see and smell it.</text>
		<text>• During a long rest, you can prepare and serve a meal that helps you and your allies recover from the rigors of adventuring, provided you have suitable food, cook's utensils, and other supplies on hand. The meal serves up to six people, and each person who eats it regains two additional Hit Dice at the end of the long rest. In addition, those who partake of the meal have advantage on Constitution saving throws against disease for the next 24 hours.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Grudge-Bearer">
		<name>Grudge-Bearer (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Dwarf</prerequisite>
		<text>You have a deep hatred for a particular kind of creature. Choose your foes, a type of creature to bear the burden of your wrath: aberrations, beasts, celestials, constructs, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, giants, monstrosities, oozes, plants, or undead. Alternatively, you can choose two races of humanoid (such as gnolls and orcs). You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Strength, Constitution, or Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• During the first round of any combat against your chosen foes, your attack rolls against any of them have advantage.</text>
		<text>• When any of your chosen foes makes an opportunity attack against you, it makes the attack roll with disadvantage.</text>
		<text>• Whenever you make an Intelligence (Arcana, History, Nature, or Religion) check to recall information about your chosen foes, you add double your proficiency bonus to the check, even if you’re not normally proficient.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Historian">
		<name>Historian (UA)</name>
		<text>Your study of history rewards you with the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the History skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• When you take the Help action to aid another creature’s ability check, you can make a DC 15 Intelligence (History) check. On a success, that creature’s check gains a bonus equal to your proficiency bonus, as you share pertinent advice and historical examples. To receive this bonus, the creature must be able to understand what you’re saying.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Human Determination">
		<name>Human Determination (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Human</prerequisite>
		<text>You are filled with a determination that can draw the unreachable within your reach. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• When you make an attack roll, an ability check, or a saving throw, you can do so with advantage. Once you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Infernal Constitution">
		<name>Infernal Constitution (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Tiefling</prerequisite>
		<text>Fiendish blood runs strong in you. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Constitution score by 1, up to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You have resistance to cold and poison damage.</text>
		<text>• You have advantage on saving throws against being poisoned.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">constitution +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Investigator">
		<name>Investigator (UA)</name>
		<text>You have an eye for detail and can pick out the smallest clues. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Investigation skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You can take the Search action as a bonus action.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats" name="Master of Disguise">
		<name>Master of Disguise (UA)</name>
		<text>You have honed your ability to shape your personality and to read the personalities of others. You gain the following benefits</text>
		<text>• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the disguise kit. If you are already proficient with it, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• If you spend 1 hour observing a creature, you can then spend 8 hours crafting a disguise you can quickly don to mimic that creature. Making the disguise requires a disguise kit. You must make checks as normal to disguise yourself, but you can assume the disguise as an action.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Medic">
		<name>Medic (UA)</name>
		<text>You master the physician’s arts, gaining the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Medicine skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• During a short rest, you can clean and bind the wounds of up to six willing beasts and humanoids. Make a DC 15 Wisdom (Medicine) check for each creature. On a success, if a creature spends a Hit Die during this rest, that creature can forgo the roll and instead regain the maximum number of hit points the die can restore. A creature can do so only once per rest, regardless of how many Hit Dice it spends.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Menacing">
		<name>Menacing (UA)</name>
		<text>You become fearsome to others, gaining the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Intimidation skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack with an attempt to demoralize one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Intimidation) check contested by the target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, the target is frightened until the end of your next turn. If your check fails, the target can’t be frightened by you in this way for 1 hour.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Naturalist">
		<name>Naturalist (UA)</name>
		<text>Your extensive study of nature rewards you with the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Nature skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You learn the druidcraft and detect poison and disease spells. You can cast detect poison and disease once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Orcish Aggression">
		<name>Orcish Aggression (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Half-orc</prerequisite>
		<text>As a bonus action, you can move up to your speed toward an enemy of your choice that you can see or hear. You must end this move closer to the enemy than you started.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Orcish Fury">
		<name>Orcish Fury (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Half-orc</prerequisite>
		<text>Your fury burns tirelessly. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Strength or Constitution score by 1, up to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• When you hit with an attack made with a simple or martial weapon, you can roll one of the weapon’s damage dice an additional time and add it as extra damage of the weapon’s damage type. Once you use this ability, you can’t use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
		<text>• Immediately after you use your Relentless Endurance trait, you can use your reaction to make one weapon attack.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Perceptive">
		<name>Perceptive (UA)</name>
		<text>You hone your senses until they become razor sharp. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Perception skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• Being in a lightly obscured area doesn’t impose disadvantage on your Wisdom (Perception) checks if you can both see and hear.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Performer">
		<name>Performer (UA)</name>
		<text>You master performance so that you can command any stage. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Performance skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• While performing, you can try to distract one humanoid you can see who can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Performance) check contested by the humanoid’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, you grab the humanoid’s attention enough that it makes Wisdom (Perception) and Intelligence (Investigation) checks with disadvantage until you stop performing.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Prodigy">
		<name>Prodigy (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Half-elf or human</prerequisite>
		<text>You have a knack for learning new things. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase one ability score of your choice by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain one skill proficiency of your choice, one tool proficiency of your choice, and fluency in one language of your choice.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Quick-Fingered">
		<name>Quick-Fingered (UA)</name>
		<text>Your nimble fingers and agility let you perform sleight of hand. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Sleight of Hand skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• As a bonus action, you can make a Dexterity (Sleight of Hand) check to plant something on someone else, conceal an object on a creature, lift a purse, or take something from a pocket.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Second Chance">
		<name>Second Chance (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Halfling</prerequisite>
		<text>Fortune favors you. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Dexterity, Constitution, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• When a creature you can see hits you with an attack roll, you can use your reaction to force that creature to reroll. Once you use this ability, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Silver-Tongued">
		<name>Silver-Tongued (UA)</name>
		<text>You develop your conversational skill to better deceive others. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Deception skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• When you take the Attack action on your turn, you can replace one attack with an attempt to deceive one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you that can see and hear you. Make a Charisma (Deception) check contested by the target’s Wisdom (Insight) check. If your check succeeds, your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks from the target and your attack rolls against it have advantage; both benefits last until the end of your next turn or until you use this ability on a different target. If your check fails, the target can’t be deceived by you in this way for 1 hour.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">charisma +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats" name="Spear Mastery">
		<name>Spear Mastery (UA)</name>
		<text>Though the spear is a simple weapon to learn, it rewards you for the time you have taken to master it. You gain the following benefits.</text>
		<text>• You gain a +1 bonus to attack rolls you make with a spear.</text>
		<text>• When you use a spear, its damage die changes from a d6 to a d8, and from a d8 to a d10 when wielded with two hands. (This benefit has no effect if another feature has already improved the weapon's die.)</text>
		<text>• You can set your spear to receive a charge. As a bonus action, choose a creature you can see that is at least 20 feet away from you. If that creature moves within your spear's reach on its next turn, you can make a melee attack against it with your spear as a reaction. If the attack hits, the target takes an extra 1d8 piercing damage, or an extra 1d10 piercing damage if you wield the spear with two hands. You can't use this ability if the creature used the Disengage action before moving.</text>
		<text>• As a bonus action on your turn, you can increase your reach with a spear by 5 feet for the rest of your turn.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Squat Nimbleness">
		<name>Squat Nimbleness (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Dwarf, gnome, or halfling</prerequisite>
		<text>You are uncommonly nimble for your race. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Strength or Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• Increase your walking speed by 5 feet.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Acrobatics or Athletics skill. If you’re already proficient in the skill, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any check you make with it.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Stealthy">
		<name>Stealthy (UA)</name>
		<text>You know how best to hide. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Dexterity score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Stealth skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• If you are hidden, you can move up to 10 feet in the open without revealing yourself if you end the move in a position where you’re not clearly visible.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">dexterity +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Survivalist">
		<name>Survivalist (UA)</name>
		<text>You master wilderness lore, gaining the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Wisdom score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Survival skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You learn the alarm spell. You can cast it once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">wisdom +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Skills" name="Theologian">
		<name>Theologian (UA)</name>
		<text>Your extensive study of religion rewards you with the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• You gain proficiency in the Religion skill. If you are already proficient in the skill, you add double your proficiency bonus to checks you make with it.</text>
		<text>• You learn the thaumaturgy and detect evil and good spells. You can cast detect evil and good once without expending a spell slot, and you regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
		<modifier category="ability score">intelligence +1</modifier>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Wonder Maker">
		<name>Wonder Maker (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Gnome (rock)</prerequisite>
		<text>You master the tinker techniques of your people. You gain the following benefits:</text>
		<text>• Increase your Dexterity or Intelligence score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</text>
		<text>• When you make a check using your proficiency with tinker’s tools, you add double your proficiency bonus to the check.</text>
		<text>• When you make a device with your Tinker trait, you have the following additional options for what you make:</text>
		<text>Alarm. This device senses when a creature moves to within 15 feet of it without speaking aloud a password chosen when you create it. One round after a creature moves into range, the alarm makes a shrill ringing that lasts for 1 minute and can be heard from up to 300 feet away.</text>
		<text>Calculator. This device makes doing sums easy.</text>
		<text>Lifter. This device can be used as a block and tackle, allowing its user to hoist five times the weight the user can normally lift.</text>
		<text>Timekeeper. This pocket watch keeps accurate time.</text>
		<text>Weather Sensor. When used as an action, this device predicts weather conditions in a 1-mile radius over the next 4 hours, showing one symbol (clouds, sun/moon, rain, or snow) for each hour.</text>
	</feat>
	<feat UA="Feats for Races" name="Wood Elf Magic">
		<name>Wood Elf Magic (UA)</name>
		<prerequisite>Elf (wood)</prerequisite>
		<text>You learn the magic of the primeval woods. You learn one druid cantrip of your choice. You also learn longstrider and pass without trace, each of which you can cast once without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to cast the spell in this way when you finish a long rest. Wisdom is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
	</feat>
<item>
    <name>Alchemy Jug</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>12</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This ceramic jug appears to be able to hold a gallon of liquid and weighs 12 pounds whether full or empty. Sloshing sounds can be heard from within the jug when it is shaken, even if the jug is empty.</text>
    <text>You can use an action and name one liquid from the table below to cause the jug to produce the chosen liquid. Afterward, you can uncork the jug as an action and pour that liquid out, up to 2 gallons per minute. The maximum amount of liquid the jug can produce depends on the liquid you named.</text>
    <text>Once the jug starts producing a liquid, it can't produce a different one, or more of one that has reached its maximum, until the next dawn.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Liquid — Max Amount:</text>
    <text>Acid — 8 ounces</text>
    <text>Basic poison — 1/2 ounce</text>
    <text>Beer — 4 gallons</text>
    <text>Honey — 1 gallon</text>
    <text>Mayonnaise — 2 gallons</text>
    <text>Oil — 1 quart</text>
    <text>Vinegar — 2 gallons</text>
    <text>Water, fresh — 8 gallons</text>
    <text>Water, salt — 12 gallons</text>
    <text>Wine — 1 gallon</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 150</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bag of Beans</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>0.5</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Rare</text>
    <text>Inside this heavy cloth bag are 3d4 dry beans. The bag weighs 1/2 pound plus 1/4 pound for each bean it contains.</text>
    <text>If you dump the bag's contents out on the ground, they explode in a 10-foot radius, extending from the beans. Each creature in the area, including you, must make a DC 15 Dexterity saving throw, taking 5d4 fire damage on a failed save, or half as much damage on a successful one. The fire ignites flammable objects in the area that aren't being worn or carried.</text>
    <text>If you remove a bean from the bag, plant it in dirt or sand, and then water it, the bean produces an effect 1 minute later from the ground where it was planted. The DM can choose an effect from the following table, determine it randomly, or create an effect.</text>
    <text />
    <text>d100 — Effect: </text>
    <text>01 — 5d4 toadstools sprout. If a creature eats a toadstool, roll any die. On an odd roll, the eater must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or take Sd6 poison damage and become poisoned for 1 hour. On an even roll, the eater gains 5d6 temporary hit points for 1 hour.</text>
    <text>2-10 — A geyser erupts and spouts water, beer, berry juice, tea, vinegar, wine, or oil (DM's choice) 30 feet into the air for 1d12 rounds.</text>
    <text>11-20 — A treant sprouts (see the Monster Manual for statistics). There's a 50 percent chance that the treant is chaotic evil and attacks.</text>
    <text>21-30 — An animate, immobile stone statue in your likeness rises. It makes verbal threats against you. If you leave it and others come near, it describes you as the most heinous of villains and directs the newcomers to find and attack you. If you are on the same plane of existence as the statue, it knows where you are. The statue becomes inanimate after 24 hours.</text>
    <text>31-40 — A campfire with blue flames springs forth and burns for 24 hours (or until it is extinguished).</text>
    <text>41-50 — 1d6 + 6 shriekers sprout (see the Monster Manual for statistics).</text>
    <text>51-60 — 1d4 + 8 bright pink toads crawl forth. Whenever a toad is touched, it transforms into a Large or smaller monster of the DM's choice. The monster remains for 1 minute, then disappears in a puff of bright pink smoke.</text>
    <text>61-70 — A hungry bulette (see the Monster Manual for statistics) burrows up and attacks.</text>
    <text>71-80 A fruit tree grows. It has 1d10+20 fruit, 1d8 of which act as randomly determined magic potions, while one acts as an ingested poison of the DM's choice. The tree vanishes after 1 hour. Picked fruit remains, retaining any magic for 30 days.</text>
    <text>81-90 — A nest of 1d4 + 3 eggs springs up. Any creature that eats an egg must make a DC 20 Constitution saving throw. On a successful save, a creature permanently increases its lowest ability score by 1, randomly choosing among equally low scores. On a failed save, the creature takes 10d6 force damage from an internal magical explosion.</text>
    <text>91-99 — A pyramid with a 60-foot-square base bursts upward. Inside is a sarcophagus containing a mummy lord (see the Monster Manual for statistics). The pyramid is treated as the mummy lord's lair, and its sarcophagus contains treasure of the DM's choice.</text>
    <text>00 — A giant beanstalk sprouts, growing to a height of the DM's choice. The top leads where the DM chooses, such as to a great view, a cloud giant's castle, or a different plane of existence.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 152</text>
    <roll>5d4</roll>
    <roll>1d100</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bag of Holding</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>15</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This bag has an interior space considerably larger than its outside dimensions, roughly 2 feet in diameter at the mouth and 4 feet deep. The bag can hold up to 500 pounds, not exceeding a volume of 64 cubic feet. The bag weighs 15 pounds, regardless of its contents. Retrieving an item from the bag requires an action.</text>
    <text>If the bag is overloaded, pierced, or torn, it ruptures and is destroyed, and its contents are scattered in the Astral Plane. If the bag is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, but the bag must be put right before it can be used again. Breathing creatures inside the bag can survive up to a number of minutes equal to 10 divided by the number of creatures (minimum 1 minute), after which time they begin to suffocate.</text>
    <text>Placing a bag of holding inside an extradimensional space created by a Heward's handy haversack, portable hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10 feet of the gate is sucked through it to a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 153</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Boots of Striding and Springing</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While you wear these boots, your walking speed becomes 30 feet, unless your walking speed is higher, and your speed isn't reduced if you are encumbered or wearing heavy armor. In addition, you can jump three times the normal distance, though you can't jump farther than your remaining movement would allow.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 156</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Bracers of Archery</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While wearing these bracers, you have proficiency with the longbow and shortbow, and you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls on ranged attacks made with such weapons.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 156</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Brooch of Shielding</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While wearing this brooch, you have resistance to force damage, and you have immunity to damage from the magic missile spell.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 156</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Broom of Flying</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This wooden broom, which weighs 3 pounds, functions like a mundane broom until you stand astride it and speak its command word. It then hovers beneath you and can be ridden in the air. It has a flying speed of 50 feet. It can carry up to 400 pounds, but its flying speed becomes 30 feet while carrying over 200 pounds. The broom stops hovering when you land.</text>
    <text>You can send the broom to travel alone to a destination within 1 mile of you if you speak the command word, name the location, and are familiar with that place. The broom comes back to you when you speak another command word, provided that the broom is still within 1 mile of you.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 156</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Cap of Water Breathing</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>While wearing this cap underwater, you can speak its command word as an action to create a bubble of air around your head. It allows you to breathe normally underwater. This bubble stays with you until you speak the command word again, the cap is removed, or you are no longer underwater.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 157</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Chime of Opening</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Rare</text>
    <text>This hollow metal tube measures about 1 foot long and weighs 1 pound. You can strike it as an action, pointing it at an object within 120 feet of you that can be opened, such as a door, lid, or lock. The chime issues a clear tone, and one lock or latch on the object opens unless the sound can't reach the object. If no locks or latches remain, the object itself opens.</text>
    <text>The chime can be used ten times. After the tenth time it cracks and becomes useless.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 158</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Decanter of Endless Water</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This stoppered flask sloshes when shaken, as if it contains water. The decanter weighs 2 pounds.</text>
    <text>You can use an action to remove the stopper and speak one of three command words, whereupon an amount of fresh water or salt water (your choice) pours out of the flask. The water stops pouring out at the start of your next turn. Choose from the following options:</text>
    <text>• "Stream" produces 1 gallon of water.</text>
    <text>• "Fountain" produces 5 gallons of water.</text>
    <text>• "Geyser" produces 30 gallons of water that gushes forth in a geyser 30 feet long and 1 foot wide. As a bonus action while holding the decanter, you can aim the geyser at a creature you can see within 30 feet of you. The target must succeed on a DC 13 Strength saving throw or take 1d4 bludgeoning damage and fall prone. Instead of a creature, you can target an object that isn't being worn or carried and that weighs no more than 200 pounds. The object is either knocked over or pushed up to 15 feet away from you.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 161</text>
    <roll>1d4</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Driftglobe</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This small sphere of thick glass weighs 1 pound. If you are within 60 feet of it, you can speak its command word and cause it to emanate the light or daylight spell. Once used, the daylight effect can't be used again until the next dawn.</text>
    <text>You can speak another command word as an action to make the illuminated globe rise into the air and float no more than 5 feet off the ground. The globe hovers in this way until you or another creature grasps it. If you move more than 60 feet from the hovering globe, it follows you until it is within 60 feet of you. It takes the shortest route to do so. If prevented from moving, the globe sinks gently to the ground and becomes inactive, and its light winks out.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 166</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Eyes of Minute Seeing</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>These crystal lenses fit over the eyes. While wearing them, you can see much better than normal out to a range of 1 foot. You have advantage on Intelligence (Investigation) checks that rely on sight while searching an area or studying an object within that range.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 168</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Eyes of the Eagle</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>These crystal lenses fit over the eyes. While wearing them, you have advantage on Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on sight. In conditions of clear visibility, you can make out details of even extremely distant creatures and objects as small as 2 feet across.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 168</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Folding Boat</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>4</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Rare</text>
    <text>This object appears as a wooden box that measures 12 inches long, 6 inches wide, and 6 inches deep. It weighs 4 pounds and floats. It can be opened to store items inside. This item also has three command words, each requiring you to use an action to speak it.</text>
    <text>One command word causes the box to unfold into a boat 10 feet long, 4 feet wide, and 2 feet deep. The boat has one pair of oars, an anchor, a mast, and a lateen sail. The boat can hold up to four Medium creatures comfortably.</text>
    <text>The second command word causes the box to unfold into a ship 24 feet long, 8 feet wide; and 6 feet deep. The ship has a deck, rowing seats, five sets of oars, a steering oar, an anchor, a deck cabin, and a mast with a square sail. The ship can hold fifteen Medium creatures comfortably.</text>
    <text>When the box becomes a vessel, its weight becomes that of a normal vessel its size, and anything that was stored in the box remains in the boat.</text>
    <text>The third command word causes the folding boat to fold back into a box, provided that no creatures are aboard. Any objects in the vessel that can't fit inside the box remain outside the box as it folds. Any objects in the vessel that can fit inside the box do so.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 170</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gem of Brightness</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This prism has 50 charges. While you are holding it, you can use an action to speak one of three command words to cause one of the following effects:</text>
    <text>• The first command word causes the gem to shed bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. This effect doesn't expend a charge. It lasts until you use a bonus action to repeat the command word or until you use another function of the gem.</text>
    <text>• The second command word expends 1 charge and causes the gem to fire a brilliant beam of light at one creature you can see within 60 feet of you. The creature must succeed on a DC 15 Constitution saving throw or become blinded for 1 minute. The creature can repeat the saving throw at the end of each of its turns, ending the effect on itself on a success.</text>
    <text>• The third command word expends 5 charges and causes the gem to flare with blinding light in a 30-foot cone originating from it. Each creature in the cone must make a saving throw as if struck by the beam created with the second command word.</text>
    <text>When all of the gem's charges are expended, the gem becomes a nonmagical jewel worth 50 gp.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 171</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gloves of Missile Snaring</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>These gloves seem to almost meld into your hands when you don them. When a ranged weapon attack hits you while you're wearing them, you can use your reaction to reduce the damage by 1d10 +your Dexterity modifier. provided that you have a free hand. If you reduce the damage to 0, you can catch the missile if it is small enough for you to hold in that hand.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 172</text>
    <roll>1d10+%2</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Gloves of Swimming and Climbing</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While wearing these gloves, climbing and swimming don't cost you extra movement, and you gain a +5 bonus to Strength (Athletics) checks made to climb or swim.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 172</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Goggles of Night</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>While wearing these dark lenses, you have darkvision out to a range of 60 feet. If you already have darkvision. wearing the goggles increases its range by 60 feet.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 172</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Hat of Disguise</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While wearing this hat, you can use an action to cast the disguise self spell from it at will. The spell ends if the hat is removed.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 173</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Helm of Comprehending Languages</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>While wearing this helm, you can use an action to cast the comprehend languages spell from it at will.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 173</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Heward's Handy Haversack</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>5</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Rare</text>
    <text>This backpack has a central pouch and two side pouches, each of which is an extradimensional space. Each side pouch can hold up to 20 pounds of material, not exceeding a volume of 2 cubic feet. The large central pouch can hold up to 8 cubic feet or 80 pounds of material. The backpack always weighs 5 pounds, regardless of its contents.</text>
    <text>Placing an object in the haversack follows the normal rules for interacting with objects. Retrieving an item from the haversack requires you to use an action. When you reach into the haversack for a specific item, the item is always magically on top.</text>
    <text>The haversack has a few limitations. If it is overloaded, or if a sharp object pierces it or tears it, the haversack ruptures and is destroyed. If the haversack is destroyed, its contents are lost forever, although an artifact always turns up again somewhere. If the haversack is turned inside out, its contents spill forth, unharmed, and the haversack must be put right before it can be used again. If a breathing creature is placed within the haversack, the creature can survive for up to 10 minutes, after which time it begins to suffocate.</text>
    <text>Placing the haversack inside an extradimensional space created by a bag of holding, portable hole, or similar item instantly destroys both items and opens a gate to the Astral Plane. The gate originates where the one item was placed inside the other. Any creature within 10-feet of the gate is sucked through it and deposited in a random location on the Astral Plane. The gate then closes. The gate is one-way only and can't be reopened.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 174</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Lantern of Revealing</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>2</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>While lit, this hooded lantern burns for 6 hours on 1 pint of oil, shedding bright light in a 30-foot radius and dim light for an additional 30 feet. Invisible creatures and objects are visible as long as they are in the lantern's bright light. You can use an action to lower the hood, reducing the light to dim light in a 5-foot radius.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 179</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ring of Jumping</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While wearing this ring, you can cast the jump spell from it as a bonus action at will, but can target only yourself when you do so.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 191</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ring of Mind Shielding</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While wearing this ring, you are immune to magic that allows other creatures to read your thoughts, determine whether you are lying, know your alignment, or know your creature type. Creatures can telepathically communicate with you only if you allow it.</text>
    <text>You can use an action to cause the ring to become invisible until you use another action to make it visible, until you remove the ring, or until you die.</text>
    <text>If you die while wearing the ring, your soul enters it, unless it already houses a soul. You can remain in the ring or depart for the afterlife. As long as your soul is in the ring, you can telepathically communicate with any creature wearing it. A wearer can't prevent this telepathic communication.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 191</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Ring of Swimming</name>
    <type>RG</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>You have a swimming speed of 40 feet while wearing this ring.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 193</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Robe of Useful Items</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This robe has cloth patches of various shapes and colors covering it. While wearing the robe. you can use an action to detach one of the patches, causing it to become the object or creature it represents. Once the last patch is removed, the robe becomes an ordinary garment.</text>
    <text>The robe has two of each of the following patches:</text>
    <text>• Dagger</text>
    <text>• Bullseye lantern (filled and lit)</text>
    <text>• Steel mirror</text>
    <text>• 10-foot pole</text>
    <text>• Hempen rope (50 feet, coiled)</text>
    <text>• Sack</text>
    <text>In addition, the robe has 4d4 other patches. The DM chooses the patches or determines them randomly.</text>
    <text />
    <text>d100 — Patch:</text>
    <text>01-08 — Bag of 100 gp</text>
    <text>09-15 — Silver coffer (1 foot long, 6 inches wide and deep) worth 500 gp</text>
    <text>16-22 — Iron door (up to 10 feet wide and 10 feet high, barred on one side of your choice), which you can place in an opening you can reach; it conforms to fit the opening, attaching and hinging itself</text>
    <text>23-30 — 10 gems worth 100 gp each</text>
    <text>31-44 — Wooden ladder (24 feet long)</text>
    <text>45-51 — A riding horse with saddle bags (see the Monster Manual for statistics)</text>
    <text>52-59 — Pit (a cube 10 feet on a side), which you can place on the ground within 10 feet of you</text>
    <text>60-68 — 4 potions of healing</text>
    <text>69-75 — Rowboat (12 feet long)</text>
    <text>76-83 — Spell scroll containing one spell of 1st to 3rd level</text>
    <text>84-90 — 2 mastiffs (see the Monster Manual for statistics)</text>
    <text>91-96 — Window (2 feet by 4 feet, up to 2 feet deep), which you can place on a vertical surface you can reach</text>
    <text>97-00 — Portable ram</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 195</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Rope of Climbing</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <weight>3</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This 60-foot length of silk rope weighs 3 pounds and can hold up to 3,000 pounds. If you hold one end of the rope and use an action to speak the command word, the rope animates. As a bonus action, you can command the other end to move toward a destination you choose. That end moves 10 feet on your turn when you first command it and 10 feet on each of your turns until reaching its destination, up to its maximum length away, or until you tell it to stop. You can also tell the rope to fasten itself securely to an object or to unfasten itself, to knot or unknot itself, or to coil itself for carrying.</text>
    <text>If you tell the rope to knot, large knots appear at 1-foot intervals along the rope. While knotted, the rope shortens to a 50-foot length and grants advantage on checks made to climb it.</text>
    <text>The rope has AC 20 and 20 hit points. It regains 1 hit point every 5 minutes as long as it has at least 1 hit point. If the rope drops to 0 hit points, it is destroyed.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 197</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Sending Stones</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Sending stones come in pairs, with each smooth stone carved to match the other so the pairing is easily recognized. While you touch one stone, you can use an action to cast the sending spell from it. The target is the bearer of the other stone. If no creature bears the other stone, you know that fact as soon as you use the stone and don't cast the spell.</text>
    <text>Once sending is cast through the stones, they can't be used again until the next dawn. If one of the stones in a pair is destroyed, the other one becomes nonmagical.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 199</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Slippers of Spider Climbing</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While you wear these light shoes, you can move up, down, and across vertical surfaces and upside down along ceilings, while leaving your hands free. You have a climbing speed equal to your walking speed. However, the slippers don't allow you to move this way on a slippery surface, such as one covered by ice or oil.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 200</text>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of Magic Detection</name>
    <type>WD</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>This wand has 3 charges. While holding it, you can expend 1 charge as an action to cast the detect magic spell from it. The wand regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 211</text>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wand of Secrets</name>
    <type>WD</type>
    <weight>1</weight>
    <text>Rarity: Uncommon</text>
    <text>The wand has 3 charges. While holding it. you can use an action to expend 1 of its charges, and if a secret door or trap is within 30 feet of you, the wand pulses and points at the one nearest to you. The wand regains 1d3 expended charges daily at dawn.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 211</text>
    <roll>1d3</roll>
  </item>
  <item>
    <name>Wings of Flying</name>
    <type>W</type>
    <text>Rarity: Rare</text>
    <text>Requires Attunement</text>
    <text />
    <text>While wearing this cloak, you can use an action to speak its command word. This turns the cloak into a pair of bat wings or bird wings on your back for 1 hour or until you repeat the command word as an action. The wings give you a flying speed of 60 feet. When they disappear, you can't use them again for 1d12 hours.</text>
    <text />
    <text>Source: Dungeon Master's Guide, page 214</text>
    <roll>1d12</roll>
  </item>
<race UA="Eberron" name="Changeling">
		<name>Changeling</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 1, Cha 1</ability>
		<proficiency>Deception</proficiency>
		<trait>
			<name>Duplicity</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception skill.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shapechanger</name>
			<text>As an action, you can polymorph into any humanoid of your size that you have seen, or back into your true form. However, your equipment does not change with you. If you die, you revert to your natural appearance.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and two other languages of your choice.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race UA="Waterborne Adventures" name="Minotaur">
		<name>Minotaur</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Str 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Conqueror’s Virtue</name>
			<text>From a young age, you focused on one of the three virtues of strength, cunning, or intellect. Your choice of your Strength, Intelligence, or Wisdom score increases by 1.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Horns</name>
			<text>You are never unarmed. You are proficient with your horns, which are a melee weapon that deals 1d10 piercing damage. Your horns grant you advantage on all checks made to shove a creature, but not to avoid being shoved yourself.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Goring Rush</name>
			<text>When you use the Dash action during your turn, you can make a melee attack with your horns as a bonus action.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Hammering Horns</name>
			<text>When you use the Attack action during your turn to make a melee attack, you can attempt to shove a creature with your horns as a bonus action. You cannot use this shove attempt to knock a creature prone.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Labyrinthine Recall</name>
			<text>You can perfectly recall any path you have traveled.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Sea Reaver</name>
			<text>You gain proficiency with navigator’s tools and vehicles (water).</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race UA="Gothic Heroes" name="Revenant">
		<name>Revenant</name>
		<ability>Con 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Subrace</name>
			<text>Having met a cruel and undeserved end, you have returned to the realm of the living. As a revenant, you thirst for revenge against those who wronged you in life, or seek to complete a final, critical task you left unfinished.</text>
			<text>The revenant subrace can be applied to any race that has a subrace, and replaces that race’s existing subrace options. Alternatively, you can apply this new subrace to a race without subrace options using the modification options provided below.</text>
			<text>Your DM might also allow you to take this subrace for a slain character. In that case, your character rises from the dead with its original subrace replaced (or with the necessary modifications made to its base traits), filled with a determination to seek vengeance or complete its mission.</text>
			<text>This Subrace is from Unearthed Arcana: Gothic Heroes, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before selecting this option.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Ability Score Increase</name>
			<text>Your Constitution score increases by 1, replacing any other subrace Ability Score Increase</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Relentless Nature</name>
			<text>Your DM assigns a goal to you—typically, one related to your character’s death. The goal must be a specific task you can complete, such as slaying an enemy or liberating an area and its people. Until you fulfill that goal, you gain the following benefits:</text>
			<text>• If you are below half your hit point maximum at the start of your turn, you regain 1 hit point.</text>
			<text>• If you die, you return to life 24 hours after death. If your body is destroyed, you reform within 1 mile of the place of your death at a spot determined by the DM. If your equipment was also destroyed, you do not regain it.</text>
			<text>• You know the distance and direction between you and any creature involved in your goal, such as a person you seek vengeance against or someone you pledged to defend. This awareness fails if the creature is on another plane of existence.</text>
			<text>When your goal is complete, you finally find rest. You die and cannot be restored to life.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race UA="Eberron" name="Shifter (Beasthide)">
		<name>Shifter (Beasthide)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 1, Con 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Your lycanthropic heritage grants you the ability to see in dark conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting</name>
			<text>On your turn, you can shift as a bonus action. Shifting lasts for 1 minute or until you end it on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
			<text />
			<text>While shifting, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution bonus (minimum of 1). You also gain a feature that depends on your shifter subrace, described below.</text>
			<text />
			<text>You must finish a short or long rest before you can shift again.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting Feature</name>
			<text>While shifting, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race UA="Eberron" name="Shifter (Cliffwalk)">
		<name>Shifter (Cliffwalk)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Your lycanthropic heritage grants you the ability to see in dark conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting</name>
			<text>On your turn, you can shift as a bonus action. Shifting lasts for 1 minute or until you end it on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
			<text />
			<text>While shifting, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution bonus (minimum of 1). You also gain a feature that depends on your shifter subrace, described below.</text>
			<text />
			<text>You must finish a short or long rest before you can shift again.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting Feature</name>
			<text>While shifting, you gain a climb speed of 30 feet.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race UA="Eberron" name="Shifter (Longstride)">
		<name>Shifter (Longstride)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 2</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Your lycanthropic heritage grants you the ability to see in dark conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting</name>
			<text>On your turn, you can shift as a bonus action. Shifting lasts for 1 minute or until you end it on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
			<text />
			<text>While shifting, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution bonus (minimum of 1). You also gain a feature that depends on your shifter subrace, described below.</text>
			<text />
			<text>You must finish a short or long rest before you can shift again.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting Feature</name>
			<text>While shifting, you can use the Dash action as a bonus action.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race UA="Eberron" name="Shifter (Longtooth)">
		<name>Shifter (Longtooth)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 1, Str 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Your lycanthropic heritage grants you the ability to see in dark conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting</name>
			<text>On your turn, you can shift as a bonus action. Shifting lasts for 1 minute or until you end it on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
			<text />
			<text>While shifting, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution bonus (minimum of 1). You also gain a feature that depends on your shifter subrace, described below.</text>
			<text />
			<text>You must finish a short or long rest before you can shift again.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting Feature</name>
			<text>While shifting, you can make a bite attack as an action. This is a melee weapon attack that uses Strength for its attack roll and damage bonus and deals 1d6 piercing damage. If this attack hits a target that is your size or smaller, the target is also grappled.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race UA="Eberron" name="Shifter (Wildhunt)">
		<name>Shifter (Wildhunt)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Dex 1, Wis 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Your lycanthropic heritage grants you the ability to see in dark conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting</name>
			<text>On your turn, you can shift as a bonus action. Shifting lasts for 1 minute or until you end it on your turn as a bonus action.</text>
			<text />
			<text>While shifting, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution bonus (minimum of 1). You also gain a feature that depends on your shifter subrace, described below.</text>
			<text />
			<text>You must finish a short or long rest before you can shift again.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Sylvan.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Shifting Feature</name>
			<text>While shifting, you gain advantage on all Wisdom-based checks and saving throws.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<race UA="That Old Black Magick" name="Tiefling (Abyssal)">
		<name>Tiefling (Abyssal)</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Cha 2, Con 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Darkvision</name>
			<text>Thanks to your infernal heritage, you have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Infernal Legacy</name>
			<text>You know the thaumaturgy cantrip. Once you reach 3rd level, you can cast the hellish rebuke spell as a 2nd-level spell; you must finish a long rest in order to cast the spell again using this trait. Once you reach 5th level, you can also cast the darkness spell; you must finish a long rest in order to cast the spell again using this trait. Charisma is your spellcasting ability for these spells.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and Abyssal.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Abyssal Fortitude</name>
			<text>Your hit point maximum increases by half your level (minimum 1)</text>
			<modifier>Hit Points +1</modifier>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Abyssal Arcana</name>
			<text>Each time you finish a long rest, you gain the ability to cast cantrips and spells randomly determined from a short list. At 1st level, you can cast a cantrip. When you reach 3rd level, you can also cast a 1st-level spell. At 5th level, you can cast a 2nd-level spell.</text>
			<text>You can cast a spell gained from this trait only once until you complete your next long rest. You can cast a cantrip gained from this trait at will, as normal. For 1st-level spells whose effect changes if cast using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, you cast the spell as if using a 2nd-level slot. Spells of 2nd level are cast as if using a 2nd-level slot</text>
			<text>At the end of each long rest, you lose the cantrips and spells previously granted by this feature, even if you did not cast them. You replace those cantrips and spells by rolling for new ones on the Abyssal Arcana Spells table. Roll separately for each cantrip and spell. If you roll the same spell or cantrip you gained at the end of your previous long rest, roll again until you get a different result.</text>
			<text />
			<text>d6 — 1st level — 3rd level — 5th level:</text>
			<text>1 — dancing lights — burning hands — alter self</text>
			<text>2 — true strike — charm person — darkness</text>
			<text>3 — light — magic missile — invisibility</text>
			<text>4 — message — cure wounds — levitate</text>
			<text>5 — spare the dying — Tasha's hideous laughter — mirror image</text>
			<text>6 — prestidigitation — thunderwave — spider climb</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Feral (Variant)</name>
			<text>Your Intelligence score increases by 1, and your Dexterity score increases by 2. This replaces the Ability Score Increase trait.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Appearance (Variant)</name>
			<text>Your tiefling might not look like other tieflings. Rather than having the physical characteristics described in the Player's Handbook, choose 1d4 + 1 of the following features: small horns; fangs or sharp teeth; a forked tongue; catlike eyes; six fingers on each hand; goatlike legs; cloven hoofs; a forked tail; leathery or scaly skin; red or dark blue skin; cast no shadow or reflection; exude a smell of brimstone</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
<race UA="Eberron" name="Warforged">
		<name>Warforged</name>
		<size>M</size>
		<speed>30</speed>
		<ability>Str 1, Con 1</ability>
		<trait>
			<name>Composite Plating</name>
			<text>Your construction incorporates wood and metal, granting you a +1 bonus to Armor Class.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Living Construct</name>
			<text>Even though you were constructed, you are a living creature. You are immune to disease. You do not need to eat or breathe, but you can ingest food and drink if you wish.</text>
			<text />
			<text>Instead of sleeping, you enter an inactive state for 4 hours each day. You do not dream in this state; you are fully aware of your surroundings and notice approaching enemies and other events as normal.</text>
		</trait>
		<trait>
			<name>Languages</name>
			<text>You can speak, read, and write Common and one other language of your choice.</text>
		</trait>
	</race>
	<spell>
		<name>Cause Fear (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>N</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>60 feet</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
		<classes>Warlock, Wizard, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</classes>
		<text>You awaken the sense of mortality in one creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or become frightened for the duration. A target with 25 hit points or fewer makes the saving throw with disadvantage. The spell has no effect on constructs or undead.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Ceremony (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<ritual>YES</ritual>
		<time>1 hour</time>
		<range>Touch</range>
		<components>V, S, M (25gp worth of powdered silver)</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous (see text)</duration>
		<classes>Cleric, Paladin</classes>
		<text>You perform one of several religious ceremonies.When you cast the spell, choose one of the following ceremonies, the target of which must be within 10 feet of you throughout the casting.</text>
		<text>Atonement: You touch one willing creature whose alignment has changed, and you make a DC 20 Wisdom (Insight) check. On a success, you restore the target to its original alignment.</text>
		<text>Bless Water: You touch one vial of water and cause it to become holy water.</text>
		<text>Coming of Age: You touch one humanoid old enough to be a young adult. For the next 24 hours, whenever the target makes an ability check, it can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the ability check. A creature can benefit from this ceremony just once.</text>
		<text>Dedication: You touch one humanoid who would willingly convert to your religion or who wishes to be dedicated to your god’s service. For the next 24 hours, whenever the target makes a saving throw, it can roll a d4 and add the number rolled to the save. A creature can benefit from this ceremony just once.</text>
		<text>Funeral Rite: You bless one corpse within 5 feet of you. For the next 24 hours, the target can’t become undead by any means short of a wish spell.</text>
		<text>Investiture: You touch one willing humanoid. Choose one 1st-level spell you have prepared and expend a spell slot and any material components as if you were casting that spell. The spell has no effect. Instead, the target can cast this spell once without having to expend a spell slot or use material components. If the target doesn’t cast the spell within 1 hour, the invested spell is lost.</text>
		<text>Marriage: You touch adult humanoids willing to be bonded together in marriage. For the next 24 hours, each target gains a +2 bonus to AC and saving throws while they are within 30 feet of each other. A creature can benefit from this ceremony just once.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Chaos Bolt (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>120 feet</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Sorcerer</classes>
		<text>You hurl an undulating, warbling mass of chaotic energy at one creature in range. Make a ranged spell attack against the target. On a hit, the target takes 2d8 damage. Choose one of the d8s. The number it rolled determines the type of damage, as shown below.</text>
		<text>d8----Damage Type</text>
		<text>1----Acid</text>
		<text>2----Cold</text>
		<text>3----Fire</text>
		<text>4----Force</text>
		<text>5----Lightning</text>
		<text>6----Poison</text>
		<text>7----Psychic</text>
		<text>8----Thunder</text>
		<text>If you roll the same number on both d8s, the chaotic energy leaps from the target to a different creature of your choice within 30 feet of it. Make a new attack roll against the new target, and make a new damage roll, which could cause the chaotic energy to leap again. A creature can be targeted only once by this mass of chaotic energy.</text>
		<text>At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 2nd level or higher, each target takes extra damage of the type rolled. The extra damage equals 1d6 for each slot level above 1st.</text>
		<roll>2d8</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Conjure Barlgura</name>
		<level>4</level>
		<school>C</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>60 feet</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Up to 10 minutes</duration>
		<classes>Wizard, Sorcerer</classes>
		<text>You summon a barlgura that appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The barlgura disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</text>
		<text />
		<text>The barlgura is hostile to all non‑demons. Roll initiative for the barlgura, which has its own turns. At the start of its turn, it moves toward and attacks the nearest non‑demon it can perceive. If two or more creatures are equally near, it picks one at random. If it cannot see any potential enemies, the barlgura moves in a random direction in search of foes.</text>
		<text />
		<text>As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground using the blood of an intelligent humanoid slain within the past 24 hours. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned barlgura cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Conjure Hezrou</name>
		<level>7</level>
		<school>C</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>60 feet</range>
		<components>V, S, M (food worth at least 100 gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
		<classes>Wizard, Sorcerer</classes>
		<text>You summon a hezrou that appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The hezrou disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</text>
		<text />
		<text>The hezrou’s attitude depends on the value of the food used as a material component for this spell. Roll initiative for the hezrou, which has its own turns. At the start of the hezrou’s turn, the DM makes a secret Charisma check on your behalf, with a bonus equal to the food’s value divided by 20. The check DC starts at 10 and increases by 2 each round. You can issue orders to the hezrou and have it obey you as long as you succeed on the Charisma check.</text>
		<text />
		<text>If the check fails, the spell no longer requires concentration and the demon is no longer under your control. The hezrou then focuses on devouring any corpses it can see. If there are no such meals at hand, it attacks the nearest creatures and eats anything it kills. If its hit points are reduced to below half its hit point maximum, it returns to the Abyss.</text> 
		<text />
		<text>As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground using the blood of an intelligent humanoid slain within the past 24 hours. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned hezrou cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts.</text>
	</spell>	
	<spell>
		<name>Conjure Lesser Demon </name>
		<level>3</level>
		<school>C</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>60 feet</range>
		<components>V, S, M (a vial of blood from an intelligent humanoid killed within the past 24 hours)</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
		<classes>Wizard, Sorcerer</classes>
		<text>You summon up to a total of eight manes or dretches that appear in unoccupied spaces you can see within range. A manes or dretch disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</text>
		<text />
		<text>The demons are hostile to all creatures. Roll initiative for the summoned demons as a group, which has its own turns. The demons attack the nearest non‑demons to the best of their ability.</text>
		<text />
		<text>As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground with the blood used as a material component. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned demons cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts. Using the material component in this manner consumes it.</text>
		<text />
		<text>At Higher Levels. When you cast this spell using a spell slot of 6th or 7th level, you summon sixteen demons. If you cast it using a spell slot of 8th or 9th level, you summon thirty‑two demons.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Conjure Shadow Demon</name>
		<level>4</level> 
		<school>C</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>60 feet</range>
		<components>V, S, M (a vial of blood from an intelligent humanoid killed within the past 24 hours) </components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
		<classes>Wizard, Sorcerer</classes>
		<text>You summon a shadow demon that appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The shadow demon disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</text>
		<text />
		<text>Roll initiative for the shadow demon, which has its own turns. You can issue orders to the shadow demon, and it obeys you as long as it can attack a creature on each of its turns and does not start its turn in an area of bright light. If either of these conditions is not met, the shadow demon immediately makes a Charisma check contested by your Charisma check. If you fail the check, the spell no longer requires concentration and the demon is no longer under your control. The demon automatically succeeds on the check if it is more than 100 feet away from you.</text>
		<text />
		<text>As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground using the blood of an intelligent humanoid slain within the past 24 hours. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned shadow demon cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Conjure Vrock </name>
		<level>5</level>
		<school>C</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>60 feet</range>
		<components>V, S, M (a gem worth at least 100 gp, which the spell consumes)</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 hour</duration>
		<classes>Wizard, Sorcerer</classes>
		<text>You summon a vrock that appears in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The vrock disappears when it drops to 0 hit points or when the spell ends.</text>
		<text />
		<text>The vrock’s attitude depends on the value of the gem used as a material component for this spell. Roll initiative for the vrock, which has its own turns. At the start of the vrock’s turn, the DM makes a secret Charisma check on your behalf, with a bonus equal to the gem’s value divided by 20. The check DC starts at 10 and increases by 2 each round. You can issue orders to the vrock and have it obey you as long as you succeed on the Charisma check.</text>
		<text />
		<text>If the check fails, the spell no longer requires concentration and the vrock is no longer under your control. The vrock takes no actions on its next turn and uses its telepathy to tell any creature it can see that it will fight in exchange for treasure. The creature that gives the vrock the most expensive gem can command it for the next 1d6 rounds. At the end of that time, it offers the bargain again. If no one offers the vrock treasure before its next turn begins, it attacks the nearest creatures for 1d6 rounds before returning to the Abyss.</text>
		<text />
		<text>As part of casting the spell, you can scribe a circle on the ground using the blood of an intelligent humanoid slain within the past 24 hours. The circle is large enough to encompass your space. The summoned vrock cannot cross the circle or target anyone in it while the spell lasts.</text>
	</spell>
<spell>
		<name>Guiding Hand (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>D</school>
		<ritual>YES</ritual>
		<time>1 minute</time>
		<range>5 feet</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 8 hours</duration>
		<classes>Bard, Cleric, Druid, Wizard, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</classes>
		<text>You create a Tiny incorporeal hand of shimmering light in an unoccupied space you can see within range. The hand exists for the duration, but it disappears if you teleport or you travel to a different plane of existence. When the hand appears, you name one major landmark, such as a city, mountain, castle, or battlefield on the same plane of existence as you. Someone in history must have visited the site and mapped it. If the landmark appears on no map in existence, the spell fails. Otherwise, whenever you move toward the hand, it moves away from you at the same speed you moved, and it moves in the direction of the landmark, always remaining 5 feet away from you. If you don’t move toward the hand, it remains in place until you do and beckons for you to follow once every 1d4 minutes.</text>
		<roll>1d4</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Hand of Radiance (UA)</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>EV</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Self (5-foot radius)</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Cleric</classes>
		<text>You raise your hand, and burning radiance erupts from it. Each creature of your choice that you can see within 5 feet of you must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 1d6 radiant damage.</text>
		<text>The spell’s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</text>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>3d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Healing Elixir (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>C</school>
		<time>1 minute</time>
		<range>Self</range>
		<components>V, S, M (alchemist's supplies)</components>
		<duration>24 hours</duration>
		<classes>Wizard, Warlock, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</classes>
		<text>You create a healing elixir in a simple vial that appears in your hand. The elixir retains its potency for the duration or until it’s consumed, at which point the vial vanishes.</text>
		<text>As an action, a creature can drink the elixir or administer it to another creature. The drinker regains 2d4 + 2 hit points.</text>
		<roll>2d4+2</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Infestation (UA)</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>C</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>30 feet</range>
		<components>V, S, M (a living flea)</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Sorcerer, Wizard, Warlock, Druid, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</classes>
		<text>You cause mites, fleas, and other parasites to appear momentarily on one creature you can see within range. The target must succeed on a Constitution saving throw or take 1d6 piercing damage. If the target takes any of that damage, the target moves 5 feet in a random direction. Roll a d8 for the direction: 1, north; 2, northeast; 3, east; 4, southeast; 5, south; 6, southwest; 7, west; or 8, northwest.</text>
		<text>The spell’s damage increases by 1d6 when you reach 5th level (2d6), 11th level (3d6), and 17th level (4d6).</text>
		<roll>1d8</roll>
		<roll>1d6</roll>
		<roll>2d6</roll>
		<roll>3d6</roll>
		<roll>4d6</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Primal Savagery (UA)</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>T</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Self</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Druid</classes>
		<text>Your teeth or fingernails lengthen and sharpen. You choose which. Make a melee spell attack against one creature within 5 feet of you. On a hit, the target takes 1d10 piercing or slashing damage (your choice). After you make the attack, your teeth or fingernails return to normal.</text>
		<text>The spell’s damage increases by 1d10 when you reach 5th level (2d10), 11th level (3d10), and 17th level (4d10).</text>
		<roll>1d10</roll>
		<roll>2d10</roll>
		<roll>3d10</roll>
		<roll>4d10</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Puppet (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EN</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>120 feet</range>
		<components>S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Bard, Warlock, Wizard, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster) </classes>
		<text>Your gesture forces one humanoid you can see within range to make a Constitution saving throw. On a failed save, the target must move up to its speed in a direction you choose. In addition, you can cause the target to drop whatever it is holding. This spell has no effect on a humanoid that is immune to being charmed.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Sense Emotion (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>D</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Self</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
		<classes>Bard, Warlock, Wizard, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</classes>
		<text>You attune your senses to pick up the emotions of others for the duration. When you cast the spell, and as your action on each turn until the spell ends, you can focus your senses on one humanoid you can see within 30 feet of you. You instantly learn the target’s prevailing emotion, whether it’s love, anger, pain, fear, calm, or something else. If the target isn’t actually humanoid or it is immune to being charmed, you sense that it is calm.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Snare (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>A</school>
		<time>1 minute</time>
		<range>Touch</range>
		<components>V, S, M (30 feet of cord or rope, which is consumed by the spell)</components>
		<duration>Until dispelled or triggered</duration>
		<classes>Ranger, Druid, Wizard, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</classes>
		<text>While you cast this spell, you use the cord or rope to create a circle with a 5-foot radius on a flat surface within your reach. When you finish casting, the cord or rope disappears to become a magical trap.</text>
		<text>The trap is nearly invisible and requires a successful Intelligence (Investigation) check against your spell save DC to be found.</text>
		<text>The trap triggers when a Small creature or larger moves into the area protected by the spell. The triggering creature must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or fall prone and be hoisted into the air until it hangs upside down 3 feet above the protected surface, where it is restrained.</text>
		<text>The restrained creature can make a Dexterity saving throw with disadvantage at the end of each of its turns and ends the restrained effect on a success. Alternatively, another creature that can reach the restrained creature can use an action to make an Intelligence (Arcana) check against your spell save DC. On a success, the restrained effect also ends.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Sudden Awakening (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>EN</school>
		<time>1 bonus action</time>
		<range>10 feet</range>
		<components>V</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Sorcerer, Wizard, Bard, Ranger, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</classes>
		<text>Each sleeping creature you choose within range awakens, and then each prone creature within range can stand up without expending any movement.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Toll the Dead (UA)</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>N</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>60 feet</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Cleric, Warlock, Wizard, Fighter (Eldritch Knight), Rogue (Arcane Trickster)</classes>
		<text>You point at one creature you can see within range, and the sound of a dolorous bell fills the air around it for a moment. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw or take 1d8 necrotic damage. If the target is missing any of its hit points, it instead takes 1d12 necrotic damage.</text>
		<text>The spell’s damage increases by one die when you reach 5th level (2d8 or 2d12), 11th level (3d8 or 3d12), and 17th level (4d8 or 4d12).</text>
		<roll>1d8</roll>
		<roll>1d12</roll>
		<roll>2d8</roll>
		<roll>2d12</roll>
		<roll>3d8</roll>
		<roll>3d12</roll>
		<roll>4d8</roll>
		<roll>4d12</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Unearthly Chorus (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>I</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Self (30-foot radius)</range>
		<components>V</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 10 minutes</duration>
		<classes>Bard</classes>
		<text>Music of a style you choose fills the air around you in a 30-foot radius. The music spreads around corners and can be heard from up to 100 feet away. The music moves with you, centered on you for the duration.</text>
		<text>Until the spell ends, you make Charisma (Performance) checks with advantage. In addition, you can use a bonus action on each of your turns to beguile one creature you choose within 30 feet of you that can see you and hear the music. The creature must make a Charisma saving throw. If you or your companions are attacking it, the creature automatically succeeds on the saving throw. On a failure, the creature becomes friendly to you for as long as it can hear the music and for 1 hour thereafter. You make Charisma (Deception) checks and Charisma (Persuasion) checks against creatures made friendly by this spell with advantage.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Virtue (UA)</name>
		<level>0</level>
		<school>A</school>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>Touch</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>1 round</duration>
		<classes>Cleric</classes>
		<text>You touch one creature, imbuing it with vitality. If the target has at least 1 hit point, it gains a number of temporary hit points equal to 1d4 + your spellcasting ability modifier. The temporary hit points are lost when the spell ends.</text>
		<roll>1d4+SPELL</roll>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Wild Cunning (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>T</school>
		<ritual>YES</ritual>
		<time>1 action</time>
		<range>120 feet</range>
		<components>V, S</components>
		<duration>Instantaneous</duration>
		<classes>Ranger, Druid</classes>
		<text>You call out to the spirits of nature to aid you. When you cast this spell, choose one of the following effects</text>
		<text>• If there are any tracks on the ground within range, you know where they are, and you make Wisdom (Survival) checks to follow these tracks with advantage for 1 hour or until you cast this spell again.</text>
		<text>• If there is edible forage within range, you know it and where to find it.</text>
		<text>• If there is clean drinking water within range, you know it and where to find it</text>
		<text>• If there is suitable shelter for you and your companions with range, you know it and where to find it.</text>
		<text>• Send the spirits to bring back wood for a fire and to set up a campsite in the area using your supplies. The spirits build the fire in a circle of stones, put up tents, unroll bedrolls, and put out any rations and water for consumption.</text>
		<text>• Have the spirits instantly break down a campsite, which includes putting out a fire, taking down tents, packing up bags, and burying any rubbish.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell>
		<name>Zephyr Strike (UA)</name>
		<level>1</level>
		<school>T</school>
		<time>1 bonus action</time>
		<range>Self</range>
		<components>V</components>
		<duration>Concentration, up to 1 minute</duration>
		<classes>Ranger</classes>
		<text>You move like the wind. For the duration, your movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks. In addition, the first time you make a weapon attack on your turn before the spell ends, you make the attack roll with advantage, and your speed increases by 30 feet until the end of that turn.</text>
	</spell>
</compendium>