<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<baseclass>
		<name>Warlock</name>
		<hd>8</hd>
		<proficiency>Wisdom, Charisma, Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature, Religion</proficiency>
		<numSkills>2</numSkills>
		<armor>light armor</armor>
		<weapons>simple weapons</weapons>
		<tools>none</tools>
		<wealth>4d4x10</wealth>
		<spellAbility>Charisma</spellAbility>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<slots>2,1,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<slots>2,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<slots>2,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4">
			<slots>3,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<slots>3,0,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<slots>3,0,0,2,0,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<slots>3,0,0,0,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8">
			<slots>3,0,0,0,2,0,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<slots>3,0,0,0,0,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,2,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,3,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,4,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,4,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,4,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<slots>4,0,0,0,0,4,0,0,0,0</slots>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Proficiencies</name>
				<text>You are proficient with the following items, in addition to any proficiencies provided by your race or background.</text>
				<text>Armor: light armor</text>
				<text>Weapons: simple weapons</text>
				<text>Tools: none</text>
				<text>Skills: Choose two skills from Arcana, Deception, History, Intimidation, Investigation, Nature, and Religion</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Starting Equipment</name>
				<text>You start with the following items, plus anything provided by your background.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>• (a) a light crossbow and 20 bolts or (b) any simple weapon</text>
				<text>• (a) a component pouch or (b) an arcane focus</text>
				<text>• (a) a scholar's pack or (b) a dungeoneer's pack</text>
				<text>• Leather armor, any simple weapon, and two daggers</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Alternatively, you may start with 4d4 x 10 gp to buy your own equipment.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature>
				<name>Otherworldly Patron</name>
				<text>At 1st level, you have struck a bargain with an otherworldly being of your choice - the Archfey, the Fiend, or the Great Old One, each of which is detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 1st level and again at 6th, 10th, and 14th level.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Pact Magic</name>
				<text>Your arcane research and the magic bestowed on you by your patron have given you facility with spells. See chapter 10 for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 for the warlock spell list.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Cantrips</text>
				<text>You know two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. You learn additional warlock cantrips of your choice at higher levels, as shown in the Cantrips Known column of the Warlock table. (one additional at levels 5, 10)</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spell Slots</text>
				<text>The Warlock table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</text>
				<text>	For example, when you are 5th level, you have two 3rd-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell thunderwave, you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 3rd-level spell.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher</text>
				<text>At 1st level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the warlock spell list.</text>
				<text>	You learn a new warlock spell every time you gain a level from 2 through 9, then another every odd level. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what's shown in the table's Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 6th level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace it with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spellcasting Ability</text>
				<text>Charisma is your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells, so you use your Charisma whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your Charisma modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a warlock spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</text>
				<text>	Spell save DC: 8 + Proficiency bonus + Charisma modifier</text>
				<text>	Spell attack modifier: Proficiency bonus + Charisma modifier</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Spellcasting Focus</text>
				<text>You can use an arcane focus (found in chapter 5) as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
			</feature>
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature>
				<name>Eldritch Invocations</name>
				<text>In your study of occult lore, you have unearthed eldritch invocations, fragments of forbidden knowledge that imbue you with an abiding magical ability.</text>
				<text>	At 2nd level, you gain two eldritch invocations of your choice. Your invocation options are detailed at the end of the class description. When you gain certain warlock levels, you gain additional invocations of your choice. (one additional at levels 5, 7, 9, 12, 15, 18)</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you gain a level in this class, you can choose one of the invocations you know and replace it with another invocation that you could learn at that level. A level prerequisite in an invocation refers to warlock level, not character level.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="3">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Chain</name>
				<text>You learn the find familiar spell and can cast it as a ritual. The spell doesn't count against your number of spells known.</text>
				<text>	When you cast the spell, you can choose one of the normal forms for your familiar or one of the following special forms: imp, pseudodragon, quasit, or sprite.</text>
				<text>	Additionally, when you take the Attack action, you can forgo one of your own attacks to allow your familiar to use its reaction to make one attack of its own.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Blade</name>
				<text>You can use your action to create a pact weapon in your empty hand. You can choose the form that this melee weapon takes each time you create it (see chapter 5 for weapon options). You are proficient with it while you wield it. This weapon counts as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
				<text>	Your pact weapon disappears if it is more than 5 feet away from you for 1 minute or more. It also disappears if you use this feature again, if you dismiss the weapon (no action required), or if you die.</text>
				<text>	You can transform one magic weapon into your pact weapon by performing a special ritual while you hold the weapon. You perform the ritual over the course of 1 hour, which can be done during a short rest. You can then dismiss the weapon, shunting it into an extradimensional space, and it appears whenever you create your pact weapon thereafter. You can't affect an artifact or a sentient weapon in this way. The weapon ceases being your pact weapon if you die, if you perform the 1-hour ritual on a different weapon, or if you use a 1-hour ritual to break your bond to it. The weapon appears at your feet if it is in the extradimensional space when the bond breaks.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Pact Boon: Pact of the Tome</name>
				<text>Your patron gives you a grimoire called a Book of Shadows. When you gain this feature, choose three cantrips from any class's spell list. The cantrips do not need to be from the same spell list. While the book is on your person, you can cast those cantrips at will. They don't count against your number of cantrips known. Any cantrip you cast with this feature is considered a warlock cantrip for you. If you lose your Book of Shadows, you can perform a 1-hour ceremony to receive a replacement from your patron. This ceremony can be performed during a short or long rest, and it destroys the previous book. The book turns to ash when you die.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="4" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<feature>
				<name>Eldritch Invocation</name>
				<text>You learn an additional eldritch invocation</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<feature>
				<name>Eldritch Invocation</name>
				<text>You learn an additional eldritch invocation</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="8" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<feature>
				<name>Eldritch Invocation</name>
				<text>You learn an additional eldritch invocation</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="11">
			<feature>
				<name>Mystic Arcanum (6th level)</name>
				<text>At 11th level, your patron bestows upon you a magical secret called an arcanum. Choose one 6th-level spell from the warlock spell list as this arcanum.</text>
				<text>	You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
				<text>	At higher levels, you gain more warlock spells of your choice that can be cast in this way: one 7th-level spell at 13th level, one 8th-level spell at 15th level, and one 9th-level spell at 17th level. You regain all uses of your Mystic Arcanum when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12" scoreImprovement="YES">
			<feature>
				<name>Eldritch Invocation</name>
				<text>You learn an additional eldritch invocation</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="13">
			<feature>
				<name>Mystic Arcanum (7th level)</name>
				<text>At 13th level, your patron bestows upon you a magical secret called an arcanum. Choose one 7th-level spell from the warlock spell list as this arcanum.</text>
				<text>	You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<!-- Archetype features -->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<feature>
				<name>Eldritch Invocation</name>
				<text>You learn an additional eldritch invocation</text>
			</feature>
			<feature>
				<name>Mystic Arcanum (8th level)</name>
				<text>At 15th level, your patron bestows upon you a magical secret called an arcanum. Choose one 8th-level spell from the warlock spell list as this arcanum.</text>
				<text>	You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="16" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="17">
			<feature>
				<name>Mystic Arcanum (9th level)</name>
				<text>At 17th level, your patron bestows upon you a magical secret called an arcanum. Choose one 9th-level spell from the warlock spell list as this arcanum.</text>
				<text>	You can cast your arcanum spell once without expending a spell slot. You must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<feature>
				<name>Eldritch Invocation</name>
				<text>You learn an additional eldritch invocation</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="19" scoreImprovement="YES">
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="20">
			<feature>
				<name>Eldritch Master</name>
				<text>At 20th level, you can draw on your inner reserve of mystical power while entreating your patron to regain expended spell slots. You can spend 1 minute entreating your patron for aid to regain all your expended spell slots from your Pact Magic feature. Once you regain spell slots with this feature, you must finish a long rest before you can do so again.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<!-- Repeated Eldritch Invocation -->
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
				<text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Aspect of the Moon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You no longer need to sleep and can't be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
				<text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list; they do not have to be from the same class's spell list. The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</text>
				<text>	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
				<text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
				<text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
				<text>You can read all writing.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
				<text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
				<text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Ever-Living Ones</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Grasp of Hadar</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move that creature in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Improved Pact Weapon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Blade feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</text>
				<text>	Finally, the weapon you conjure can be a shortbow, longbow, light crossbow, or heavy crossbow.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lance of Lethargy</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
				<text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
				<text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
				<text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<!-- Newly available Invocations (level prerequisite)-->
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Cloak of Flies</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you're incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Smite</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Depths</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</text>
				<text>	You can also cast water breathing without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Maddening Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mire the Mind</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast slow once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: One with Shadows</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move or take an action or a reaction.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Signs of Ill Omen</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast bestow curse once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thirsting Blade</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Tomb of Levistus</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per warlock level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5" IL="IL">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
				<text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Aspect of the Moon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You no longer need to sleep and can't be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
				<text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list. The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</text>
				<text>	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
				<text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
				<text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
				<text>You can read all writing.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
				<text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
				<text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Ever-Living Ones</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Grasp of Hadar</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move that creature in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Improved Pact Weapon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Blade feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</text>
				<text>	Finally, the weapon you conjure can be a shortbow, longbow, light crossbow, or heavy crossbow.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lance of Lethargy</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Maddening Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
				<text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
				<text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
				<text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7">
			<!-- Newly available Invocations (level prerequisite)-->
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Bewitching Whispers</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast compulsion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Dreadful Word</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast confusion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ghostly Gaze</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As an action, you gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don't already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Relentless Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Your curse creates a temporary bond between you and your target. As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Sculptor of Flesh</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast polymorph once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Trickster's Escape</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast Freedom of Movement once on yourself without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="7" IL="IL">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
				<text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Aspect of the Moon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You no longer need to sleep and can't be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
				<text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list. The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</text>
				<text>	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Cloak of Flies</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you're incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
				<text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
				<text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Smite</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
				<text>You can read all writing.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
				<text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
				<text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Depths</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</text>
				<text>	You can also cast water breathing without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Ever-Living Ones</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Grasp of Hadar</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move that creature in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Improved Pact Weapon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Blade feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</text>
				<text>	Finally, the weapon you conjure can be a shortbow, longbow, light crossbow, or heavy crossbow.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lance of Lethargy</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Maddening Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
				<text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mire the Mind</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast slow once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
				<text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: One with Shadows</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move or take an action or a reaction.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Signs of Ill Omen</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast bestow curse once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
				<text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thirsting Blade</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Tomb of Levistus</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per warlock level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9">
			<!-- Newly available Invocations (level prerequisite)-->
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ascendant Step</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast levitate on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Minions of Chaos</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast conjure elemental once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Otherworldly Leap</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast jump on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Whispers of the Grave</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast speak with dead at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="9" IL="IL">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
				<text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Aspect of the Moon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You no longer need to sleep and can't be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
				<text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Bewitching Whispers</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast compulsion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list. The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</text>
				<text>	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Cloak of Flies</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you're incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
				<text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Dreadful Word</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast confusion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
				<text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Smite</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
				<text>You can read all writing.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
				<text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
				<text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ghostly Gaze</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As an action, you gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don't already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Depths</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</text>
				<text>	You can also cast water breathing without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Ever-Living Ones</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Grasp of Hadar</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move that creature in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Improved Pact Weapon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Blade feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</text>
				<text>	Finally, the weapon you conjure can be a shortbow, longbow, light crossbow, or heavy crossbow.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lance of Lethargy</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Maddening Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
				<text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mire the Mind</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast slow once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
				<text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: One with Shadows</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move or take an action or a reaction.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Relentless Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Your curse creates a temporary bond between you and your target. As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Sculptor of Flesh</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast polymorph once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Signs of Ill Omen</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast bestow curse once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
				<text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thirsting Blade</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Tomb of Levistus</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per warlock level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Trickster's Escape</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast Freedom of Movement once on yourself without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12">
			<!-- Newly available Invocations (level prerequisite)-->
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lifedrinker</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 12th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with your pact weapon, the creature takes extra necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="12" IL="IL">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
				<text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ascendant Step</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast levitate on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Aspect of the Moon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You no longer need to sleep and can't be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
				<text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Bewitching Whispers</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast compulsion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list. The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</text>
				<text>	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Cloak of Flies</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you're incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
				<text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Dreadful Word</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast confusion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
				<text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Smite</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
				<text>You can read all writing.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
				<text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
				<text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ghostly Gaze</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As an action, you gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don't already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Depths</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</text>
				<text>	You can also cast water breathing without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Ever-Living Ones</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Grasp of Hadar</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move that creature in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Improved Pact Weapon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Blade feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</text>
				<text>	Finally, the weapon you conjure can be a shortbow, longbow, light crossbow, or heavy crossbow.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lance of Lethargy</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Maddening Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
				<text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Minions of Chaos</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast conjure elemental once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mire the Mind</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast slow once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
				<text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: One with Shadows</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move or take an action or a reaction.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Otherworldly Leap</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast jump on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Relentless Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Your curse creates a temporary bond between you and your target. As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Sculptor of Flesh</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast polymorph once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Signs of Ill Omen</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast bestow curse once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
				<text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thirsting Blade</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Tomb of Levistus</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per warlock level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Trickster's Escape</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast Freedom of Movement once on yourself without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Whispers of the Grave</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast speak with dead at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15">
			<!-- Newly available Invocations (level prerequisite)-->
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Chains of Carceri</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level, Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast hold monster at will—targeting a celestial, fiend, or elemental—without expending a spell slot or material components. You must finish a long rest before you can use this invocation on the same creature again.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Master of Myriad Forms</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast alter self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Shroud of Shadow</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast invisibility at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Visions of Distant Realms</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast arcane eye at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Witch Sight</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can see the true form of any shapechanger or creature concealed by illusion or transmutation magic while the creature is within 30 feet of you and within line of sight.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="15" IL="IL">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
				<text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ascendant Step</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast levitate on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Aspect of the Moon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You no longer need to sleep and can't be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
				<text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Bewitching Whispers</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast compulsion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list. The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</text>
				<text>	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Cloak of Flies</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you're incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
				<text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Dreadful Word</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast confusion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
				<text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Smite</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
				<text>You can read all writing.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
				<text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
				<text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ghostly Gaze</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As an action, you gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don't already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Depths</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</text>
				<text>	You can also cast water breathing without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Ever-Living Ones</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Grasp of Hadar</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move that creature in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Improved Pact Weapon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Blade feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</text>
				<text>	Finally, the weapon you conjure can be a shortbow, longbow, light crossbow, or heavy crossbow.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lance of Lethargy</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lifedrinker</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 12th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with your pact weapon, the creature takes extra necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1).</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Maddening Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
				<text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Minions of Chaos</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast conjure elemental once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mire the Mind</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast slow once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
				<text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: One with Shadows</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move or take an action or a reaction.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Otherworldly Leap</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast jump on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Relentless Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Your curse creates a temporary bond between you and your target. As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Sculptor of Flesh</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast polymorph once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Signs of Ill Omen</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast bestow curse once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
				<text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thirsting Blade</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Tomb of Levistus</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per warlock level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Trickster's Escape</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast Freedom of Movement once on yourself without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Whispers of the Grave</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast speak with dead at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18">
			<!-- Newly available Invocations (level prerequisite)-->
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="18" IL="IL">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
				<text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ascendant Step</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast levitate on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Aspect of the Moon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You no longer need to sleep and can't be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
				<text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
				<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Bewitching Whispers</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast compulsion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list. The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</text>
				<text>	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Chains of Carceri</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level, Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast hold monster at will—targeting a celestial, fiend, or elemental—without expending a spell slot or material components. You must finish a long rest before you can use this invocation on the same creature again.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Cloak of Flies</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you're incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</text>
				<text>	The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
				<text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Dreadful Word</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast confusion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
				<text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Smite</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
				<text>You can read all writing.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
				<text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
				<text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ghostly Gaze</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As an action, you gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don't already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Depths</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</text>
				<text>	You can also cast water breathing without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Ever-Living Ones</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Grasp of Hadar</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move that creature in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Improved Pact Weapon</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Blade feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
				<text>	In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</text>
				<text>	Finally, the weapon you conjure can be a shortbow, longbow, light crossbow, or heavy crossbow.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lance of Lethargy</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lifedrinker</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 12th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with your pact weapon, the creature takes extra necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1).</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Maddening Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
				<text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Master of Myriad Forms</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast alter self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Minions of Chaos</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast conjure elemental once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mire the Mind</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast slow once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
				<text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: One with Shadows</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move or take an action or a reaction.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Otherworldly Leap</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast jump on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Relentless Hex</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Your curse creates a temporary bond between you and your target. As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Sculptor of Flesh</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast polymorph once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Shroud of Shadow</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast invisibility at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Signs of Ill Omen</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast bestow curse once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
				<text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thirsting Blade</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Tomb of Levistus</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per warlock level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Trickster's Escape</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast Freedom of Movement once on yourself without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Visions of Distant Realms</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast arcane eye at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Whispers of the Grave</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can cast speak with dead at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Witch Sight</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can see the true form of any shapechanger or creature concealed by illusion or transmutation magic while the creature is within 30 feet of you and within line of sight.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<!-- Unearthed Arcana Eldritch Invocations-->
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature UA="Revised Class Options" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Frost Lance (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="5">
			<feature UA="Revised Class Options" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Kiss of Mephistopheles (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can cast fireball as a bonus action using a warlock spell slot. The spell must be centered on the creature you hit with eldritch blast.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<!-- Eldritch Invocations from Warlock & Wizard not repeated/replaced in Revised Class Options-->
		<autolevel level="2">
			<feature UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Caiphon's Beacon (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: The Great Old One patron</text>
				<text/>
				<text>The purple star Caiphon is the doom of inexperienced mariners. Those who use its deceptive light to guide their travels invariably come to ruin. You gain proficiency in the Deception and Stealth skills, and you have advantage on attack rolls against charmed creatures.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, without replacement</text>
			</feature>
			<feature UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Chronicle of the Raven Queen (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: The Raven Queen patron, Pact of the Tome feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can place a corpse's hand or similar appendage on your Book of Shadows and ask one question aloud. After 1 minute, the answer appears written in blood in your book. The answer is provided by the dead creature's spirit to the best of its knowledge and is translated into a language of your choice. You must use this ability within 1 minute of a creature's death, and a given creature can only be asked one question in this manner.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, without replacement</text>
			</feature>
			<feature UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Raven Queen's Blessing (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: Raven Queen patron, eldritch blast cantrip</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you score a critical hit with your eldritch blast cantrip, pick yourself or an ally you can see within 30 feet of you. The chosen creature can immediately expend a Hit Die to regain hit points equal to the roll + the creature's Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 hit point).</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, without replacement</text>
			</feature>
			<feature UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Seeker's Speech (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: The Seeker patron</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Your quest for knowledge allows you to master any spoken language. When you complete a long rest, you can pick two languages. You gain the ability to speak, read, and write the chosen languages until you finish your next long rest.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, without replacement</text>
			</feature>
			<feature UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Claw of Acamar (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: The Great Old One patron, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can create a black, lead flail using your Pact of the Blade feature. The flail's head is sculpted to resemble a pair of grasping tentacles. The weapon has the reach property. When you hit a creature with it, you can expend a spell slot to deal an additional 2d8 necrotic damage to the target per spell level, and you can reduce the creature's speed to 0 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, in favor of Eldritch Smite</text>
			</feature>
			<feature UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Curse Bringer (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: The Hexblade patron, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can create a greatsword forged from silver, with black runes etched into its blade, using your Pact of the Blade feature. If you reduce a target cursed by your Hexblade's Curse to 0 hit points with this sword, you can immediately change the target of the curse to a different creature. This change doesn't extend the curse's duration.</text>
				<text>	When you hit a creature with this weapon, you can expend a spell slot to deal an additional 2d8 slashing damage to the target per spell level, and you can reduce the creature's speed to 0 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, in favor of Eldritch Smite</text>
			</feature>
			<feature UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mace of Dispater (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: The Fiend patron, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>When you create your pact weapon as a mace, it manifests as an iron mace forged in Dis, the second of the Nine Hells. When you hit a creature with it, you can expend a spell slot to deal an additional 2d8 force damage to the target per spell level, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, in favor of Eldritch Smite</text>
			</feature>
			<feature UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard" optional="YES">
				<name>Eldritch Invocation: Moon Bow (UA)</name>
				<text>Prerequisite: The Archfey patron, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
				<text/>
				<text>You can create a longbow using your Pact of the Blade feature. When you draw back its string and fire, it creates an arrow of white wood, which vanishes after 1 minute. You have advantage on attack rolls against lycanthropes with the bow. When you hit a creature with it, you can expend a spell slot to deal an additional 2d8 radiant damage to the target per spell level.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
				<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, in favor of Eldritch Smite</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</baseclass>
	<!-- PHB/Official Eldritch Invocations as Spells -->
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Agonizing Blast</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
		<text/>
		<text>When you cast eldritch blast, add your Charisma modifier to the damage it deals on a hit.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Armor of Shadows</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can cast mage armor on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ascendant Step</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast levitate on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Aspect of the Moon</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You no longer need to sleep and can't be forced to sleep by any means. To gain the benefits of a long rest, you can spend all 8 hours doing light activity, such as reading your Book of Shadows and keeping watch.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beast Speech</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can cast speak with animals at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Beguiling Influence</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You gain proficiency in the Deception and Persuasion skills.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Bewitching Whispers</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast compulsion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Book of Ancient Secrets</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Tome feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can now inscribe magical rituals in your Book of Shadows. Choose two 1st-level spells that have the ritual tag from any class's spell list. The spells appear in the book and don't count against the number of spells you know. With your Book of Shadows in hand, you can cast the chosen spells as rituals. You can't cast the spells except as rituals, unless you've learned them by some other means. You can also cast a warlock spell you know as a ritual if it has the ritual tag.</text>
		<text>	On your adventures, you can add other ritual spells to your Book of Shadows. When you find such a spell, you can add it to the book if the spell's level is equal to or less than half your warlock level (rounded up) and if you can spare the time to transcribe the spell. For each level of the spell, the transcription process takes 2 hours and costs 50 gp for the rare inks needed to inscribe it.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Chains of Carceri</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 15th level, Pact of the Chain feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast hold monster at will—targeting a celestial, fiend, or elemental—without expending a spell slot or material components. You must finish a long rest before you can use this invocation on the same creature again.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Cloak of Flies</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>As a bonus action, you can surround yourself with a magical aura that looks like buzzing flies. The aura extends 5 feet from you in every direction, but not through total cover. It lasts until you're incapacitated or you dismiss it as a bonus action.</text>
		<text>	The aura grants you advantage on Charisma (Intimidation) checks but disadvantage on all other Charisma checks. Any other creature that starts its turn in the aura takes poison damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum of 0 damage).</text>
		<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Devil's Sight</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can see normally in darkness, both magical and nonmagical, to a distance of 120 feet.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Dreadful Word</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast confusion once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Sight</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can cast detect magic at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Smite</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Once per turn when you hit a creature with your pact weapon, you can expend a warlock spell slot to deal an extra 1d8 force damage to the target, plus another 1d8 per level of the spell slot, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eldritch Spear</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
		<text/>
		<text>When you cast eldritch blast, its range is 300 feet.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Eyes of the Rune Keeper</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can read all writing.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Fiendish Vigor</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can cast false life on yourself at will as a 1st-level spell, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gaze of Two Minds</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can use your action to touch a willing humanoid and perceive through its senses until the end of your next turn. As long as the creature is on the same plane of existence as you, you can use your action on subsequent turns to maintain this connection, extending the duration until the end of your next turn. While perceiving through the other creature's senses, you benefit from any special senses possessed by that creature, and you are blinded and deafened to your own surroundings.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Ghostly Gaze</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>As an action, you gain the ability to see through solid objects to a range of 30 feet. Within that range, you have darkvision if you don't already have it. This special sight lasts for 1 minute or until your concentration ends (as if you were concentrating on a spell). During that time, you perceive objects as ghostly, transparent images.</text>
		<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Depths</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can breathe underwater, and you gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed.</text>
		<text>	You can also cast water breathing without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Gift of the Ever-Living Ones</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Whenever you regain hit points while your familiar is within 100 feet of you, treat any dice rolled to determine the hit points you regain as having rolled their maximum value for you.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Grasp of Hadar</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can move that creature in a straight line 10 feet closer to you.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Improved Pact Weapon</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Blade feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can use any weapon you summon with your Pact of the Blade feature as a spellcasting focus for your warlock spells.</text>
		<text>	In addition, the weapon gains a +1 bonus to its attack and damage rolls, unless it is a magic weapon that already has a bonus to those rolls.</text>
		<text>	Finally, the weapon you conjure can be a shortbow, longbow, light crossbow, or heavy crossbow.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lance of Lethargy</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Lifedrinker</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 12th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>When you hit a creature with your pact weapon, the creature takes extra necrotic damage equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum 1).</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Maddening Hex</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
		<text/>
		<text>As a bonus action, you cause a psychic disturbance around the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. When you do so, you deal psychic damage to the cursed target and each creature of your choice within 5 feet of it. The psychic damage equals your Charisma modifier (minimum of 1 damage). To use this invocation, you must be able to see the cursed target, and it must be within 30 feet of you.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mask of Many Faces</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can cast disguise self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Master of Myriad Forms</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast alter self at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Minions of Chaos</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast conjure elemental once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mire the Mind</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast slow once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Misty Visions</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can cast silent image at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: One with Shadows</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>When you are in an area of dim light or darkness, you can use your action to become invisible until you move or take an action or a reaction.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Otherworldly Leap</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast jump on yourself at will, without expending a spell slot or material components.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Relentless Hex</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 7th level, Hex spell or a warlock feature that curses</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Your curse creates a temporary bond between you and your target. As a bonus action, you can magically teleport up to 30 feet to an unoccupied space you can see within 5 feet of the target cursed by your Hex spell or by a warlock feature of yours, such as Hexblade's Curse and Sign of Ill Omen. To teleport in this way, you must be able to see the cursed target.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Repelling Blast</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
		<text/>
		<text>When you hit a creature with eldritch blast, you can push the creature up to 10 feet away from you in a straight line.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Sculptor of Flesh</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast polymorph once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Shroud of Shadow</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast invisibility at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Signs of Ill Omen</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast bestow curse once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thief of Five Fates</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>You can cast bane once using a warlock spell slot. You can't do so again until you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Thirsting Blade</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can attack with your pact weapon twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Tomb of Levistus</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>As a reaction when you take damage, you can entomb yourself in ice, which melts away at the end of your next turn. You gain 10 temporary hit points per warlock level, which take as much of the triggering damage as possible. Immediately after you take the damage, you gain vulnerability to fire damage, your speed is reduced to 0, and you are incapacitated. These effects, including any remaining temporary hit points, all end when the ice melts.</text>
		<text>	Once you use this invocation, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Trickster's Escape</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 7th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast Freedom of Movement once on yourself without expending a spell slot. You regain the ability to do so when you finish a long rest.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Visions of Distant Realms</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast arcane eye at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Voice of the Chain Master</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: Pact of the Chain feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can communicate telepathically with your familiar and perceive through your familiar's senses as long as you are on the same plane of existence. Additionally, while perceiving through your familiar's senses, you can also speak through your familiar in your own voice, even if your familiar is normally incapable of speech.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Whispers of the Grave</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 9th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can cast speak with dead at will, without expending a spell slot.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Witch Sight</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 15th level</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can see the true form of any shapechanger or creature concealed by illusion or transmutation magic while the creature is within 30 feet of you and within line of sight.</text>
	</spell>
	<!-- Unearthed Arcana Eldritch Invocations as Spells -->
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Caiphon's Beacon (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: The Great Old One patron</text>
		<text/>
		<text>The purple star Caiphon is the doom of inexperienced mariners. Those who use its deceptive light to guide their travels invariably come to ruin. You gain proficiency in the Deception and Stealth skills, and you have advantage on attack rolls against charmed creatures.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
		<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, without replacement</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Chronicle of the Raven Queen (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: The Raven Queen patron, Pact of the Tome feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can place a corpse's hand or similar appendage on your Book of Shadows and ask one question aloud. After 1 minute, the answer appears written in blood in your book. The answer is provided by the dead creature's spirit to the best of its knowledge and is translated into a language of your choice. You must use this ability within 1 minute of a creature's death, and a given creature can only be asked one question in this manner.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
		<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, without replacement</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Claw of Acamar (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: The Great Old One patron, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can create a black, lead flail using your Pact of the Blade feature. The flail's head is sculpted to resemble a pair of grasping tentacles. The weapon has the reach property. When you hit a creature with it, you can expend a spell slot to deal an additional 2d8 necrotic damage to the target per spell level, and you can reduce the creature's speed to 0 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
		<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, in favor of Eldritch Smite</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Curse Bringer (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: The Hexblade patron, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can create a greatsword forged from silver, with black runes etched into its blade, using your Pact of the Blade feature. If you reduce a target cursed by your Hexblade's Curse to 0 hit points with this sword, you can immediately change the target of the curse to a different creature. This change doesn't extend the curse's duration.</text>
		<text>	When you hit a creature with this weapon, you can expend a spell slot to deal an additional 2d8 slashing damage to the target per spell level, and you can reduce the creature's speed to 0 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
		<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, in favor of Eldritch Smite</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Revised Class Options">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Kiss of Mephistopheles (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: 5th level, eldritch blast cantrip</text>
		<text/>
		<text>When you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can cast fireball as a bonus action using a warlock spell slot. The spell must be centered on the creature you hit with eldritch blast.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Revised Class Options">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Frost Lance (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: eldritch blast cantrip</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Once on each of your turns when you hit a creature with your eldritch blast, you can reduce that creature's speed by 10 feet until the end of your next turn.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Mace of Dispater (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: The Fiend patron, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>When you create your pact weapon as a mace, it manifests as an iron mace forged in Dis, the second of the Nine Hells. When you hit a creature with it, you can expend a spell slot to deal an additional 2d8 force damage to the target per spell level, and you can knock the target prone if it is Huge or smaller.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
		<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, in favor of Eldritch Smite</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Moon Bow (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: The Archfey patron, Pact of the Blade feature</text>
		<text/>
		<text>You can create a longbow using your Pact of the Blade feature. When you draw back its string and fire, it creates an arrow of white wood, which vanishes after 1 minute. You have advantage on attack rolls against lycanthropes with the bow. When you hit a creature with it, you can expend a spell slot to deal an additional 2d8 radiant damage to the target per spell level.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
		<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, in favor of Eldritch Smite</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Raven Queen's Blessing (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: Raven Queen patron, eldritch blast cantrip</text>
		<text/>
		<text>When you score a critical hit with your eldritch blast cantrip, pick yourself or an ally you can see within 30 feet of you. The chosen creature can immediately expend a Hit Die to regain hit points equal to the roll + the creature's Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 hit point).</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
		<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, without replacement</text>
	</spell>
	<spell PS="PS" UA="Warlock &amp; Wizard">
		<name>Eldritch Invocation: Seeker's Speech (UA)</name>
		<classes>Warlock Eldritch Invocation</classes>
		<level>1</level>
		<text>Prerequisite: The Seeker patron</text>
		<text/>
		<text>Your quest for knowledge allows you to master any spoken language. When you complete a long rest, you can pick two languages. You gain the ability to speak, read, and write the chosen languages until you finish your next long rest.</text>
		<text/>
		<text>This Eldritch Invocation is from Unearthed Arcana: Warlock &amp; Wizard, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
		<text>	This was deprecated in Unearthed Arcana: Revised Class Options, without replacement</text>
	</spell>
</compendium>
