<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Warlock">
		<name>Warlock (Fiend)</name>
		<autolevel level="1">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>Otherworldly Patron: The Fiend</name>
				<text>You have made a pact with a fiend from the lower planes of existence, a being whose aims are evil, even if you strive against those aims. Such beings desire the corruption or destruction of all things, ultimately including you. Fiends powerful enough to forge a pact include demon lords such as Demogorgon, Orcus, Fraz'Urb-luu, and Baphomet; archdevils such as Asmodeus, Dispater, Mephistopheles, and Belial; pit fiends and balors that are especially mighty; and ultroloths and other lords of the yugoloths.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>Expanded Spell List: The Fiend lets you choose from an expanded list of spells when you learn a warlock spell. The following spells are added to the warlock spell list for you.</text>
				<text/>
				<text>1st - burning hands, command</text>
				<text/>
				<text>2nd - blindness/deafness, scorching ray</text>
				<text/>
				<text>3rd - fireball, stinking cloud</text>
				<text/>
				<text>4th - fire shield, wall of fire</text>
				<text/>
				<text>5th - flame strike, hallow</text>
			</feature>
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Fiend: Dark One's Blessing</name>
				<text>Starting at 1st level, when you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points, you gain temporary hit points equal to your Charisma modifier + your warlock level (minimum of 1).</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="6">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Fiend: Dark One's Own Luck</name>
				<text>Starting at 6th level, you can call on your patron to alter fate in your favor. When you make an ability check or a saving throw, you can use this feature to add a d10 to your roll. You can do so after seeing the initial roll but before any of the roll's effects occur.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a short or long rest</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="10">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Fiend: Fiendish Resilience</name>
				<text>Starting at 10th level, you can choose one damage type when you finish a short or long rest. You gain resistance to that damage type until you choose a different one with this feature. Damage from magical weapons or silver weapons ignores this resistance.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
		<autolevel level="14">
			<feature optional="YES">
				<name>The Fiend: Hurl Through Hell</name>
				<text>Starting at 14th level, when you hit a creature with an attack, you can use this feature to instantly transport the target through the lower planes. The creature disappears and hurtles through a nightmare landscape.</text>
				<text>	At the end of your next turn, the target returns to the space it previously occupied, or the nearest unoccupied space. If the target is not a fiend, it takes 10d 10 psychic damage as it reels from its horrific experience.</text>
				<text>	Once you use this feature, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</text>
			</feature>
		</autolevel>
	</subclass>
	<spellList class="Warlock (Fiend)">
		<index name="Blindness/Deafness"/>
		<index name="Burning Hands"/>
		<index name="Command"/>
		<index name="Fire Shield"/>
		<index name="Fireball"/>
		<index name="Flame Strike"/>
		<index name="Hallow"/>
		<index name="Scorching Ray"/>
		<index name="Stinking Cloud"/>
		<index name="Wall of Fire"/>
	</spellList>
</compendium>
