<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<compendium version="5">
	<subclass baseclass="Barbarian" UA="Barbarian Primal Paths">
		<name>Barbarian (Ancestral Guardian)</name>

		<autolevel level="3">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Primal Path: Path of the Ancestral Guardian (UA)</name>
                <text>Some barbarians hail from cultures that revere their ancestors. These tribes teach that the warriors of the past linger on in the world as mighty spirits who can guide and protect the living. When barbarians who follow this path rage, they cross the barrier into the spirit world and call on these guardian spirits for aid.</text>
                <text>	Barbarians who draw on their ancestral guardians fight to protect their tribes and their allies. With the spirits' help, they can hinder their foes even as they strike powerful blows against them.</text>
                <text>	In order to cement ties to their ancestral guardians, barbarians who follow this path cover themselves in elaborate tattoos that celebrate their ancestors' deeds. These tattoos tell epic sagas of victories against terrible monsters and other fearsome rivals.</text>
                <text />
                <text>This Primal Path is from Unearthed Arcana: Barbarian Primal Paths, and as such may not be allowed in your game. Consult your DM before choosing this option.</text>
            </feature>
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Path of the Ancestral Guardian: Ancestral Protectors</name>
                <text>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, spectral warriors appear when you rage. These warriors distract a foe you designate and hinder its attempts to evade you. While you're raging, you can use a bonus action on your turn to choose one creature you can see within 5 feet of you. Until the start of your next turn or until your rage ends, the chosen creature has disadvantage on any attack roll that doesn't target you, and if the creature takes the Disengage action within 5 feet of you, its speed is halved until the end of its turn.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="6">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Path of the Ancestral Guardian: Ancestral Shield</name>
                <text>Beginning at 6th level, the guardian spirits that aid you can provide protection for your allies. If you are raging and an ally you can see within 30 feet of you takes bludgeoning, piercing, or slashing damage, you can use your reaction to transfer your resistance to those damage types to the ally. The resistance applies to the incoming damage. Until the start of your next turn, the ally keeps the resistance and you lack it, unless you also have it from a source other than Rage.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="10">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Path of the Ancestral Guardian: Consult the Spirits</name>
                <text>At 10th level, you gain the ability to consult with your ancestral spirits. Right before you make an Intelligence or a Wisdom check, you can give yourself advantage on the check. You can use this feature three times, and you regain expended uses when you finish a long rest.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

		<autolevel level="14">
            <feature optional="YES">
                <name>Path of the Ancestral Guardian: Vengeful Ancestors</name>
                <text>At 14th level, your ancestral spirits grow powerful enough to strike your foes. When you or an ally you can see within 30 feet of you is damaged by a melee attack while you're raging, you can use your reaction to cause the attacker to take 2d8 force damage from the spirits.</text>
            </feature>
		</autolevel>

	</subclass>
</compendium>