<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<compendium version="5">
<subclass baseclass="Blood Hunter" HB="HB">
	<name>Blood Hunter (Lychan)</name>
	<autolevel level="3">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Lycan</name>
			<text>Of the many terrible curses that plague the realm, few are as ancient or as feared as Lycanthropy. Passed through blood, this affliction seeds a host with the savage strength and hunger for violence of a wild beast. Those that shun the curse spend their lives burying their wild, bestial urges deep inside. However, the power of a rising full moon makes the curse too strong to resist, and the host transforms into a terrifying animal-humanoid hybrid controlled by murderous impulse. Those that embrace the dark nature of their curse learn to harness their bestial gifts, but also succumb to the evil, vicious temperament that drives the beast within.</text>
			<text>	The Order of the Lycan is a proud order of blood hunters who undergo "The Taming, " a ceremonial inflicting of lycanthropy from a senior member. These hunters then use their abilities to harness the power of the monster they harbor without losing themselves to it. Through intense honing of one's own willpower, combined with the secrets of the order's blood magic rituals, members learn to control and unleash their hybrid form for short periods of time. Enhanced physical prowess, unnatural resilience, and razor sharp claws make these warriors a terrible foe to any evil that crosses their path. Yet, no training is perfect, and without care and complete focus, even the greatest of blood hunters can temporarily lose themselves to the bloodlust.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Lycan: Heightened Senses</name>
			<text>Starting when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you begin to adopt the improved abilities of a natural predator. You gain advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</text>
		</feature>
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Lycan: Hybrid Transformation</name>
			<text>Upon choosing this archetype at 3rd level, you begin to learn to control the lycanthropic curse that now lives in your blood. As an action, you can transform into your Hybrid form. This form lasts for 1 minute. You can speak, use equipment, and wear armor in this form. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using an action on your turn. You automatically revert to your normal form if you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die. The benefits of this form replace the rules for Lycanthropy within the Monster's Manual.</text>
			<text>	You can use this feature twice. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest. While you are transformed, you gain the following features:</text>
			<text>  • Feral Might. You gain a bonus to melee damage rolls equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down). You also have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</text>
			<text>  • Resilient Hide. While you are not wearing heavy armor, you can a +1 bonus to your AC.</text>
			<text>  • Predatory Strikes. Your unarmed strikes are considered a single weapon in regards to your crimson rite feature. You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes. When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike, you can make another unarmed strike as a bonus action. Unarmed strikes deal 1d4 slashing damage.</text>
			<text>  • Cursed Weakness. You have vulnerability to damage from silvered weapons.</text>
			<text>  • Bloodlust. At the start of your turn, if you've taken any damage since the beginning of your last turn, you must make a Wisdom saving throw to maintain control. The DC equals 10, or 15 if you have no more than half of your hit points left. On a failed save, you must move directly towards the nearest creature to you and use the Attack action against that creature. If there is more than one possible target, the DM chooses the target. Your turn immediately ends, and you regain control.</text>
			<text>	If you are under an effect that prevents you from concentrating (like the Barbarian's rage feature), you automatically fail this saving throw.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="7">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Lycan: Improved Transformation</name>
			<text>At 7th level, when you have an active rite while in your hybrid form, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</text>
			<text>	In addition, your hybrid form gains the Stalker's Prowess feature.</text>
			<text>	Stalker's Prowess. Your speed increases by 10 feet. You also can add 10 feet to your long jump distance and 3 feet to your high jump distance.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="11">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Lycan: Advanced Transformation</name>
			<text>	Starting at 11th level, you learn to unleash and control more of the beast within. Your hybrid transformation now lasts for up to 10 minutes.</text>
			<text>	Your unarmed strikes damage increase from 1d4 to 1d6.</text>
			<text>	In addition, your hybrid form gains the Improved Resilient Hide feature.</text>
			<text>	Improved Resilient Hide. You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons that aren't silvered.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="15">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Lycan: Iron Volition</name>
			<text>Beginning at 15th level, you've honed your willpower to better resist the violent urges of your lycanthropic curse. Whenever you make a Wisdom saving throw to maintain control of your hybrid form, you do so with advantage.</text>
			<text>	In addition, your hybrid form gains the Pack Hunter feature.</text>
			<text>	Pack Hunter. You have disadvantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of your allies is within 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn't incapacitated.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
	<autolevel level="18">
		<feature optional="YES">
			<name>Order of the Lycan: Hybrid Transformation Mastery</name>
			<text>At 18th level, you have wrestled your inner predator and mastered it. You can now use your hybrid transformation feature three times between rests.</text>
			<text>	You also gain the Blood Curse of the Howl for your blood malediction feature. This does not count against your blood curses known.</text>
			<text>	Blood Curse of the Howl. As an action, you howl at a creature within 30 feet, chilling their blood and stunning them with fear. If the target creature can hear you, they must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equals 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier) or be stunned until the end of your next turn. </text>
			<text>	AMPLIFY: This curse affects every creature within 15 feet of you.</text>
			<text>	Your unarmed strikes damage increases from 1d6 to 1d8.</text>
		</feature>
	</autolevel>
</subclass>
</compendium>
